<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_0">
        <text>Regarding your assignment…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_1">
        <text>Oh, I’m listening. Any luck in finding that notebook?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_10">
        <text>Yes. I found the notebook. In it were the coordinates of some meeting. I found a note where the meeting was supposed to take place, which led me to the old tunnel. Most importantly, I had to wait until night, which is when the meeting was supposed to take place. And so it did: I met a bandit who wanted twenty-five thousand from me. I had to drop him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_11">
        <text>That’s very strange. We should check out the case right away. There might be some very useful information inside…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_12">
        <text>All right. I’ll take care of the case… and I suggest you take care of the money that you owe me now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_13">
        <text>It can’t be. There’s a stalker base nearby. The bandits from the northern outpost know these parts well, so they would have known better than to go through there. It wasn’t someone local; I can tell you that. And what did he offer you for the money?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_14">
        <text>It was likely supposed to be payment for the case that he had.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_15">
        <text>Do you have it? We should check what’s inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_16">
        <text>I have the case, but the lock’s too strong. I can’t get it to open at all, and it weighs almost nothing. I doubt there’s anything useful inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_17">
        <text>That’s very strange. We should take a look at the case right away. There might be some very useful information inside…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_18">
        <text>All right. I’ll take care of the case. Just remember that, whatever’s inside, I won’t be giving it to you for free.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_2">
        <text>Yes. I found the notebook and paid twenty-five thousand for it. Now I expect thirty thousand back from you. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_3">
        <text>Shit… How come? What happened? Can you put it briefly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_4">
        <text>Not much I can say. I met a bandit in the tunnel who took away twenty-five grand from me, as per your request.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_5">
        <text>It can’t be. There’s a stalker base nearby. The bandits from the northern outpost know these parts well, so they would have known better than to go through there. It wasn’t someone local; I can tell you that. And what did he want for the money? And how did you end up there in the first place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_6">
        <text>I found a notebook at the site of the firefight. In it were the coordinates of some meeting. I found a note where the meeting was supposed to take place, which led me to the old tunnel. It was a trap, and I was forced to pay twenty-five thousand for some case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_7">
        <text>We need to see what’s inside the case. Do you have it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_8">
        <text>I have the case, but the lock’s too strong. I can’t get it to open at all, and it weighs almost nothing. I doubt there’s anything useful inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_actor_give_keys_9">
        <text>Oh, I’m listening. Any luck in finding that notebook?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_0">
        <text>Any luck with the case? Is it open?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_1">
        <text>Ha. Got it to open after all. It was a very tough nut to crack. What I found in the case was a flash drive and a folder with documents of some kind. I haven’t touched any of it, so don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_2">
        <text>Thanks, Van. What do I owe you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_3">
        <text>It was a lot of work, so it’ll be two thousand. Then you can have your stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_4">
        <text>All right. Here’s your money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_5">
        <text>I don’t have that much money on me…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_6">
        <text>Then I don’t have any flash drive or folder for you. Come visit me when you have the funds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys2_7">
        <text>Fantastic! The case and its contents are now yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_0">
        <text>Regarding the case…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_1">
        <text>Ready to pay for having it opened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_2">
        <text>Yes. Here’s the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_3">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_4">
        <text>Fantastic! The case and its contents are now yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys3_5">
        <text>Then come visit me when you have the funds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys_0">
        <text>Listen, Van, I have a case that needs opening. Can you take a look?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys_1">
        <text>Show me what you’ve got…\n \nWell, this is some strong protection. Whoever had this case certainly didn’t want it to fall into the wrong hands. All right… I can’t promise anything, but I’ll do my best to help you out. Leave the case here. After I’m done, I’ll get in touch with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys_2">
        <text>Thank you! Take the case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_furgon_crash_keys_3">
        <text>As I said, I can’t promise anything. Bypassing a lock like this won’t be easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_0">
        <text>Sidorovich, I have something for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_1">
        <text>Well, don’t be shy. Show me what you’ve got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_2">
        <text>A very interesting folder of documents and a flash drive from a case, as well as an old notebook and a note from a bandit. I think the information here will interest you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_3">
        <text>Give me more details. Where is this case from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_4">
        <text>I got a hold of the case through a strange series of events. Too long to explain. It was given to me by a bandit by the name of Skull. The documents contain information about collaboration between the bandits and the military. Will you take it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_sidorovich_zabral_flashAndDoc_5">
        <text>Well, it’s clear that the information is valuable. Frankly, I don’t care where you got it, but it’s good that you brought it here. Have this; you deserve it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_0">
        <text>The case is open. There was only a flash drive and a document folder inside. Here. Have a look.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_1">
        <text>All right. Let’s take a look…\n \nUh-huh… The flash drive contains a partial recorded conversation involving Borov and some other anonymous fellow. This is interesting. Let’s see what the documents hold…\n \nOh, wow… The picture’s getting clearer. It seems our faceless man is from the military… What you’ve discovered here, Beast, is quite literally worth its weight in gold. I don’t think Borov and his henchmen are gonna be too happy about this leak. And I think I know what to do with all of this.\n \nI’ll give you thirty grand for the docs and the flash drive. If you’re selling that notebook with the note, I’ll give you an additional three grand. I hope it’ll cover all of your expenses. So, we got a deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_10">
        <text>Then I’ll wait for my money. See you later!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_2">
        <text>Take it and give it to someone else. I have no use for it, and I have enough things on my plate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_3">
        <text>There’s just one other thing: after the events at the railroad embankment, I’ve gone short of money. Because of that, you’ll have to wait a day or two. I’ll return everything; I’ll return even more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_4">
        <text>All right. There’s no rush. But still, don’t take *too* long. Strange things happen to those in debt; they die for various reasons. Do you understand? And let the case stay here. It’ll be safer that way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_5">
        <text>No. For the second time, I’m not buying that. You will return the case without receiving the flash drive or the documents while remaining in debt. If I were in your shoes, I’d pay it as soon as possible. The Zone doesn’t favor those in debt, and neither do I. So, until I see my money, you better not cross paths with any mercenaries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_6">
        <text>Yes. I’ll pay you back everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_7">
        <text>Then I’ll wait for my money. See you later!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_8">
        <text>No. For the second time, I’m not buying that. You will return the case without receiving the flash drive or the documents while remaining in debt for my services. If I were in your shoes, I’d pay it as soon as possible. The Zone doesn’t favor those in debt, and neither do I. So, until I see my money, you better not cross paths with any mercenaries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dialog_zohan_pda_fleshka_u_menja_9">
        <text>Yes. I’ll pay you back everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_0">
        <text>Stop, merc! Don’t shoot! I give up!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_1">
        <text>Calm down. I wasn’t planning on shooting. You should tell me how you got here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_2">
        <text>I came from the Garbage to deliver some goods to Sidorovich. I decided to stop and catch my breath. I went under the bridge, by the fire, to tie my shoes, and then you showed up out of nowhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_3">
        <text>All right. Calm down. You can continue on your way. I’ll be going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_4">
        <text>Phew. You had me confused there. I think I’ll have a break and sit here a bit longer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_bobik_vagon_5">
        <text>Yeah. Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_0">
        <text>Shilov, I hope you haven’t sent the stalkers to the anomaly yet?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_1">
        <text>No. I was just getting ready to tell the people about the “Hidden Path.”</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_2">
        <text>Forget it. Don’t do it. It’s a trap.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_3">
        <text>Well, spill the beans and tell me what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_4">
        <text>You remember that corpse I told you about that I saw on the way here? So, after I talked to you, I had a sudden tingling feeling in my head, and even heard a voice. It was calling me. I don’t know how, but I knew where to go. Later on, it was clear to me that a controller was behind this, the fucking thing. Tell me: have you ever seen a controller in the Cordon? Neither have I; they don’t usually come around these parts.\n \nI think this has to do with the anomaly. I don’t know if I should share this, but I have a theory: what if someone who’s gone into the anomaly teleports into a predetermined anomalous area, and, at the same time, not far away from that very anomaly, some kind of beast appears? I don’t know exactly how the anomaly summons mutants, but there’s something very strange going on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_5">
        <text>If someone else was telling me this, I would’ve just told them to sober up. You, though… I can trust you, and if you say that anomaly is dangerous, then so be it. Although, I’m still gonna tell the scientists about it, and share your theory. I’ll share the pay with you. In the meantime, how about we share a bottle of my best vodka? I’ve been keeping it for a rainy day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_kill_controller_6">
        <text>Sure. A drink won’t hurt. Bye!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_0">
        <text>Orest told me you had some work that needs doing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_1">
        <text>Heh… Yeah. I’ve got some work, but how much will your services set me back, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_10">
        <text>As you know, merc… That’s your business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_11">
        <text>Don’t come to me with these types of assignments in the future. Good day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_2">
        <text>That depends on what kind of work you’re offering me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_3">
        <text>Fine. We’ll deal with that later. You’ve probably noticed by now that there’s an anomaly above the railroad embankment? A “Big Bubble,” it seems. That’s what the stalkers here call it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_4">
        <text>Let’s say I’ve noticed it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_5">
        <text>Well, I have a theory that I want to put into practice. I was listening when Scar, one of your men, told me about an anomaly that he encountered in the Red Forest. It’s called the “witch circle.” From his description, it resembles the one that’s “hanging” with us above the railroad embankment. According to what he said, it’s something like a teleporter: if you walk into the anomaly, it’s supposed to take you to another place. As it turns out, I need a volunteer to check whether it’s all true.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_6">
        <text>Why haven’t you sent any of the stalkers there until now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_7">
        <text>Truthfully, the local stalkers are rather afraid of even getting close to the anomaly. They use the tunnel under the embankment to get to Sidorovich. It’s not hard to understand where they’re coming from; this place has been full of unsettling rumors for a long time. Even though it’s all a load of crap, it scares the youngsters. I want to find out where that teleporter leads. I guarantee you that there will be no harm in going into it. I’d go there myself, but I can’t abandon my trading post. Will you go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_8">
        <text>I’ll go check this “Big Bubble.” Wait here, and I’ll be back with some answers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest1_9">
        <text>No, thanks. I value my own life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_0">
        <text>I just came out of the anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_1">
        <text>You actually went into it?! Tell me everything you saw. Is it really a witch’s circle?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_2">
        <text>Slow down a minute. You were right: the anomaly definitely works as a teleporter. It brought me to the tunnel outside the rookie village…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_3">
        <text>Hot damn! My theory proved true. Now, the stalkers will have an easier time getting to the village…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_4">
        <text>Hold on. I’ve had a strange feeling of some kind ever since I got out of the anomaly. I… can’t really put my finger on it. I met a stalker in the tunnel and spoke to him. He was alive, but when I was going back to you, I saw his dead body not far away from the farm. Doesn’t that seem a little strange to you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_5">
        <text>This is the Zone, my friend. Somebody’s always dying here, and the circumstances are almost always mysterious. Have your reward; take a drink; loosen up. You helped me, and I appreciate it. I think the scientists at Yantar will be interested in hearing about this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_6">
        <text>You work for the scientists?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_7">
        <text>Sometimes; not always. In return, they give me ammo from their warehouses. Freaking eggheads… They have no idea how to shoot a gun in the first place, and yet, the government sends them crates full of ammunition. If only we had firepower like that… Anyway, I won’t waste any more of your time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_shtik_quest_was_anomaly_8">
        <text>All right. I’ll go. Good luck!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola2_0">
        <text>I assume you’ve gathered my money?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola2_1">
        <text>Yeah. I even went to my own hideout; I kept a stash there for an emergency. So I decided to give up my loot and use all of the money I saved for this. I’m sure everything will pay off soon. Do you have the documents and the flash drive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola2_2">
        <text>Yeah. Here they are. Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola2_3">
        <text>Have this. You earned it. And thank you again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola_0">
        <text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola_1">
        <text>Well, I retrieved my loot from my hideout and sold it to Sidorovich. So now I’m ready to pay you my debt. I don’t want any bad blood with the mercs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_zohan_po_povode_dola_2">
        <text>Oh, now we’re talking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys2_0">
        <text>I want to ask you about something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys2_1">
        <text>Speak up. You know not to keep me waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys2_2">
        <text>I found a case not long ago. I want to know what’s inside, but it’s locked. It’s a tough lock, too, so there’s no chance in breaking it open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys2_3">
        <text>There’s a guy in the village. Goes by Van. Go talk to him; he helped me with a similar problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys_0">
        <text>I want to ask you about something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys_1">
        <text>Ask, and I’ll do my best to answer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys_2">
        <text>I found a case not long ago. I want to know what’s inside, but it’s locked. It’s a tough lock, too, so there’s no chance in breaking it open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kro_pomojet_vzlomat_keys_3">
        <text>Hmm… Let me think. I don’t know. Go see Van; he might be able to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_0">
        <text>Stop right there! Drop your guns! Hands on your head!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_1">
        <text>Calm down. I’m with the guys from the checkpoint. I found your note by the overturned wagon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_2">
        <text>Got the dough?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_3">
        <text>Remind me, how much is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_4">
        <text>You don’t get it? Trying to cheat me? Give me twenty-five grand, or I’ll bust a cap in your ass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_5">
        <text>Slow down. Here’s your cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_6">
        <text>’Kay. Seems like you have everything. Take the case and forget everything that just happened. Got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_7">
        <text>Hold on! What kind of case is this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="lisiy_dialog_tonnel_start_8">
        <text>Mmm… I don’t have the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_0">
        <text>You wanted something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_1">
        <text>Yes, Beast. There’s something I need to talk to you about. But first, promise me that you won’t tell anyone about this. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_2">
        <text>All right. Won’t tell anyone. What’s the matter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_3">
        <text>We ran into a few bandits by accident. Usually, they don’t go beyond the overturned Zaporozhets car… My point is: they were looking for something, and we just stumbled upon them on the road. Their behavior was also really strange. I saw one of them drop an old notebook during a firefight, and then I saw a gunshot… After that, my vision went black, and when I woke up, I saw you. I also saw them take captives and leave the area. You understand? Wherever I went, I couldn’t find them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_4">
        <text>Okay. And what do you suggest we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_5">
        <text>Can you go there, where you found me, and take a second look? Maybe you can find something. I have a gut feeling that those bandits were there for a reason. Don’t worry: I’ll pay up. You know me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_6">
        <text>All right. I’ll see what I can find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zohan_flair_quest_start_7">
        <text>I have better things to do than waste my time looking for something only God knows about.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>