<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="amk_metka">
		<text>GPS marker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_metka_s">
		<text>GPS marker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_amk_metka">
		<text>GPS markers are used in the Zone for marking stashes. If the marker is placed inside a stash, the stash will show up on your map along with a list of the stash’s contents.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	

	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1">
		<text>Note from Seriy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1">
		<text>Note from Seriy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1_descr">
		<text>A stalker’s note written on a sheet of paper torn out of a notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_mail_shpala">
		<text>Note from Crosstie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_mail_shpala_descr">
		<text>A stalker’s note written on a sheet of paper torn out of a notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_title">
		<text>Scavenger’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_title">
		<text>Scavenger’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_descr">
		<text>This PDA used to belong to a stalker nicknamed Scavenger. It is not locked and can be accessed. To open, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_a2_suget_5_gui_razia_title">
		<text>Barmitsa-PC radio transmitter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_a2_suget_5_gui_razia_descr">
		<text>The Barmitsa-PC radio transmitter is used to contact Russian military radio stations, such as R-159, R-163, R-168, and others. It is equipped wiuth a built in voice changer. The radio is built for military use in the field and is therefore very light and damage-resistant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_warning_module">
		<text>Decoder module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_warning_module_descr">
		<text>This device was made by scientists working in the Zone in order to see safe paths in anomalous areas. It can also block the activity of weak anomalous fields. Requires batteries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_bloknot">
		<text>Personal notepad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_bloknot_descr">
		<text>Sometimes, writing things down can help you find solutions…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tainik_padalshika">
		<text>Scavenger’s container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tainik_padalshika_descr">
		<text>A metal container used for storing loot, secured by a complex lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_radio_pharos">
		<text>Radio beacon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_radio_pharos_descr">
		<text>A device used for tracking radio signals within a large radius. In the Zone, this device can be used to locate stalkers by the signal of their PDAs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_rezerv_key_door">
		<text>Stockpile key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_rezerv_key_door_descr">
		<text>This key is used to open the armory containing the stockpile.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_klim">
		<text>Klim’s flash drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_klim_descr">
		<text>According to Sidorovich, this flash drive contains some very valuable information, and it used belong to a stalker named Klim. This is the flash drive Sidorovich asked me to bring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_container_name">
		<text>Orest’s package</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_container_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich has given me this fairly heavy case and told me to give it to Orest. He hasn’t told me what’s inside, and, to be honest, I don’t really want to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_pda_leader_base">
		<text>Father Valerian’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_pda_leader_base_descr">
		<text>This PDA used to belong to Father Valerian, who is now dead. The PDA is locked, and I can’t access it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_knife_killer">
		<text>Murder knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_knife_killer_descr">
		<text>This sharp hunting knife most likely belongs to the one who killed Lefty. If I can find the owner, then I can find out the murderer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_chimik_pda_title">
		<text>Chemist’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_chimik_pda_descr">
		<text>This PDA belonged to Chemist, the man who killed Lefty and Limp. This PDA might have some more useful information may prove he is, in fact, the murderer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_esc_pashalka_shved_pda_title">
		<text>Swede’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_pashalka_shved_pda_descr">
		<text>A PDA of dead stalker, whose body I found not far from the military outpost in Cordon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="blck_val_miklucha_pda">
		<text>Miklukha’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_miklucha_pda_descr">
		<text>A PDA, formerly possessed by deceased Freedom leader Miklukha. The PDA is password protected, so I can’t access it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_transiver_title">
		<text>R-250M2 radio transmitter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_transiver_descr">
		<text>The R-250M2 is a communications receiver that works on short waves and is favored by many radio hobbyists. Two versions of this receiver have been produced: the R250/M/M2 for land forces and R-670/M for the Russian Navy. The original 1949 version was a dual conversion superheterodyne with a tuning range of 1.5–25.5 MHz spread over twelve bands. The final version, the R-250M2, was produced from 1968 until 1980. The main change was the tube type, as the set moved from metal octal tubes to miniature tubes.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pb_quest_shell_brelok">
		<text>Shell’s dogtag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_shell_brelok_desc">
		<text>Shell is dead, and all he had on him was his dogtag. I should show this to Marcus.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_key_to_prison">
		<text>Cell key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_key_to_prison_descr">
		<text>A backup key to the Outpost cell. Since the death of Chemist, the key has been kept by Sologub, who leaves the key on the cupboard so that other guards can use it if necessary.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pb_quest_spez_razia">
		<text>DC 12V 9800mAh battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_spez_razia_descr">
		<text>A lithium-ion battery that’s feat for radios. It has a fairly large capacity. It doesn’t seem to have suffered any damage, which is very lucky considering this battery was taken out of a broken radio transmitter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_kanistra_gas">
		<text>Jerry can with fuel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_kanistra_gas_descr">
		<text>A metallic jerry can with a 10 liter capacity. Filled with diesel fuel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_bolt_box_small_title">
		<text>Bag of bolts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_bolt_box_small_descr">
		<text>A bag containing 5 bolts. Stalkers enjoy storing bolts in bags of this type.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
