<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_0">
        <text>Stop right there, you monster! Take another step and you're dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_1">
        <text>Markus, it's me… What's the matter with you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_10">
        <text>An old man led me out of the spatial anomaly. He called himself “Hermit.” He brought me to this place and told me I'd be safe here. He also told me something about you and Stronglav: he said that you were the one who created the creature after you were caught in a blowout in the Cordon. Since then, Stronglav has been with you the whole time. He was only able to manifest himself as a separate entity from you after you stepped into the space bubble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_11">
        <text>That's hard to believe… but if it's true, how do we get rid of this thing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_12">
        <text>I don't know. We need to warn the others. We need to be ready for Stronglav…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_13">
        <text>All right. Let's go warn the others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_2">
        <text>Don't try anything, you filth! Hermit told me every single detail! Do you think I'm gonna believe you're the real Beast? I'm no fool…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_3">
        <text>It's me, Markus. I don't know what that old man told you, but it really is me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_4">
        <text>Yeah? And how are you going to explain your attempt on my life? When I followed you into this space bubble, you attacked me. How do you explain that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_5">
        <text>What? But it wasn't me. It was probably Stronglav playing one of his sick games. I've never tried to hurt you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_6">
        <text>Maybe you're telling the truth, but I'm not about to lower my gun. It's for my own sake. What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_7">
        <text>I came here from the Outpost. Those damn Monolith fanatics caught Savage and hauled him into the laboratory. I tried to save him, but he died. Stronglav took over his mind. I blew up the lab entrance so that Stronglav would remain trapped inside, and I hope we never see that bastard again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_8">
        <text>So you don't get it?… Beast, that creature—Stronglav—you won't be able to get rid of him like that. He most certainly followed you here… Hermit told me about your link to Stronglav. You see, wherever you go, he'll come after you…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_markus_meet_good_end_9">
        <text>What?! Markus, what link are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_0">
        <text>Greetings, Beast. We meet again. Listen to me carefully. I don't have much time… Stronglav has grown in power. He's trying to control my mind, but I can still resist him at the moment…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_1">
        <text>What are you talking about? Stronglav couldn't have gone in here. I blew up the passage behind me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_10">
        <text>You're just lucky, but your luck won't save you forever… Remember: as long as you're alive, Stronglav will continue to exist…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_11">
        <text>So the only way to destroy him is to kill myself?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_12">
        <text>Yes. Unfortunately, that is the only way.\n \nHere… Take your old pistol. I found it in… Ah, what's the difference?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_13">
        <text>Why didn't you bring us out of the anomaly that one time? You helped me, but what about the guys, Sledgehammer and Marcus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_14">
        <text>I couldn't. You had to understand everything and go down this path… There was no other option…\n \nResisting him is getting more difficult… Promise me that when you meet Stronglav face to face, you will make the right choice… Farewell, Beast…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_15">
        <text>I promise! Farewell, old man…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_2">
        <text>No, Beast. You're making a mistake, and there's so much that you don't know… Stronglav is here, and he's following you wherever you go. Your connection to him is deeper than you might have thought.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_3">
        <text>What? What connection are you talking about, old man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_4">
        <text>Do you remember the emission in the Cordon? The one that struck you? After waking up, didn't you feel like some part of you was gone?… Did you feel the emptiness inside?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_5">
        <text>What are you saying? How do you know about the emission?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_6">
        <text>Don't be fooled. I've been following you for a long time. I know much about you… After the emission, part of your soul broke away from you, and that part took away your main qualities with it… and since then, this splinter has always accompanied you—always watched you—but… he was only able manifest himself as a separate entity after you appeared in the spatial bubble. The energy from the bubble has made him very strong, but has not given him a material body…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_7">
        <text>So… I created this beast?… How can I stop it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_8">
        <text>Stop it?! I'm afraid you won't like this method… Stronglav's current goal is to attain a material body, but the only body in which he can take root is yours… If he succeeds, your mind will disappear forever; *you* will disappear forever…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_otshelnik_meet_to_bad_end_game_9">
        <text>He has already tried to conquer my conscience, but he failed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_0">
        <text>What are you doing here, merc? Were you behind that explosion?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_1">
        <text>What I'm doing here?! I fought my way through the laboratory and tried to save a friend, which all went to hell… I had to block the way to your station in order to stop the creature that was chasing me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_10">
        <text>Okay. I'll show you where he is, but if you try anything stupid, you'll be sorry for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_11">
        <text>Don't worry. I won't do anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_2">
        <text>What?… You came from the lab? Well, it's a good thing you blocked the path to it… The outpost you came from has been closed for a long time. The mutants would constantly barge into it and attack us. We very rarely go there, and if we do, it's only to grab the equipment from the warehouse. And what kind of creature were you trying to stop?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_3">
        <text>Hard to describe. I can only say that it's been chasing me from the moment I ended up in a spatial anomaly, even after leaving it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_4">
        <text>It can't be. Another poor soul… A stalker came to us a few days ago and claimed that he got out of the anomaly as well. We didn't believe his nonsense, because his condition was bad, but now, we've got the same situation… So how do you feel, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_5">
        <text>I'll live. Can you tell me the stalker's name?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_6">
        <text>Well, he said he goes by Markus. Why do you ask? Would you happen to know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_7">
        <text>I do. Where is he?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_8">
        <text>He's still here, helping the scientists in the lab.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_zmeelov_digger_meet_start_9">
        <text>Okay. Can you show me the way to the lab?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, we meet again, Beast! I like your new style… You'll certainly fit right in with those fanatics.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_1">
        <text>I'm not gonna bother with you anymore, Hatchet. This isn't the time or place for conflicts. Get the hell out of here, or else it's personal!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_2">
        <text>Well, you're certainly not very polite. Time changes everyone, Beast, but you remain the same. From the very first day when you were rescued by Fish, I knew you were a real prick. You betrayed everyone! You even betrayed the man who taught you everything. The man who thought of you as a brother. The man who was willing to give you one last mag of ammo. The man who was willing to cut someone's throat just for you alone!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_3">
        <text>Shut the fuck up, Hatchet! You can't judge me! You don't know who I am! I'm warning you one last time: put your weapons on the ground and get out of here while you still can. And take your boys with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_4">
        <text>Not only are you an absolute scoundrel, but you also have a lot of fucking nerve. We'll just have to blow your brains out of your stupid head!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_killer_tesak_dialog_5">
        <text>As you wish, Hatchet. I gave you the chance to leave…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_lutiy_prisoner_dialog_0">
        <text>Aah, damn it… Beast, you shouldn't have followed me… This thing… It came out of nowhere; it was controlling the fanatics, and now it's trying to get into my head… It lured you here, Beast…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_lutiy_prisoner_dialog_1">
        <text>Savage, what the fuck are you talking about? That vile thing's still around there somewhere. Come on, man. We've got to get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_lutiy_prisoner_dialog_2">
        <text>No, no, no. It's too late… Listen, Beast: Petrovich showed me how to reconfigure your PDA. You won't be mixed up with the fanatics any longer. Aah… It's trying to get into my head again!… Stop it, Beast! Please… Don't worry about me. I can keep on going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx7_lutiy_prisoner_dialog_3">
        <text>I'll stop it, Savage. I promise!</text>
    </string>
</string_table>