<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_10">
        <text>They call that thing the “pseudoflesh,” and it's not as easy to deal with as a regular flesh… Many people tell stories about it, and even though I don't really care much for legends, when I saw the creature myself, I realized that all the stories about it were true.\n \nI remember this one time, I was walking around the Garbage when I heard a cry for help. I crouched down and slowly started to make my way towards the screams, but then I noticed something was off… The speech was all slurred, and I could barely understand what was being said. So, anyway, I crawled up to an old Kamaz car and hid behind the hood. I took a peek, and you wouldn't believe what I saw and heard… That pseudoflesh was screaming like a human being. I wanted to kill it as quickly as possible, but I couldn't get my gun out in time, and it escaped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_11">
        <text>Interesting story. And you think the mutant is wandering around here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_12">
        <text>Yeah. I'm telling you, its lair is somewhere out there. It's been acting too calm recently. In that area, there's a small cave where, even in very hot and sunny days, it still remains moist. The pseudoflesh is most likely inside. When we get closer, you should attack from the hill on the right side while I attack from the left. When you catch sight of that awful creature, make it run towards me, and I'll finish it off. But watch your back; there might be other mutants there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_13">
        <text>Got it. We headin' out now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_14">
        <text>Yeah. We should go. If all the things they say about it are true… We need to get rid of this problem right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_15">
        <text>Lead the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_17">
        <text>Yeah! We did it! We finally slayed that god awful creature. That's the one; I'm sure of it. Just like when I saw it back then.\n \nWell, a deal's a deal. You've helped me, and in return, I'll help you. When I leave the Outpost, I'll take you with me. Also, here. Take this. Extra payment for a job well done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_18">
        <text>Don't mention it. If you need anything else, you know where to find me. What are we gonna do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_19">
        <text>I'll keep that in mind. Well, you can go back to base. As for me, I want to study this mutant a bit. Maybe I can take something that's worth selling. When I leave the Outpost, I'll send you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_2">
        <text>Hello there, merc! I take it you talked to Rasputin?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_20">
        <text>All right. See you later!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_22">
        <text>Listen, I can't seem to find it… The damn thing's probably hiding somewhere, and finding it is going to take forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_23">
        <text>Maybe someone killed it already?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_24">
        <text>I highly doubt that. We'd definitely know about anyone killing it. You know how much hunters like bragging about their spoils? If one of them would have hunted down the creature, then the entire Outpost would know about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_25">
        <text>All right. So what are we going to do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_26">
        <text>Okay… We need to inspect the other part of this dump. Let's head over to the spot where I first saw it. Maybe we'll find it there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_27">
        <text>All right. Let's go, then…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_29">
        <text>You can go back to base. When I leave the Outpost, I'll message you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_3">
        <text>Yeah. I talked to him. Listen, Rasputin said that you were able to get me out of the Outpost. Is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_31">
        <text>So Rasputin said that you, along with some other stalker—Savage, I think—tried to blow up the Monolith construction site. Did you manage to pull it off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_32">
        <text>No. I don't want to talk about it. Can we leave the Outpost already?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_33">
        <text>Well, yeah. That's why I came here. I'm going to the bar; I have some business there. And after that, I'm heading to Yantar. If you want, you can come with. I'm heading out right now; you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_34">
        <text>Yeah. I'm ready. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_4">
        <text>Sure I can do that, but not for free. Money is not what I need, though. Instead, I need your help with a mission. If you help me with that, then I'll take you with me when I leave the Outpost. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_5">
        <text>All right. What sort of help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_6">
        <text>I need your help with finding and killing a certain mutant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_7">
        <text>Why won't you ask any of the hunters? They have more experience with that sort of thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_8">
        <text>Well, the thing is that I'm hunting this mutant for the scientists; they've asked me to bring them a piece of its flesh for further research. They promised to pay me a hefty sum for a job well done, but if I take the entire group, then everyone would want a piece, and there's not enough to go around for everyone. Bringing just one man with me is also out of the question, as it can lead to some unnecessary conflict, if you know what I mean. I'd rather take someone from outside our group and not tell them about this in first place. It's better that way. So are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_9">
        <text>Sure. I'll help you. First, though, tell me what mutant we're hunting here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_11">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_12">
        <text>Not yet… and I doubt I'll ever forget about it. Either way, we made it out, and that's what's important. Now we can carry on with our lives. Perhaps I'll see my family again soon. Right now, though, I'd like some time to myself. I'll talk to you later…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_13">
        <text>All right. I hope everything turns out well for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_2">
        <text>Finally you're out. Man, was that Saurel guy stubborn, but I did manage to convince him to free you. How are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_3">
        <text>Not too bad… By the way, the guard told me that Marcus didn't make it out of the anomaly. What the hell happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_4">
        <text>Yeah… It's true we couldn't contact you or Marcus, so Forester went back to look for the two of you, but he only found you. I hope he's all right. Being trapped alone inside the spatial anomaly must be maddening… Let's hope that Forester can reach the Red Forest so he can send Marcus the coordinates and help him escape.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_5">
        <text>Yeah. Let's hope he finds his way out. So how's everyone else? Is anyone from our group still here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_6">
        <text>No. Everyone left with the guide yesterday. You can't blame them, though, after what they've been through. I wouldn't be surprised if they end up leaving the Zone after this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_7">
        <text>All right… And what about you? What plans do you have for the future?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_8">
        <text>I'm not planning to go anywhere any time soon; I've decided to stay at the Outpost for a while and try to forget about that godforsaken anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_9">
        <text>And have you managed to forget about it, even slightly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_0">
        <text>Looks like it's over… Thanks, merc. We wouldn't have pulled it off alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_1">
        <text>Don't thank me just yet. There's still a chance the bandits could attack again. Saurel told me you found out about this attack by listening in on the bandits' hidden radio frequency, right? Do you have a radio tuned to their frequency?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_2">
        <text>I do. We should check if anyone was able to inform the bandits about our ambush.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_3">
        <text>Yeah. We need to know what the bandits are planning.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_end_0">
        <text>Damn it. They're sending another squad here. What should we do, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_end_1">
        <text>Don't panic. You two should get back to your position and prepare for our “guests.” I'm going back to my sniping position in the attic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_10">
        <text>Yeah, yeah. I know that already. Just listen 'til the end and then decide, okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_11">
        <text>Go on, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_12">
        <text>I bet you know about the big Monolith platoon that settled down nearby, right? Those assholes have been a pain in everyone's ass for a long time; both for us and for the stalkers on the farm. Those psychos have killed five of my guys. I doubt I need to tell you how many problems they cause for us, and for you too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_13">
        <text>And?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_14">
        <text>To make matters worse, they get backup and ammunition from somewhere, and their base is constantly growing. Soon, there won't be enough room for all of them. They'll take over the whole Outpost, and they'll kill us all off in the process. It seems the only option is to get out of here, but not too long ago, we managed to find out who's in command of the platoon. Werewolf is his name, but that's not all: we also know how to kill him without taking any casualties. And perhaps even wipe out some of his close friends while we're at it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_15">
        <text>Interesting… And how do you plan to kill him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_16">
        <text>We'll swat him like a fly. Two days ago, one of my fighters pulled a guy out of a Zharka. Well, he turned out be from the Monolith… and not just any regular cultist, but one of the high ranks in Werewolf's platoon. We managed to get some info out of him. It turns out that tomorrow, Werewolf is heading to a meeting with some other high ranking Monolith officer. This meeting will take place in the factory with minimal security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_17">
        <text>And you think two important Monolith officers won't have good security with them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_18">
        <text>I never said that. Obviously, Werewolf's guards and that other dude would be real professionals, but the thing is that this meeting is so secret that a regular Monolith fighter won't even know about it. We need all the help we can get here. To tell you the truth, I didn't want any outside help at first, but because these assholes iced five of our best guys, we have little to no chance of pulling off this operation alone now. That's why we're taking all the help we can find, and we could really use the help of a skilled fighter such as yourself. So what do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_19">
        <text>I need to think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_2">
        <text>No pasaran! Good to see you, Beast!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_20">
        <text>All right, Miklukha. I'll go with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_21">
        <text>There's no time to think. The meeting is going to take place soon, so we need to start the assault ASAP. More than that, though, we probably won't get another chance like this one seeing how the number of Monolith troops keeps increasing, and soon, they'll wipe us all out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_22">
        <text>I knew you were a real man.\n \nAll right. If you're in, then we should get going at once and prepare for the ambush at the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_23">
        <text>Lead the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_25">
        <text>I can't talk now, Beast. I'm too busy…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_3">
        <text>Do I know you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_4">
        <text>Oh, yeah. Forgot to introduce myself. My name's Miklukha; commander of this Freedom squad. As for you, there's no need to introduce yourself. I've already heard all about you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_5">
        <text>And what have you heard about me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_6">
        <text>Nothing too good, to be honest. However, I do know for a fact that you are a professional, and I just so happen to need someone like you for a job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_7">
        <text>What's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_8">
        <text>I need someone very dangerous taken out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_9">
        <text>Sorry, but I can't help you with that. I'm done being a hitman.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_0">
        <text>Greetings, servant of the Monolith. What brings you here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_1">
        <text>We came here to strengthen the Monolith's might on this earth.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_2">
        <text>We did not expect any reinforcements today… Where do you come from, and why are there only two of you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_3">
        <text>Um… I was sent here by my priest, along with five others. We came here through Limansk. Our path was full of tests and challenges that the Monolith prepared for us. However, not everyone withstood the Monolith's test, and only two of us survived. We were supposed to arrive here a few days later, but the Monolith showed us a faster way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_4">
        <text>Praise the Monolith for guiding you here. If you did not die on the way here, the Monolith has chosen you. You are needed here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_5">
        <text>I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_0">
        <text>Thank the Monolith, infidel, for he is the one who spared your life… If it was up to me, I would have killed you on the spot. But the Monolith forbids me to do so because he chose you for his trial. We are holding your friend hostage, in case you want to save him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_1">
        <text>You have Savage? What sick game are you playing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_2">
        <text>Silence, infidel! I am the only one who is allowed to speak here. Our prophet took your friend away to the north. I've marked the exact location on your PDA. If you want to save him, I suggest you go there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_3">
        <text>I don't need your suggestions on what to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_11">
        <text>All right. We're here. I'm going to stay on the farm for a while. If you need my services, I'll be here in the neighboring house. Good luck, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_12">
        <text>You too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_14">
        <text>Hey, merc. You need to get somewhere?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_16">
        <text>Can you get me to the metallurgical factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_17">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_18">
        <text>Sure I can. And since you're on an assignment for Saurel, I won't charge you anything this trip. So, are you ready to move out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_19">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_2">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. You the one who whacked these bandits? I was nearby and heard some gunshots, so I decided to check what's up. I thought the bandits were attacking stalkers again, so I wanted to lend a hand. But I see you managed all by yourself. What about you? You looking for something, or are you just passing through?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_20">
        <text>Well, we're here. I'll stay here and wait for you. When you decide to get back to the northern farm, come see me again. Just keep in mind that I won't wait here *too* long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_21">
        <text>All right, then. I don't think I'll be long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_23">
        <text>So, merc, are you ready to get back to the northern farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_24">
        <text>Yeah. We need to tell Saurel that someone killed Lefty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_25">
        <text>Yeah. It's a bit of a shituation, if you ask me… Lefty was a good dude, even though he did kill his friend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_26">
        <text>I doubt Lefty's the one behind Lame's murder. Lefty also got killed. The real killer's probably trying to tie up any loose ends.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_27">
        <text>If you say so. It's none of my business anyway. We heading back to the farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_28">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_3">
        <text>I was sent here by Saurel; that's all you need to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_30">
        <text>Hey, merc. You need to get somewhere?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_31">
        <text>I need to get to the metal factory again. Will you get me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_32">
        <text>Of course. Tit for tat. Ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_33">
        <text>Yeah. Let's move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_35">
        <text>Ready to go back to the farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_36">
        <text>Yeah. Let's move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_37">
        <text>I need to get to the anomalous grove. Can you get me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_38">
        <text>I'd be happy to get you there, but the problem is that the place is always filled with either boars or bandits. I'd much rather just get you to the farm that's nearby. It's a lot safer. From there, you can continue on your own, or I can get you to the nearby metal factory, if you'd like. So what do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_39">
        <text>A Freedomer by the name of Miklukha told me to come by; he gave me his coordinates. His location is far off, and I need someone to show me a safe path. Can you do that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_4">
        <text>So you're that mercenary who got out of the spatial anomaly with some other stalkers? In that case, I won't ask any questions. Just one thing, though: are you heading to the northern farm, by any chance?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_40">
        <text>I need to get to the old school. Can you lead me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_41">
        <text>All right. Let's go to that farm.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_42">
        <text>Tell you what: lead me to the metal factory, and from there, I'll go on my own.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_43">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_46">
        <text>Miklukha? Yeah, I know the guy. He organized a small base with his buds in the old school. We can head out right now if you like. So, are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_47">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_48">
        <text>Sorry, merc. I can't get you to the old school, seeing how Freedom's abandoned it. I heard that bandits took over that place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_49">
        <text>Fine. Then forget about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_5">
        <text>Yeah. I'm going there; I need to talk to Saurel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_50">
        <text>Will you get me to the Panskiy farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_51">
        <text>Yeah. No problem. Are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_52">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_53">
        <text>Sure. No problem. Ready to move out now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_54">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_6">
        <text>Wanna go together? I know all the safe routes around these parts. Plus, it'll be less boring that way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_7">
        <text>Are you a guide? Can you get me out of the Outpost?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_8">
        <text>Nah. I'm just a guy who knows the ins and outs of this place, but as for getting out of here, that's a whole nother story. The area around the Outpost is filled with dangerous anomalies, and only a professional can get you out of here safely. We have a guide who hangs out in the farm, but I don't know if he's there right now. Uh, anyway, I got a little carried away. We heading out to the northern farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_9">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_11">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_13">
        <text>Saurel told me that Lefty's dead. That true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_14">
        <text>Afraid so. Rasputin, can you help me with something? You know pretty much every stalker in the base, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_15">
        <text>May he rest in peace… As for the stalkers here, yeah. I know all of them. I'm the barman, after all. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_16">
        <text>Can you tell me who this knife belongs to?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_17">
        <text>That's Chemist's knife. He was looking for it all over the place. He was really nervous he couldn't find it; kept yelling and cursing while messing up the place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_18">
        <text>Where is he now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_19">
        <text>Well, he was looking for his knife everywhere. Then he said he remembered where he left it and that he was going there to retrieve it. Give him his knife when you get the chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_2">
        <text>Hey, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_20">
        <text>All right. I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_22">
        <text>Hey, merc. You wanna buy something or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_24">
        <text>You here on business, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_26">
        <text>So it turned out that Chemist killed Lefty? Damn. He had us all fooled… At least that asshole's dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_27">
        <text>I made him pay for what he did. Listen, I still have his knife… Maybe you wanna buy it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_28">
        <text>I made him pay for what he did.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_29">
        <text>Hmm… It's a good knife, so I'll give you three thousand rubles for it. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_3">
        <text>I'm no mercenary anymore. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_30">
        <text>Deal. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_31">
        <text>Nah. I'll keep it for myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_32">
        <text>All right. Here's your cash. So are you here on business or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_33">
        <text>Man, why you gotta be like that? Fine. I'll buy it for forty-five hundred rubles. That's the most I'm willing to pay for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_34">
        <text>Fine. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_35">
        <text>Money's not the problem here. It's just that this knife might come in handy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_36">
        <text>Great! Here's your cash. By the way, are you here on business, or did you just come here to sell the knife?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_37">
        <text>Fine. You don't want to sell it, that's your choice. I was wondering… Are you here on business, or did you just come here for a drink? If it's the former, I have some jobs I need taking care of.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_38">
        <text>Man, thanks for getting rid of that scumbag. I was wondering… Are you here on business, or did you just come here for a drink? If it's the former, I have some jobs I need taken care of.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_39">
        <text>Yeah. Saurel told me that you might have some jobs for me, and seeing that the guide won't be here for a while, I might as well earn some extra cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_4">
        <text>Sure thing, buddy… There's no such thing as a former mercenary. By the way, everyone here calls me Rasputin. And you're Beast, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_40">
        <text>Yeah. I have a job for you; nothing too hard. So one of my regulars spotted a rare artifact inside the anomalous grove near the metal factory. The artifact in question is a Kolobok, and I want it. The guy who told me about it couldn't get a hold of it. He told me that the artifact is located on the tallest tree there, and when he tried to get it, he fell off the tree and almost broke his neck. Anyway, can you do this for me? All you have to do get the artifact and come back here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_41">
        <text>Are you sure it's still there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_42">
        <text>I doubt anyone managed to get their hands on it. It's not like we have any rock climbers here. I'll even part with a Veles detector so you can find what I need more easily. And if you find any other artifacts, they're yours. Or you can sell them to me. So are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_43">
        <text>All right. I'll get you that artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_44">
        <text>Great! Here's the detector and coordinates to that place, in case you forget where it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_45">
        <text>Got it. I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_47">
        <text>Did you get that artifact yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_48">
        <text>Yeah. I have the artifact. Wasn't easy to get a hold of. What's more is that after I got it, I was ambushed by bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_49">
        <text>No kidding? And what did you do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_5">
        <text>I am…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_50">
        <text>It doesn't matter. What matters is that I got the artifact, safe and sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_51">
        <text>Nothing. I just ran off with the artifact. They couldn't catch up to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_52">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_53">
        <text>You did the right thing. They got what they deserved. The bandits have really gotten out of control, and this isn't the first time they go robbing someone here.\n \nAll right. Give me that artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_54">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_55">
        <text>Man, these bandits have gotten out of control; not the first time they pull this shit. I need to tell Saurel about this. Give me the artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_56">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_57">
        <text>And here's your reward, just like I promised. If you find any more artifacts, bring them here. I'll buy them off you for a higher price than anyone else around here; you can trust me on that. By the way, Saurel said he wanted to see you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_58">
        <text>Here's your reward. Pleasure doing business with you, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_59">
        <text>All right. I'll go see what he wants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_6">
        <text>Listen, Beast: I know that Saurel told you to deal with Lefty, but I doubt he's the one behind Lame's murder. They were good friends, and they could kill for one another. They always went on raids together; practically best friends. I've never seen a friendship as tight as theirs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_61">
        <text>Welcome to my bar, Beast. Are you here on business, or do you want a drink?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_62">
        <text>I had the artifact, but it was stolen by bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_63">
        <text>What?! And you just let them take it? I know you quit being a mercenary, but this is too much. How could you just let them take the artifact? I never thought you'd do something like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_64">
        <text>I don't care what you think. I'm not going to risk my life for your artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_65">
        <text>Whatever. No point in arguing over it now. I should have asked someone else to this job anyway. Ugh… By the way, Saurel told me he wants to see you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_66">
        <text>Okay. I'll go talk to him. Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_68">
        <text>Greetings, Beast! Listen: a mutant hunter came to the Outpost not too long ago. He said he needs a good marksman for a job, so I instantly thought of you. He leads the group of hunters that hangs out near the wagon, and he goes by “Hunter.” Have you heard about him before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_69">
        <text>No. Haven't heard of him. That's one ridiculous name, by the way: Hunter the hunter. Do you know anything about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_7">
        <text>So what? They were both drunk off their asses. Besides, I've seen similar things happen before.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_70">
        <text>Oh, yeah. I have plenty of stories about Hunter. I've known him for a long time. As a matter of fact, everyone knows and respects him… and some even fear him. He's a good friend and partner, and a good fighter. He's been everywhere in the Zone; came here in 2006. He himself said that the Zone is the best place for him. He adapted to this place quickly because he was a hunter before coming to the Zone.\n \nAfter he entered the Zone, he started selling mutant parts to people who needed them in the outside world. For a while, he also worked as a guide for tourists who wanted to see the Zone and hunt small mutants for fun. There's rich people who would pay for something like that. One guy, an American, came here to make a documentary film about the Zone… He died. That was the first and last tourist lead by Hunter. Since then, he stopped working as a guide for tourists. It's also where Hunter got his nickname. The American kept calling him “Hunter.”</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_71">
        <text>What does he need done?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_72">
        <text>I didn't ask him that. Why don't you go talk to him and see what he wants?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_73">
        <text>All right. I'll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_75">
        <text>Welcome to my bar, Beast. Are you here on business, or just to have a drink?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_76">
        <text>I think you'll make the right choice… By the way, if you want to make some extra cash, bring me some mutant parts, and I'll pay for them. It's one of the easiest ways to make money here at the Outpost, if you know how to field dress a mutant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_77">
        <text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_8">
        <text>Even if he was drunk, Lefty's not the kind of guy who would kill his best friend. Beast, I'm only asking to let Lefty explain himself before you do anything to him. Maybe he can convince you otherwise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_9">
        <text>All right. We'll see how things pan out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_10">
        <text>Well, he couldn't have gotten very far. Besides that, he's still here at the Outpost, although I don't know his exact whereabouts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_11">
        <text>All right. I'll try to find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_13">
        <text>What's up, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_15">
        <text>So, Beast, have you dealt with our problem?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_16">
        <text>Haven't discovered the real killer yet, so no.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_17">
        <text>What's that supposed to mean?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_18">
        <text>Lefty didn't kill Lame. I talked to him, and I could tell he wasn't lying. He told me about how he and Lame got a hold of some good loot and that they were drinking to celebrate. When they were drinking, they told a few other guys about their discovery; hence, Lefty's not the only one with a reason to kill Lame. Also, when Lefty disappeared after arguing with Lame, he was captured by bandits, so that means he couldn't have made it back to base. It's very unlikely that Lefty is behind Lame's death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_19">
        <text>All right. Tell you what: bring Lefty here, and we'll question everyone who drank with him that night. I won't tolerate rats and murderers around here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_2">
        <text>Listen up, merc. I've heard about your line of “work,” and if you try anything funny, I will deal with you accordingly. Are we clear on that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_20">
        <text>All right. I'll go get Lefty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_22">
        <text>Beast, where's Lefty? Did you bring him to our base?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_23">
        <text>Lefty's dead. The killer is “cleaning up” after himself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_24">
        <text>That bastard… We need to find whoever's behind this as soon as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_25">
        <text>Let's not rush this. It's not like we can revive the dead, and if we make a move too early, more innocent people might get hurt. But don't worry. I'll find out who did this, and I'll deal with them. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_26">
        <text>Fair enough. As long as you get it done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_27">
        <text>By the way, did you find out who drank with the victims?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_28">
        <text>Yeah. There were two other men: Burnt and Chemist.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_29">
        <text>I'll find out soon enough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_3">
        <text>Don't worry. After I went through in the space anomaly, I've decided to move on from my past. I'm tired of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_31">
        <text>Beast, go find Lefty. We'll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_33">
        <text>So, Beast, any luck finding the murderer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_34">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_36">
        <text>So, Beast, any luck finding the murderer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_37">
        <text>Yeah: it was Chemist. He wanted the loot to himself, so he snuffed out both of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_38">
        <text>What? Are you sure? I never thought Chemist would do something like this… He was one of my best and most trusted men, and what a piece of shit he turned out to be… May both Lame and Lefty rest in peace. They were good stalkers too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_39">
        <text>What's done is done. What's important is that we've avenged Lame's death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_4">
        <text>I see. And how are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_40">
        <text>What is this world coming to?… I still can't believe Chemist did this. He was the last I'd suspect; I even considered putting Burnt in the cage, but after questioning him, I was convinced he wasn't guilty.\n \nHere. Take this. It's your reward for helping us out. You helped us get rid of a huge menace, and that's worth a lot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_41">
        <text>Thanks, and goodbye. This is probably the last time we'll ever see each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_42">
        <text>Hey. Wait up. Where are you going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_43">
        <text>I'm leaving the Outpost. I don't like it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_44">
        <text>So nobody told you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_45">
        <text>About what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_46">
        <text>There's no way out of the Outpost right now; every way out is blocked off. One path has been taken over by Monolith, who are constantly patrolling it. The second path is covered by anomalies, and only an experienced guide can lead you through it safely… and our guide is gone right now. He's out escorting a group of stalkers through the Red Forest, and you're going to have to wait until he comes back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_47">
        <text>Goddamn it… All right, then. Guess I'll have to be your guest for a while. Do you have any more jobs for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_48">
        <text>Not right now, but if you need work, go talk to Rasputin. He always has something that needs doing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_49">
        <text>Understood. See you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_5">
        <text>Tanned and rested. Your jail cells are like a holiday resort…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_51">
        <text>What's up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_53">
        <text>It's a good thing you came by, Beast. A few problems have popped up, and I need you to help me out with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_54">
        <text>What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_55">
        <text>We managed to find a hidden radio frequency used by the bandits, so we tuned our radios to it. One day, when we were listening in, we overheard the bandits planning an attack on our base at night. They're planning on freeing the captive bandits here, and we need to halt their advance. Will you give us a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_56">
        <text>Sure. I'll help. What's the plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_57">
        <text>The plan is this: we seize control of the farm near the anomalous grove, and when the bandits get close, three of us will take them at the front, one man will take up a sniper position, and the rest will open fire at them from the abandoned buildings nearby. The bandits have no idea about our counterattack, so that should give us a great advantage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_58">
        <text>I'll take the sniper position. I've done sniping contracts plenty of times.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_59">
        <text>All right. I'll make sure to supply you with all the necessary gear. Anyway, I suggest you get ready; our ambush is taking place tonight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_6">
        <text>Sorry about locking you up, but we had to take measures. Savage vouched for you and told me about how you helped everyone in the space anomaly, so I decided to set you free. And even though things are fine and dandy around here, we could use the help of someone like you, and seeing as my men saved you from a group of bandits, you do owe them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_60">
        <text>All right, Saurel. I'll go get ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_61">
        <text>Right, right. Go get ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_63">
        <text>What's up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_65">
        <text>Any news, Beast? Did you manage to fight off the bandits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_66">
        <text>Both of your men are alive. We managed to repel the bandits as well as their backup party.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_67">
        <text>We repelled the bandits along with their backup party. However, not all of us got out alive: Tailor died.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_68">
        <text>Great news, Beast! I didn't want to interfere with the eavesdropping, so I didn't contact you through the radio. What's this “backup party” you mentioned?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_69">
        <text>After we disposed of the first group, we overheard additional bandits on the radio. They were sending a scout party to see what's going on. They probably got spooked when the first team didn't answer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_7">
        <text>All right. What's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_70">
        <text>Oh. I see… Anyway, I doubt those scumbags will ever show their faces around here again. Thanks for helping us fight them off, Beast. Here's your reward… And by the way, keep the sniper rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_71">
        <text>Thank you. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_72">
        <text>May he rest in peace. He was a good stalker. He would always put his neck on the line to save his fellow stalkers. We should give him a proper burial… You said something about a second group of bandits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_74">
        <text>Hey. What's up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_8">
        <text>We had an incident the day before you came here. Long story short, we have a killer on the loose; one of our stalkers got his throat slit. He and his friend were squabbling about something and got into a fight, and after a while, one of them, Lame, was found dead, while his friend Lefty disappeared somewhere. Your job is to find Lefty and make him pay for his actions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_9">
        <text>Where should I look for him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_0">
        <text>Can you answer a few questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_1">
        <text>Ask away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_22">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_221">
        <text>Ask away, and I'll tell you what I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_222">
        <text>Ever since my first day here, I've been wondering: is the Zone really expanding, or is it just hearsay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223001">
        <text>What do you think? Of course it's true. Way back when, the Zone was a lot smaller than it is now. When the Zone emerged, its borders stretched out north of Rostok. I don't know the exact boundaries, but what we do know is that the Zone's first border was somewhere around the military warehouses.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223002">
        <text>How fast is it expanding? Right now, there are plenty of anomalies here. Were they fewer here before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223003">
        <text>Believe what you want, but a year ago, this place was completely devoid of anomalies. Five years ago, this place wasn't even considered part of the Zone, and back then, the army had an outpost in the northern part of the Garbage. But after the Zone started to expand, the military was forced to relocate. I have no idea how it's expanding so rapidly, and that's something for the eggheads at Yantar to deal with. Not me.\n \nThe Zone expands in bursts; usually after an emission. Back then, emissions were a lot more scarce. They would take place about once a month, and they were a lot more powerful than they are right now. The Zone would expand with every blowout; however, with time, the blowouts have started to diminish in power, though they occur a lot more frequently these days. We now have a blowout every few days, but it wasn't always like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223004">
        <text>What's gonna happen to the Zone's barrier? From what I understand, it's not the first border set up by the government.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223005">
        <text>Well, you got that right. The barrier in the Cordon is the third border they've set up until now. They started building it when the Zone began to expand for the first time. Back then, a lot of people died near the perimeter; some died from the blowout, but most of them died from mutant attacks. Nobody ever saw anything like it before. The number of mutants coming from the center was enormous; there were thousands of them. In turn, the government sent everything they had at them. They turned this place into a war zone. Tanks, helicopters, artillery, and everything in between was stationed here to fight off the insane waves of mutants. At one point, they considered carpet bombing the whole area, but luckily for us, the mutants stopped flooding the Zone at that point. After the incident, the surrounding world started taking the Zone a lot more seriously. Instead of restoring the old perimeter, they put a few pillboxes around the Garbage, and they didn't stop there. In case a threat were to break through the Garbage, they would have a backup solution. The military outpost in the Cordon used to be that backup solution.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223006">
        <text>Why does the Cordon outpost look so weird? What I mean is, why does it look like a military warehouse more than anything? Same thing with the wall they built around the Zone. Why does it go over the perimeter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223007">
        <text>That's because that place was never supposed to be a military outpost but rather a warehouse where all sorts of military technology would be stored and repaired. It was also used to repair and refuel vehicles that would carry cargo in and out of the CNPP. And after the mutant breakout that I mentioned earlier, the military took over that warehouse and made it their base. As for the wall, they only started building it after the blowout struck. Because the engineers worked in a hurry, they made some kind of calculation error. As a result, the wall was actually built south of the outpost. Eventually, they tried to rebuild it so that the wall would at least cover some of the outside buildings, and the result is what you see today.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223008">
        <text>Where are the gates, though? When I looked, there was no gate. Just an open entrance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_223009">
        <text>They're not there anymore. They got rid of them. A few months ago, a big flock of mutants smashed through those gates. The strange thing was that there were no blowouts that day. Out of nowhere, a flock of boars and flesh appeared and started breaking through the barrier, slaughtering a few soldiers in the process. Then, when the military called in a chopper, something completely bizarre happened: the mutants instantly ran away as if they knew something was coming. Instead of repairing the gates, they decided to just get rid of them, seeing as they were going to build a second barrier anyway. Did you see it, by the way? It looks amazing; a fine piece of work indeed. Everything there is as it should be: flamethrowers, mortars, fortified trenches, and pillboxes; it's all there. Hell, the minefield alone is a work of art. Not a single rodent gets past it. They must've spent billions, considering all the gear that's located there. Seems like NATO takes its defense budget seriously.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2231">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_224">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_225">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2251">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_226">
        <text>Question 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_227">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2271">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_228">
        <text>Question 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_229">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2291">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_230">
        <text>Question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_231">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_2311">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3">
        <text>What exactly do you want to know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_33">
        <text>Know anything interesting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_331">
        <text>Did you hear about the American spies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_332">
        <text>Nope. What about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_333">
        <text>Well, a year ago, Rasputin got a job to escort three foreigners through the Zone. He was promised very good pay, so he agreed. However, he's a smart guy, so he checked out what they had in store for him. He found out through his sources that those foreigners were no regular tourists but rather CIA agents. Rasputin didn't want to lose the cash he was promised, but at the same time, he didn't want to screw over the stalker that would take the job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330001">
        <text>So what did he do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330002">
        <text>He told me about his situation, and after a while, we both came up with a solution. We picked someone who could really handle himself: Elijah Muromskiy. That guy was tough as nails: two meters tall, huge shoulders, and strong as hell. One time, he broke a boar's neck with his bare hands just for the hell of it. If anything ever went down, he could handle it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330003">
        <text>So what happened then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330004">
        <text>Elijah arrived on time and met the tourists, after which he led them to the designated areas. The tourists wanted to inspect the mutants from afar and take a few pictures, and maybe even hunt a few of them. But Elijah could barely speak any English, and he couldn't understand what his clients wanted from him. They only thing Elijah understood was that our guests wanted to hunt down some mutants, and so that's what he did for the entire trip.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330005">
        <text>I think I know where this is going…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330006">
        <text>Nah, you don't. Shut up and listen: for three days, Elijah escorted our American clients. He went everywhere with these guys and showed them everything. In the Agroprom underground, they were attacked by a bloodsucker that almost killed one of the tourists. In Yantar, Elijah “accidentally” forgot to mention that there were zombies there, so when one of the corpses stood up, one guy almost had a heart attack. When they were traveling between one location and another, he would “accidentally” run into flocks of boars and other small time mutants. On the third day, Elijah suggested they sleep in the construction site in the Dark Valley. He, of course, “forgot” to bring up the presence of burers there. I don't even know who was more scared: the burers at the sight of Elijah or the Americans who were terrified by the burers. When Elijah told us about this, we all burst out laughing.\n \nThat's not all, though. The next morning, the tourists wanted to go home, so they went to Sidorovich so that he could smuggle them back across the border. However, the same day the tourists planned to leave, a group of three guys came to the Zone. They were escorted through the border by the military. It turned out that this was a CIA group sent into the Zone for some kind special preparation program. Sidorovich was dumbfounded: why send one CIA group and then another one right after? He asked the tourists why the CIA did this, to which they replyed—in broken Russian—that they weren't CIA and had nothing to do with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330007">
        <text>So the whole time, Elijah was just scaring a few American tourists… Ha ha ha! Damn. That's too damn funny.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330008">
        <text>Yeah. He almost gave them a heart attack. By the way, Elijah also escorted the real spies, in the same route. The burers were happy about it, though! Ha!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3330009">
        <text>Thanks. I needed a good laugh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3331">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_334">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_335">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3351">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_336">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_337">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3371">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_338">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_339">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3391">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_340">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_341">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_3411">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_4">
        <text>Where are you from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_44">
        <text>I was born in Okha, which is in Sakhalin. You know where that is, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_44001">
        <text>Sakhalin? Of course I know where it is. It's an island in the far east of Russia, close to Japan. You sure traveled a long way to get here. What did you do there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_44002">
        <text>Well, it was a town full of workers. The town's main export was gas and oil and even wood. I could always find work in those area. But ever since my childhood, I had a need for adventure. I just couldn't imagine myself being stuck in one place for the rest of my life. At the time, I traveled through every forest in the region. When I turned eighteen, I joined the military. For me, it was the only way to get off that island and see the world.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_441">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_5">
        <text>How did you end up in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_52001">
        <text>That's a tough one…\n \nI don't know whether it was a chain of coincidences or if the Zone itself chose me, but here I am. Back in the army, I did well at everything. I've loved sports since I was a little kid, so even two years in the Spetsnaz wasn't too bad for me. Though, the war in Afghanistan was coming to an end; I was barely sent to any war zones, and I didn't see a lot of fighting, which was lucky for me. When the war finally ended, I was sent to military school, where I got a military career.\n \nWhile I was in school, I met a woman who I eventually married. I didn't have any kids, though, but that turned out for the best. After I finished school, I would travel from garrison to garrison, so I didn't have time to raise any children. And then I was sent to Chechnya. That's where I lost my Marina… I was a complete dimwit for bringing her with me there in spite of warnings from my officers about attacks by Dadaev forces. And I… I'm such an idiot: I couldn't save her.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_52002">
        <text>Didn't mean to remind you… Sorry. I didn't know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_52003">
        <text>Forget about it. It's my cross to bear, and I'll have to live with it for the rest of my life. Maybe that's why the Zone led me here. What do you think? I've been through a lot after the First Chechen War; so much that I can't even tell you about it right now. Nevertheless, I remember the day the Zone emerged like it was yesterday. You just can't ever forget such chaos.\n \nIn the first few hours, nobody could even understand what was going on. People weren't sure whether the reactor exploded, a meteorite fell, or if it was the beginning of a nuclear war. Moscow was just as riled up as Kiev was. That was around the time we were sent to the Zone. I'll never forget that day. I almost lost my entire team because of those bureaucratic rats. To them, it was no big deal—throwing soldiers' lives away—considering they just had to know what those anomalies were capable of… The bastards. I still don't know how Dima, Sergey, and I made it out alive. The Zone must have guided us.\n \nAnyway, when we made it back to the HQ, I was ready to shoot the general who ordered the operation. And I almost did it; I had the gun pointed between his eyes. But I was captured. After that, I was thrown in jail. If it wasn't for my friends who helped me escape, I'd probably be stuck somewhere in Russia right now, behind bars. After I escaped the military camp, I had two choices: either live in the Zone or spend the rest of my life hiding in the outside world. I choose the former. I'd rather live freely in the Zone than rot in some shitty prison.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_52004">
        <text>That's one hell of a story. Do you ever miss your hometown?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_52005">
        <text>You know, at first, I didn't miss it at all; I was too busy trying to stay alive. Back then, the Zone was a lot more dangerous than it is now, and it was almost completely devoid of people to boot. Even though I'm an experienced soldier who's seen all the horrors of war, none of those horrors could compare to what I've seen in the Zone. When your friend gets caught in an anomaly, flies up into the air, and gets torn to shreds, there's nothing you can feel but pure fear. Nevertheless, you can't lose your skill and experience, and so I managed to survive somehow. After some time, when I gained some experience and got a bit more comfortable here, that's when I started to feel a longing for home. Nowadays, I really want to go home and see my parents one last time; I don't even know if they're alive or not. I'd even go back to prison if it means seeing my hometown again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_551">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_6">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_66">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_661">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_7">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_77">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_771">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_777">
        <text>That's all I know. I've told you everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_8">
        <text>question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_88">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_881">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_999">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_stavrid_about_9990">
        <text>text in default</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_10">
        <text>He caught this signal in the factory, located in the same area as one of the exits to the spatial anomaly. That's where we found you. I think these messages are coming from people who, like you, got stuck inside the space anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_11">
        <text>I'll be glad to help. Might be able to save Marcus too. One question, though: how exactly are you going to pull them out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_12">
        <text>It's simple, really: before leaving, Forester gave me the exact coordinates to the anomaly exit. We just have to send it to the stalkers trapped inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_13">
        <text>Sure. If you have the transmitter, I'll do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_14">
        <text>Excellent. I knew I could count on you. I'll give you the transmitter, and you'll take it to the right spot and send them the coordinates. Don't worry; the device already has all the data recorded in its memory. All you have to do is send it to the stalkers on the other side. If they get our signal, they should be able to find their way out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_15">
        <text>All right. Give me the transmitter. I'll send them the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_17">
        <text>So, did you do what I asked?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_18">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc! Need anything fixed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_20">
        <text>You're awake, Beast. Good. We were really worrying about you for a while. What the hell happened to you at the factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_21">
        <text>I transmitted the coordinates, but they fell into the wrong hands. It wasn't such a good idea. Can't do anything about it now, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_22">
        <text>Beast, what the hell are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_23">
        <text>There's no time to go into detail, but it's likely that all of us are in grave danger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_24">
        <text>If it's an attack, we'll can fight it off with ease, considering the massive protection we have here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_25">
        <text>I hope that's the case. Anyway, here's your transmitter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_26">
        <text>All right, then… By the way, I unlocked the PDA you brought me here before. I read what's in there and gave it to Saurel. Hope you don't mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_27">
        <text>I don't mind. What sort of info was there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_28">
        <text>Go talk to Saurel. He'll tell you everything in full detail. I have to get back to work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_29">
        <text>Fine. I'll go see him, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_31">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You need anything repaired?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_33">
        <text>Hey, Beast. I take it you're here about the PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_34">
        <text>Yeah. That's right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_35">
        <text>Just so you know, Saurel is sending you on a very dangerous mission. But what can you do, right? We all put our lives at stake here every single day.\n \nAll right. I made some changes to your PDA. Now the Monolith will think you're one of their own. By the way, you don't have to worry about friendly fire, since everyone in the base was warned you two were going undercover. We also informed the hunter team nearby, so there should be no problem with them either. Good luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_36">
        <text>Thanks. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_38">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You need anything repaired?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_4">
        <text>Hey, merc. Are you here on business?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_40">
        <text>Damn, Beast. You look like shit… Did you manage to stop the Monolith? Also, where's Savage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_41">
        <text>The bastards took him captive and hid him inside the laboratory, thinking I'd go after him. They must've prepared some kind of trap for me. I'm not going, though, since he's dead either way. I'm not gonna throw my life away for nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_42">
        <text>Fuck, man… Poor Savage. In my opinion, though, you made the right choice. For all we know, Savage is already dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_43">
        <text>Can you reset my PDA, Petrovich?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_44">
        <text>Sure thing. Let's see… Here you go. Good as new. So where are you off to now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_45">
        <text>I'll go talk to Hunter. I was told by Saurel he's ready to leave the Outpost, and I'm going with them…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_46">
        <text>In that case, Beast, goodbye. This might be the last time we see each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_47">
        <text>Goodbye, Petrovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_49">
        <text>Goodbye, Beast. This might be the last time we see each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_5">
        <text>Hey, Petrovich, can you hack this PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_6">
        <text>I can try. I've done it before. But I can't promise anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_7">
        <text>All right. Here's the PDA. Give it a shot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_8">
        <text>Sure. I'll have a look. Listen, Beast: I have a favor to ask you. I haven't told this to anyone; not even to Saurel. I've been catching a distress signal on my radio that's being transmitted on a hidden frequency. After a while, I couldn't pick it up anymore, but then a stalker came to me and said he was catching that same signal when he was near the factory. At first, I didn't believe him, but he brought me a recording that convinced me otherwise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_9">
        <text>And? Where are you going with this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_0">
        <text>Hey, Antibiotic, can you give me the Chimera figurine? The one on your table?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_1">
        <text>Sorry, but I'm not giving it away like that. Now, if you're willing to place a bid on it, that's a different story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_10">
        <text>A thousand? Don't you think it's worth a bit more than that? Fifteen hundred at the very least.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_11">
        <text>So be it. I'll sell it to you for fifteen hundred.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_12">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_13">
        <text>And here's your figurine. Don't lose it; it's a unique piece. Only one in the world.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_14">
        <text>Thanks. Good day to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_15">
        <text>For two thousand, it's all yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_16">
        <text>All right. Here's the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_2">
        <text>And how much do you want for it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_3">
        <text>How much will you give?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_4">
        <text>I'll give you five hundred rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_5">
        <text>I'll give you a thousand rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_6">
        <text>I'll give you fifteen hundred rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_7">
        <text>I'll give you two thousand rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_8">
      <text>Money's tight right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_9">
        <text>That's way too small of a sum. Maybe you can place a higher bid?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_0">
        <text>Do you need any help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_1">
        <text>It's a good thing you asked. I have something I need taken care of; someone tried to help me with this before, but he couldn't find anything substantial. The thing is: I need your help with completing a collection.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_2">
        <text>What sort of collection?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_3">
        <text>Way back when, we had a guy at the Outpost who would make figurines; it was his hobby.\n \nAt one point, he got the idea to make a figurine for the mutants in the Zone, and since he had such a good photographic memory, his results were very accurate. After a while, the guy disappeared somewhere, but his figurines remained; he sold all of them to the local stalkers. I started to develop a liking for those figurines when I got my hands on the bloodsucker sculpture, and after that, I wanted to complete the entire collection. Perhaps if you look around the stashes at the Outpost and ask around, you can find something.\n \nSo what do you say? Help me out here? I'll give you a thousand rubles for each figurine you find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_4">
        <text>All right. I'll try and look for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_5">
        <text>Sorry. I don't have the time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_6">
        <text>If you want to help, then help me complete my collection. You'll help me out a lot if you find a few at least.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_7">
        <text>All right. I'll try and look for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_8">
        <text>I'm still short on time. I'm not going to do that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_0">
        <text>About the figurine collection…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_1">
        <text>Yeah? You find any figurines?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_10">
        <text>I found a pseudogiant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_11">
        <text>I found a snork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_12">
        <text>Excellent. Here's your reward, merc; just as we agreed. Is that all, or have you found any other figurine?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_13">
        <text>You already have all the mutant figurines.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_14">
        <text>Oh? Oh. I didn't notice that you already found all the figurines. Excellent work, merc. Thank you so much for your help. As a token of my gratitude—besides the money—I'll give you a forty percent discount on all repairs and modifications.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_15">
        <text>Well, thanks for the discount. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_2">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_3">
        <text>I found a blind dog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_4">
        <text>I found a pseudodog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_5">
        <text>I found a boar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_6">
        <text>I found a flesh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_7">
        <text>I found a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_8">
        <text>I found a controller.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_9">
        <text>I found a chimera.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_0">
        <text>Rasputin, can you give me the pseudogiant figurines that's on that shelf?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_1">
        <text>What do you need it for? It doesn't just sit there, you know. It's part of my bar's entourage, and I've gotten used to it being there for so long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_2">
        <text>Petrovich asked me to find figurines of all mutants in the Zone. You have one of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_3">
        <text>I'll give it to you for a thousand. No questions asked.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_4">
        <text>He's been begging for it for quite a while. I was going to give it away, but he already sent you on a hunt for all the figurines. So if he really wants it, then take it. I'll get something else to replace it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_5">
        <text>Well, okay. If you need it so badly, take it. Was just curious why you needed it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_6">
        <text>Thanks. You've really helped me out. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_7">
        <text>Doesn't really matter to me. Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_11">
        <text>Yo, man! You wanna take a few shots at the ravens?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_111">
        <text>I do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1111">
        <text>Great. You can play my games just for fun, earn some money, or try to score a record. Take your pick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_112">
        <text>Nah. I don't feel like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1121">
        <text>'Kay, man. I'm always here if you change your mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_21">
        <text>Here's your stuff, like we agreed. All fair and square. So, you wanna go for some more?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_31">
        <text>It really do be like that sometimes. You wanna try again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_41">
        <text>Where the hell were you going, man? Shooting behind the fence? That ain't part of the game. Maybe you wanna have a go by the rules this time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_51">
        <text>Clock's ticking! Less babbling, more shooting!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_511">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_61">
        <text>You shoot like a real man! You should go for money. Want to try again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_0">
        <text>I'll do it for money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1">
        <text>Now that's what I like to hear! I don't need to go over the rules with you, do I?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11">
        <text>Yeah. Let's start.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111">
        <text>Not just yet, bro! So what do you think? How many of them birdies can you get in a minute?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111111">
        <text>Sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111111">
        <text>All right, man. Ready your gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111111">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112">
        <text>I don't have that much money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111121">
        <text>Well, can you choose something that'll fit your pocket?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111211">
        <text>Yeah. I'll pick a different amount of ravens.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111212">
        <text>No. Not interested.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112121">
        <text>Then you can play just for fun. Or for records… but that'll drain your pockets dry. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_12">
        <text>Tell me the rules.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_121">
        <text>Playing for money's the most fun. You tell me how many ravens you can take out in a minute, you place your bets, and you step forward. If you win your bet, you get double the sum. If you lose, the paper's all mine. And keep in mind: the more birdies, the bigger the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_13">
        <text>Mmm… I don't feel like playing anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_questions_0">
        <text>Are there any general rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_questions_1">
        <text>Basically none. I keep time, you get ready for the signal, then rain fire. If you manage to get as many as you bet within a minute, you win. You choose how you want to take out the birds out. Just remember that if you leave the fence, the game's off. So what'll it be: fun, money, or record time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_quit_0">
        <text>Eh. I don't like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_quit_1">
        <text>Okay, then. If anything, I'm always here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_0">
        <text>I'll try scoring a record.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1111">
        <text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11111">
        <text>Now let's see what skills you got!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1112">
        <text>Agreed, but no money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11121">
        <text>Then a few simpler choices: money or just for fun. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1113">
        <text>I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_12">
        <text>Remind me of the rules.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_121">
        <text>This is for the real boys. If you feel you got the strength to score the highest record, you place a bet, and not a small one, either. If you get it, I'll give you back the money you bet with twice on top… and also the title of champion, which ain't so fucking bad. If not, I keep the paper.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_13">
        <text>I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_0">
        <text>Just for fun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_1">
        <text>Some exercise, huh? You got the rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_11">
        <text>Yes. Let's shoot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_111">
        <text>'Kay. How many ravens are you getting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_11111">
        <text>Sure. Well, don't just stand there. Shoot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_111111">
        <text>Yep.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_21">
        <text>No. Tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_211">
        <text>Well, you wanna try shooting crows just for fun. Meaning you don't wanna earn any cash. You just wanna train, or you might be feeling down. You choose how many ravens you drop within a minute, and you try to get it done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_31">
        <text>I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_311">
        <text>Not a question. Your choices are the same: for money or for a record. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_0">
        <text>Greetings, sir. What were you doing on the tree?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_1">
        <text>What? Got a problem?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_2">
        <text>No, God forbid. Everything is fine. If you give us the artifact you found in the grove, though, it'll be even better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_3">
        <text>Oh, fuck off… You better leave before I put a bullet between your eyes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_4">
        <text>I'm not giving you anything. Go back to where you came from.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_5">
        <text>All right. Take the artifact and be on your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_6">
        <text>That's it! We're feeling nice today, so be thankful that we don't strip your clothes and make you walk around the Zone naked.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_7">
        <text>Uh-huh…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_0">
        <text>We're out. Now listen up: head to the old school in the morning. I'll be waiting there with my pals. I meet you there, you get your shooters. And remember: we never had this conversation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_1">
        <text>And I know what to do without you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_2">
        <text>Perfect. Take the key. Got no time to waste, so we'll scram. Gonna wait for you where we've agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_3">
        <text>I'll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_2">
        <text>'Sup, merc! Thanks again for helping us out of that hole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_3">
        <text>Let's not beat around the bush. You got my weapons?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_4">
        <text>Of course. I keep my word… These babies are brand new; haven't even been fired yet. Everything is just right. By the way, I hope nobody caught word of our deal yesterday?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_5">
        <text>No. Everything went fine. Give me the guns.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_6">
        <text>They're all yours. Here. And some more info for ya: go see Bookmaker in the yard. He can organize some real fun for you. Not to mention there's money in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_7">
        <text>Great. I'll talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_9">
        <text>Look who showed up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_10">
        <text>He he. Just try and get me. So we have a deal? I'll wait for the key at nighttime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_11">
        <text>Yeah. We have a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_13">
        <text>So did you retrieve the key?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_14">
        <text>Yes. I have the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_15">
        <text>Still haven't found it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_16">
        <text>Beautiful, merc. Give it to me. Time's short, and we need to get out of here without a sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_17">
        <text>Hold your horses. How are we going to return the key back to where it was?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_18">
        <text>I know: we'll meet by the house. You go off now and wait for me there while I open this cell with my bro and sneak out in your direction. I'll mark the exact place for you, where I'll give you the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_19">
        <text>And when will I get the gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_2">
        <text>Hey, merc! I heard you're looking for a Vikhr gun. I could help you out with that, but I'm gonna need a little something from you first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_20">
        <text>We'll talk everything out when we're out of here. Need to get out before the stalkers notice anything. Wait for me at the place we've agreed on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_21">
        <text>Okay. Here's the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_22">
        <text>Great. Now you head off and wait for me at the meeting point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_23">
        <text>Got it. I'm heading out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_25">
        <text>Merc, what the hell are you still doing here? Go to the meeting point. Don't waste time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_26">
        <text>I'll think about your offer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_28">
        <text>So what'll it be, merc? You gonna help us out of this shithole?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_29">
        <text>I haven't decided yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_3">
        <text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_30">
        <text>I have the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_31">
        <text>Well, it's nice that you have the key and all, but the moon's not up yet… and we need to get out at nighttime. Come back later; preferably after midnight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_32">
        <text>Okay. I'll come back at nighttime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_4">
        <text>What do you think? I wanna get out of this hole. If you help me, I could part with it. Don't worry; no one's gonna get whacked. You just need to find the key for this cell.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_5">
        <text>And how do you want me to go about finding it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_6">
        <text>Won't be that hard. There are two keys for this cage: one's held by Saurel while the other is… or, should I say, *was* guarded by Chemist. Chemist's key, however, is being held by Sologub right now. I heard from a stalker that Sologub just leaves his key on his nightstand while he's out like a light. You just need to fetch the key while he's asleep and return the key back to where you took it from once we're out of here. If everything goes as planned, they won't even know a thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_7">
        <text>Sounds like a plan, but how can I trust your offer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_8">
        <text>Trust? Ha. You can trust me. I gave you my word, and I always keep it. Especially since you have no way out of this place without a gun… and I have two of those. I'm not looking for any funny business. You won't be getting any gun without my help. They're guarded by quite a serious man, and he gives them only to me. If we get out of here, I'll give them both to you. I swear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_9">
        <text>Looks like I have no choice. But if you try to trick me, you're as good as dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_0">
        <text>Rasputin, turn off the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_1">
        <text>Yeah? Sure. Getting tired of it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_2">
        <text>Done. Were you building up a headache there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_3">
        <text>You don't like my repertoire? That's fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_0">
        <text>Rasputin, turn on the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_1">
        <text>You want some music? Fine. I don't mind that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_2">
        <text>Man, I wouldn't mind listening to a good song myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_3">
        <text>Done. Listen to your heart's content. It's the only thing that's free of charge here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_0">
        <text>What the…?! Oh. It's you, merc… Go back to where you came.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_1">
        <text>As a matter of fact, I came here to help you. Isn't that what you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_2">
        <text>Look, you've been a pain in the ass already. What are you doing poking your nose into other people's business? I should've killed you on the spot while you were doing time. You're going down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_3">
        <text>Well, you've said your last word…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>Got any work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>What do you think? Of course we do. Not only that, but the job we have is a dirty one. We need six blind dog tails for an assignment from the scientists. We will be very grateful if you help us out with this. Are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_2">
        <text>Fine. I'll help you with the tails.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_3">
        <text>Great. And don't worry about the reward; you'll get an honest sum for honest work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_4">
        <text>Got it. I'll be off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_5">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_10">
        <text>Greetings, merc. Do you have any business here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc. Do you have any business here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_4">
        <text>You got the six blind dog tails?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_5">
        <text>Yes. I have the tails. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_6">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_7">
        <text>Great. You helped me good. Here's your honest reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_8">
        <text>Thanks. I'll be going now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_10">
        <text>Well, anyone could've done it. Listen: I went on a hike with Lame not long ago, and the Zone gave us a special gift. Basically, we stumbled upon a load of artifacts and crammed it all into a container that we agreed to hide. From there, we split up. Lame managed to return to the base before I did. All in all, we were feeling happy and generous, so we shared a few drinks with another couple of stalkers. Next, the dimwit tells me that he brought the container to the base. I lost my temper and pushed him over.\n \nThat's when the conflict started. Rasputin messaged me thereafter, saying that the container was gone. Whoever stole the container made it look like I was the guilty one so that the stalkers would go after me instead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_11">
        <text>Who do you think is behind it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_12">
        <text>I have no idea. I know for sure that it couldn't have been Rasputin, Skew, or, obviously, Saurel. Beast, I beg you, go explain everything to Saurel. I don't want things to be like this. I'm not afraid to die, but I don't want to die as a rat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_13">
        <text>I'll go talk to him, then get back to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_14">
        <text>You won't be able to contact me; I lost my PDA somewhere while escaping the bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_15">
        <text>Then stay here and don't move. I'll come back here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_17">
        <text>Beast, I beg you, speak to Saurel about letting me back. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_18">
        <text>Fine. I'll speak to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_2">
        <text>Hey, who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_3">
        <text>I'm Beast. I came here for you. Any last words?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_4">
        <text>Damn it! So Saurel sent you here? Don't think I ever saw you in the base before.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_5">
        <text>I arrived yesterday while you were slipping away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_6">
        <text>Oh, I didn't slip away anywhere. I just went for a walk to relax. Then Rasputin sent me a message about Lame's death. Everyone thought I was the killer, and then the bandits went after me, and I couldn't go back. And no… I didn't kill Lame. He was like a brother to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_7">
        <text>Only you would've had any reason to do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_8">
        <text>Well, yeah. We had a bit of an argument, but I wouldn't go as far as to kill a man because of some disagreements.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_9">
        <text>Then who could've done it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_0">
        <text>So, Beast, you ready to deal with those fanatics?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_1">
        <text>I'm ready, though why did you decide to get mixed up in all of this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_2">
        <text>I wanted to help you out and thank you for everything that you did for me. It means a lot, and Sologub's too short on experience to go on such missions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_3">
        <text>Hmm… Well, all right. Can we go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_4">
        <text>Yeah. We'll get going right away; Petrovich already reconfigured my PDA. I don't recommend taking the road that goes by the school. There are tons of anomalies there. Better stay on the path that stretches from the factory; it's longer but safer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_5">
        <text>I'll support you. Let's move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_10">
        <text>This is all very strange…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_11">
        <text>Well, then. I'm guessing that scumbag lied to us and there won't be any meeting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_12">
        <text>It seems that way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_14">
        <text>Fuck! It's an ambush! Beast, get to cover ASAP! We'll cover you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_15">
        <text>What are you talking about? I'm staying with you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_16">
        <text>No! Beast, we're too few. We won't last five minutes in these numbers. Get to the stalkers and call for assistance right now. Only you can convince them to help us. Go on! Get out of here! Time is short. Don't worry about the exit! We'll cover you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_17">
        <text>I'm off, Miklukha! You stay here, and I'll get you some people.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_2">
        <text>So, we have some time before meeting with the Monolith. One more thing: we have to wait for the deal to begin, and then we smack that scum. Most importantly, we take out everyone and everything, and let no one escape. If anyone survives and runs off, then… Basically, we're screwed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_3">
        <text>It'll be all right. Just don't make any fuss before we get our chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_4">
        <text>Yeah. You nervous?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_5">
        <text>Not at all. When are we kicking it off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_6">
        <text>Right now, Spotty's hiding in one of the terminals while we stay in the shop. We'll go through the northern entrance of the factory; it'll be safer that way. On the way there, we need to clear the vicinity of any mutants so that they don't come after us later when the fighting starts. You'll come with me and help me out. I recommend you bring a silencer; it won't do us any good if we attract attention.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_7">
        <text>Understood. Let's move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_9">
        <text>It's quiet here… Too quiet. The fanatics should have set up a perimeter already, but there's not a soul here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_0">
        <text>Tell me a story, brother.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_1">
        <text>My brother, the Monolith summoned me this night. I spoke with it. It was glorious in its splendor. I was almost blinded by its light, which endowed me with great vigor! I sense its might dwelling amongst us! It told me that only ardent faith is capable of vanquishing the wicked. It said that only the faithful will be blessed with its power. Furthermore, it revealed to me that our victory is impending!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_2">
        <text>My brother, have you heard that several infidels snuck near the antennas recently? The Monolith guided us, and my brethren noticed them in time. One fell and evaporated. We've eliminated the second, and the third took off running. Cowards. They're all cowards. Only true faith leaves no space for fear! Two ran away, but the Monolith is shrewd and omniscient. Hence, it needs them alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_3">
        <text>I recall us patrolling the edges of the Red Forest and stumbling upon a lone infidel. He had already started turning, and we did not kill him, but he was still existent in this half-beastly state… I realize that the sage Monolith has done it for us all: once again, he unmasked for us the true face of our enemy. Now our faith has been hardened yet further! It is nearing, my brother! The victory over the infidels is nearing, and then the Monolith shall fulfill our innermost desire! Rightfully shall it bless the devout with its presence; its glory; its magnificence! May we forever dwell in its brilliance!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_4">
        <text>Not long ago, the Monolith tested my faith, and I nearly wandered off the righteous path. But I withstood! Praise the Monolith! Its challenges forge us! We were on our way back from the Dark Valley, and I fell slightly behind my brethren. The evil took this advantage and promptly started enticing me. And… I hesitated. The pure images were corrupted; the enemy whispered to me that we were merely slaves to the Monolith. But then it occurred to me: this was a challenge. I remembered the Monolith's shine and might, and my will, my courage was restored. Since then, I fear no challenge and know no hesitation. Praise the Monolith!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_5">
        <text>I've been in the Dark Valley. The infidels are abundant there, since the Monolith's power hasn't reached those lands yet. We had been on guard duty. At night, we were attacked. We fought those animals fiercely. My brethren's prowess was honored: the Monolith summoned them soon after. But for me, he prepared another challenge. My weapon would not fire. But then the Monolith said: “You are with me, and my strength is with you. If you stay true to your faith, you shall crush your foes and move nearer to me!” And I became a shadow. I crouched and crept towards their right side. The daft, foolish spies were blind to it. They thought they'd finish us and laugh over the hollow bodies of our brethren. But I had already faced their backs. And the Monolith's force struck them out of my hands. Thus it killed them. I am gleeful to serve you, the supreme one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_6">
        <text>I have nothing more to share with you, brother.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_0">
        <text>What do you want, fresh meat? Was gonna hit the sack right before you showed up…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_1">
        <text>You'll get your beauty sleep later… I want to know how long I've been here. What is this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_10">
        <text>Uh-huh. Good luck with that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_11">
        <text>Yeah. Night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_2">
        <text>The hell you on about? Did the stalkers hit you over the head?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_3">
        <text>Thing is, I don't remember how I got here…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_4">
        <text>Our guy told me that you got out of a bubble with the stalkers… Well, congrats! You managed to get from one cage to another. In case you didn't figure it out, you're at the Outpost now. You've spent no more than an hour in the stalker base. But don't worry; you didn't miss anything. He he.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_5">
        <text>Why the hell am I behind bars?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_6">
        <text>You weren't lucky. Neither was our bro. By the way, Saurel heard a lot about you, so he put you in the best room they got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_7">
        <text>Who's Saurel?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_8">
        <text>Like, that bastard's the head of this camp. You'll get to talk to him. Until then, go get some sleep. I don't wanna hear any more of your questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_9">
        <text>Fine. I'll have to wait until morning anyway. Maybe Savage will have a chance to speak to this Saurel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_0">
        <text>Listen closely, merc. I'll only say this once: Saurel is letting you go, but don't do anything stupid, or you'll pay for it. Severely. Got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_1">
        <text>Understood, sir. In that case, may I have my equipment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_2">
        <text>Of course. Here's everything that you carried.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_3">
        <text>Excellent. Where is my group?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_4">
        <text>Well, part of your group is in the base, while the others have left the Outpost with a guide. Some other guy, Markus, got lost somewhere. Your friend, Savage, tells me that he ended up in an anomaly and never escaped. Go talk to him; I might've missed a few details. Oh, and by the way, go talk to Saurel. He wants to talk to you about something important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_5">
        <text>Got it. Release me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_6">
        <text>Well, part of your group is in the base, while the others have left the Outpost with a guide. Some other guy, Markus, got lost somewhere. Your friend, Savage, tells me that he ended up in an anomaly and never escaped. Go talk to him; I might've missed a few details. Oh, and by the way, go talk to Saurel. He wants to talk to you about something important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_7">
        <text>Got it. Release me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_8">
        <text>I almost forgot: your Duty buddy wanted you to have this canteen. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_9">
        <text>Thank you. Open the door.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_0">
        <text>I've got a few things of interest. You buying?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_1">
        <text>Show me what you've got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_10">
        <text>It's the guy who was with you in the spatial anomaly, right? Savage told me about him. I'll give you fifteen hundred rubles for that PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_11">
        <text>Well, it might be useful. Have a thousand rubles for this scribble. No more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_12">
        <text>Excellent.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_13">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_2">
        <text>Chemist's old knife.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_3">
        <text>Chemist's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_4">
        <text>The PDA of a stalker from the Final Day faction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_5">
        <text>Scavenger's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_6">
        <text>A note from Gray.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_7">
        <text>Finally decided to sell something? You can have forty-five hundred for that. A beautiful knife, indeed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_8">
        <text>Hmm… Interesting… Have two thousand rubles for it. You can never have too much information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_9">
        <text>What the!… Where did you get that? Uh, never mind. Don't tell me. I still want to rest easy at night. You can have seven thousand for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_0">
        <text>I'm out of water. Could you refill my canteen?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_1">
        <text>Of course, but it'll set you back two thousand rubles. Water purification's not a simple business, you know. So, deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_2">
        <text>Deal. Have two thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_3">
        <text>No. I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_4">
        <text>Great. Your order is already up. I knew you would come to get some water, so I refilled a few canteens beforehand. Right now, I'll refill the empty one that you just brought me. Come back any time you need water.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_5">
        <text>All right. I'll drop by.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_10">
        <text>No. I wasn't that far away when I was keeping an eye on you. At first, you fiddled with some kind of device, and then you stood up and started talking to yourself without moving a muscle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_11">
        <text>What are you saying? You sure you aren't mixing up any of this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_12">
        <text>No. I haven't lost my mind just yet. Hear me out: you collapsed, and then I heard a horrifying laugh… Some figure with a black trenchcoat knelt beside your body. So I waited a bit longer, then ran out and popped a few shots at the guy, but he disappeared in an instant. After that whole freakshow, I brought you back to base. It took me two trips; one for you and one for all your belongings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_13">
        <text>Thank you so much, man. If there's anything I can do for you, let me know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_14">
        <text>I'll keep that in mind. Now, can you tell me what you saw? Did you think you were talking to someone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_15">
        <text>Yes… Petrovich gave me a transmitter so I could send the coordinates to an exit to a few stalkers in the space bubble. After that was done, the stalkers appeared in front of me. It was Fish and his men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_16">
        <text>What “Fish”? Did you know this guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_17">
        <text>Yeah. When I had just gotten into the Zone, he saved me and got me to join up with the mercenaries. Eventually, Fish was cast out from the Syndicate, and he expected me to come with him. I stayed. Fish blamed me for it and made it clear that we would see each other again. I didn't hear from Fish for the longest time, but then someone messaged me and told me that he and his squad were found dead in Yantar. And this whole time, I thought he was dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_18">
        <text>So he's most likely dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_19">
        <text>But I saw him with my own two eyes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_2">
        <text>Come to your senses? That's great. How are you holding up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_20">
        <text>There was no one near you. That's for sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_21">
        <text>I might as well tell you another thing: the figure you saw next to me; I met him before in the space bubble. He's very dangerous. It's good you showed up and saved me when you did. Thank you again. Now excuse me. I need to have a word with Petrovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_22">
        <text>So that's what it was… Listen: I suggest you keep your mouth shut about this creature, lest there be any misunderstandings. I'm also gonna keep quiet about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_23">
        <text>You're right. See you later!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_25">
        <text>What is it, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_3">
        <text>S-S-Shit… Not very well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_4">
        <text>Could've been worse. Guess I saved you there. Had I not been there in time, you would've been a goner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_5">
        <text>So I owe you with my life?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_6">
        <text>Guess you could say that. Good thing I had the guts to do that. Otherwise, I can't imagine what would've happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_7">
        <text>Can you tell me what happened? Where's the trio that tried to kill me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_8">
        <text>I was just about to tell you that there was no one near you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_9">
        <text>You found me when I was passed out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_0">
        <text>Well, well… What have we here? Could it be Beast? Long time no see…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_1">
        <text>Hello, Fish…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_2">
        <text>Didn't expect to see me again, did you? He he. I told you we'd meet again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_3">
        <text>I didn't expect you to come out of the bubble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_4">
        <text>And why do you think we got lucky? We came back from a place that's worse than hell. And for what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_5">
        <text>I have no idea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_6">
        <text>Debts must be paid. And you'll pay for them with your blood!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_7">
        <text>Don't even start…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_10">
        <text>That's good… And I think I'm gonna have a drink…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_11">
        <text>What made you start drinking?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_12">
        <text>What?… Do I need a reason?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_13">
        <text>No, but I can tell you have a reason. Come on; spill the beans and tell me what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_14">
        <text>It's all stupid… Came here with Sashka a long time ago; one of the first stalkers. He knew the whole area like the back of his hand. Ugh…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_15">
        <text>What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_16">
        <text>I somehow got into an argument with him. And he… decided to go on a raid on his own, while I stayed in the base… and Sashka never returned. I looked for him for a looong time, but there was no trace of him anywhere. But not long ago, I saw him. Or rather what was left of him…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_17">
        <text>Nothing you can do about it. And you better lay off the booze.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_18">
        <text>Yeah, I get it… Can you help me, buddy? I saw Sashka around a group of zombies. He became one of them. Probably somewhere in the field of that… Whatchamacallit? He ended up in that terrible psy-emission, and it fried his brains right off the bat. Put his soul to rest, won't you? I can't watch my friend suffer together with other good men. Can't do anything about it myself, either. Can't even lift my hand…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_19">
        <text>Don't worry. I'll take care of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_2">
        <text>Aha! W-What? What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_20">
        <text>Thaaank you so much. I won't forget about this. The zombies are in the graveyard. Not far from the base… I'll give you a marker…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_21">
        <text>Send it and I'll go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_23">
        <text>W-What? Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_24">
        <text>I put your friend out of his misery, along with his friends in the graveyard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_25">
        <text>T-That's great… Thanks, man… I won't forget this… Take this…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_26">
        <text>Thanks for the shooter. Take my advice, Skew: get off the booze. Drinking all day long help your friend come back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_28">
        <text>W-W-What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_29">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_3">
        <text>How'd you get so shit-faced?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_4">
        <text>Eeeh… Had to… He he.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_5">
        <text>What are you laughing at?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_6">
        <text>Yeeeah… Just remembered a funny joke. Ugh. It's so boring here…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_7">
        <text>Can I help you with anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_8">
        <text>Weeell, help me, then. Let's… Let's have a drink…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_9">
        <text>No, thanks. I've stopped drinking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_0">
        <text>Are you Baldy? I need to talk to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_1">
        <text>That's me. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_10">
        <text>What's done is done. Best to fulfill your friend's last wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_11">
        <text>Spotty asked me to find you. You know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_12">
        <text>Spotty? Crap. What happened to him? He's still alive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_13">
        <text>No. He lost his mind and killed himself. He was in terrible condition. I couldn't make out anything he said.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_14">
        <text>No, no, no! Was there anyone else with him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_15">
        <text>He was alone. He talked nonsense about the Scorcher and some Humpback…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_16">
        <text>This is all my fault… Humpback and Spotty were doomed because of me. In the heat of it all, I left them and ran off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_17">
        <text>Tell me what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_18">
        <text>Humpback, Spotty, and I spent a long time preparing to break through the north. We didn't have enough time to wait for the Scorcher to cool down, and Spotty acquired some information from a member of Final Day. From Swede, it seems.\n \nWe were halfway through the Red Forest when the Scorcher turned on without warning. Spotty lost it; he went unconscious, fell off a slope, and after that, disappeared somewhere. He wasn't where he should've been after the fall. No reply on my PDA, either. I panicked and decided on abandoning the mission and going back. Humpback was dead set on finding Spotty, but that would've been suicide for us. Still, I went with Humpback's plan. He descended the slope to look for Spotty where he should've been. And then the Scorcher hit us.\n \nI regained consciousness outside a military base. Until now, I figured they were both dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_19">
        <text>What's done is done, Baldy. Don't punish yourself for the past.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_2">
        <text>Spotty asked me to find you. And hand you this artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_3">
        <text>Spotty? Crap. What happened to him? So he's still alive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_4">
        <text>No. He lost his mind and killed himself. He was in terrible condition. I couldn't make out anything from him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_5">
        <text>No, no, no! Was there anyone else with him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_6">
        <text>He was alone. He was raving about the Brain Scorcher and some Humpback. Then he asked me to bring you this artifact and told me that you would pass it on to his wife.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_7">
        <text>This is all my fault… Humpback and Spotty were doomed because of me. In the heat of it all, I left them and ran off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_8">
        <text>Tell me what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_9">
        <text>Humpback, Spotty, and I spent a long time preparing to break through the north. We didn't have enough time to wait for the Scorcher to cool down, and Spotty acquired some information from a member of Final Day. From Swede, it seems.\n \nWe were halfway through the Red Forest when the Scorcher turned on without warning. Spotty lost it; he went unconscious, fell off a slope, and after that, disappeared somewhere. He wasn't where he should've been after the fall. No reply on my PDA, either. I panicked and decided on abandoning the mission and going back. Humpback was dead set on finding Spotty, but that would've been suicide for us. Still, I went with Humpback's plan. He descended the slope to look for Spotty where he should've been. And then the Scorcher hit us.\n \nI regained consciousness outside a military base. Until now, I figured they were both dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_start_2">
        <text>What do you want, merc? I'm not really in the mood for chit-chat…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_11">
        <text>Glad you're still in one piece, merc. I won't be questioning you about what happened at the factory; if you have anything to share, just say it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_12">
        <text>It's all right. Don't let it go to your head. What info did Miklukha have on his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_13">
        <text>Okay. Let's take a look at what's on there. Petrovich didn't manage to decrypt all of the entries, but we managed to find some useful information nonetheless. Miklukha had a spare plan for driving the Monolith out of the Outpost. It was rather simple: acquire a Monolith disguise, infiltrate their base, and destroy the structure with explosives. I think this plan deserves a try, but first, we need to get hold of a Monolith bodysuit, as well as one of their PDAs. That task will be up to you and Sologub. After you find a disguise, meet up with Sologub at their base, set up the explosive charges, then detonate them and return back here. That's the plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_14">
        <text>Not a bad idea, but where do I get two Monolith outfits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_15">
        <text>I checked all my channels. There's a trader offering us two Monolith suits, but in exchange, he wants an SR-3 Vikhr assault rifle. I have no clue where to find it. Rasputin's suppliers can't get a hold of it, either. Can you check your channels?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_16">
        <text>My channels won't be of any help. After what happened in the space bubble, it's best to not contact the Syndicate at all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_17">
        <text>That's bad, but still, try to ask around about this. Perhaps we might find a Vikhr.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_18">
        <text>Fine. I'll try to get a hold of it. We'll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_2">
        <text>What is it, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_20">
        <text>What is it, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_22">
        <text>Beast, where have you been? Shit's happened. The bandits that were in the cage escaped last night. What I don't understand is how they were able to get out in the first place. I have a suspicion one of my men helped them. You haven't noticed anything recently, have you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_23">
        <text>Nope. Haven't noticed anything… By the way, I've got the rifle for the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_24">
        <text>All right. I'll deal with the escape later. Where'd you get that shooter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_25">
        <text>Well… Some old contacts helped me out…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_26">
        <text>Very good. Now we can bring Miklukha's plan to life and wipe out the Monolith once and for all.\n \nOh, yeah: we decrypted another entry on Miklukha's PDA. Turns out there's a laboratory under the Outpost that's used by the Monolith to bring in munitions and new fighters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_27">
        <text>This just keeps getting better… So first, we need to strike at their base in the construction site. We'll continue from there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_28">
        <text>Piece of cake. We'll need to wait for the bodysuits, though. Don't know how long it'll take for them to arrive. Give me the rifle; I'll send it to the trader in exchange for the package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_29">
        <text>Okay. Here you are.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_3">
        <text>The Freedomers are pinned down by the Monolith at the factory. I need your help, Saurel. Give me a few good men so I can help Miklukha.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_30">
        <text>Great. You can go. As soon as I receive the package with the suits, I'll contact you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_31">
        <text>Understood. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_33">
        <text>The package is still on the way, Beast. Drop by later, okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_35">
        <text>Great news, Beast! The package with the outfits has arrived. Now we can get to work and carry out our previously mentioned plan. You ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_36">
        <text>Guess I'm ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_37">
        <text>I know, I know: the plan's not ideal, and there's a chance they'll see through it, but that chance is small as all hell. Monolithians are mindless; they won't realize it's a setup.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_38">
        <text>All right. Where's Sologub right now? Is he good to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_39">
        <text>Ah, yeah: regarding Sologub, he's not going with you… Savage, on the other hand, was itching to be his replacement. At first, I didn't agree to it, but in the end, I figured things would be easier with him by your side. He's already donned a bodysuit, and is waiting for you downstairs. First, though, go see Petrovich. He'll reconfigure yours and Savage's PDAs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_4">
        <text>Sorry, but I can't risk my own men. You got out, and that's what's matters. The rest do not. We're not close enough to Freedom to die for their sake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_40">
        <text>Give me the rundown once more, then I'll go talk to Petrovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_41">
        <text>All right. Here's the plan: you and Savage will infiltrate the Monolith base. Once you're in, you'll attach the explosive charges to the column on the second floor of the building while Savage tries to distract the Monolith. After you set the charges, return to our base immediately so you don't end up like them. That's the plan. Now take your Monolith bodysuit and the charges. Break a leg, you two.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_42">
        <text>We'll get this done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_44">
        <text>The package has yet to arrive, Beast. Drop by later, okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_46">
        <text>What happened there, Beast? Where's Savage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_47">
        <text>We were compromised… Seems the Monolith took away Savage into the laboratory, and now they're waiting for me to come save him. I don't know what they thought up, but they need to lure me into the laboratory for something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_48">
        <text>Well, then… Sad to see such a good plan lead to failure… So there's one thing I don't understand: how do you know they brought Savage into the laboratory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_49">
        <text>They knocked me out. When I came to, there was no one at the Monolith base except for a single Monolith fighter. He told me about it all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_5">
        <text>How can you say that? If we don't help them right this instant, they'll die.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_50">
        <text>So there are no more Monolith at the base? Did they all leave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_51">
        <text>Yeah, but I doubt they're leaving for good…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_52">
        <text>As I understand it, you're setting out to rescue Savage, right? I doubt it'll be worth it. It's suicide. Just forget about it. On top of that, Hunter arrived at the farm half an hour ago. He was looking for you; said he's ready to get you out of the Outpost. Just go to him. Savage is history by now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_53">
        <text>I need to save Savage. I can't just leave him behind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_55">
        <text>Perhaps you'll reconsider that ridiculous notion of yours? If you head into the laboratory, you're as good as dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_56">
        <text>I need to save Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_57">
        <text>Perhaps you're right. There's no guarantee Savage is still alive…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_58">
        <text>Exactly! My advice is to go to Petrovich. He'll reset your PDA. After that, get out of that damn Monolith outfit and go see Hunter. Just don't go down into that laboratory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_59">
        <text>All right. So be it. I'll talk to Petrovich and then see Hunter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_6">
        <text>They're probably dead by now. I can't risk losing my men, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_61">
        <text>Good luck, Beast! I hope we see each other again…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_63">
        <text>Hello, Beast. Have you managed to find any clues on where to get that SR-3 Vikhr?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_64">
        <text>Seems like it. One of the bandits in the farm cell told me that if I free them, he'll get me a Vikhr.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_65">
        <text>Those slippery bastards… Can't we just put needles under their nails and get the location of the weapons that way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_66">
        <text>They asked me to steal Sologub's key at nighttime and hand it to them. In exchange, they're giving me the gun. They also promised not to use any force; instead, they'll just sneak out without any fuss.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_67">
        <text>So that's how it is… What do you think? Can we trust them to keep their word?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_68">
        <text>I think we can trust them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_69">
        <text>I don't really think the bandits are trustworthy, but we have no other options right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_7">
        <text>Ah, shit… Fine. I'll try to save them myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_70">
        <text>We've come this far… You'll have to go along with their plan. However… I have an idea: we can play along with the bandits. I'll give you the key to the cage. You pass it on to the bandits, and I'll warn the guys on the farm so they'll be ready for anything. If everything goes as planned and the bandits keep their word, we'll let them live, but we don't want to see them ever again. Does that sound good to you, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_71">
        <text>Sounds like a plan. Better than just stealing the key for the bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_72">
        <text>I doubt that'll work. The bandit told me the guns are held by a third party. I can only get them if the bandits are set free.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_73">
        <text>What goddamn freedom plan did that bandit have in mind for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_74">
        <text>Okay, so, let's do it like this: you take the key, tell them you stole it from Sologub, and after the “escape,” you come back to me and tell me everything. Sound good?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_75">
        <text>Sounds good. Let's do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_79">
        <text>How did it go, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_80">
        <text>The bandits escaped. No fuss, no muss. They told me I can come for the Vikhr at the old school in the morning. Here's your key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_81">
        <text>Well, then. Let's see if they keep their word…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_82">
        <text>We'll find out in the morning. No use in guessing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_84">
        <text>Well, Beast. Did the bandits keep their word? Did you get the gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_85">
        <text>Yes, surprisingly. They kept their word. I have the SR-3 Vikhr.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_86">
        <text>Very good. Now we can bring Miklukha's plan to life and wipe out the Monolith once and for all. Oh, yeah, we decrypted another entry on Miklukha's PDA. Turns out there's a laboratory under the Outpost that's used by the Monolith to acquire munitions and new fighters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_87">
        <text>This just keeps getting better… Anyway, first we need to strike at their base in the construction site. We'll go on from there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_88">
        <text>The bandits escaped. No fuss, no muss. They told me I can come for the Vikhr at the old school in the morning. Now I'll go return both your key and Sologub's key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_9">
        <text>What is it, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_91">
        <text>What is it, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_92">
        <text>Let's chat after you give the key to the bandits. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stavrid_zavod_zasada_93">
        <text>All right. I'm going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_0">
        <text>Listen, Rasputin: I'm looking for a rifle. It's called the SR-3 Vikhr. Can you get a hold of it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_1">
        <text>I already spoke to Saurel about that. I can only tell you the same thing: my suppliers don't have the means to acquire that rifle. It's a very rare piece.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_2">
        <text>Okay. Thanks for the answer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_3">
        <text>Not at all. If you ever need help, come see me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_2_0">
        <text>I'm looking for an SR-3 Vikhr. Do you know where to find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_2_1">
        <text>You gonna get it in exchange for those Monolith suits from the trader? Nah. I don't know. There's one thing I can tell you: if Rasputin can't find that rifle, there's not much of a chance anyone else will. Sorry, but it's the truth.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_3_0">
        <text>Hey, Skew, I need an SR-3 Vikhr. Know where to find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_3_1">
        <text>N-No… No idea… I don't need your p-problems… I already h-have my own……</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_4_0">
        <text>Looking for an SR-3 Vikhr. Know where I can find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_4_1">
        <text>No clue. If Rasputin can't help you with that, go see Petrovich. Maybe he can get it for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_5_0">
        <text>Hi, Petrovich. I'm trying to find an SR-3 Vikhr rifle. Any chance you can get a hold of one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_5_1">
        <text>Hmm. No. I won't be able to find one, and I doubt anyone else at the Outpost can.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
