<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_0">
        <text>Who the hell are you?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_1">
        <text>A stalker, just a stalker. You must be the Piano Man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_2">
        <text>Maybe I am, maybe I'm not. It depends. What do you want from me? How did you even find me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_3">
        <text>Then you must be you. It didn't take much effort to find you, first I found your flash drive and then you. The stalkers from the camp at the farm are looking for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_4">
        <text>Looking for me? What the hell do they want with me? To mess with my head again? Telling the newbies how to live? Ah?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_5">
        <text>How the hell should I know? They asked me to do it, I did it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_6">
        <text>All right, then let's make a deal with you, you go to Tocha now, and explain that you found me, but I'm not going back to the camp, if they want something from me, then let them get their asses up and go. Is that clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_7">
        <text>More than clear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Stalker, stop! Who are you and what are you looking for here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Hunter, I answer to Snake. I'm looking for my comrade, Bison, do you know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_10">
        <text>Oh, yeah! Well, I'll talk to our leader, he's a smart guy and not bad in electronics, so I think with this question for sure will help, but if not, then we will think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Well, then here are two PDA and I need any information about your technique, as the name, what in general, in addition to repairs are fond of or what he did before he disappeared.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_12">
        <text>The technician's name is Piano Man, I can't say what he is into, I have not seen him and I can't say anything about his recent dealings but I will talk to the guys and I will let you know right away. By the way, last time the Technician was seen near the old factory, there is also gravitation archi-anomaly, I will throw you the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Ok, then I'll go there first, and on the way I might be able to clean up the mutants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hunter, it's good, now we'll have someone to shoot game, and we have eighty percent of green and with wildlife of the Zone, they do not really get along, well, if you understand me. As for your Bison, then he was here, there were two stalkers with him, one I think his name was Carpenter, and the other ... Hm ... either Phoenix, or Felix, like that cat from the ads in general.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Well that's something about the local fauna, I think I can help you with that, if you pay me well and tell me more about Bison and the guys who were with him. By the way, do you have a technician at the camp?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_4">
        <text>It's not much, but it's enough to live on, and our technician is missing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Missing how? And you did not look for him?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_6">
        <text>We did, but where to look for him and to whom? The greens?! Who are afraid to stick their noses in the camp, or us experienced stalkers, who can't go further than the camp, because we're guarding this very Green, in short, it's like in the proverb: I'm both eager and impatient...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Listen, I could help you find your technician, if you want, but I need a favor in return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_8">
        <text>That'd be great! What kind of favour would you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_9">
        <text>I have two PDAs, both are locked, but one of them seems to be cloned or the information is well erased, so I need to unlock one, but with the other one I need to find out who owns or owned it and if possible to get the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_0">
        <text>So you're the hunter who decided to help with the search for our Technician?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_1">
        <text>That's what I'm here about, by the way. I was in the neighbourhood where your tech was found, and I found a flash drive, but the problem is... the flash drive is blocked.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_2">
        <text>Oh, yeah? I take it you want me to unlock it? If so, give me the flash drive and go for a walk. I'll let you know when I'm done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_3">
        <text>All right, I'll be waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_0">
        <text>There you are, any luck finding the Piano Man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_1">
        <text>Yes, he asked me to tell you a few words.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_10">
        <text>Snake, don't interrupt and listen. So Felix, like a blank sheet of paper, but pretty quickly got into everything that was going on, first he wandered around, then he did some of our errands, and in the end it turned out that the blues were after him, he sort of solved the issue, just shot everyone. I don't know how it happened, but Garik went to the site of the massacre and saw the bodies... So where was I... Oh right! After he went through with the blues, he gathered up his stuff and headed for the old factory, there's some anarchists there too, you were passing by, by the way, when you went looking for the Piano Man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_11">
        <text>Yeah, I remember that factory, lots of mutants...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_12">
        <text>That's what it is. So that's where you look for him, if you're lucky.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_13">
        <text>All right, thanks for the tip.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_2">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_3">
        <text>Verbatim: I'm not going back to camp. If they want something from me, they can get off their ass and go. There you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_4">
        <text>I heard you, by the way, about those PDAs. I was able to unlock one of them. Can't help you with the other one, it's nobody's, they just put a password on it and added our camp coordinates and that's it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_5">
        <text>Yeah... Not much, but better than nothing. By the way, regarding the pure PDA, I assumed so, but since I have no knowledge, I had to drag you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_6">
        <text>I see, well Snake, if you want to help us, you're always welcome.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_7">
        <text>Speaking of help, I think we can help each other. I don't know if Garik told you why I'm here, but I'd better tell you again. I'm here looking for Bison and his band or what's left of it. The PDAs I gave you belonged to members of his group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_8">
        <text>Garik told me the purpose of your visit, I can't tell you much. But I'll tell you what I know. The bison had been here before, and there were two others with him: Carpenter and Felix, they were looking for some kind of miracle artifact or something like that, and they stayed with us for about three days, and then they just took off. The only thing that might help you is that we found Felix afterwards, but he was weird, like his brain had been formatted into a flash drive...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_9">
        <text>That's interesting, where's Felix now?</text>
    </string>

    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_0">
        <text>What about the case?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_1">
        <text>Here it is, safe and sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_11">
        <text>In progress.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_2">
        <text>Great, here's the gun and some butterflies to go with it, like we talked about. By the way, our leader wants to talk to you, he's sitting at the table to my right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_3">
        <text>Thank you. A chat, all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_4">
        <text>By the way, if you happen to want to earn some money and help our humble clan, you know where to find me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_5">
        <text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_0">
        <text>...Thank you again, Snake! If it wasn't for you, I'd be eaten by blind dogs...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_1">
        <text>Come on, you made it. The rest doesn't matter. Why don't you tell me what happened to you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_2">
        <text>Oh... Well, you know what we went on, so I won't tell you again. Well, yesterday me, Bison and Greek went to a village, and rumour has it that we may get some loot there, so to say, to take our minds off our main task. We arrived in the village before we knew it, as a sniper was already firing at us, and then some more guys joined in. We tried to hold them back, but it was in vain, so we decided to leave. I told the guys that I would cover the retreat and try to catch up. They set off, and I started shooting in all directions, so as to draw fire all over myself, so that the boys had time to hide. In the end, as soon as the guys were out of their sight, the fighting began to die down... I thought that was it... I finally hit somebody, and they decided to wait until I was out of ammo. I didn't sit behind the cabin for long, one of the attackers came around me and shot me, lucky he didn't hit me in the heart, but it was close by. I bled to death for a couple of hours and then started crawling towards the camp, but I was exhausted and I sent out a call for help, and there you were.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_3">
        <text>Born with your shirt on, who attacked you? Were you able to see?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_4">
        <text>Not only could I see, I could hear them talking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_5">
        <text>That's more interesting, tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_6">
        <text>Mercenaries attacked us, and our conversation made it clear that they were hired to eliminate Bison, and our group was just eliminated along the way. I don't know who or why decided to take out Bison, but the fact remains that the mercenaries hunted Bison.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_7">
        <text>Oh, man... Where the hell are we supposed to find him? Where could he have gone with the Greek?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_8">
        <text>We didn't have a permanent camp, so I can't give you a specific location. I'm sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_9">
        <text>All right, you get some rest, get your strength back. I'm still working for the local guys, see if they can help me find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_0">
        <text>Hey, stalker! Where are you from and where's your gear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_1">
        <text>Me? I'm a prisoner of war, but they're probably keeping it for safekeeping... Anyway, fuck it, the main thing is that I managed to get away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_2">
        <text>Yeah... You lucky bastard! I'll say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_3">
        <text>Yeah, listen, maybe you can help me out. At least I need a gun, I'm not going anywhere without one...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_4">
        <text>Can I help? I think I can. Look, I'll give you the gun and the olives, and you take something for me. Agreed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_5">
        <text>It's a deal! What's to be picked up and where?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_6">
        <text>Well, if you go northwest, there's a ravine, and in the ravine there's a cluster of anomalies, and there's a container there, which is what I need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_7">
        <text>Sounds easy, so I'll give it a shot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_wounded_buriy_0">
        <text>Help me...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_first_dialog_wounded_buriy_1">
        <text>Brown?! Shit, I'll carry you to the camp, hold on brother!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_0">
        <text>Peace be with you, Garik! Touha said you got a distress signal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_0">
        <text>Too bad about the guy...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_1">
        <text>I agree, it's not a good fate. But on the plus side, the creature's been killed, which means we've reduced the chance of anyone else dying. All right, shall we move back?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_2">
        <text>I agree... Yeah, let's go back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_1">
        <text>Yeah, there is that, and the signal's not far from here. Listen, let's check it out, shall we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_2">
        <text>Come on, there's nothing to do yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_0">
        <text>Oh, Snake! I got a report of a couple of stalkers in good outfits near the southwestern farm, heading for the swamp, which isn't too far away. That's probably who you're looking for. There's also a lone mercenary there, not that you'd be interested in him, but still.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_1">
        <text>A mercenary? Are you sure about that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_2">
        <text>I think so. All our groups are marked on my PDA, and this is the first time we've seen these guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_3">
        <text>All right, I'll go check and see if it's really Bison and the Greek.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello, just like we talked about. Me and my guys are here and ready for whatever we need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_1">
        <text>That's great, Lieutenant! Don't you have any questions about the operation?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_2">
        <text>Snake, I already told you, I've known you for a long time, so I know that you wouldn't call me and the guys for nothing, that's why we're here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_4">
        <text>You're flattering me, but come on, I'll get some more guys and we'll move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_second_dialog_0">
        <text>My men and Tochya's men are ready, shall we go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_second_dialog_1">
        <text>Let's go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_0">
        <text>The enemy has been destroyed, the fighters are on the defensive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_1">
        <text>Roger, have you seen Bison?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_2">
        <text>We have... He's behind that building. Snake, he's dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_3">
        <text>What?! No!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_0">
        <text>Have you or your men seen any Mercenaries around here lately?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_0">
        <text>I have good news.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_1">
        <text>I didn't think the Duty boys would be so quick to agree. They've got their own score to settle with the mercs, though. By the way, when are we expecting them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_2">
        <text>Duty's quad leader said they'll be here at the farm around midnight tomorrow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_3">
        <text>Great, let's get ready then. By the way, while you were talking to the Debtors, Garik picked up another S.O.S. Go check it out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_4">
        <text>All right, I'll go talk to Garik.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_1">
        <text>I did, just yesterday Syndicate men came here, they're stationed at the northern checkpoint. Why they're here, I can't say - I don't know. And to be honest, I don't really want to know. It's dangerous to know about mercs' plans, it's been tested more than once.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_2">
        <text>I hear you, listen, do you have any desire to remove uninvited guests?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_3">
        <text>I say that I do not mind, but I'm afraid that after the elimination of a group of these scum, others will still come.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_4">
        <text>I do not think, not so long ago a group of Dutyovtsy eliminated quad mercs in the vicinity of the former research institute, and after there was no one saw them, I think, that with this group will be as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_5">
        <text>You think so? I don't really want to take any chances, but if the comrades from the valiant Duty group arrived here and took part in the elimination, the Mercs wouldn't notice our presence.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_6">
        <text>Hmm... I think I might be able to invite them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_7">
        <text>Now we're talking! As soon as the Dutyovs come, then I'll allocate people to you, I think that's fair!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_8">
        <text>Right, I'll go and see if I can get in touch with the lads.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_0">
        <text>Greetings! Can you hack into the PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_1">
        <text>After the radio stuff you brought me, I think I'm capable of a lot of things now! So give me your PDA and come back in a couple of hours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_2">
        <text>Glad to hear it! Here's the PDA, let me know when it's ready if you don't mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_0">
        <text>Got your message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_1">
        <text>Which one? Ah? That's right! I'd forgotten, it's busy, but the PDA, I unlocked it, there's not much information, some markings on the map, some mention of a group, an artefact and a couple of notes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_2">
        <text>All right, let me check it out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_0">
        <text>Found the artifact-- there it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_1">
        <text>Great, an artifact of a gravitational nature! Here's a little present for you from me, and there's something our salesman wanted from you, talk to him, while I think about how to help you with your problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_2">
        <text>Thank you, this gun will come in handy, and as for the merchant, I'll go talk to him now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_0">
        <text>Found an artifact-- here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_1">
        <text>Great, an artifact of electrical nature! Here's a little present for you from me and there's something our merchant wanted from you, talk to him, while I will think how to help you with your problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_2">
        <text>Thank you, not a bad gun - it will come in handy, and as for the merchant, I'll go talk to him now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_0">
        <text>Found an artifact-- here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_1">
        <text>Great, an artifact of the acidic nature! Here is a small present for you from me, and there our merchant wanted something from you, you should talk to him, and in the meantime I will think how to help you with your problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_2">
        <text>Thank you, any gun will do no harm now, and as for the merchant, I'll go and talk to him now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello, hello, what's your name?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_1">
        <text>I answer to Snake, I'm a hunter by profession.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_10">
        <text>Anybody, I'll mark a few anomalous fields for you in PDA, you'll have a chance to wander there. By the way, I don't advise you to go to bros now, revenge is a thing... But there's no hurry! I also don't advise going to the village north of here. The lads said they spotted a posse of unknowns there, and there's a creature wandering around... I'd advise you to keep your ear to the ground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_11">
        <text>All right, I hear you. I'm going to check out the anomalies...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_2">
        <text>All right, hunter Serpent. My name's Tokha, I'm in charge here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_3">
        <text>I get it, Garik said you wanted to talk to me about something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_4">
        <text>Yes, so I'm wondering, how did you end up with those guys, how did you manage to get away from there, and what are you even doing in that godforsaken land?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_5">
        <text>Oh, that's probably the funniest part! I'll just start at the beginning and then we'll get to the bottom of it. So I'm looking for a stalker nicknamed Bison and his group, or rather what's left of it. My search led me to a sewer, which was a shortcut to here. Already going up to the top of my head they kicked me and took away my clothes, I woke up in the den of bandits, and of course it was strange that nobody guarded me, but I used it, went away through a fence, and now I have run into your camp. That's how it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_6">
        <text>What a story, though, it's hard to envy. I got out, though, and thank God. I'll give you something for that, but don't expect that you'll have to work for the good of our clan, and I don't think you'll refuse, because you have no other choice. I'll also try to help you with the search, but that's for later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_7">
        <text>Yeah, well... To refuse is to die, that's not much of a prospect. What do you need to do and how can you help me find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_8">
        <text>Here's your gear, some medical supplies. I see you already have a gun, but one gun will not be enough for this area, there's a cache somewhere, the owner can hardly use it, but it will be just fine for you, it's somewhere in the camp, you'll find it in general. As for business, you'll have to work as an artifact collector first, it's a dangerous job, but if you have the right skills and a good detector, it won't be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_9">
        <text>Yeah, thanks. A collector, you say? What kind of artifacts are you looking for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Who's who? And what faction?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Stalker, just a stalker. They call me Snake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_2">
        <text>What are you looking for here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_4">
        <text>I don't like you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_5">
        <text>And I'm not a woman for you to like...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Yes? Shit, I didn't replace it, okay, joke's on you, but if you do your duty you can come here as if you were at home.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Go ahead, I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_8">
        <text>To the east of our camp, there are bandits. As you know, they're in our way, so if they disappeared, we'd appreciate it. You know what I mean?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Yeah, I'll be back soon.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_done_0">
        <text>What about my reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_done_1">
        <text>Here you go, it's well earned!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_sk_done_0">
        <text>The unit is dead, but the bandits are also dead...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_sk_done_1">
        <text>I'm sorry to hear that... Anyway, here's what you've earned.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_0">
        <text>Do you need any help? Tokha said you wanted something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_1">
        <text>Remember I hired you to take out a gang of bandits that were ripping off our guys on the outskirts of the camp, so it's time to clean up their lair.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_2">
        <text>You say clean up... I don't mind, but I ain't going in there alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_22">
        <text>I don't feel like it, so some other time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_3">
        <text>I wouldn't send you in there alone, it's too risky. I've already arranged for the guys who'll be taking part in the cleanup and they'll be waiting for you not far from the bandit camp. The man in charge is called Thunder.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_4">
        <text>Now we're talking! I'll be on my way, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_0">
        <text>You must be our extra shooter. Well, don't worry, my boys are smart! It's not the first time they've held a gun, so let's move, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1">
        <text>We did!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_0">
        <text>I think we got 'em all!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_1">
        <text>I guess so, OK, we'll hold down the fort here, you go back to the camp, you'll be rewarded for your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_2">
        <text>All right, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_0">
        <text>The unit is dead...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_1">
        <text>What?! How?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_2">
        <text>They were killed by monoliths, I don't know the exact details, but it's true. When I explored the village, I spotted a squad of monoliths and dead bodies in the barn, so I decided to take a look, but I had to fight those fanatics first. In the end, I examined the bodies, it was your fighters, the leader of the detachment found some documents, here you go [Give documents] - maybe it's important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_3">
        <text>Well... It's not a pleasant situation, to say the least. Damn, we lost guys like that... Oh, God bless you guys. Leave the paperwork, that's probably what they went for... Shit...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_4">
        <text>All right, I'll leave you to it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_0">
        <text>Greetings! Heard on the air that you have a missing unit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_1">
        <text>Yeah, there's that. The guys just haven't been in contact yet, although they should have been back in camp a long time ago, but they're not. I've called in a search party, but so far there are no results.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_2">
        <text>If you want, I can help with the search.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_3">
        <text>That'd be nice! Look [Got the map], this is where the guys got in touch last time - it's an abandoned village, mutants live there mostly, but there are a couple of houses where you can stop for a rest, and here they could stop before returning to the base. I think you should take a look at the village, for I have sent a squad to the supposed resting place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_4">
        <text>All right, I hear you. I'll let you know as soon as I hear anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_0">
        <text>Is there anything I can do for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_1">
        <text>Can I help you? Maybe you can. See, we just got our base set up, haven't had time to clear the area yet. And there's bandits here, robbing the stalkers who bring me the loot. At that rate, I'll soon have nothing to trade with. Yesterday there was another bandit squad. Insolent - what are you: right in front of our base! Couldn't you clean them up a bit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_11">
        <text>No, you can't do anything now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_2">
        <text>No problem! They'll remember my lesson for a long time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_22">
        <text>You know, maybe some other time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_0">
        <text>It's about the bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_1">
        <text>How'd it go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_2">
        <text>I got them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_22">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_222">
        <text>Don't take too long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_3">
        <text>Thanks a lot! Here's your reward!</text>
    </string>

</string_table>
