<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="dm_about_story_talk">
		<text>Those who have long trampled the Zone, as far as I know, are interested in something other than dough, booze and a wish fulfiller. Maybe I'm wrong, but I think I heard in the bar, that there is a fashion for philosophical sayings among you. You want to tell me a funny parable?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_story_end">
		<text>Oh, thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_zonanews_end">
		<text>Thank you. (chuckles)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_1">
		<text>Well, there's a tendency among experienced walkers. We get hooked on one thing and then another. Listen. The story goes that once King Mahmud overtook his retinue. As he was riding at full gallop along the river, he suddenly saw a little boy by the water catching a seine. The child seemed very unhappy. The king sharply stopped the horse, and approaching the boy, he asked him: 
   - My child, why do you look so sad? I've never met a sadder man than you. 
   The boy replied: 
   Your Majesty, there are seven of us brothers. Our father is dead and we live with our mother in dire need. To get by, I go to the river every day and cast a net. If I don't catch a single fish in a day, I stay hungry for the night. 
   My son," said the king, "if you don't mind, I will help you. The boy agreed, and King Mahmud cast the net himself, which at the touch of the king's hand came back with a rich catch. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2">
		<text>Huh, when you've been balancing life and death for years, any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. A man's out in the field sowing wheat. The day is coming to an end, and he can't finish his work... He prayed: Oh, Lord, if I had a helper, we'd be done sowing in no time... 
   Look, a bear crawled out of the bushes and said to him: "Come on, man, I will help you, it will be more fun together. 
   The man was delighted and agreed. They sowed the field on time and hugged each other goodbye... 
   It's harvest time... The man didn't have time to reap the harvest... Look, a familiar bear crawled out of the bushes and said: "Come on, man, I'll help you, it's easier for both of us". And the work started... They've harvested crops the man has never seen before. 
   So he says to the bear: "Come on, Mishenka, let's go to my house. You helped me sow and reap... Let's go and sit at the table: let's drink, eat, talk... 
   The bear agreed, the man's generosity pleased him. 
   They are sitting at the table, rejoice, and the bear keeps saying: "Well, man, if it weren't for me, you wouldn't have sown the whole field... If it wasn't for me, you wouldn't have had such a harvest... 
   And the man thinks: "Look how big and strong he is, he'll take everything from me and break my bones... He's praising himself for a reason..." 
   The man grabs the pitchfork and stabs the bear. The bear roared in pain... ...and runs off into the woods. 
   Time passed... ...and the sowing season came again... The man went out into the field to sow, but without a helper, only half of the field was sown. It's harvest time, but he's only halfway through the harvest... 
   He walks home, despondent... He sees a bear crawling out of the bushes. The man says reproachfully: "Why didn't you come to help me sow and reap...? I gave you food and water, and you?" 
   To which the bear, pointing to his chest, replies: "I have a pain here..." 
   The man walks up to the bear, gropes and says: "It's all healed, Misha!" And the bear says: "The wound has healed... IT HURTS!!!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3">
		<text>Well - we're not so much over-the-top philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here's a story.  An unknown poet once came to a king and said: 
   - "O king, who has no equal in the heavens! I have composed a hymn in your honour, and my creation is brighter than all the verses that other poets have hitherto composed for you, as Sirius is brighter than all the lights in the night sky. 
   With these words he handed the king a sheet on which was written only the name of this ruler. The king looked at the sheet and became angry: 
   - Where are the verses? - he shouted. - Have you gone mad? You did not sing of our royal glory, you did not sing of our victories and our good deeds. You have not even mentioned that I have made this kingdom with my own hands! You dare to mock me? 
   But the poet was not frightened by the king's anger and replied with dignity: 
   - All the king's wisdom, mercy and might and all military glory are contained in this name, and anyone who reads it will at once imagine all the deeds accomplished by the king. For the name is the symbol of thy kingdom, and it is in itself above the thickest book of eulogies. So I was right before you when I called what was written by my hand an incomparable hymn glorifying you and your deeds! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4">
		<text>Hmmm, now I recall one of the last.  A long time ago in the Middle Kingdom (as China was then called), the best, mightiest fighters of the world gathered for a tournament. The contest was judged by a great Chinese sage. Finally, after thousands of battles, he chose three of the greatest warriors and asked each of them to tell him how they trained. 
   The great, fierce-looking fighter was the first to rise and say: 'Every morning at sunrise I break down trees, stones, planks - anything that comes my way. All around my dwelling for a day's journey is turned to ashes, a desert. 
   - That's fine," said the wise man. - And how do you train? - he asked another fighter. 
   A tall, thin man, more like a monk or an ascetic, came up. 
   - Every morning at sunrise, he said, "I meditate. I take my body under the control of mind and will and make it as light and quick as a thought. 
   - Perfect," said the sage. - How do you train? - He asked the third warrior. 
   An ordinary looking man, unremarkable in appearance, stood up. If he hadn't won a thousand fights recently, no one would have guessed he was a warrior and a great one at that. 
   - I don't train at all," said the third man. - I just try to be present in everything I do. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5">
		<text>Now that someone here understands us. I say. I think I've had an epiphany. So listen. Once upon a time, there was Godelo. He had a wife who was always nagging him about his father interfering with their lives, and Godelo couldn't calm his wife down. 
  Godelo's father, listening to his wife's cries day after day, called his son and said to him: 
  - Son, I see that I am disturbing your family welfare with my presence, let me go to the mountains to live... 
  - Godelo listened to his father and at first he refused, but there was nothing to do... 
  The father started to get ready as he called his son to him and said: 
  - I have just one problem: I will not be able to get to the mountains on my own, why don't you carry me in the basket on your shoulders and I will help myself. 
  - "All right," said Godelo, agreeing. 
  He put his father in a basket and carried him up the mountain. He brought his father, dropped him off, and was about to leave when his father followed him: 
  - Wait, son, don't forget to take your basket, your son may need it. 
  Godelo felt ashamed, realized his mistake, repented, put his father back in the basket and brought him home. 
  ...and threw his wicked wife out of the house. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6">
		<text>Well, there's a tendency among experienced walkers. We get hooked on one thing and then another. Listen. One pilgrim walked many thousands of steps to meet the Teacher and finally stood before him, asking to share the highest wisdom. 
  - Then take a sip from this stream and describe to me the taste of the water. - The teacher told him. 
  - I have already heard and understood this Truth, said the seeker a little disappointed. 
  - Tell me, what do you understand? - Teacher asked. 
  - Water cannot be described by words; you have to drink it and not talk about it, the same goes for Truth... 
  - Now imagine - I'm sitting near a stream, and a crowd of people like you are standing in line for me to describe the taste of water to them, even though many of them have already heard this description from other Gurus. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7">
		<text>When you've been balancing life and death for years, any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. A girl was walking along the road, beautiful as a fairy. Suddenly she noticed a man following her. She turned around and asked: 
  - Tell me, why are you following me? 
  The man replied: 
  - O lord of my heart, your charms are so irresistible that they command me to follow you. They say that I play the lute, that I am privy to the mysteries of poetry and that I can awaken the anguish of love in the hearts of women. And to you I want to declare my love, because you have captivated my heart! 
  The beautiful woman looked at him silently for a while, then said: 
  - How could you fall in love with me? My little sister is much prettier and more attractive than me. She's coming after me, look at her. 
  The man stopped, then turned around, but saw only an ugly old woman in a patched cloak. Then he quickened his steps to catch up with the girl. Lowering his eyes, he asked in a voice expressing resignation: 
  - Tell me, how could a lie come out of your mouth? 
  She smiled and replied: 
  - You too, my friend, did not tell me the truth when you pledged your love. You know perfectly all the rules of love and pretend that your heart burns with love for me. How could you turn around to look at another woman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8">
		<text>Well - we're not so much over-the-top philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here's the story. A merchant sent his son to learn the Secret of Happiness from the wisest of men. The young man walked for forty days through the desert and finally came to a beautiful castle that stood on top of a mountain. The wise man he was looking for lived there. However, instead of the expected meeting with the wise man, our hero found himself in a room where everything was buzzing: traders were coming and going, people were talking in the corner, a small orchestra was playing sweet melodies and there was a table full of the most exquisite dishes of the area. The sage was talking to various people and the young man had to wait about two hours for his turn. 
  The wise man listened attentively to his explanation of the purpose of his visit, but answered that he did not have time to tell him the Secret of Happiness. He suggested he take a walk around the palace and come back in two hours. 
  - However, I have one favour to ask," the wise man added as he handed the young man a small spoon in which he dropped two drops of oil. - Keep this spoon in your hand the whole time you are walking so that the oil does not spill out. 
  The young man began to go up and down the palace stairs, keeping his eyes on the spoon. After two hours he returned to the sage. 
  - Well," he asked, "have you seen the Persian carpets that are in my dining room? Have you seen the park which the head gardener has been creating for ten years? Have you noticed the beautiful parchments in my library? 
  The young man had to confess in embarrassment that he had seen nothing. His only concern was not to spill the drops of oil the wise man had entrusted to him. 
  - Well, go back and see the wonders of my universe," the wise man told him. - You cannot trust a man if you are not familiar with the house in which he lives. 
  Relieved, the young man took the spoon and again went for a walk around the palace; this time, paying attention to all the works of art hung on the walls and ceilings of the palace. He saw the gardens surrounded by mountains, the delicate flowers, the delicacy with which each of the works of art had been placed exactly where it was needed. 
  Returning to the sage, he described in detail all that he had seen. 
  - Where are the two drops of oil I entrusted to you? - The wise man asked. 
  Nathan looked at the spoon and saw that all the oil had been poured out. 
  - That is the only advice I can give you: the secret of happiness is to look at all the wonders of the world and never forget the two drops of oil in your spoon. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9">
		<text>Hmmm, now I recall one of the last. Once upon a time in an Indian kingdom-state, there was an old monarch who spent his whole life deciding one purely Oriental question: what is the essence of power? He finally decided to find the strongest man in his kingdom in order to learn from him what the essence of strength was. As a reward for that hero the Indian tsar nominated a horse from his stables, and at the request of the winner of the contest: if he wants white - he gets a white horse, if he wants black - he gets a black one. To solve this difficult task associated with the eternal problem of choice, he gathered the wisest men of his kingdom and sent them to inspect the towns and villages.
  The monarch's task was indeed an unusually difficult one - the wise men had walked in many a pair of sandals, but they had not found the strongest man. They arranged competitions, gave many tasks to the aspirants to win, but the effect was zero: none of the subjects of the Indian king could unreservedly claim the right to be called the strongest man of the Indian kingdom. 
  The wise men had already despaired of finding a man to whom they could hand over one of the best horses in the royal stable... These "experts" were scratching their heads! They were not able to bear their own heads. Suddenly, while they were passing through a small village in India, they noticed a giant man. He was lying on a huge trestle bed in the middle of a large garden surrounding his house. "What immense power is hidden in this man!" - the wise men exclaimed and decided to put him to three tests. 
  "Can you break a horseshoe with one hand?" - the wise men asked the giant man. The man answered them nothing, but simply broke the horseshoe with his hand. "Can you uproot the tree?" - Again the wise men asked him. He answered them nothing, but simply put his two hands around the ten metre high tree and pulled it out of the ground in one fell swoop. "Truly you are strong, man! But can you block the river?" - the wise men asked a third time. The giant man answered them nothing, but approached the river, lifted a huge stone lying on the bank into the air and threw it into the stream, and the river stood up. "Praise the gods! - exclaimed the wise men. - Truly you are the strongest man on earth! Choose any of the king's horses: take the black one if you want, take the white one if you want!" 
  And just as the giant man put his hand above his head to scratch the back of his head before announcing his decision, a small, puny woman in a dark outfit suddenly appeared on his doorstep. "Husband, I warn you: if you choose a white man, you'll be in trouble! I can't vouch for myself!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10">
		<text>Well, now someone's starting to understand. Oh, man. I've had an epiphany in my life. So listen. There was a time when Genghis Khan was approached by the wife of a prince, asking her to free her relatives. 
  Genghis Khan said: 
  - Here, before you stand your husband, your son, and your brother. I will release only one, who will you choose? 
  Without thinking, she answered: 
  - My brother. 
  - Explain to me why? 
  The woman said: 
  - I can find a husband, I can give birth to a son, but I cannot create a brother. 
  After hearing this, Genghis Khan released all three. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11">
		<text>Well, how can I tell you, there is such a tendency among experienced walkers. We get hooked on one thing and then another. Listen. ...The gates of Zhongdu swung open, and steppe tribesmen streamed into the richest city in the Celestial Empire, shrieking and waving their weapons furiously. 
  Li Cui, known in Zhundu as Nosy Li, a stray of no lineage, who had come to the city from unknown climes just prior to the invasion, was a frail and disheveled Li Cui, limping through the lanes of the western suburbs, hoping for fortune. 
  If the great Guanyin helps him escape unharmed, he will become a shaved-headed saffron-robed monk, living on alms and indifferent to mundane concerns - and may other fools give perilous advice to the feeble-minded Son of Heaven, the dumbass emperor, and may the poor Celestial be raped and pillaged by any and all, be it greedy dignitaries, dirty Mongols, or... 
  Before he realized that Guanyin was now looking in a different direction, Nosy Li halted abruptly, hissing in pain at his bruised knee, and hauling the short, three-elbowed staff to his chest. 
  At the end of the lane, a tall, leather-clad Mongol grinned cheerfully, brandishing a long spear with a crossbar beneath its spearhead tube. 
  The disgraced warlord Li Kui, called Nosy Li in Zhundu and Blue Tiger Hou in the capital, sighed deeply and walked slowly toward the smirking steppeman, an effort of will forcing himself to stop limping. 
  The mongol waited until the frail ragamuffin approached, and lazily jabbed his spear in front of him. 
  A moment later the weapon was almost torn from his grasp, and when the astonished warrior jerked backward, holding the lance upward, a hollowed out staff flew into his face, hiding like a silkworm in a cocoon from prying eyes the Blue Tiger Hou's straight sword-jian. 
  The city was already on fire. Bitter smoke wafted through the streets of Zhongdu, ahead of the looting warriors of the indomitable Temujin Genghis Khan; The smoke rushed ahead of the invaders, making its way to the western outskirts, the acrid smoke made the throat farther and the leg of Li Kui unbearably sore, and the Mongol struck skillfully and ferociously, now with the tip, now with the back of the shaft, And so much had to move until Guanyin deigned to turn her benevolent gaze to Zhundu and to the abandoned alley, where Nosy Li had twice managed to reach the Mongol's wrists with his blade. 
  Now all that was left was to wait. To wait and not to fall under the spear, whose movements became more and more unsteady and trembling. And when they waited - to put the last forces in a last jump. 
  ...He never let go of his spear, this unlucky warrior in light leather armor. Coughing and cowering, he sat against the wall of someone's house, clutching his pierced side with his right hand while his left continued to rest on a lance. And above them, over the wounded Mongol and the powerless spear, breathing heavily and trying not to shift his weight on his injured leg, stood Li Kui, the former commander of Li's left wing, the former Blue Tiger Hou, the former Nosy Li, the future abbot of the monastery near Mount Utayshan, a tired little man. 
  Standing there, he watched the Mongol's face grow increasingly pale and his splitting wrists bleed less and less. 
  The Mongol raised his head with difficulty - and their gazes met. 
  Li Kui sighed, tore his cloak into strips, crouched beside the Mongol and began to bandage the invincible Genghis warrior's hands tightly. 
  Lee didn't know why he was doing this... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12">
		<text>Heh, when you've been balancing life and death for years any fool sooner or later becomes a philosopher. So listen. The king's daughter was as beautiful as the moon and enchanted all who were lucky enough to get a glimpse of her. One day a dervish was about to eat some bread and was about to eat it when he suddenly saw her and froze in amazement. His fingers were unclenched and the bread fell to the ground. As he passed by, the Princess smiled at the dervish. His body shook with delight, the bread was left lying in the dust and he almost lost his senses. The dervish remained in that state for seven years. The street became his home and stray dogs his neighbours. The Princess was fed up with the mad dervish and her bodyguards decided to kill him. She summoned him to her house and told him 
  - No alliance between us is possible. You must leave the city immediately, because my servants want to kill you. 
  The unhappy lover answered her thus: 
  - Since I have seen you, life has no value to me. They will shed innocent blood. But before I die, I beseech thee, grant me my one wish, for thou art the cause of my ruin. Tell me, why then did you smile at me? 
  - Fool!" said the Princess. - When I saw what a laugh you made of yourself, I smiled out of pity, that is all. 
  And, having said that, the princess fled. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13">
		<text>Well, we're not so great philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here's the story. There was a conversation between two wise men about love. One said: 
  - It is the nature of love to always bring torment and distress, and the one in love is always tormented and suffering. 
  The other objected: 
  - Shut up, you have apparently never experienced the sweetness of reconciliation after a quarrel and have never known the taste of connection after separation. No one in the world is purer and gentler than the pure of heart in love, and no one is dirtier than those who are far from the thought of love. 
  In the beauty of a man's heart is the glow of love's glow: 
  If the heart is ugly, it does not honour beauty! 
  Let the ignorant remember the sayings of the wise: 
  Where the breed honours the breed, the souls are confirmed. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14">
		<text>Hm, I recall a recent one. There once was a man who was obsessed by a mad love and was tormented by love. The beauty of the one he loved was incomparable even to the beauty of heavenly maidens. She was said to outshine the sun and the moon by her beauty. And in addition this her incomparable beauty was dangerous for people not only because it threatened everyone with the torment of love, but also because this beauty was clever and ruthless. 
  And so one day a man in love with her, thinking he was alone, said to himself: 
  - My God! Her face is more beautiful than a rose and her trunk more slender than a cypress! Her whole appearance is brighter than a peacock, and her gait is more graceful than that of a pheasant! 
  It turned out that his beloved was nearby at the time and had heard his words. Openly she stood before him and said: 
  - You probably wanted to flatter me with your comparisons, but they have only angered me, and I consider them for myself as shameful. You have compared my face to a rose, but where have you seen such beautiful eyes and eyebrows as mine? You have compared my loin to a cypress, but does the cypress have my mobility and ardour? You have compared my whole appearance to that of a peacock, but has anyone ever burned with love when contemplating peacocks? You have compared my walk to that of a pheasant, but who among men will ever soothe his soul in the recollection of a walking pheasant? 
  - Forgive me! - cried the lover. - I foolishly imagined that you could be described in words! 
  The words made the moon-faced woman all the more furious and she said in fury: 
  - For this foolishness of yours, I will have you! 
  Then the lover fell at her feet with the words: 
  - O incomparable unearthly Beauty! All my unspeakable speeches were caused by my true and pure love for thee. There is no malice, no reproach or even any complaint in them, and if they seemed inappropriate to thee, kindly do not charge me harshly for this fault, consider them a sign of my ignorance and ignorance, and I myself shall then perish from shame and disgrace! 
  And so long did he seek and utter the words of repentance that the beauty was pacified and gave up her intention of taking revenge on this man who was in love with her. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15">
		<text>Well, at least someone has begun to understand us. Well, well, well. So much for an epiphany in life. So listen.  There was a thief in the old days. One day he robbed the treasury of the sultan. The padishah sent all his detectives after him. The thief was caught and his loot taken away. Then the sultan asked his chief vizier: 
  - What to do with this thief? 
  - All the people of the city should be gathered and the thief should be slaughtered in front of all the people," replied the vizier. 
  The Emperor had a daughter. The padishah asked her: 
  - Is the Vizier right? 
  - The Vizier reasoned in essence," replied the girl. 
  Then the padishah asked the middle vizier: 
  - What to do with this thief? 
  - We must stack more firewood, put the thief on it and set it on fire. 
  Again the padishah asked his daughter: 
  - How do you find what the vizier said? 
  And the daughter of the Vizier answered again: 
  - Your vizier has reasoned in essence. 
  Finally the Padishah asked his younger vizier: 
  - What to do with the thief? 
  - We should clothe the thief from head to toe, give him everything so that his belly is always full, and let him go. 
  The Padishah again asked his daughter: 
  - How do you find what the Vizier said? 
  - 'Your vizier has reasoned in essence,' the girl replied. 
  Then the padishah said: 
  - 'You said of each of the three viziers that he reasoned in essence. What do you mean by that, explain it to us. 
  And the girl answered: 
  - The chief vizier, who said that the thief should be slaughtered, must be of butchers by birth. Your middle vizier must be of brick-firing stock. And the younger vizier is by all accounts a nobleman. 
  The Padishah checked and it turned out that the girl was right. The thief was dealt with as the junior vizier advised: he was fed to his heart's content, given money for expenses and spared from death. And the junior vizier was made chief vizier. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16">
		<text>Well, how can I tell you, there is such a tendency among experienced walkers. We get hooked on one thing and then another. Listen. Once a gang of robbers went out to plunder. 
  Once they'd got a lot of stuff, they started to divide it up amongst themselves. All the shares were equal, and only a dress made of the finest thread - it was considered to be the worst share - was given to the weakest in the gang. And the weakest one, having received his share, became enraged. He began to shout that he had been outmanoeuvred. 
  When he came to the city to sell his garment, all the rich men started to offer him a lot of money. What he got on his own was twice what all his companions got together. 
  Then he rejoiced and jumped for joy. It is like the laymen who, not knowing whether giving alms will result in a reward or not, give out a small amount of alms (part of their income). But when they are reborn in heaven and experience immense bliss, they begin to regret - they regret that they did not give out extensive alms (their entire fortune). They are like one who, having received large sums of money for a dress, rejoices. It is the same with giving alms. 
  That's why along with rejoicing they have regrets for the incompleteness of the deed. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17">
		<text>Huh, when you're balancing between life and death for years any fool sooner or later becomes a philosopher. So listen. Once upon a time there was a family: husband, wife and daughter. The family was poor, poor, and could barely make ends meet. The husband and wife began to think how they could get rich. 
  - We're living in poverty now. Let's look for a rich man, settle down with him, see what he is doing, and we will imitate him in everything. 
  So they did. They broke down their hut and built a new one next to the rich setkhei's house. The setkhei made his workers work the field and vegetable garden and then sent them out to sell the crops. The poor tried to imitate the setkhei in what they could, working in the field and then selling part of the harvest in the bazaar. Gradually they were doing better and better and their income was increasing. 
  The husband and wife decided to thank the setkhei from whom they had learned to farm in secret. The husband took a handful of gold and went to the rich man. 
  - Why have you brought me gold? - The sethei wondered. 
  - I was a poor man. So my wife and I decided to destroy our hut and settle near your house and imitate you in all things. Our business quickly improved, the family became rich, and out of gratitude we asked you to accept our gift. 
  - Since you yourself believe that you have acquired all your wealth thanks to me, then it is my wealth. You should give me all your fortune and I will decide for you what share to give. 
  - But I did not remain ungrateful and brought you the gold. If I had known that you would demand my entire fortune, I would have brought you nothing. 
  Dutyo argued sethey and the former poor man. Finally, they went to the judge. The judge could not settle their dispute, and took them both to the king. The former poor man bowed and said: 
  - 'Your Majesty, I settled near the house of the setkhei and watched how he farms, how he sends his workers to work the field and to trade in the bazaar. I imitated the setkhei in whatever way I could, and achieved prosperity and good fortune in my affairs. Out of gratitude, I brought gold to the setkhei, who helped me without my knowing it, but the setkhei demands my entire fortune. Please, Your Majesty, sort out this matter justly. 
  The King turned to the Sethei: 
  - "Is this man's case correct? 
  - All is right, Your Majesty. 
  The king realized that the Sethei was greedy, and said: 
  - Sethei, do you have children? 
  - A son, Your Majesty. 
  - And you? - The king turned to the former poor man. 
  - A daughter, your majesty. 
  - So that there will be no quarrel between you, I command the two families to intermarry. Then you will have nothing to share. 
  Sethei and the former poor man bowed low to the king and left to follow the king's wise decision. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18">
		<text>Well - we're not so much over-the-top philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here's the story. Once upon a time, there lived a hermit man in the desert. Once upon a time, he was a good carpenter in his homeland. But by chance, life took him to the desert. A rich man came to know about the master and sought him out: 
  - "They say you are a good craftsman. So I want to order from you an oak table and chairs for my hall. I will come for my order in a month and I will pay you well. 
  And he left. After the appointed time, the rich man came to the craftsman again and asked: 
  - Where are my table and chairs? 
  - Yes, I am a good craftsman. But this is not enough. In order for me to fulfill your order, I also need wood and tools, which I do not have... 
  Desire alone is not enough: you also need capabilities... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19">
		<text>Hm, I now recall one of the last. A letter arrived in Shamil's army informing some warrior that his wife had died. The letter was received by Shamil himself. He decided to check on that soldier and sent for him. When he arrived, Shamil said: 
  - A letter has come for you with the news that your father has died. 
  - If so, the roof of our house has fallen off, and I need to go home," replied the warrior. 
  - No, not my father died, but your brother did. 
  - Then the wall of the house collapsed and I have to go to the funeral. 
  - It turned out that it was not your brother who had died, but your mother. 
  - So the house started to fall down. I have to go home. 
  - Not your mother, but your sister passed away. 
  - A flower has fallen from my heart, I must go home. 
  - I was checking up on you. In fact, your wife is dead. 
  - If so, the whole house has fallen apart and there's nothing left of it. There's no reason for me to go home now. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20">
		<text>I can't believe someone's starting to understand us. Well... I've had an epiphany in my life. So listen. There were two men driving towards each other. One was in a hurry to help his benefactor, the other was in a hurry to celebrate. They met on a narrow bridge and did not want to give way to each other. They argued and argued and went to the judge. The judge could not understand their case, so he took them both to the king. 
  The king asked: 
  - Explain to me why you didn't want to give way to each other. 
  One of the disputants answered: 
  - Your Majesty, I was in a hurry for the feast, I met this man on the bridge, but he would not let me pass. 
  The second disputant said: 
  - At one time a man did me a great favour. Now he was in trouble. I rushed to his aid. That is why I did not give way. 
  The king ruled as follows: 
  - The one who rushed to the feast must compensate the one who rushed to the aid of his benefactor. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_baiki_talk">
		<text>What interesting things can you tell us about life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_baiki_end">
		<text>Quite entertaining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_1">
		<text>The regiment I served in had a rather large outbuildings. Decent-sized greenhouse, pigsty, and even had a horse called Buket.
A soldier of Romani nationality looked after the pigs in the pigsty. One pig farrowed in winter. Everybody was rejoicing, the pigs were counted and weighed, and at night one of them died... In the morning, the deputy comes to see the farrower, and the gypsy (I don't remember his name) shows him the newly-born pig. So what to do? They wrote one off.
And the gypsy, being a fool, didn't throw the piggy away, but threw it in a snowdrift. A day or two later, he takes one of the pigs alive (because of the age, I do not remember, whether he just ate it with his friends, or sold it to the locals), and the deputy clerk presents him the dead one, hiding it in a snowdrift.
Another one was written off. And that one went back to the snowdrift. Alas, in a second attempt to trick the bosses in the same way, his swindle failed.
The regiment commander was very angry when it was reported to him. He came to the pigsty personally. For some reason he particularly disliked the radio that stood in the room where the gypsy slept. It was a big, ancient radio in a wooden case. And he made the soldier drag the receiver from the pigsty to the parade ground, where the whole regiment was standing. And then to march along the square together with the receiver. And when the deputy officer asked, "How long?" He answered: "Till Nikolay Slitchenko sings...".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_2">
		<text>The big diesel submarine was at sea, on combat duty. According to the daily plan, the so-called anti-disaster measures - actions aimed at not fighting the actual accidents - were carried out. In the central post the brigade's deputy commander was peacefully gnawing on breadcrumbs. The comrade was notable for his rather exuberant temper, but on that day he had not touched anyone.
And the crew of the boat had a midshipman by the name of Pozhar, a man of a breed who is always needed by everybody. This time Deputy Brigadier suddenly needed him for something. When it was discovered that the midshipman was not in his regular position, a command was given across the boat:
- Report which compartment the midshipman is in!
The command was given and in the commotion it was immediately forgotten.
Suddenly, from the diesel compartment, they reported over the loudspeaker:
- Central, Fire in bay five! (But you can't see the capital letters in the verbal!!!
The reaction of the central post was immediate and unambiguous. Short bells rang out, followed by words that made even the thickest of skinheads wince:
- Emergency alarm! Fire in bay five!
There was something to make your soul ache. There was a lot to burn in the diesel compartment...
The boatswain on command shifted the horizontal rudders to float, acoustics intensely listened to the horizon (would not bump into someone on the surface), bilge engineers prepared to activate a very serious fire-extinguishing system for the fifth compartment.
The central post yelled:
- Fifth! Fifth, report the situation! What's burning in there!
The diesel crew replied calmly and embarrassed:
- There's nothing on fire. The command was to report in which compartment midshipman Fire was in, so we did.
After the emergency alarm was canceled, there was a "debriefing" in the central post, with all the terms from the naval lexicon used. Then the deputy commander announced over the loudspeaker:
- Attention, submarine comrades! From now until the end of the autonomy this b...c. will have the surname Ivanov!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_3">
		<text>In the early 2000s I was actively involved in organising and preparing various charity events, where the main trump card was an opportunity to meet very serious people on an equal footing. And to help children, of course. While organising one of these events, which took place in a departmental hotel, I helped a woman from the "I can do anything, but I don't want anything for myself" class. In return for the enormous amount of work involved in preparing and collecting the money, I was promised some extremely valuable contacts among sponsors.
Actually, at any charity event, especially a large-scale one, there are 4 main categories of people - the real sponsors, the organisers of the event with their various artists etc., and the "support staff". The organizers of the event with their various artists, "service personnel", children or other recipients of charity, and, actually, the category we would like to single out, because we will talk about it further - their majesties, the freeloaders. Of course not all of them are full-fledged freeloaders - some of them contribute a little to the fund to help children, but don't get me wrong, if they are preparing a banquet for sponsors for 100 quid per person, then they actually count not for 200 rubles for the lottery ticket they bought.
At the very beginning of the event I looked around the hall and noticed each of the 4 groups of invitees. There weren't that many freeloaders this time - still the control was on the level, but still they were present, because the table was full of food and drinks, and the programme included celebrity performances and other goodies. The evening was divided into 2 parts - during the first part there was a story about for whom the money was raised, children's performance and in the closing there was a charity auction.
It was the auction that revealed the total freeloaders. For they never buy anything and try not to show themselves in front of the auctioneer actively working with the hall, but often silently leave the hall during the auction (charity auctions differ by the fact that they often sell the work of children themselves, and without active work with the hall to promote children's creativity product, the proceeds of the auction will be miserable). It was at the auction, I was very surprised by the behavior of one of the freeloaders, who attracted my attention from the first glance into the hall. This was a guy of about 30 and a ponytail, completely rustic looking, very simply dressed (although freeloaders always try to blend in) and with the look of a child from a small Siberian town who was taken to the Kremlin Christmas tree for the first time in his life. The guy didn't even buy a raffle ticket, which completely killed me.
There was a lot of organizing to do, and it all fell on my young shoulders (I was 22), but the event was responsible and, as they say in the famous movie "These are kids!
In intermission the woman to whom I helped, has executed the promise and has actually acquainted me with some very serious people from Russia and not only.
When I asked if there was anyone really cool, she hesitated and said she couldn't answer. Actually, even the contacts I received were quite enough for serious accomplishments, and I decided to score.
During the second part there were performances by artists, which I was directly involved in organising. And whether the stars were aligned, or the atmosphere was favourable - in general, the festival was a success with a capital letter - the sponsors' eyes were burning, I was dripping with sweat and I ate nothing in the morning. A freeloader I spotted rejoiced like a child, clapped and ate in both cheeks.
After the event, all the guests came around with a piggy bank and they poured a sum that no one really counted on, but the freeloaders shoved a hundred roubles each at best, while my village guest poured nothing at all. In general, the woman organiser was happy. When the guests started to leave, she said: "Okay, you've helped me a lot, I'll show you a 'hero of our time'. But you have to promise me that you won't tell anyone about him and won't ask him any questions - he's a very shy person and he's never really known for his help.
This man has financed the construction of new buildings for 300 children in our orphanage and all the infrastructure, as well as the installation of a gas pipeline from the nearest village. I gave her my word.
We walked out the hotel door together and she pointed me to the very country boy who was getting behind the wheel of an ordinary second-hand Volga.
To say that there was a revolution in my mind is nothing to say. The fact that I personally saw this construction site, which was moving at a revolutionary speed. And even then I understood very well how much gas supply costs and who I had to be to approve it in such a short time.
It was at that moment that the phrase "a really serious person" came to me.
Since then, when I look at the "freeloaders" at such events, I always remember those childish, full of love and simple joy eyes, and look for such people among them.
Sometimes I find them. And immediately I understand everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_4">
		<text>It was a long time ago. At the very beginning of the 1990s. I worked as a young professional in a renowned institute that designed our supercomputers. They did not pay me much, and I had to screw around. 
Once we were in Perm to earn some extra money. There some cooperative society sold to the local factory like NefteOrgSintez a batch of Chinese crap (players, toasters, a couple of TV sets) to encourage their employees. Of course, the reject rate was over 50. So, here's the story:
Having repaired these wonders of technics, we are sitting in airport, weather is bad, snow with rain. A flight to Moscow has been postponed for the second time. We are having a drink in a restaurant. After a while I realise that I can't drink any more - I could die! Let me go for a walk in the freezing cold - to sober up a bit... and I found myself at an airfield. I saw: some military transport was being loaded.
- Where are we flying to? - I asked.
- To Moscow.
- Take it with you.
- Bring three bladders and get on board.
— Gut!
I fly like a bullet to get vodka, a bag with a pair of pants already with me for some reason, and back. I reach home very cheerfully. I think the crew were drinking with us. (I vaguely remember a phrase exchanged by a man in a pilot's uniform: To fly is bullshit! The main thing is to land!") We landed in Zhukovsky. We were taken out of the territory in an UAZ truck under a tarpaulin. Then I don't remember. It's four in the morning, I sleep in a soft bed at home. The phone rings. My wife reluctantly answers the phone. In my sleep, I can hear her trying to say something to the person on the other end of the line for about five minutes. Finally she shoves the phone at me with the words: "Tell him that! - Hello," I say.
- Who is it? Dimon, you?
- Well.
Pause.
- Fucking hell! Asshole! Asshole!
Et cetera.
- We've got the entire Perm police force on their ears! A man with money is missing! The traffic cops are looking at the cars when they leave. The plane took off without us (it's a flight)! And you, you bastard, you're home on the couch, sleeping on the couch!
Anyway, the next day I took a sick day. Just in case...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_5">
		<text>That was long ago, when planes flew drunk and there were no terrorists.
We had one guy on watch, let's say Vasya. He spends a month on the job, a month at home fasting, so he can't really relax. The last day of the shift
with the guys, and in a state of autopilot with the help of the same wretches on the plane. And the collection for the bus from the territory of the base, lies his rucksack,
and good jokers, of which there are plenty, put a valve in the backpack.
The valve is a thing of this length 25 cm, 8.3 cm in diameter and weighs four pounds.
That's it - he loads, flies, meets his beloved wife, the salary is taken away at once, his baggage is thrown into the wash, and there is a piece of metal on the floor.
- Vasya, what's this for?
Who wants to admit that you were tricked and you dragged an unnecessary piece of metal over 3,000 km.
- This is a necessary item for the countryside, and you go to the shop.
The wife has gone to the shop and Vasya, angry with a hangover, looks at the device and throws it out the window in disgust. Steps of his wife in the hallway, an object which resembles a forty-turn medicinal potion is placed on the table, Vasya opens his eyes.
- Vasya, you dragged the spare part all the way from the shop and I saw the same thing lying under the window.
Vasya's valve stands proudly on the table...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_6">
		<text>I did my duty as a radio operator at the "Zhilny" reserve command post in 1978-1980. I used to salute officers without my hat. There was a deputy major, I do not remember his full name. I was called by our commander "Filipok", colonel Filipov, a commander from God. I entered the cabinet and, as it should be according to the regulations, I reported, putting my right hand to my temple. I did not wear my cap after taking off my earphones, as I was on the combat duty. 
Our deputy political officer was also with Filipko. So he says:
- You don't put your hand on an empty head.
I should have said nothing, but the devil made me answer:
- Sometimes a head with a cap and cockade buzzes like an empty can.
Filipok smiled, and the deputy officer twisted. That's it, I think, the lip is secured.
Having listened to the order and answered:
- Yes, let me do it, - I left the office.
I do not know how the other officers found out about this case, but in about three hours they began to prophesy that I would become a general.
By the way, all the officers shook hands with us conscripts after saluting, one deputy general never did...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_7">
		<text>An ordinary hose is a long rubber gut. "Pretending to be a hose" for a Soviet soldier is the same as playing misunderstood, passively sabotaging the orders of his commanding fathers. Sometimes at the expense of their fellow soldiers, so "rubbers" - those who take their service seriously and gain positive points in the eyes of their superiors by any means (rubbing) - do not like hosers very much. However, there are also hosers in law who are like the Russian spy Stirlitz: "What is there to catch! He is cunning and will get away with it anyway". Such people are treated with love.
There are few conscripts who do not want to go home soon. More often than not, they dream quietly about it. Some try to cheat. There was a legend in our unit about a soldier who entered the barracks for the first time and immediately went in search of the heaviest weight. He did it every spare minute, and was encouraged for this zeal by his company commander. Only a month later the boy came to the medical unit and said:
- "My left hand is dry...
The chief medical officer measured the circumference of both arms, but of course only the difference in the results, as he was supposed to do according to the instructions...
- Let's check the trend, warrior," said the major, slightly surprised. After a couple of weeks of even more intensive exercises with kettlebells the difference increased and by the end of the calendar month the soldier went to his native Grodno...
For some reason he didn't manage to find any followers - evidently, even the most stupid ones realised that the epidemic of desiccation would not go unnoticed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_8">
		<text>This story happened at the time when my uncle was in the Soviet army, around 1980.
Somehow, two soldiers brought sand to their military unit on a ZIL truck. In principle, a dump truck is a very handy thing, you pull the lever, and the loose material falls out in a neat pile, succumbing to the laws of gravity. But as it was in deep autumn with rain and hoar-frost the sand in the truck body froze a little. And it didn't want to fall out as it was inclined. But the driver and his partner were an example of good mindedness and decided that in the highest point of body's rising the sand couldn't hold together in any case and it would fall down on the ground like a punishment from heaven. Usually, it happens this way, but our fellows didn't take into account that they had parked the truck on a slight slope. And the sand which is not falling out seriously raises the centre of gravity of their machine, as a result ZILok falls on a side (thus the sand at last come off from a body), in a cabin, naturally our soldiers fall at each other.
The history, however, is rather habitual - dump trucks are overturned rather frequently. The most interesting thing happened immediately after the fall; a crowd of soldiers, who were observing the unloading process with interest, immediately ran up to the cab of the ZIL, smashed almost all the glass with their mighty pink boots and whatever materials were at hand, and pulled out two of our friends from the cab, grabbing for whatever they could; as a result, one of them had a torn uniform, the other one's face was scratched.
As it turned out, the soldiers who were watching were frightened by the explosion and decided to heroically rescue our drivers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_9">
		<text>I don't remember who told me this story, but it goes like this. This story took place in the days of the Soviet army. In one of the regions of our immense motherland there was a military unit, I do not remember what kind of unit it was. Whether infantry, or artillery, but it doesn't matter. Here and imagine, quiet, dark summer night, all part sleeps strong, heroic sleep. In one of barracks, as it is necessary to be awake, the sergeant on duty (an old-serviceman who has hardly more than a month left till demobilization) and the private (just called up "spirit") stand on the bedside table, struggling with sleep with all their might, And the sergeant takes a deep nap in the so-called "Lenin's room". I should note at once, as this will play a role in the future, the orderlies and attendants were equipped with only one weapon - the bayonet-knife, which was as strictly controlled as any other weapon.
And then at one point, when the night was in full swing, the young soldier suddenly realized that either his stomach had not yet adapted to soldier food, or he had caught some kind of infection, or both. And that unless he takes urgent action, the entire contents of his bowels will drain into his boots. In an anguished whisper, so as not to wake up the company, he calls the officer on duty. In the same whisper, he swears and curses at the "spirits" that are keeping him from demobilizing, and asks the reason for the interruption of his sweet sleep. The young man quickly, clearly and concisely, as the military code teaches, states the reason for the alarm. The sergeant, grumbling and cursing all young men and their delicate mothers' stomachs again, lets the orderly go to the toilet, and himself stands at his post. The fruits of civilisation in the form of the sewer system did not arrive in this section, and for the needs of nature there was a wooden toilet, which stood alone, and in the most remote place, for three points, and without any partitions. 
And so the young man with enviable speed overcoming the distance from the barracks to the sanitary building, on the fly unbuttoning his ammunition, reclines over one of the holes and blissfully relaxed. And then, at the climax of the action, the bayonet knife, issued to defend the country, slips from his belt and falls into the hole with a mocking "boom". When the soldier realises what has happened, the force of his heel's urges increases threefold. The images in his head are of being judged for the loss of his weapon, but even worse, of what the sergeant will do to him... He is soaked with sweat that he crawls into the barracks and tells his sergeant everything. 
When the sergeant understands that he will be beaten up no less, and maybe even more, and that his demobee will be moved to the very end of the line, he already begins to feel sick to his stomach. But Russian soldier, as they say, is invincible and will find a way out of any situation. After some hesitation the sergeant comes up with what seems to him to be the only solution at the moment. He puts the young man in an OZK suit (regular army protective kit designed to protect against chemical weapons), a gas mask and sends him back. He sends him back, as if to say: go, dive, search and do not come back without a knife. The young man has started to carry out the order without thinking too much. 
But here is bad luck, at this very time, the officer on duty, a major in the Soviet army, has got a craving. He goes to the above-mentioned establishment and with a peaceful look settles over the hole. 
And now imagine the major's reaction, when out of the next box, suddenly something in a gas mask, covered in shit and holding a dagger in his hand comes out. As the assistant on duty later recounted, the major ran into the control room with wild eyes, one hand up his unbuttoned trousers and the other waving his service Makarov, he smelled like shit a mile away and shouted something about saboteurs or unclean forces. 
As a result the unit was put on alert. After some investigation, the two soldiers were given 15 days in the brig and the major was sent to get his nerves better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_10">
		<text>It went like this. There were training jumps in one of the military units. The process of the jump itself, as such, with an ordinary airborne parachute (D-5) does not seem difficult enough. 
You fall out of the plane, count to yourself: "501, 502, 503" - and after that, having flown not less than 60 m, try to find the filled parachute dome above your head. Having found the canopy in the right place, you land carefully. Everything was going according to plan - you dropped out, opened the canopy, landed. But here's the trouble, one poor bastard was unlucky. No, the dome opened, but he didn't reach the ground. A gust of wind blew the dome to pine trees surrounding the landing site. And here's a vivid picture: a soldier hangs in the branches of a mighty ship pine at the height of 10 metres like a puppet. It's impossible to reach the trunk, it's possible to crawl up the slings, but the same problem of getting down on the ground arises. Usually, in such cases they open the reserve parachute (it is located on the chest) and, using its slings, descend to the ground. As the fighter is young, several advisers rushed to his aid. Having enjoyed the picture they all started shouting together: "Pull the spare! Then everything happened as in the movies. The frightened paratrooper took out his slingshot... ...cut the lines of the main parachute in one fell swoop and pulled the ring of the reserve parachute...
Ð. S. I have to ascertain - the record on parachute jumps from extra low altitude was not established at that time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_11">
		<text>There was a student nicknamed Yellow in my group at the military department. A unique swearer, apparently from the womb. Well and the usual trouble for students happened to him - during self-preparation his officer-teacher caught him keenly playing cards with one more idiot... that is a student. 
As a punishment they gave him a bucket of quick-drying paint, brushes and an order to paint all the tables and chairs in the lecture room. The work was done, handed over to the officer on duty, the brushes washed...
The cleaning lady came the next morning to wash the floor and the first thing she did was to turn all the chairs upside down, placing them on the tables. Her second action was to go to the teacher's room, from where she returned with the deputy head of the department and showed him the three letters, familiar to everyone since childhood, repeated many times on the unpainted back side of the chairs. That same day a couple of cheerful painters appeared before the bright eyes of the head of the department.
- What the hell are you students doing?" gently scolded them.
Yellow suddenly sprang into line, clicked his heels and reported
- Sorry comrade colonel, it came out!
- How many times you blurted it out, - the colonel marvelled.
- And that's how many times it came out, that's how many times I wrote, - phlegmatically finished Yellow...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_12">
		<text>I used to work in the institute of instrument-making in Moscow on Kutuzovsky; next to the entrance there is a monument to heroic pilot Valentina Grizodubova, those who have passed by it, surely noticed a granite woman with a flight helmet. In Soviet times they used to develop airborne radar systems there, but after the collapse of the USSR they mostly switched to commercial orders, you have to eat for something. And then the Ministry of Defence ordered me to create a kind of "black box", the purpose of which I will not talk about for obvious reasons. About the fact, that in the process of adjustment to sit in the technical compartment of A-50 for several hours is not to sit in the easy chair of "Boeing" and sip brandy, too, I will not tell, the story is not about it. Colonels-generals from the ministry came to inspect the prototype of our product. One of the points of the act of acceptance is the test of the tightness of the case. The casing has a tricky shape, but for simplicity of description let it be just a cube with one-meter edge. The method of leak test is purely Soviet, no complicated measuring instruments, the casing is sunk with a winch into a giant aquarium of thick Plexiglas, three meters deep. If air bubbles are seen floating in the water, the entire device is discarded, together with all the electronics inside, according to the test regulations.
Have you ever seen abandoned factories in the movies? The room with the aquarium looked something like that, and the last time the aquarium was cleaned it was probably in the Soviet times. The water had become rusty and murky. The winch, which was pulling the tested product under the water, had been stolen a long time ago, probably scrapped. We called a worker to drown the body with his hands. Let me remind you that this is not a balloon - it is a big sealed aluminium cube. The worker did not manage to sink the cube on his own. We, simple engineers, refused to help the worker - our job is to come up with schemes, not to play with cubes. But the soldiers seized the worker's initiative, three men in uniforms with plenty of stars rolled up their sleeves, climbed the ramp around the aquarium and began pushing the stubborn cube down, shouting "and one! and two! and three! 
They almost succeeded in doing so. At the last moment the cube tumbled on its side, and all except the prudent worker could not hold on and ended up in the aquarium. Those standing nearby jumped away and shook the dirty water off their clothes, the "gurgle" was not a bad one. The aquarium began chaos, just try to imagine what was happening: soldiers trying to get out, someone constantly stepping on someone, sending him down (and the depth is three meters), then falls down himself, and stepped on him. A metal cube floating around a meter long circle complements the picture, and they tried to grab hold of it, as a lifebuoy, but it kept turning over and hitting the next resurfacing one on the different parts of the body. The phrase "fuck, help me" was the most censurable, I will not quote the rest of the shouts of the soldiers and the words of those who were watching. 
It went on like that for half a minute, maybe more, until a worker, who had fallen on the ramp, came out of his stupor and gave the drowning men a hand. The muddy soldiers in drenched uniforms were taken away somewhere, probably to treat us to a 40-degree sedative, and the "presentation" of the machine was over. We had a smoke break, discussed what had happened and went back to work. Contrary to expectations, no one was "in trouble". And later it became known that our "black box" was allowed by the military, although a couple of tests after the visiting committee of "free pool" (so we had a joke) the device was not used.
PS. Before the arrival of high officials product of course previously subjected to all tests, except for bathing in the notorious aquarium, can this prototype still flies on one of the "Russian Avaks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_13">
		<text>I happened to find myself in hospital with the most banal sciatica. I was about 25 years old at the time - a real fop, a favourite of women and a real Don Juan. To make an accurate diagnosis, I decided to make an image of the spinal column. And for this, it would seem, quite simple procedure, turns out, pre enema is done - so that all kinds of excesses in the intestines do not interfere with a picture of all my set of intervertebral hernias (alas, even in such young years it happens to the back).
Having grabbed a fair roll of toilet paper, I go where I'm told to. I was in the treatment room (one of the three). There was an old lady in a white coat. Lay down here, on the baby's couch, on the side. So I laid down. Took a dose. Auntie leaves. I see a toilet in the corner of the room. There's no hint of any partitions or cubicles. It's just sitting there all alone in the corner, beckoning. It stands on a kind of foundation, and if you climb on it, you will look like a proud bird on a rock. And the process inside me was already in full swing. I jump to the door, looking for something that looks like a latch, a lock - no! I peek out into the corridor, estimating the distance to the place I knew. I realise with all my gut that I will not make it there and I jump onto the snow-white toilet with a white-tailed eagle.
As it turned out later that day the hospital was full of trainees from the local medical school. The picture is not for the nervous ones: in the red corner of the room, in the frontal seat, a young eagle was standing proudly, tenaciously holding a roll of paper in its claws. The process of preparing the spine for the photo session is in full swing and is already virtually unstoppable. After every minute the door to the room opens and the pretty head of an innocent creature in a white coat appears:
- Is Mary Ivanna here? Ouch!
Another minute. Another equally pretty head:
- And Mary Ivanna... Ow!
How many trainees have been lucky enough to observe the proud bird perched on that damned earthenware ledge, I can't remember now. There were a lot of them. And one prettier than the other. But it didn't make me very happy somehow....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_14">
		<text>It was in the Army. I went to the Irkutsk Military Aviation School with my brother. We were twins. Not exactly alike, but you can't really tell at once. Once, when passing exams, my brother got into the infirmary (they put him to bed).
But how could he take the exam if they wouldn't let him out of the infirmary (the army, damn it)? I refused to take the exam for both of them at once, but why not to lie in my brother's place while he was taking it? So I took the exam that day, ran to the infirmary, and changed clothes with my brother. The thing was that I had never been in the infirmary and had no idea where anything was. So my brother explained: go up to the first floor, enter such-and-such a ward, find such-and-such a bed in such-and-such a row, it was yours! Without any problem I found the bed and went to sleep. I lie there, rejoicing in life. I think I'll get some sleep after the exam.
Five minutes later a nurse comes in and says: "Gov for a shot!" I'm thrown out of bed, screaming: "What shot? I'm fine." She's like, "I don't know anything. I'm waiting in the Procedure Room." I think I'm in trouble, that's it! I'm about to get skinned for my brother. I'm thinking, what do I do? And I got this crazy idea to sit in the bathroom.
I was in the bathroom for 20 minutes. I think it's time to come out. I crawl out of the toilet, thinking I'm gonna sneak into my room. I see some lady standing there in a dressing gown. She sees me and says, "Oh, Gov, take these cans to the canteen." P-o-o-o!!! How do I know where the canteen is? So I take the cans and walk down the corridor, hoping I'm going in the right direction. Madam of the joint presses on me: like what is it that he is slowing down? I walk down the corridor, cursing my brother and reading the signs on the doors. On the last door, I see a sign saying "Canteen".
Oh, thank God! Found it! I threw those cans in and raced to my room. And just as I was laying down, this nurse came back: "Gov, how long can we wait for you? Let's go." And that was it! I finally got my shot of penicillin in the ass for my brother. Then we laughed for a long time, especially me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_15">
		<text>This funny story happened in the glorious Soviet army. They sent the cadets out to clean a howitzer. People fussed with the bannister, everyone ran back and forth, the bannister was lavishly sprinkled with a special detergent which contained SEVEN alkalis!
Since it was happening in our country, the cadets cleaned the gun without protective suits or even gloves. And then, one of them had to "take a piss".
Took a piss, got back in line. He feels somehow uncomfortable, and the main thing is that with every minute the discomfort gets stronger and stronger! Looked at it, baaaah! My dick is swollen, red and four times bigger than usual!
When I got to the hospital, I was told that the cadet washed the swollen dick well, put bandages on it (incompetently) and went to the infirmary.
There was no doctor on site. There was only a young paramedic sitting in the waiting room. The young paramedic looked sternly at the wounded soldier and asked about the wounded soldier:
- What's up, soldier?
- Well... see for yourself...
A little embarrassed, the boy pointed at his fly open, his penis in a Gordian knot sticking out.
- Oh, my God! What on earth have you done to him!? (genuinely surprised by the nurse)
- I was cleaning a gun...
The cadet was not allowed to finish his speech, because of the wild laughter of the girl-feldsher and the doctor who arrived in time, the work of the medical unit was simply paralyzed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_16">
		<text>I served in Germany. Here in Russia I could go on leave or go AWOL, but there, even if I was, where could I go? Germans everywhere! One day we went on a field trip. When we got there we heard over the grapevine that there was a lake not too far away where a nudist beach was located, which in the mid-eighties was something unimaginable, and the mere thought of it could be compared to the power of five kilotons of Viagra. - Great! - I said to Igor, and began to think of a plan of action.
The next evening, due to the temporary absence of officers, we decided to take a chance. Of those who had previously shown the courage to go, only three of us remained - Igor, Musa and I. The rest of us squinted our brains and excused ourselves. In short, we pissed ourselves. Like real scouts, we agreed to go to the beach unnoticed, disguised as Germans. The lake was not big, so we decided to swim from the other side and come ashore as if nothing had happened. So here we were, on the other side of the lake, pulling off our uniforms. At this point doubts began to creep in about the possibility of being undetected.
Musa was covered with gowns like "GSVH", "I love like an angel, I laugh like a devil", and other combinations of the soldier's folklore. There were tattoos everywhere, intensified by dense black vegetation starting from the top of his head and up to his heels. I had a feeling that he was a snowman. In short, he did not look very much like a German. But being a man from the mountains, Musa had good eyesight and a hot temper. Apparently having already seen tits through his natural binoculars, Musa immediately became tense along with his little brother. - Nah, I'm not taking my panties off," he declared. Despite the fact that our secret journey would be exposed at the first sight of Musa, we still tried to persuade him to take off those blue, washed out HB shorts, for which our army is famous, which we succeeded not without difficulty.
Musa was all right. And here we were in the middle of the lake, swimming like real Germans, the first fragments of naked bodies were already being flashed, women's voices were already being heard, and we were almost on the shore. Preemptively suppressing all natural instincts, which were not affected even by the cold water, Igor and I went to the shore, trying not to look around, and settled down on the sand, as if nothing had happened. Only then did we discover that Musa was standing waist-deep in the water with his mouth wide open and his eyes wider open.
The nearby Germans grinned. A parachute with Cyrillic letters peeped out of the bushes of hair on Musa's chest, but Musa still believed that he looked like a German. We started to give stealthy signs saying, "Come on out. Musa shook his head in a strange way and answered in pure German: "Nein! Standing like a stone in the cold water for fifteen minutes, Musa attracted the attention of half the beach, causing smiles and encouraging phrases in German, shimmering red shades of embarrassment under his fur. Time to rescue a comrade, we thought. Going into the water and approaching him from the back, we started to gently push him to the shore.
Musa resisted, swearing in Russian, for some reason, like radio operator Cat during the birth, revealing a military secret. Musa could not resist our pressure and found himself on the shore. Realising he could not deal with us easily, he fell on his stomach. But as the secrecy of our operation had already been compromised, laughing out loud and waving everything we could, we dragged Musa by the arms onto the sand to the resounding "I'm your mother's laugh" and applause of the onlookers. Musa stayed like that the whole time on his stomach, attracting the local females to us. As a result, Igor and I several times went AWOL in the nearest village to our newly baked girlfriends, but without Musa.
Z.I. Musa ran very fast back into the water).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_17">
		<text>There was a pilot in our regiment, and he was famous for landing on a forced landing on a jet plane with a stalled engine four times. The fourth time was the funniest).
The deal was this. 
The airfield was on the Lena River. I took off all right, but at 600 metres I got a stalled engine.
I have to say that jets without engine power fly like bricks thrown out of windows. So what to do? Below him there's a town, but straight ahead is Lena, straight as an arrow, the ice is thick, it's winter outside.
he dives the plane and heads for the river. I have to add, that he flies to the training ground, there are bombs under wings, rockets, in general the view is fantastic.
Anyway, he lands on its belly and glides over the ice, gliding well - the speed is really high. He glides for two kilometres, stops, opens the cabin lantern and sees a man, five metres away, fishing.
and, of course, he can't hear a thing. Then our brave pilot unbuckles his oxygen mask and yells: "Hey, buddy, you got my hole!"
The guy turns around and when he sees what the fellow is fishing with, he gives such a jerk, that according to the pilot it would be impossible to catch up with him even on afterburner. Such a story happened in our glorious Air Force,
when paraffin was plentiful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_18">
		<text>This was a real-life incident that happened to me in the mountains of the Caucasus in the spring of '95. I was studying then in Krasnodar at Faculty of Journalism of Moscow State University (Kuban branch) and was regularly in the mountains with a backpack in the company of the same amateur (and self-motivated) tourists. Out of equipment - at the best, a few meters of rope, sometimes an ice-axe. That time we were climbing Achishkho mountain. Who doesn't know, it's in the outskirts of coming Olympic Games. Then, almost twenty years ago - the places are quite wild. We started to ascend on the second day, after spending overnight at some half-dead camping site. The mountain, in principle, is not difficult. There is nothing for a climber to do there, if only to train on cliffs. For the tourist it is the most suitable. The slope though steep, but it is quite possible to climb without special equipment. The main difficulty at that moment consisted in weather conditions. End of April - beginning of May. The slope, the mountain and plateau were covered with very thick layer of snow. A lot of deep cracks, avalanche danger still, of course. Plus to all strong wind with wet snow. In that hike in sub-zero temperatures I froze my left hand. I had an ice-axe in my right hand; it worked and did not get hurt. However, this is prehistory.
At one "fine" moment when only a hundred metres remained to the pass and the steepness of the slope exceeded 60 degrees (I can lie, but it was very steep), clever me decided that it would be easier to go up to the left of the main group. As I was not in a bundle it was decided - done. I realized my mistake in only five meters. But it was too late to go down and I tried to return to the previous course horizontally. The snow underfoot was not too frozen, rather wet and unreliable. Anyway, I slipped and rolled down as well as a bobsledder. There was no fear, just a feeling that everything was not happening to me. At first I tried to slow down with an ice-axe. Then I picked up speed, was thrown up and my forehead hit something hard. My Afghan cap flew off my head, but the worst thing was that my glasses were torn off. With my eagle-eye-vision of -7 it was equal to almost complete blindness. And I flew like that, tumbling, for about two hundred metres. I woke up on the ground. I lay down and did not need anything. The most difficult thing was to make myself rise on my feet. I stood up and was shaking, I could not feel my arms and legs, but I could not feel any pain. I realised in my head that the march was ruined and that there was no way out for me without eyes - to the valley with a good guide. Minutes later I saw our commander Gennady Ognev descend from the top of the fog (unfortunately, he was killed in the mountains and is no longer alive).
- Are you all right?
- Alive, I think...
- Now...
Goes down a few meters and comes back with my cap.
- Here, you'll catch a head cold.
I ask him, slurring my words, if he has seen my glasses anywhere. Gennady laughs nervously and harshly observes that I have made better snow digging than any tractor and that my body has negotiated the cracks as well as a slalom racer. So, the glasses will be found by archaeologists in 25 thousand years. And here is where the unbelievable happens. The commander suddenly leans over and pulls out glasses from under the sole of my left shoe. ALL OF THEM!
- Well, boy, you're gonna live a hundred years.
I never would have believed such luck if it hadn't happened to me personally.
... And half an hour later, at the pass, Svetlana from our group was feeding us from her hand with chocolate, her own hands were not working.
... And the next night I saw a real ghost in the premises of an abandoned weather station near Achishkho. .</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_19">
		<text>We were celebrating a girl's birthday one day. Myself and some of her important fellows were on time, but the rest of the guests were late. For obvious reasons, no one waited for the latecomers - the party was in full swing. 
Those who showed up were simply given a penalty ticket and welcomed into the friendly company.
By the time about 30% of the guests had arrived, everyone was pretty gassed. The ringleader went to the toilet. A few minutes later we hear a drunken girl screaming from the toilet:
- Open the door!!!
We, like true gentlemen, simply could not leave the lady in distress and, with a friendly hooting, carefully removed the door to the toilet from the hinges. The first thing we heard from the girl sitting on the throne in the posture of a proud eagle were the words:
- DOLLARS! OPEN THE FRONT DOOR....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_20">
		<text>It was during the second campaign in the Chechen Republic. A group of heroes, having successfully completed their mission and reached Mazdok without losses (those who know what I mean), was waiting for the plane in the camp at the airfield. 
At the time there was a transit base in the area of the Mozdok airfield, a large tent village (or small tent city, whatever you liked) with streets, alleys, a headquarters (town hall), a canteen and so on and so forth attributes. They were given two tents at the edge of the village, but everyone got into one (the collective), and after buying an anti-stress drug for the last voyage money from the local pharmacy they went into nirvana (the plane was due to arrive the next day morning). Among the heroes was a canine specialist with a dog (a spaniel bitch) nicknamed Katya. Waking up in the morning he did not find the dog that had been asleep all night. Thinking that Katya had gone out to do dog stuff and finding herself in the same need, only human, the dog handler came out of the tent and found his partner not within sight, began to call first softly so as not to wake up the camp, and then louder - Katya, Katenka, where are you? With this he went round all the streets and alleys of the camp, but the dog was nowhere to be found. And then he had a terrible thought (reinforced not yet fully vaporized vapors of anti-stress medication) - The dog is lost!!! The flight's in a couple of hours, there's no way to cancel it, so it's a total fiasco! With those thoughts and groaning in a full voice - Katya, Katya, where are you my girl, went out into the main street (where the staff, mess hall, etc.), which had already overlooked the takeoff. Just then a girl's head peeks out of one of the tents and playfully says, "I'm here", and at the same time Katya appears from the next tent, expressing her guilt over the crime (she was obviously going for the smell of food). A man's tear rolls up from the tent, but his soul demands retribution and the soul gives out in the camp: Oh you s-s-s-bitch, oh you pr-r-o-hostess, sneaking around in other people's tents. In a second the camp is covered by a wild cackle.
It turned out (well, coincidentally) lieutenants / crew celebrated the birthday of a local soldier Katerina, which lasted until morning and no one expected that not the camp will temporarily have a namesake and it will happen to her bad story, which is still long after remembered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_afgan_talk">
		<text>I heard some of the stalkers did their service in the hot spots. Do you know anything about the Afghan and Chechen wars? Maybe eyewitness accounts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_afgan_end">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_1">
		<text>An acquaintance of mine told me a story recently. I'll tell it to you now. The intelligence section of the 5th Directorate of the KAD managed to infiltrate an agent into the Dushmans. In Pakistan they turned him over and sent him back to Kabul with a mission to blow up a school, gave him two kilos of plastic explosives, a meter-long piece of fire wire and two detonator caps. He brought all this to the KAD and reported his assignment. The KGB advisers asked me to examine it and give an opinion: was it really an explosive? I nibbled off a piece of plastic and held up a lighted match. People jumped to their sides. The plastic flashed brightly. The cord of fire ignited properly, too. Everything is fine, the quality is excellent. To test the detonator capsules, one of them will have to be tried out. However, the councillors did not want unnecessary noise in the location. They wondered what to do next. Blowing up the school was not an option and neither was failing the agent's verification mission. The school was located near the airport and was a two-storey wooden structure, similar to a barn. I had my eye on "imported" explosives and suggested to the councillors:
  - Guys, give it to me. Imported explosives are needed for foreign actions. In return, I'll make you a bomb out of Soviet plastic. The explosion will be a blast: windows will blow out in the whole area, and the school will be unharmed.
  The senior councillor squinted slyly:
  - 'Or maybe you've decided to register it as your trophy?
  - Ugh! - I took offence and left.
  The next day I was the first to hear from my Afghan colleagues about a night-time Dushman sabotage. A patrol spotted a man in the dark, fiddling with a cable well near the school, and called out to him. The unknown man took off running. Sarbozes [4 - Sarboz is a soldier] leaned over the manhole to see what was the matter. At that moment an explosion was heard. Two soldiers were injured. On top of that, the power cable shorted out and the wooden school burned to the ground.
  In the morning, I congratulated the councillors on the successful operation. They went pale and rushed to their underlings. They came back sour and reported to their bosses. The chief took a philosophical view of what happened:
  - "What a great job we did scrambling the agent!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_2">
		<text>I heard something. That's what our mentor at Cordon told us at the campfire. I'll tell you about it. An unarmed Hoshal approaches the gates of the villa where our hero has taken refuge. Just at his misfortune a jeep rides up. Hoshal is shot in the neck at point blank range with a submachine gun. Soldier of the operational regiment saw Hoshal fall and hit the jeep with an RPG-7. Two more militants sneak along the wall. Wounded and knocked out by a nearby grenade blast, Hoshal retrieves the pistol he has just been shot with and shoots the insurgents. Hoshal is carried away. The car is on fire. The villa lurks. A friend, Rashid, appears on the scene. He commands the grenade launcher to open fire on the windows. However, both grenades go just above the roof and explode somewhere in the city. Rashid sends a driver with the keys to his office. He has four American-made M-72 disposable grenade launchers (my gift) hidden under the couch. Soon the driver returns with the grenade launchers. Rashid carefully puts a round in each window. Screams are heard, smoke is billowing. The sobered and frightened prince from the basement calls the MGB on the phone, asking for a ceasefire. He has a pile of dead bodies. He surrenders.
  We visit Hoshal in the hospital. There are two automatic riflemen standing by his bed and room door 24 hours a day," the prince managed to order his subordinates to eliminate the entire Operational Regiment command together with the advisers. He was, of course, overreacting. We had absolutely nothing to do with it. However, our leadership has sounded the alarm:
  - Fuck them and a few advisers, it will be worse if we lose Kandahar!
  The prince must not be killed, he must be pacified. He was immediately sent to Sochi on a special flight with two faithful wives. He took two sacks of money with him: one with dollars, the other with the cheques of the foreign trade company.
  In fairness it should be noted that the father-king publicly condemned the prank of his unwise offspring. On his return from the Union, the prince returned to his fiefdom, Kandahar. However, the relatives of the slain fighters lashed out at the prince. He fled behind the cordon. He soon sent a tearful letter to a KGB adviser, inviting him to visit...Pakistan.
  Hoshal recovered quickly. Amazingly, the 9mm Makarov bullet went through between the trachea and carotid artery without hitting any vital nerves, vessels or skeleton.
  Rashid found himself in the fool's role as the blood enemy of his friend and drinking buddy of yesterday. Gotta get ready for a showdown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_3">
		<text>Yes, the older lads at the bonfire used to say that. A while ago, one of them told me this. A narrow path, a ditch with water winds next to it. Dense bushes all around. You could not see anything further than a few meters. The path winds and disappears around a bend. Ambush on the head! A 50-metre stretch of detonating cord, a hand grenade is tied to it every 5 metres, ten grenades in all. All this is placed in a ditch with water and camouflaged with grass on top. This time we'll detonate using an electric detonator. The rings of the grenades are pulled out. Their triggers are held in place with twine wrapped around the cord. Having brought the enemy patrol close, the bomber presses the button. Explosion! What would a normal soldier do if the explosion came within half a metre of his foot? Naturally he would fall on the path. If even the mujahedeen quickly come to their senses and turn their heads to the sides, it's too late: there are grenades lying all around.
  Grenades popping off! Now our machine gunner should flush the remaining spirits to the ground with long bursts in the bushes while the bomber runs off at full speed!
  Since the head patrol moves in the "green zone" at a distance of visibility (5-10 meters) from the core of the column, we will certainly snag five to seventeen "ghosts" with our grenade mines. We do not need any trophies. Our task is to hit them properly so they would not walk in our street again. We'll use RGD-5 grenades for training purposes. In a combat situation, we'll have to use F-1s. The F-1's solid kill radius is 3.7 meters. We'll reduce it to 2.5 meters to be sure. So, if a grenade explodes every five meters in the enemy column, even if it is spread on the ground, it will not be a problem.
  Tests at the range showed that detonating cord could throw F-1 grenades from 0,5 to 15 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_4">
		<text>Many people didn't want to remember that. From the words of an experienced soldier I will tell you a story. As the workload of the Pagman School increased, so did the number of accidents. No fatalities, though. I had a few accidents myself. The main reason for the "accidents" was that we used only captured ammunition, often spoiled in dungeon pits (I was not given anything else).
  Thus, every third or fourth 82mm mortar round failed to fire. Can you imagine how nerve-racking it was to take it out of the barrel? The shots of Chinese RPG-2 grenade launcher caused much trouble as well: their high-explosive charges, filled with black, smoky powder, had a bad habit of getting damp. As a result twice instead of firing the powder slowly burned down and the grenades fell out of the barrel several meters away from the shooter. One, thank God, did not explode. The other, bursting, hit three men, including myself, with shrapnel. The incident happened during the second business trip. At the villa, soaping up under the shower, I found a lot of small pimples on my body, which for some reason scratched my palms. I took a closer look - small splinters. I had to dig them out with a needle. My bunkmate Alexander Ivanovich, seeing my green-soaked belly, became alarmed:
  - Go to the doctor, you might get septicaemia!
  - Yeah, the doctor will report me to his superiors, I'll get a slap on the wrist and I'll be banned from work.
  I found a large piece of shrapnel in a leather wallet in my trouser pocket: it was stuck without penetrating a thick wad of money, an Afghani. Had the shrapnel hit a palm width to the right, the case would have ended sadly. On this occasion adviser Vitaly the next day told a fresh anecdote:
  - Beck was returning from a business trip, his wife was happy to see him and asked what present he had brought from Afghanistan. And sad Beck pulls a dried-up man's body on a string out of his pocket.
  Another reason for the accidents was that I was still training "expendable material" at the Special Forces school. The needs of the front demanded a large number of skilled fighters. They should not be afraid of close explosions and whistling bullets. As an example, I can compare the performance of two teachers sent from Moscow: in six months my colleague, who trained pyrotechnicians for a special laboratory, graduated ten Afghans. Over the same period, I trained more than a hundred Special Forces soldiers. But that doesn't mean their training was inferior. Observant Afghans have drawn the conclusion that explosions are feared either by totally ignorant people or by professionals who know a lot. My students, it turns out, occupied an intermediate level of semi-professionals who were not afraid of anything.
  What happened during the class did not happen. Once they shot themselves under their feet with an AGS-17; another time a heavy trophy 82mm mortar bomb fell twenty meters away from the shooters. The cadet mistakenly filled the mine with a cartridge from a 12-gauge hunting rifle instead of the standard knockout cartridge.
  A nightmarish episode occurred when an OZM-72 pop-up mine went off in the Afghan's hands! If it had exploded, two thousand pellets would have turned us into minced meat! Fortunately it had no primer, so it just flew twenty metres in the air, tangentially hitting an Afghan on the forehead and knocking him out - and us all around fell into a deep stupor for a few seconds.
  The cadets were quite often scratched while throwing hand grenades RGD-5 and RKG-3m while standing. There were two explosions while picking up unexploded ammunition at the range. The main thing at the range is to take care of your eyes, you need to wear protective glasses.
  One unpleasant incident is particularly memorable. I was conducting training sessions on hand grenades with a group of Special Laboratory of 5th Department of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of Ukraine. I have plenty of these trophy grenades. All grenades are conditionally divided into two classes according to the type of fuse: instantly firing and grenades with retarder, which detonate several seconds after being thrown. The first type includes our antitank RKG-3, another one - shaped with parachute, with plastic body in the form of half-liter bottle, either Chinese or Pakistani manufacture, our antipersonnel RGO and RGN, and also a defensive grenade of absolutely nightmarish design, manufactured in Egypt. It was cylindrical in shape, with enameled casing, wrapped in the middle with thin elastic metal band. It was pierced through with a pin-check, and the ring of the check had a lead seal. When the pin is pulled and the grenade is tossed the elastic spring is unwound in flight and flies away from the case. When the grenade touches the surface, it explodes. The worst thing is that underneath the casing there are metal gears that break into numerous fragments the size of a pinky fingernail when detonated.
  The second class includes our conventional F-1, RGD-5, RG-42 with UZRGM primers and similar British, American and Belgian primers. The same is applied to German F-1s with long wooden grip and American M-46 with chisel igniters.
  So, I told my Afghan friends about the structure of grenades and rules of their handling, and took them to the range. I explained that the instant-action grenades should be handled carefully, thrown high and far, and should be hidden immediately. With grenades of the second class one can be especially unceremonious, for example, even F-1s should not be thrown, but simply lowered behind the muzzle. One fool has mixed up everything and has thrown the Egyptian instant grenade not far away. It fell in the liquid mud and didn't explode because the spring hadn't had time to unwind all the way. I warned the officer on duty about the failed grenade and instructed the sergeant to destroy it with an overhead charge. He did not. After lunch, the Afghan lieutenant went to that area to take a leak and, seeing an interesting toy, picked it up. It clicked and the spring bounced off. He threw it aside. Explosion! Like a razor, one of his legs was pulled off down to the knee.
  There was a more unfortunate incident with an American M-46 grenade in the 40th Army. A lieutenant-paratrooper decided that if it had a teeter-totter igniter like a rocket launcher, then it was a smoke grenade. Seeing the soldiers in the smoking room, he decided to play a joke, pulled the string and threw it into the middle. The soldiers did not move. The result was a dozen dead bodies. The officer shot himself.
  I averaged one or two accidents a month. In this context, it is difficult to describe my psychological state: it could probably be called fatalism. What else was there to do? After all, you could not in any way show the cadets timidity and fear. An instructor must be an absolutely fearless person. In the end, fatigue gradually builds up, which even alcohol does not relieve. Nervous breakdowns begin, sometimes for no reason at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_5">
		<text>I was wrong to remind you. This is a sore subject for many. But let me tell you a story. The operational regiment commander (by then our battalion had grown into a regiment) invites his advisers to attend the Eid al-Mairam celebration. But the leadership, being afraid of possible excesses, didn't allow us to participate in a Muslim feast. The Afghans sulk at us. The regiment's logistician gets upset:
  - We have bought 20 thousand Afghanis worth of snacks, and you did not come! It is a mortal insult. Seryoga instructs me, as a Muslim, to settle the incident. Besides, I was on a business trip in the province at the time, so I didn't seem to have anything to do with what had happened.
  I swear to my partners that the advisers had nothing to do with this and that we too are worried about what happened. We are ready to make amends.
  The next day we arrive at the regiment as a group. In the "tablet", in addition to several litres of cognac, vodka, champagne and a case of dry wine, we brought a number of assorted rifles. On the regimental firing range we spread cloak tents. On them we lay German machine gun MG-42, nicknamed "Hitler's saw", machine gun PC, American rifle M-16, and our RPK, AKS-74.
  Two interpreter soldiers fill the horns and load the machine gun ribbons.
  After three obligatory toasts I announce a competition: a glass of alcohol to the one who hits the target! The Afghans do their best: the shots rattle. Gradually everyone gets excited. Outside my head I see Din Mamad creeping back as soon as the shooting starts. While everyone is competing in accuracy, he manages to knock over an extra glass, obligingly set up by the interpreter, and crawls back to the firing line. We all like the MG-42: rate of fire is 1300 per minute and there is almost no dispersion: at 800 meters it shoots a line at a small target!
  Having shot off ammunition and liquored up with champagne, in the arms of the partners we return to the headquarters. The incident is over. Mamad, a big, slightly slouching fellow, who had joined the battalion from the commandos, his hands were a rake to his knees, was buzzing in my ear: he suggested we go to Kabul to see the girls. He has a good "henhouse" there somewhere. He only has the strength to get to his bunk. So he passes out with his eyes open. I close his eyes:
  - Sleep well, friend Dean Mamad...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_6">
		<text>An acquaintance of mine told me a story recently. As soon as we entered the Chechen fighters' sector of control, she called off their commander and said something for a long time, pointing at me. Then she said to me: "They thought you were an FSB agent, they wanted to shoot you or take you to the mountains, but I defended you. Of course, I was grateful, but if you think about it logically, who could call me a member of the secret service? Maybe they just didn't believe her, or didn't have time to deal with me? After '96 her son, named Ruslan, gladly helped me get around all over Ingushetia, first in his nine-car porsche and then in a sports car. There was not much to talk about except women, but he was very handy for work. An acquaintance nonetheless. "Brother"... On the eve of October 4, when he volunteered to drive me to a checkpoint in Mozdok, one thing struck me. Ruslan told me that he had a beautiful girlfriend, whom he went to see almost every night, and then told me that he was married, with two children. I asked: "Does the wife know? What does she say?" He replied calmly, "What to tell her? She's crying." There was such cruelty in that calmness that I felt uncomfortable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_7">
		<text>I heard something. I will tell it from the mouth of an eyewitness. On the morning of the 4th October I overslept. Barely rinsing myself off, I grabbed my belongings and went down to the hotel lobby. Ruslan was already there. I was embarrassed that he had to wait, and I hustled around checking out of the hotel and paying for all the phone calls. Neither when we were driving round Nazran and Ruslan ran to his various addresses, nor on the Nazran-Malgobek highway did I remember that I had forgotten my passport at the hotel reception. Nor did any suspicions arise. I would have arrived in Mozdok by lunchtime anyway, and I might even have had time to be accredited by the press centre of a group of federal troops preparing to rush into Chechnya. With luck I might even have been stationed at the base of some forward unit by the evening. With luck... The decision to sell me probably only arose in Ruslan's mind when he returned to Nazran, when he resumed visiting various addresses. I can imagine the following conversation: "I have a journalist sitting in my car... - Yes? Who is he? - I think he's from "Moscow News". - Alone? Yes... - Wait, wait... Well... Go to Mohammed's house, tell him everything, tell him to get his guys together quickly. Got it? And then go to the hospital, find Said there. He'll settle up with you. You'll decide with him where to set up the place.... Ruslan did a good job for his money - I had never even thought of such a thing. The day was warm and sunny in the summer, I had submitted a story and it was published in the issue; there were five more days of business trips ahead, which meant the chance to distinguish myself and do something special for the paper. Anyway, the mood was great...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_8">
		<text>Yes, the older guys around the campfire were occasionally picking on me. The narration will be based on the words of an eyewitness. In the first few days in captivity I recalled the moment of capture with horror and pain. Stupid, bastard cattle, greedy creatures who thought they were supermen! The bombing had already been carried out with terrible force, the federal troops were on full alert, and the situation did not have any intention of kidnapping people - this was not '97, when thugs were simply beside themselves with impunity, stealing journalists one by one! After all, the federal troops may be all, but they are not the rabble that Maskhadov referred to as the "presidential guard" and "subunits of the Ministry of Sharia State Security". However decayed the Russian army may be, it is impossible to imagine its officers taking part in kidnappings of outsiders, as the Chechen bandits in uniform in sovereign Ichkeria did! Now, remembering the terrible moment when the Juda left me alone in his car in the back of the republican hospital, and he went to his allegedly beautiful friend, and an unremarkable white Chechen car with Ingush number plates stopped nearby, I realize that such a silent and swift operation was only possible because I was momentarily confused. Had I had had time to yell my head off, or at least to start a fight, things might have turned out differently. There was a busy place just around the corner from the hospital - a bus stop, a few commercial pavilions. This finally relaxed me, and when a blond man in military uniform without shoulder straps looked through the door of the Porsche with the window rolled down by the prudent Judas: "Your papers! Passport regime check", I again thought nothing wrong. I simply got out of the car and walked towards the white 'six'...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_9">
		<text>I didn't want many people to remember this, but it happened. It was our life. My ex-partner told me the story. I'll tell it in his own words. Shoving me into the backseat of their six, the thugs were wheezing in my ear: "Shut up, bitch! I'll kill you!!..", and they poked me in the side with the barrels of their pistols for reassurance. The plastic bag quickly ran out of air and I began to suffocate. All the more so as I tried to scream incessantly. From that moment on, time crumpled up for me like a piece of paper. I remember that the car immediately rushed through the streets of Nazran, someone's steady hands grabbed my belted purse containing all my documents and money, and my commander's wristwatch, a gift from my mother, the one I dived in Crete in '98, someone was pressing my head forcefully to their lap, and somewhere in the outside world, outside the plastic bag, the bandits were talking in broken Chechen or Ingush, in broken sentences. I remember that in shock I shouted nonsense like: "Basayev will kill you for me! Let me go, or you'll be sorry! Please don't shoot me! Then kill me, don't take me anywhere!" The bandit poking me in the side with his gun yelled: "One more word - I swear I'll shoot you like a dog right here!" - and hit me with the butt of the gun somewhere above my ear. Not hard, but very painful. Very soon I was weakened by the lack of air. I gasped and was no longer demanding, but begging to breathe a little. The car was still racing at full speed and, as far as I could tell now, all the time on tarmac. I wheezed out: "You Chechens! Better slaughter, don't choke!" One bandit replied: "We're not Chechens. We are Arabs," and all four of them cackled in a disgusting, vile, deliberately nasty voice. But the edge of the bag was lifted, and the air in the car, reeking of the bodies of the five sweaty men, seemed as refreshing as a sea breeze. 
		Then they put him in another car: "Get out, bitch, quick, I'll kill you! Come here! Come here!" - and then to a third car. The bandits changed everywhere. In the second car, they were "kind" - they lifted the bag so that I could breathe not only through my mouth but also through my nose and gave me a smoke. In the third car they were "bad" again, silent and embittered. I remember the softness of the ground when they put me under a fruit tree ("Aha, it's not far from Assinovskaya! There used to be a fruit and berry state farm here. Salam alaikum, Chechnya...". I was lying down, my arms and shoulders were stiff from the ropes, and the two machine gunners were forbidding me even to move, so as to somehow reduce the unbearable pain in my shoulders. After five minutes or an hour, I heard the sound of a car approaching from behind the trees. The thugs picked me up with kicks (my hands were twisted, incredibly difficult to stand up) and drove off again like a sheep, accompanying me with meaningless evil shouts. It was already dark when they took me to the zindan. My new place of residence (not for long, just for a fortnight, as I found out later) was an unfinished garage among the ruins and piles of broken bricks.I could not believe then that just a few hours earlier I had been free, able to plan my next steps and "sway" if anyone wanted to interfere. Now I can't believe that I was the hostage - and therefore not quite human, and not even human at all - and that any of the bandits, at their own mind and mood, would have done anything to me with complete impunity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_10">
		<text>You should have reminded me. This is a sore subject for many people. This is what our commander told us. Now that the wave of panic terror, pain and constant tension has subsided, I often think: could it have been otherwise? After all, all the circumstances that led to that fateful moment on October 4, 1999, at about 3 or 4 p.m., when four bandits took me away in their car, now look like a chaotic collection of coincidences and absurdities. If only I had not suddenly decided to visit acquaintances in Nasran the day before... If the bellboys at the Assa Hotel there had not been such charming and affable girls, whom I did not wish to offend with mistrust (I had gone up to them two days before the seizure, and jokingly and sternly asked them "Won't you lose my passport?" The girls got worried and offered to give it back to me, to which I replied, "No, no, you'll have it safer - I always lose everything")... If it wasn't for my damned forgetfulness... If only Ruslan had had an old Zigulenok instead of a sports two-seater Porsche, which offers a fast and comfortable ride to Mozdok... Every business trip is made up of these "ifs", be it to a "hot spot" or a safe country. But no matter how many business trips I have had in the years I have worked for Moskovskiye Novosti, the circumstances have always worked out as best as possible. Probably the limit of luck was exhausted, and on that last trip to Ingushetia something bad would have happened on the eve of the next big war. Luckily it was "only" hostage-taking. Luckily there was always a little hope, even on the darkest of days.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_11">
		<text>An acquaintance of mine told me a story recently. Or rather it was not even a story, but an eyewitness account. Thinking back now on the people who have known me since '96, who called me "nephew" and "brother" and who set bandits on me in cold blood, I feel a quiet, quiet disappointment, apart from a deafening anger and desire for revenge and hatred. Not so much in their decency as in their intelligence. What a stupid and greedy person I had to be to bring me into the clutches of the bandits without any disguise or trace! There were only two explanations for this treachery when I was still in prison: either they thought I was a complete fool, unable to draw the simplest conclusions, or they had been told that I would not stay alive. The second explanation made me sick. I shall not name the "tipsters" - the mother and the son - although their name has already appeared in the Moscow News. The couple are now in pre-trial detention, and the story of my capture is just a small episode in the rampage of the merry family. Even before, in '96, the mother looked somewhat suspicious - she was too businesslike, too "tight-lipped" back then, with extensive links in international humanitarian organizations and among the Chechen fighters. She spoke of her unselfish and noble nature, of freeing Russian prisoners of war out of the call of her heart, and of the many times she had stared death in the face in this difficult task. To be fair, I should note that she was indeed not too afraid when the two of us went to the embattled Grozny on March 7, 96. At the time I did not understand why she wanted to do this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_12">
		<text>I have heard something. Or rather, I read the former commander's latest sketches. Here listen. On April 4 at about 15.00 the gunner of the BMP shook us: "Stand up, we will go soon!" And really, in 15 minutes we moved forward... 600 meters to the road it took us an hour and a half. The spirits were above us, shooting at us like at a shooting gallery. The 2nd and 3rd platoons came to the road from our company, the 1st and control of the company remained in the position two hundred meters behind, the 2nd and 6th companies went around Gojskoe on the left. 
They decided to move behind the road, asked me to cover, but my SVD did not fire: a grenade fragment hit the bolt. I dismantled the rifle. There were some other pieces of metal in the receiver, it looked like splinters too. I checked everything, tried the rifle - nothing, works. 
Our group went behind the road, throwing grenades at the spirits. At first a pair of machine-gunners and a gunner attached themselves to the place. And already under a cover others left. We knocked out the spirits from the position. By all appearances there were about twenty of them. Retreating, they left five for cover. Those poor bastards were blown to bits by grenades. Dug holes under the road didn't help them either. 
We're holding our ground. At the same time, the 6th and 2nd Companies were engaged in a heavy fighting in the "green area". Eleven men, together with the platoon commander, who was acting commander-in-chief, laid down there. Two weeks later the spirits asked us to take the corpses as they were already badly decomposed. But it was some time later; meanwhile we blocked the right flank of the 2nd and 6th companies. In one of the holes we found a live "Czech", who had managed to kill the kid who had found him. We tried to smoke him out - all in vain. We poured paraffin into the hole, set it on fire and threw grenades. Apparently, the entrance to the shelter was knee-jerk, so they didn't get to him... 
While the matter was settled, we looked, the main forces of the company approached. It appeared that they, having lost four men, could not overcome a field. Our platoon leader fought with the company because of their late approach. The platoon leader shouted: "No clear instructions from the commander!" Platoon leader: "Kombat's drunk. You should have made the decision yourself!" While they were sorting things out, we examined the Chechen trenches and dugouts, finishing off the wounded. After a while, the command: "Stand back!" That this is nonsense is clear to everyone. One of the conscripts-debates tried to explain by radio that we should secure our position, because if we will not come here, the spirits will come, and we again will have to occupy a position with losses. He shouted until hoarseness, with foul language, but, certainly, he could not convince anybody. 
After ensuring the withdrawal of the 6th Company we started to move back. SAU from the 324th infantry battalion began to hammer Goyskoye, and we were divided into two groups. The first moves with all stuff, the second covers. As a whole, they departed normally, but it was not without jokes. The tank number 420 was the last to depart. It covered everybody, "as much as possible". During the assault, the spirits burned two BMPs: one of ours, and one of the 6th Company. To be sure the tank hit the wrecked BMP. And then some gunner-operator from the "two's" hit it with a bang! Tankers said later: "Of course we didn't give a shit, but when during retreat their own people hit you in the ass...". Who shot, they never found out.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_13">
		<text>Some of the older guys around the campfire used to do it. One of them must have been a former soldier. That's what he told them. It is dirty and boring, newcomers from some brigade of the Airborne Troops move around. For three whole days we worked with paratroopers to turn Khankala into an impregnable fortress. It is a little calmer now. The spirits have stopped their absurd sorties at night, they do not harass us with any excuse. Our generals are too cowardly, they assigned an entire brigade of the Air Force and a battalion of paratroopers to protect tiny Khankala, and they promise to send another regiment of motorized riflemen. Where will they be accommodated? But this is all lyric, and there is nothing to do at the moment. I'm going to radio operators, I should be informed, otherwise the war will be over and you'll never know. 
- Hello, "Broomstick".
- And "Moscow", do you have a smoke?
- What's new?
- Nothing, marines, paratroopers, motorized riflemen, and Sofrinsky are hitting
Wait a minute, Dudayev the asshole won't give up, in short life is shit and the sun is a fucking
the sun is a lantern!
- Have you heard anything about our brigade?
- Nothing concrete, we're waiting, while guarding the "jackal's
command...
I tried to tune in another wave on the radio but the crackling air was interrupted by "chukchi" guttural speech, I couldn't speak Russian so I continued walking... I was caught talking to some motorized rifle unit that was jamming the "spirits" in a five-storey block but I couldn't hear any callsigns etc. I heard a sort of abnormal mat which implied that Warrant Officer Zinoviev had a sexual relationship with a BMP in a place that was difficult to visualize on an BMP...
Good thing stretch marks, another trip by the spirits after our Behemoths was spotted in time. Fat "Broom" during my radio intercepts had time to "sleep" and jumped up to about half a meter, he bettered up from the chair crawled around the body while trying to fit his armor, grenade pouch, and eventually he stumbled on the helmet and with a wild rattle fell to the floor. It would have been a lot of fun if it hadn't been so miserable. 
In a matter of seconds I reached my equipment, looking for my eyes platoon leader, aha over there he settled down behind a piece of rebar and with great enthusiasm hrynutsya over dushmanov ko because of the natural dullness of climbed out into the open area. Either we were really good troops, and not a herd of deer, as our commander told us in the "training camp", or the cadres we encountered were not very intelligent, but we held Khankala with good conscience, and there were practically no losses among the personnel. Two "200 hundred" in six days in January 95 in Chechnya is not bad, though it is very bad, because there could have been none.
In a few minutes we assembled a combined platoon - a squadron in number - and set out to comb the area. Of course there were no spirits in the vicinity, we put up several tripwires and "torches" as there was no point in going around without our knowledge.
Another day went by, another war... Who needs it all...
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_14">
		<text>Many people did not want to remember it. This is an eyewitness account. After passing the militants' defensive lines in Grozny we got into neighbourhoods that were completely controlled by the "Dukhs". The army camouflage and our unshaven, blackened, sunken cheeks gave us every chance of passing for guerrillas in the event of a sudden meeting with the "warriors of Ichkeria. The guerrillas' mess was similar to that of our troops. In the conditions of general confusion among the insurgents, the system of badges and passwords sometimes did not work, and it was enough to shout "Allahu akbar" for us to be taken for insurgents.
Our objective was to conduct reconnaissance of the territory behind the guerrillas' fighting lines, and disrupt the enemy's communication system by planting mines to create a feeling of chaos and panic in their ranks.
They advanced exclusively in the evening, but before dark. As darkness fell, advancing through the town was dangerous, as at that time the warring parties were doubling down on all activities on the adjacent side. At night we lay low in smelly cellars or in abandoned houses in the private sector, which we had chosen after a preliminary reconnaissance so that all the entrances to our hiding place were clearly visible.
It was already beginning to get dark. We have been circling in this area for two days now, unable to find a way into a neighbouring district crawling with armed guerrillas and bearded with green armbands. We have to sit this night out and leave for the next street at dawn. I noticed this afternoon that the exit to the neighbouring street marked on our map was turned by the militants into a stronghold in case of a breakthrough by Russian tanks, covered with various large-sized junk consisting of broken-down cars and a half-burned bus.
My sixth sense told me that this improvised barricade was probably guarded by the "Dukhs", so I should not go there in haste.
Having posted guards and an observer, we lay down to rest on a pile of broken bricks. The bricks dig into our backs and the tension in our bodies prevents us from getting to sleep. I roll over on my stomach and lie down on my folded arms, a posture that is not very comfortable, but I force myself to sleep as there is a hard day tomorrow.
It was not what I would call sleep. I closed my eyes and fell into a trance of oblivion, continuing to somehow control my surroundings. I wake up suddenly. Silence. However, it became cold and uncomfortable in my stomach. After another moment at the same time I heard the crunch of debris, heavy footsteps and saw the cautiously prowling beam of a pocket lantern.
"Spotted! Where's the watcher, is he lying there already with his throat cut?" - my condition was close to panic.
I could not hear my comrades breathing nearby. So, they are awake, and just like me, huddled together in a pile of bricks.
The men with the torch (it must have been a fighter patrol) stopped not far from the entrance to our shelter.
There was a silence that seemed to last a lifetime. My heart went to my throat.
"I must pull myself together. This morning I read the Lord's Prayer and God protect me", if not to calm me down, at least to get rid of the paralysing animal fear of the unknown and to prepare myself for action.
The assault rifle is at my fingertips. The fingers of my other hand groped for the cold ribbed surface of an F-1 grenade, which had one sole purpose - not to be caught alive.
The footsteps began to recede. "Not found."
The tension had subsided. However, the anxiety for the guys who had been on the watch had not gone away.
The conditioned signal. "Ours!" Two shadow-like figures slipped towards us.
As it turned out, the fighters appeared suddenly from some basement, which we did not even pay attention to at first. When light began to fall, we cautiously left our hideout, having previously left a few "guests" in the form of two MON-50s. We went out of the cellar and after looking around we found a little-noticed passageway to the cellar, which on further inspection turned out to be a through passage to the street, which we had not been able to get to before.
Having mined this passageway too, which the guerrillas would probably still try to use, our group infiltrated behind the "spirits" in the vicinity of the tram park. There was no reason for us to linger there. The tram depot and the adjacent territory were crawling with insurgents, because Maskhadov's headquarters was located there, and the guerrillas might have stumbled on our "guests" and realized that newcomers had entered their territory. Gathering intelligence by visual observation, and trying to dispose of the cargo as quickly as possible - by placing and concealing mines - we began to prepare for withdrawal. The route of withdrawal which we had worked out and coordinated with the command of the subdivisions to the line which we should have reached after the operation turned out to be useless. It would be more accurate to say that by this time, while we were behind enemy lines, the situation had changed. The lines of contact with the enemy had shifted, and in some directions the insurgents had established new strongholds. Given the situation, we had to conduct reconnaissance and look for new escape routes.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_15">
		<text>I should have reminded you. This is a sore subject for many. Listen to an essay by a veteran. In spite of the fact that there were guys in our group who had lived in Grozny before all these events, it was very difficult to orientate oneself in the ruined city. In some places there were enemy positions five days ago, but now they may be taken by our forces, so the possibility of being hit by the federal troops' fire is high. Although there are no "smart" deaths, it is foolish to take a bullet from one of our own.
To avoid this we had to constantly carry out additional reconnaissance of the area.
I witnessed the consequences in January 1995, when our reconnaissance team ran into our own people.
Our reconnaissance group under command of Vadim ran into the Volga-Grad units (units of the 8th Army Corps commanded by General Rokhlin) in one of the Grozny districts. Lack of cooperation played a tragic role, Vadim's group was mistaken for the enemy by the Volgograds and was fired on to defeat them. One of the group was killed. Vadim jumped out of cover and started shouting: "Don't shoot! We are friendly!" When the fighters on the spot "arrested" him, it turned out that he didn't have his documents. When Vadim tried to explain himself to the men from Volgograd, he was severely beaten and almost shot. After the circumstances of the case had been clarified and a request for confirmation made to higher headquarters, Vadim, in critical condition, was taken to the hospital at Severny.
I was standing at his bedside and it pained me to listen to his choppy, stuttering speech, where he was only repeating: "Y-you r-e-understand, I was k-i-n-tusiated in Afghan and I am through with it here ...". Two hours later he was taken by a special helicopter to Mozdok, then to the hospital in the "mainland".
After running through a small square we cross an arch into a courtyard. It is as if from another life. The war has spared it so much that the ruins in the neighbouring streets give the impression that the arch through which we entered this courtyard is a gateway from one world to another. The silence is unaccustomed.
A few minutes later we became convinced that silence in war can sometimes be deceptive. Trusting the silence and the apparent calmness, we made a mistake which almost led to a tragic outcome for us. We had broken the basic rules of movement in enemy-held territory, which state: "Do not trust your eyes or your ears. Trust only your gut and animal instinct. Check seven times..." and other principles according to which we have no right to ever relax.
From the first floor window of a neighbouring house we were called out in Chechen. We were taken aback...
Without getting an answer, they opened fire on us. But either the shooters turned out to be lousy, or maybe it was because those "animal instincts" had awakened in us again, only one man in our group received a light wound in the side, and even that was just a touch, as we were instantly behind the high concrete slabs, taking cover from the enemy fire.
We did not want to waste ammunition so we decided not to focus on the enemy in the building and therefore in an advantageous position, especially as we did not know their strength and intentions. Being under the cover of the concrete slabs and bouncing back with short bursts of fire and single shots, we tried to buy time to make the "only right decision.
Through the basement windows, one by one we made our way into the three-storey house behind us. Cursing and cursing ourselves for our carelessness, the first thing we did was to help the wounded man. Two went off to reconnoitre. The rest took up defensive positions. Those who returned from the reconnaissance brought good news: at some distance from us were the lines of the Russian troops assaulting the city. Apparently, the proximity of the federal troops did not allow the guerrillas who opened fire on us in the courtyard to take more decisive action against our group, entrenched in this three-storey building. Or perhaps it was an enemy group similar to ours, whose mission was not to engage in protracted open combat. In any case, we quickly established contact with the commander of the federal troops we had approached, and after an hour we were sent to the "Severny" station by APCs.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_16">
		<text>An acquaintance of mine told me a story recently. I'll tell it to you now. "The 'ceasefire' turned into a bloody tragedy the very next morning. At 10 in the morning, on the Staropromyslovsky Road, guided claymores set on the side of the road were detonated by Chechen fighters. Fragments of an exploded 152-mm howitzer shell (tank and howitzer shells are used by the guerrillas as the main explosive charge) pierced the armour of the APC, killing the driver's mechanic instantly. The unguided APC, travelling at 70 km/h, jumped out onto the opposite side of the highway and cut through a concrete light pole and stopped, covered in blood and splattered with the brains of the soldiers of the 101st Army Brigade who were on the armour.
Four soldiers died in a matter of seconds, a fifth, whose legs were blown off, died on the way to the hospital and a sixth died on the operating table. Near the scene of the tragedy, an elderly Russian woman walked by, her face covered by the hides of her cloak, unable to hide her tears. She had to hide her tears from the crowd of Chechen youths who had gathered at the crossroads and were merrily discussing what had happened.
On the same day, five Chechen fighters captured at one of the checkpoints were brought to the GYOSH. Dressed in black, more like a uniform, they were carrying weapons, half of which were fitted with silenced firing equipment. Having left Shali after the federal forces' operation led by General Shamanov in May 1996, this group attempted to penetrate Grozny.
The leader of the group, as the investigation revealed, was at the same time the commander of the reconnaissance group of Shamil Basayev's detachment. The captured fighters testified that they had arrived in Grozny to carry out terrorist attacks. This was proved by the list of officials of the Chechen government, which was found with them, and the names and locations of their offices. During the interrogations, it became known that the fighters had also received orders to take the families and relatives of the fighters who were fighting in the mountains from Grozny by June 10. All this gave one reason to suppose that the fighters were using the "ceasefire" for their own purposes, and not peaceful ones at all. The atmosphere in Chechnya was becoming more and more heated by the day.
The unwillingness of Russia's military and political leadership to live by the laws of a war that may not have been declared, but still a war, led to the tragic events in Grozny on August 6, 1996.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_17">
		<text>I have heard something. Just now a story comes to mind. It really happened a long time ago. My company was raised to disarm a Chechen scum, with the "Vovans" (Special Forces of the Interior Ministry) working, and we only covered the scene. When the Vovan commander was brought to the village elders, he demanded that they surrender 24 AKs within two hours. To which one of the elders began to fuck up in the style of Lukashenko. He stated that a legal self-defence squad was operating in their village, but they did not have enough assault rifles themselves, so the feds were obliged to immediately give him another 20 AKs. The Vovanians were a bit taken aback by such brazenness, but we were not confused. The fucking elder got a queue in bread cutter in front of everybody, and while his legs were still twitching, the rest of the elders heard a delicate request to hand over not 24, but 100 AKs. And not in two hours, but in an hour. The Chechens managed to surrender exactly 100 assault rifles in forty minutes.
The moral of this story is as follows: politics and diplomacy are good for a partner who stays within certain limits. For a "partner" who has lost his edge, there has to be a different set of tools.
I have seen convoys of buses, the stench of which made it impossible to get within 100 meters of, as they were full of the bodies of slaughtered Russians. I saw women, evenly sawn along with chainsaws, children, hanging on posts from road signs, intestines artistically wrapped around a fence. We Russians were scrubbed off our own land like dirt from under our fingernails. It was 1992 - there were still two and a half years before the "first Chechen war".
And then things got really fun. Militants came to the village and began cleansing it of the Russians. Sometimes at night one could hear the screams of people being raped and stabbed in their own houses. No one came to help them. It was everyone for himself, everyone was shaking with fear, and some managed to base it on an ideological foundation, like "my home is my fortress" (yes, I heard that phrase just then. The man who uttered it is no longer alive - the Vainakhs have wound his entrails around the fence of his own house.) That is how we, the cowardly and stupid, were massacred one by one. Tens of thousands of Russians were killed, several thousand ended up in slavery and Chechen harems, and hundreds of thousands escaped Chechnya in their pants. 
This is how the Vainakhs solved the "Russian question" in a single republic.
And they only succeeded because we were nobodies, complete turds. Even now we are crap, but not so liquid - among the crap there are grains of steel. And when these particles get together - condopogues happen. There are not many of them yet, but the Vainakhs are good. They are the true sanitarians of the forest. As a result of their cultural and educational mission in Russia, the Russian sheep are once again becoming human.
Generally, those who have come across Chechens in their lives have reason to hate them.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_18">
		<text>The older guys used to say mean things around the campfire. Couple of veterans were there. Here, listen. There, in the war, fate brought me together with a Jew - Lev Yakovlevich Rokhlin. Originally our participation in the New Year's storm was not supposed. But when contact with the 131st motorized rifle division and 81st motorized rifle division was lost, we were thrown to help. We broke through to the 8th AC commanded by General Rokhlin and reached his headquarters. It was the first time when I saw him personally. And he did not seem to me at first sight: hunched over, with a cold, with cracked glasses... Not a general, but some tired agronomist. He gave us a task - to collect dispersed remnants of Maikop brigade and 81st regiment and bring them to Rokhlin's reconnaissance battalion. That was what we did - we gathered the pissed-out meat from the basements and led them to the position of Rokhlina reconnaissance units. There were about two companies in all. At first Rokhlin did not want to use them, but when all other groups retreated - the 8th AC was left alone in an operational encirclement in the centre of the city. Against all the fighters! Then Rokhlin lined up this "army" in front of his fighters and addressed them. It was a speech I will never forget. The general's most affectionate expressions were: "fucking monkeys" and "faggots". At the end he said: "The fighters outnumber us fifteen to one. And there's no help to be had. And if we are destined to lie here, let each of us be found under a pile of enemy corpses. Let's show how Russian fighters and Russian generals die! Don't let us down, sons..."
Lev Yakovlevich is long dead - he was dealt with without you. One less Jew, isn't there?
I already told you about Rokhlin's speech. But I have not told you what happened next. After that there was a terrible, terrible battle in which from my platoon of 19 men only six survived. And when the Chechens broke into our position and it came down to grenades and we realised we were all going to hell - I saw real Russian people. There was no fear any more. There was a kind of cheerful anger, a detachment from everything. There was only one thought in my head: "Batya" asked me not to let you down. The wounded men bandaged themselves, injected themselves with Promedol and continued to fight. 
Then the Vainakhs and I went into hand-to-hand combat. And they ran away. That was the turning point of the battle for Grozny. It was a confrontation between two characters - the Caucasian and the Russian, and ours proved the tougher. It was at that moment I understood that we could do it. We have this hard core in us, we just need to clean the crap out of it. In the melee we took prisoners. Looking at us, they weren't even whimpering - they were howling in terror. Then a radio intercept was read to us - Dudayev's order was passed over the guerrillas' radio networks: "Do not take prisoners and torture the spetsnaz from the Eighth AAC and the airborne special forces, but kill them immediately and bury them like warriors. We were very proud of this order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_19">
		<text>Many people would not like to remember it. It was a turbulent time. There were gardens between Gojskaja and Komsomolskaja, and behind them the spirits had positions of anti-tank missiles. Their operator was cool, he hit the filler three versts away. Not only that, he tried to cover the checkpoint of the 324th regiment, fired at the checkpoint, and it was all four kilometres away. It was this PTU that the commander somehow aimed at us. We proceeded from the assumption that the position wasn't badly guarded, and if one wanted to shoot the operator, one would do it silently. Therefore we asked the commander to order a VSS "Vintorez" from the RAW depot. He prescribed the rifle, but someone had to go to collect it together with the head of the service of rocket-artillery armament. He and I decided to go to the regiment in a passing convoy. 
The situation in Gojskoye was as follows: the spirits could not turn the confrontation in their favor, as we outnumbered them in firepower (artillery, aviation, etc.), and we could not take Gojskoye because of our small number. Anyway, we got the spirits, and they told us that if any other unit of the 245th MSP would approach Goyskoye, they would close the gorge and blockade the regiment. 
It arrived in Nizhniye Atagi, where we waited for the column, at half past two. It was made up of demobilised conscripts from the raid group, and also of those who were on their way to the regiment on leave for family reasons. (Naturally, they, like me, were nowhere accounted for, and so later, when the fighting was behind us, the exact number of losses in our ill-fated column was quite difficult to calculate. In particular, the Ural with the demobees, of whom there were 20, burned down after a single Bumblebee hit. They were carrying food there, and the boys were sitting on sacks on top - so they all burned down...). 
I moved along the column to find out about the mail - there were no letters. When I went back, I saw four caravans in a row, and one of them had my good friend and fellow-countryman, Arkasha. It turned out he was the deputy leader of the tank squad. Well, that's lucky! "Arkasha, do you have an empty seat in the cockpit? It wasn't befitting a sniper - a white man - to be hovering in the dust on the armour. He says: "Come and have a look for yourself!" I went in, moved the bag with vodka, which he was taking to somebody for his birthday. That's all right, I'll fit in. 
At about 14.00 we set off. At 14.10 we have passed Chishki and before an input in the gorge the shutters were pulled. Arkasha says: "Look, there are only women and children". And just yesterday the guys from the 324th regiment told me an omen: "If there are men, women and children on the road - everything is normal. If it's just chicks - no way, soon it'll be an ambush." 
The column stretched on the "mother-in-law's tongue" (it's a serpentine road). The tankers could hardly turn around on it, and I don't know how the MAZ trucks, which were pulling the unserviceable equipment, got through. All is quiet, calm. We drive on, we tell jokes. We drove through Yaryshmardy, the head of the column has left behind a turn, the tankers have passed the bridge across the dry river bed. And here - an explosion ahead, we look - the tank turret was thrown up from behind a hill, the second explosion - somewhere in the head of the column, and the third one just bang between the forward going and our tank. The explosion tore the bonnet off and smashed the windows. That was the first time I was shell-shocked. Arkasha had already got out of the car, but I got tangled up in the two door handles. Eventually I fell out of the cabin. The fire was very dense, but I had already begun to think and ran away from the tank 15 metres away, in spite of the fire of the spirits. I found some hollow in the roadside and pushed my ass in it. Nearby, an enlisted man lay down. The first shock passed and I could see how things were going. And things were not good. Pourers stood on the road. Guys from the tank platoon are shooting off in all directions as they can, it is not clear where exactly the spirits are. Arkasha pisses into the white light from under the wheel of his tank. 
Just past me a grenade hits the tank that was behind us. The tank's on fire. I figure if it blows up now, we'll all get very hot. Trying to figure out where that thing came from. I see somebody crawling about 170 metres away from us. I looked through the sight and the "strangler" was already preparing a new grenade... I brought him down with the first shot, I felt pleased with myself. I start looking for targets in the scope. One more "dushko" sits in a trench, sprinkles a machine gun. I shot, but I can't say for sure whether I killed him or not, because the bullet hit the upper edge of the parapet at chest level, behind which he was sitting. The spirit disappeared. Either I got him, or he decided not to tempt fate anymore. Again I aimed the sight and saw that the spirit "on four bones" was crawling up the hill. I only frightened him with the first shot. It began to move its limbs more actively, but had no time to escape. The second shot, like a good kick in the ass, threw him over his head. 
While I was firing at spirits, Arkasha drove away the burning pourer and threw it off the road. I listened, the machine gun seemed to be working. Something was set on fire behind us and black smoke went towards us in the gorge, I couldn't see anything through the sight. My conscript Dmitry and I figured it was time to fuck off. We got ready and rushed across the road, fell behind concrete blocks before the bridge. We couldn't lift our heads, and the machine-gunner pounded the pours, and not unsuccessfully. He set them on fire. We were lying down with Dima, a meter and a half wide river of burning paraffin was running past us in the direction of the bridge. The flames were unbearably hot, but as it turned out, that was not the worst thing. When the fiery river reached the "Ural" with charges for SAU, all this stuff started to explode. I see, some things with rags fly out of the car. Dima explained, that it is illuminating shells. We lie down and count: Dima said there were about 50 of them in the car. Meanwhile the second "Ural" with high explosive shells caught fire. It is well that it did not detonate completely, the shells were scattered aside by explosions. 
I was lying there thinking: "Shit, why isn't anybody in charge of us? It turned out later that Khattab had planned everything so well that at the very beginning of the battle the entire control tower, which was equipped with the two command and staff vehicles, was cut down by small arms fire, and the armoured personnel car was left untouched for the whole battle. 
Suddenly something in the second "Ural" with high explosive ammunition has exploded so that the back bridge with one wheel as a candle has gone upwards for 80 meters and, by our reasons, it should have fallen down directly on us. Well, we thought we were done for. But we were lucky: it fell about ten metres away. Everything was in smoke, everything exploded. Can't see anything through the sights because of the smoke. The shooting is indiscriminate, but the machine gunner of spirits stood out against the general background. We decided to get out of this hell, ran over to the green area. We allocated sectors of fire together with Dima. I was firing at the front, and he was covering my rear, watching to prevent the spirits from coming from above. We crawled out to the edge, but the tank, which was at the tail of the column, was attacked by the spirits with RPGs. Eight times they hit, but without result. Then the turret at the side of the commander's hatch was punched through. Smoke started billowing from it. Probably, the crew was wounded and the mechanic began to fall back. So backwards he passed all column and, they say, reached the regiment. 
An hour has passed since the beginning of battle. Shooting began to stop. I said: "That's it, Dima, let's go to the end of the column!" We ran under the bridge, I look, there are seven people in Afghan clothes, and beside them there are two dead bodies. We run over. One of the sitters turns around. Oh my God! He had a black beard, a hooked nose and mad eyes. I raise my rifle, pull the trigger... The rest of them turn... ours. Good, I didn't finish it. The contract soldier had a beard. He was sitting dumbfounded without me, stammering, unable to say anything. I shouted: "Uncle, I almost killed you!" And he doesn't get it. 
BMP "limp" was crawling towards us, collecting wounded. It was hit in the torsion, and it waddles so. We threw the wounded inside, got on road - around the cars are burning, something in them bursts. The shooting almost stopped. 
We go. Somewhere nearer to Argun on the road the muzhiks shout: "Guys! We have wounded people here. Help!" I jumped over to them, but the car drove on. I go over to the guys. They say: "We've got a major wounded." There's a major sitting there in camouflage, with a badge on his sleeve. He's hit through the arm and chest. Pale from loss of blood. Only thing I had was a tourniquet. Tied his arm up. We got to talking and it was found out, that he was the deputy political officer of a battalion in the Pacific Fleet. At this time someone from the guys remembered that they had beer, cigarettes, juice, etc. in the car. I covered the guys and they ran off and brought all this stuff. We are lying, drinking beer and having a smoke. It began to get dark. I thought: "It's getting dark, the spirits will come down, no help, and we're screwed!" We decided to choose a better position. We took a hillside, occupied it, lay and waited. The guys from RMG show me the situation. Dukes used RPGs to burn the cars with ammunition, and the ones with food were simply pelted with small arms. 
The artillery strikes very deliberately - only along the slopes and not hitting either the populated area or us. Then four Mi-24s arrived and worked their way through the mountains. It got dark. We hear terrible rumbling from the direction of the 324th regiment. It appeared that support was rolling. Ahead of them was a T-72, BMP followed by a tank. Near 50 meters it stopped and aimed its gun at us. I think: "That's it! The spirits haven't killed - they will kill us in the heat of the moment! We rise up, waving our hands - as if they were ours. The tank swung a trunk, turned around and as though shoots in "green area" in 20 meters from itself. From this "help" the people jumped - they creep on the grass, pour around themselves from automatic rifles. We yelled to them: "Men, why are you crawling? There is nobody here any more". It appeared, it was a reconnaissance of 324-th regiment. I came up to officers and I say: "What you here fight? We should go to the head of a column!" And they to me: as you were here and also understand, take ten men and move with them where you told. 
I walked around, found some scouts, and we moved forward. I counted over forty burned corpses. Judging by which vehicles remained intact, the spirits had a clear indication of where everything was. For example, the medical MTLB remained untouched at all, only the mechanic was hit with small arms, and the ZUU behind it was literally turned into a sieve. Then we wondered why the help arrived so late: if they had arrived an hour and a half earlier someone would have survived in the head of the column, but the only BRDM had resisted to the end and almost everyone in it was killed. 
As the guys from the 324th regiment told us later, when they reported that our column was being pounded in the gorge and it would be a good idea to rush to their aid, they were told not to move and stay where they were. Help came to us two and a half hours later, when it was all over.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_20">
		<text>I should have reminded you. It is a sore subject for many people. They found this in one of the dead men's diaries. Shit! If I get out, I'll give up smoking, drinking and stuff like that, but that's for later!
Right now I've got to hang on! Where's that fucking BON!
- Call for fucking reinforcements, they're gonna fucking kill us!
- I've told you ten times, they'll be here in an hour if they don't burn us on the way.
- We could be buried in a matchbox in an hour!
- Ask the spirits to stop shooting.
- We have to retreat, the company's been killed! The BON is lost somewhere, the paratroopers are asleep too...
I'm fed up! A little more talk like this and I myself would fall into hysterics, I must hold on, distract myself as only it is possible in this hell.
Then, as if on cue, the fire from the spirits ceased. The hissing of the mines had ceased, the ricochets had fallen silent, the cries of the Aborigines could no longer be heard. There was a silence, worse than the whistling of the mines.
- Did they run out of ammunition?
- Fuck, they were up to something, the bitches.
Then the rumble of gunfire came from the opposite side.
- What's there?
- Fuck knows!
- Guys, it's the paratroopers! They're the elite! No one else!
- Hooray!
- Get the hell out!
Without a command, without anything, all as one rose from the fortifications and rushed towards the unsightly two or three story buildings. The spirits quickly realized that they were now being fucked on both sides. Some of them broke through but were taken out almost unscathed, the rest were finished off long and hard. I vaguely remember the mopping-up of buildings (on the way to Khankala, I was slightly shell-shocked).
Then our long-awaited BON and airborne units arrived. And later a whole mini-brigade of "fathers-in-charge" arrived... A quiet (as far as is possible in Chechnya) winter evening, I sit on the steps of the new headquarters, smoke and think that finally everything is over. We're in the VVS, and that means we're cops, and cops have to protect them. So the paratroopers will beat up Grozny, and I've had enough of fighting! 
Six days later our brigade was sent to Grozny... 
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_aneki_talk">
		<text>Can you tell me a joke?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_aneki_end">
		<text>It happens.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_1">
		<text>Well, listen. Male solidarity. Sitting in the car one summer with a friend, drinking beer. The windows in the house next to us are open. Quiet all around, only ours is playing music. Oohing and moaning started coming from the first floor, we turned the music down, listened and were laughing) Suddenly the moans stopped and a girl screamed: - "That's it? The guys didn't even have time to finish the song! My mate stuck his head out and shouted: - "Don't hurt the kid, we paused it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_2">
		<text>Well, listen. At the university, at a lecture on psychology. Professor: - Today we will study the three initial stages of the human psyche as an example: surprise, irritation and anger. Taking the phone, the professor dials the first number he comes across. - Hello, may I speak to Vasya? - He doesn't live here. - Here," says the professor smiling, "is a mild surprise. Then dials the number again. - Hello, is Vasya available? - There is no such person here. Rubbing his hands together, the professor winks conspiratorially at the audience and dials a third time. - So no Vasya? - Fuck you! Well, I hope you understand the example. A student gets up from the first desk. - Excuse me, professor, but you forgot the fourth stage. - What stage is that? - The fucking stage. The student goes to the lectern and dials a number. - Good afternoon. This is Vasya. Nobody called me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_3">
		<text>Well, listen. It was December 31st. About ten o'clock in the evening. We're going out to celebrate the New Year. We're carrying three decent bags of, you know, stuff. And, of course, we're not quite sober anymore. And so, only five minutes to go, we are already anticipating the fun, and suddenly... Ten metres away, a police car pulls up gently. A sergeant got out and headed straight for us. Of course I was thinking very gloomily - at best I was going to get a few quid, at worst I would see the New Year in the police station. What a way to celebrate... A sergeant comes over: - Put the bags down! - We obediently put the bags on the snow. My friend: - Put out your hands, - he puts out his hands. - A handful! - he folds his hands in a handful of them in surprise. The sergeant reaches into his pocket and pours a handful of sweets into his hands. Then he turns around and walks towards the car. He turns around from the car and says: "Well, you expect some kind of miracle on New Year's Eve!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_4">
		<text>Well, listen. Morning formation. The company commander's frown meticulously examines the ranks of young recruits. And then his gaze stops on a recruit without a belt. - Comrade soldier. Where is your belt? On what the soldier, obviously from an intelligent family, but already gradually started to master subtleties of army lexicon, reports in a voice aspiring to cause understanding: - Comrade major. We stole it. - In the army there is no such word "pussy", - replies the company captain and our soldier gradually begins to flush red from freckles to ears understanding that with such impudent formulation he hurt the commander's delicate soul. But the company commander's next phrase put everything in its place. - There's a word in the army for "fucked up".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_5">
		<text>Well listen. After the fight, the soldiers are sitting, all angry - many of them were hurt and killed, the Germans were not knocked out from the heights. They start thinking, if Hitler is caught, what to do with him? One suggests: "Drown him in shit! ". The others say, "No, that's too easy. "The foreman smokes. Two: "Quarter the bastard! " All: "No, that's too fast. "Petty Officer smokes. Third: "Tie him up and put him in the anthill so they can eat him! "Nah, it won't look good." The foreman finished his cigarette: "Now listen, sons, what we'll really do with him! We'll take an iron rail, heat one end, and shove the other one up his ass! " Deadly silence. Finally the youngest dared: "Comrade foreman, why is it cold? It should be the other way round! "And so the allies don't pull it out!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_6">
		<text>Well, listen. The Emperor Alexander III, Prince Golitsyn and Lieutenant Rzhevsky are riding in an open lardo. Suddenly a member of the populist party runs out of the crowd and throws a bomb. Rzhevsky manages to catch it and hurls it into the Neva. The Emperor says to him: "Lieutenant, I owe you my life - ask whatever you like! The latter, without hesitation: - I ask for Princess Golitsina's hand. The Emperor to Golitsyn: - Prince, have you heard? He hesitates: - Your Majesty... - Prince, I understand. General Rzhevsky is asking for your daughter's hand. - But, Your Majesty, we're one of the oldest families in Russia... - All right, Prince, I agree to that, too. General Count Rzhevsky is asking for your daughter's hand. - Oh, Your Majesty! There's still the opinion of the world! - Prince, I accept all your conditions. Your daughter's hand is requested by my personal friend, General Count Rzhevsky. Golitsyn: I agree. And Rzhevsky shoves him off, plops down on the seat next to the Emperor and pats the Autocrat of All Russia on the knee: "Sanya, why the fuck do we need this princess! There are so many women around!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_7">
		<text>Listen. A young guy in a cafe drinks coffee and looks at a beautiful girl at a neighbouring table. Finally he decides to come over: - Girl, can I sit down? The girl screams at the whole caf?: - I'm not going to sleep with you! People turn around and smile. The guy, blushing, returns to his table. Just then the same girl joins him. - Excuse me, but the thing is that I'm a psychologist and I'm writing a dissertation on the behaviour of different types of people in inappropriate situations. The guy, all of a sudden, to the whole caf?: -What?! TWO HUNDRED QUID?! ! ? The girl runs out into the street. The guy calmly gathers himself, comes out, approaches her and says: -It's a pleasure, I'm a lawyer, and I know how to make people feel guilty...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_8">
		<text>Well, listen. Scientists have created a unique computer with artificial intelligence, a vast knowledge base, a speech processor and an emotion synthesiser. It was supposed to answer all kinds of questions. Before displaying it to the public, they decided to ask it a tricky question. - Can a man fuck a woman? - asked one of the creators. - Yes, but it is immoral to hit a woman," the computer answered. - How silly he is yet! - The creators laughed. - I will not answer any more, - said the computer. - Fuck you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_9">
		<text>Listen. There was a priest who was building a church. And all was well, but the bell tower kept falling down. They build it, it falls down. They build it again, it falls down again. And then an angel of God appeared to the priest and said: "Build your wife into the foundation and your temple will stand forever." The young priest loved his wife, but he also loved the Lord. And the temple had to be built. He grieved, cried, said goodbye to his wife (and she was a pious lady, so it is necessary), and bricked up. But the bell tower fell down anyway. Because you can't fuck around with resilience.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_10">
		<text>Well, listen. A 600 and a kopeck hit the intersection. A bull with chains as thick as his arm comes out of the 600, and the same guy comes out of the kopeck. The driver of the 600: - You got a new car just like it! Second man: You're screwed! - he calls on his mobile phone. An hour later, a zero gelding arrives. Second: - I got you a new one in an hour?! One: - Well, yeah... - Now you get me a new one! In one hour! Time's up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_11">
		<text>Well, listen. A guy tries to "glam up" a tipsy girl at a bar: "I bet you ten quid I can fuck you as good as you've ever seen and I won't even touch you. " "You're an idiot, that just can't happen. Somebody smash it! " Knocked, the guy took the girl back to his house and fucked her all night until she lost her pulse. In the morning she woke him up and said: "That really was the best sex of my life, but you kept touching me." "Get your tenner on the table," the guy muttered through sleep and turned back against the wall.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_12">
		<text>'Well listen. Scary woman, brick face, walks into a shopping centre with her two sons, looking at everyone like Lenin at the bourgeoisie, and shoving kids at the slightest occasion. The saleswoman says to her: "Hello, welcome. What cute kids! Twins? - What kind of bullshit are you talking about, light-headed? One is 9 years old, the other is 8! Are you blind or just an idiot? - No, I'm neither. I just couldn't believe that someone would fuck you twice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_13">
		<text>Well, listen. There was an unassuming bloke at the holiday home who'd been pestering a posh lady about an intimate relationship for a long time. She just mocked him, saying that with your talents... Then the man bet her that he could fuck her twenty times in a row. The only condition was that everything had to happen in complete darkness and that after each time he had to go and wash up. The bet was a car, and the woman agreed. Night fell, and the man set to work... Once, twice, three times... after the seventeenth time, the woman couldn't stand it anymore and cried out: "That's it! I've lost! I can't go on, turn on the light! The light came on and she saw a big unfamiliar man in front of her. - Who are you! ? - she shouted. - What are you doing here? Where's the little bumpy one? - Oh, he must be the entertainer. He sells tickets out front...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_14">
		<text>Well, listen. Attention! There's a new way to cheat! You should know! A group of young girls are operating. It goes like this: You leave the supermarket, go to your car, load up and want to leave. At that moment, two pretty pussies run up to the car and tearfully ask for a ride to the underground, their money has been stolen and their mother will meet them there. You say yes. One gets in the front seat, the other in the back. Suddenly, the one in front bends over and starts sucking your dick, while the other is munching on your groceries while you're mourning. The questions that many in search of an answer to are: 1) Which supermarket to look for them at? 2) What does the one behind you like to eat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_15">
		<text>Listen. Schoolgirl's going to the prom. Approaching her mother: - Mom, if I kiss a boy on the lips, can I get pregnant? Mother (smiling): No, of course not. - And if you kiss with your tongue? Mother (straining): Not either. - What if I give him a blow job? Mother (shocked): No, you won't get pregnant. - Well, what about anal sex? Mother (half faint): Jesus, daughter, you're gonna do all that at the prom?! ! - No, mum, don't worry. I'm just finding out who the father is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_16">
		<text>Well, look. Grandpa, a World War II veteran, was sent on a tour to Germany. At the embassy, the grandfather fills out a questionnaire, and there are these questions: - Date of last visit to Germany. He writes: April - May 1945. - Type of transport on which visited (necessary underline)... and the list: the plane, train, car... other. Grandpa skipped everything and wrote: T-34 tank!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_17">
		<text>Well, listen. The investigator of the prosecutor's office reports to the president: "Vasilyeva pointed at Serdyukov, Serdyukov at Chubais, Chubais at Surkov, Surkov at Medvedev, Medvedev at...". "That's enough... - interrupts Vladimir Vladimirovich - it's already quite obvious that no one is to blame for anything..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_18">
		<text>Well, listen. A competent insurance salesman: The newly arrived soldiers were cornered in a room, the insurer came on stage, smiled and said: - Guys, I know you don't want to listen to any bullshit for a long time, so I will explain to you about insurance in one minute. The meaning of insurance is simple: if you don't have it, you have been sent into combat and died - the government will send your family a letter of condolence. If you have it, you were sent into combat and die - the government will send your family $20,000. At this point he paused, looked around the room with his eyes and asked: - Who do you guys think will be sent to battle first in this scenario?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_19">
		<text>Well, listen. The husband went to bed with his wife, the husband was already taking a nap and through his sleep said: - The light... His wife slaps him on the forehead with all her might, and the poor man's eyes widen: "What for? - Who the fuck is Sveta?! I'm Galya! You're not Galya! You fucking idiot! Turn off the light!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_20">
		<text>Listen to me. A man has committed a crime. He was caught and brought before the king for trial. His act was punishable by death, but the king offered him the choice of his fate: either to be hanged, or to go behind a big, black, scary steel door. The criminal thought it over and chose the gallows. When they put the noose around his neck, he suddenly said: 'I was curious: what is behind that door? The king laughed: "Well, you see, it's a funny thing. I give this choice to everybody, and everybody chooses the gallows. - What is behind the door? - ...the criminal asks. - I won't tell anyone anyway," he added, pointing to the noose. The king answered after a while: "It's free. But people are so afraid of the unknown that they prefer the rope to the unknown!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dm_about_zonanews_talk">
		<text>Tell me a story about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_zonanewsend">
		<text>It is interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_1">
		<text>So we climb into that hangar. All around is dust, cobwebs - completely under a roof; detectors spoil total nonsense: not that nobody around, and we in the nature do not exist. Let's take up perimeter position: Sanyok in front, we to cover... And then - BANG! Such huge iron beams, rusty under the ceiling, so one comes off - and down! How Sanyok dodged it, he doesn't know, but the thing crashed exactly where he was standing. He fell down and rolled away, didn't get up at all, and started shooting from the ground! The others got scared too, idiots, and went to plant themselves in a white light. Then Sanek started yelling something about a creature in the corner. I look - I don't see any creature... Anyway, here we go, not an operation, but a mess... A bordello... We went to walk around these ruins; we walked for five minutes - carefully, so as not to find ourselves under these beams again. And nonsense, nonsense full: one, then another something will appear, they start to shoot in stages on an empty place. And two of them had no luck at all: one was walking on a smooth floor and suddenly fell into a pit, and the other got torn across the back by a broken door. We were all astonished, because it was obvious that some sort of creature was having a good time. We shot psi-protection and put a gas grenade in every corner - and waited until someone would show up, fingers on the trigger. We wait and wait... And the creature, as it turned out later, was flying or something... While we were fooling around downstairs, it was sitting quietly under the ceiling, having fun, the bitch. It only came to us late, and almost by accident. The bastard loosened a couple of beams and half the roof came down on us, four guys in a heap on the spot... That's where we got it! When Sane heard the rustling upstairs, he automatically fired - a useful reflex, damn it! What a scream! We too, of course, jumped up and shot with all our guns... The creature came screaming from above, it was making my ears pop. Well, there we took our hearts out: some of us beat it with rifle butts, others simply kicked it, and Sanyok took out a knife to disembowel it more painfully... The commander, of course, pulled them all with difficulty, or else we would have had to scrape the bugger off the floor with spoons...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_10">
		<text>Have you heard of the Guide? The very first stalker. The first to go to the Zone, and he's still alive. They say he can get you anywhere. Another thing is that it's problematic to find him - he doesn't put up posters with his address... And not everyone agrees to see him off, either. He'll take a lot of money, but if you've found him and made a deal, you can be sure he'll deliver you to the right place. That's the man to talk to. He must have seen what's under the radar...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_11">
		<text>There's a big difference between being a dude and being a dude... You think you get dough for nothing? No way! You'll only get it from a freak or a stalker... You gotta think. You gotta think there, and this is even better. Bulls don't last long here. It doesn't work without a loft... Anyway, here's the deal. The three of us were walking through the backyard with Sinia and the late Chains. We saw a deer scratching. Well, we hid. And he walks past us and doesn't notice. He's so small, but he's pulling a big sack. And he's got a machine gun. He'll shoot us with olives at any time. So Bruise says to me, "Let's feel the brainiac, what's he got there? And I said to him: "Quiet, peckerwood! You better watch where he's taking his loot." Well... The deer just fell off somewhere - we didn't even realize it. Well, we wait. He came out about twenty minutes later. While he was standing shaking off, Cepa quietly rode up behind him and knocked half a bollock out of a trellis. He and Bruise began to tear up the body: he was wearing a cool armour, and a shovel... I pissed - my lads would always give me mine, I'm in for a share in life. It's fucked up... Anyway, the guy was a tough guy. He'd rigged something so it'd blow up if someone took off his armour. I got out of there quick - not many people would show up for a gunshot or an explosion... I came back in a month. Cepa and Bruise and the deer, not a bone in sight. Nothing at all. Anyway, I figured out where he was diving in the wreckage, so I went in there myself... Well, I went through three rooms, nothing. Then I see a bunch of beds piled in the corner. Why the fuck would there be so many beds? Well, I went in there to clean it up. I did it. I see a fucking woman, a hatch. So I lift the lid, shine the torch. Holy shit! I'm in heaven. Well, what happened is my business. I didn't miss anything. If I'd had my ears open, I'd have been a stiff or still running around barefoot, like some people.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_12">
		<text>They say there's a group of fellows... Sometimes they're called shamans and sometimes druids. They say they do not carry any electronic equipment, as they are closer to nature and all that... Well, they say the Zone is all about electronics... ...it reacts more strongly to electromagnetic radiation... Yeah, and it sends monsters at you. The way they put it, the Zone is a living organism. They say that it is forbidden to get into it with devices, because the right man can cope without any extra attachments. But they carry their machine guns with them, the bastards... They wouldn't use their teeth and claws to try... On the other hand, not too many of them die in the Zone. They don't die more often than we do... So maybe they had the right idea... It's true, they come into the Zone more from the Belarusian side... It'd be good to see them... and see how many artifacts they have in their pockets...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_13">
		<text>Anybody know of any classified labs deep in the Zone? It's like they're still working... Right, right... It's not clear how anyone could survive there... without supplies, without energy... Which begs the question, maybe there aren't people working there. I've been talking to a guy. He hasn't seen the lab. No, he hasn't, but he picked up some strange conversations on the Yantar. They were talking about some kind of lab. And the other man to this, the first, swore that he had once bumped into a figure in a suit like a stalker, but more sophisticated... And like the figure told him to get out of here translucent. "Don't interfere, go away, we're working here". Well, the guy was shitting himself... of course he was! How many of us have seen that before...? On the other hand, it seems to have happened near the radar... Well, you know... Right. So I don't think it's true. But on the other hand... mutations are different, aren't they? Maybe they're not human beings anymore, but some kind of energy entity? Ah?... Come on, don't be ridiculous...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_14">
		<text>You know what? It's almost impossible to sleep in this part of the Zone... I'm lucky, I can't sleep anyway... but people have such nightmares that they don't wake up in the morning... ...from heartbreak, for example... Some move their horses, some go berserk... Recently, though, there's a rumor that there's a cure. If you really need to sleep, you should find an old bucket... or at least a big pot... a boiling pot there... It has to be whole... You put your head in there and sleep like in God's bosom... Laugh it up, laugh it up. I'll look at you in a couple of days when you're tired. Smart guys... You tell me, why the fuck are the soldiers here lately, wearing sneaky helmets? Yeah, not a peep out of them for two years, but lately they've been coming around. They got some new helmets. Guys found one body, they said. There's a grid of copper wire attached to the helmet. So, what the hell is this harness for? And in general it is "g-j-j" not for nothing, I can tell you. There is no much to choose here from anomalies - not that kind of grounds, there are safer places and there are much fatter pieces... I think they are outlining the approaches. They're preparing a bridgehead. They want to get to Sarcophagus, mark my words. It's going to be a hell of a lot worse soon. Mark my words... The main thing is for you and me to get away from here by then...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_15">
		<text>Hey, do you guys know anything about The Intercept? They say they're special forces, military personnel! But how they work, huh?! How they work! It's not like the assholes at the cordons! Not only do they go to the lowest rungs, but they've been in the Zone for months! I'm not bullshitting! They've got bases, several of them, a shitload of caches, and they've got helicopters dropping supplies off at the perimeter. Their commander is some kind of Gromov... I think his name's fake - they call him 'Major' or 'Thunder'. You don't believe me?! So Pakhomich caught an interception somehow! Caught him, and God help him, or they'd have kicked him for good... Secrecy, that's what it is! Everybody knows Pakhomych, don't they? Well, that's just it! It's not bullshit, it's a serious team. I don't know what they're up to, but they're doing a hell of a job. I wish I had a third - no, ten percent like that! - I'd have built a house in Sochi on ten floors by now... They say they have this thing... they can spot monsters from two hundred metres away. Any kind of creature! Sure as hell would be walking around the Zone spitting... They say there're some guys... Not soldiers, but some of ours... Anyway, some guys snuck into the centre of the Zone. It's not enough that they snuck in - they say they can tame beasts too! They do not go beyond the perimeter, to the Big Earth, and nobody goes to them either... well, except those who it is the nature to sarcophagus... They have artefacts enough to wipe their ass with! "The Duty Boys know about them... they know, they fight, but they don't say anything. If you ask one of these cops: "Tales", he says. Aren't they bitches?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_16">
		<text>Brothers, did you hear that some infidels got close to the antennas recently? The Monolith sent us, and the brothers spotted them in time. We took out one at once. The other two took off running. Cowards. They're all cowards. Only true faith leaves no room for fear! Two managed to escape, but the Monolith is wise and all-knowing. Then he needs them alive.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_17">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith summoned me in the night. I spoke to him. He was beautiful in his majesty. I almost went blind, but his light filled me with great power! I know, I feel, that his power abides with us all! He told me that only a strong faith can defeat evil. He told me that his power would only fill the faithful. He also told me that our victory is near!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_18">
		<text>What I think... I'm not even thinking, I'm just guessing... What if everything - all that is here - is an experiment on people? Maybe it's some kind of green men... Why? I wonder, if this is some kind of test site, what exactly are they testing here? Checking out which artifacts we drool over the most? Or are they bombs of some kind, huh? They got them all over the world, all over the labs, rich people paying for them... No, that's cool... That's what I'd like to see. You buy some shit under the table, pay a lot of money, like, "We're the best," envy them, and it fucks it up. Oh, great! Oh, I can't believe it. Oh, I don't know what's really going on. Whoever went for the radar can tell you about it. Yeah, maybe they know, but they can't say it. They just moo and drool. Maybe that's why they're drooling... Eh... That's what's making me think... It's not fun at all...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_19">
		<text>I've been to the Dark Vale. There's a lot of infidels there, because the power of the Monolith hasn't reached these places yet. We were guarding. At night we were attacked. We fought fiercely against those animals. The merits of the brothers were great: Monolith soon called them to himself. For me, he had prepared another test. My weapons were no longer firing. But then the Monolith said to me, "You are with me, and my power is with you. If you are steadfast in your faith, you will crush my enemies and come close to me!" Then I became a shadow. I ducked down and went around to their right. The foolish spies didn't notice anything. They thought they were done with us and laughed at the empty bodies of our brothers. But I could already see their backs. And then the power of Monolith struck from my hands. So it killed them all. I am happy to serve you, Perfect One!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_2">
		<text>My partner and I have been looking at this research institute for a long time. It's a desolate place. No animals around, no mutants. But whoever went there was either scared out of their wits, or never saw them again. We decided to scout around on our own. We set off in the dark, and by the time we reached the place it had already begun to dawn. We left the car in a clearing, went on a wood to the edge. We stopped there, the partner stayed below, and I got on a tree with optics to look round what was going on in vicinity. I saw the houses, not completely abandoned, almost all the windows were intact, there was not much grass in the yards, unlike in other places - up to the waist... It looked like people lived here, but there was complete silence and no movement. Suddenly bursts of gunfire hit me from the right, someone was using short rifles. I aimed my telescope over there. I saw on a roof of one of the buildings an unfamiliar guy - like a rat, hunted and shooting indiscriminately in all directions. Who - I looked and could not understand: he was alone there. And then... it started... I saw everything as if on the palm of my hand. The machine gun flew out of his hands... It was like the wings had grown on the iron... The guy opened his mouth, yelled something, took out a knife and put it in front of him. And then - holy shit! - I look, and there's another one hanging in front of him. It's hanging there with its stinger in the air, and no one is holding it. What happened next is out of the question... For five minutes they cut the man up. Little by little, bit by bit, bit by bit, bit by bit, bit by bit... Poor guy was soon covered in blood... Then, when he started to wriggle, his knife got knocked out too... The guy got lifted in the air and twisted a couple of times... I've never seen anything like that in my life - like a rag... I was wet in three seconds... Then... No, I'm not going to... Anyway, when I got my breath back, I spent another five minutes wandering around with the scope. My hands were shaking, my optics were wet with sweat... At least one creature! Nothin' in the normal and infra-red ranges. When I got down my partner looked at me and decided not to ask. When I got back to base I was drunk up to my eyebrows for a week. Then, when I got back, I asked around, see if anybody had heard anything about it. Only people started to ask me if I was crazy. That's the way it is...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_20">
		<text>Brothers, we were patrolling the outskirts of the Black Forest when we stumbled upon a lone infidel. He started to turn, so we didn't kill him, but he was still half in his animal state... I know the wise Monolith did this for all of us: he showed us again the true face of his enemies. Now our faith is even more strengthened! It's coming, brothers! Victory over the infidels is nigh, and then the Monolith will fulfill our deepest desire! He will bring the truly faithful closer to himself, to his glory, to his greatness! We shall forever shine in his glory...!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_3">
		<text>Anyway, my friend told me this. His bosses woke him up in the middle of the night and told him to run to the lab. He's sleepy, doesn't understand: what cargo? They said to him: Have you been drinking too much alcohol? There's a fresh corpse on the table, it's ready to eat! Anyway, he comes to the table. And there's something... He, in fact, the dead men from the Zone in his time has seen: and you torn, and fried vArenaey, and got mutants not one dozen, and here like a dinner in the stomach began to walk. I was a bit like a normal guy, but he had a big lumpy pumpkin on the side. And his body was a fucking concentration camp, skin and bones. But he understood it afterwards, but at first he said that he saw some mess: everything was covered with orange-red dirt, like blood... Those fuckers didn't spare any ammunition. Do-olg... search for anomalous objects, man... no fucking way!... He said it was a mixture of a colander and a torn heating pad... ...and they were walking all over him in their shitpants. It was a piece of meat in black rags. Anyway, he spent the rest of the night and half of the morning slaving away. I guess that's the creature the locals know as the illusionist: black rags, stalker visions, head six feet in circumference... The funny thing about his face, whoever saw it, they thought it was his forehead. Nah, he really has a personality, but he is very small: his blinkers are not opening, and his nose is like a pin, though his mouth is huge, just a jamb at the gate. He walks and hangs his head on his chest - he can't hold it straight... ...and guess what these things eat for lunch. Mushrooms! Mushrooms! Anyway, everyone saw - the Zone is full of mushrooms, so the "old men" give a tooth that these things are juicing from them. Gourmands, damn it... And do you know what he had stashed in a bag on his side? Well? No way! Anyway, his brains were jerky. Do you know whose? A controller's.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_4">
		<text>One fool came to our place... So we take a five-minute rest, and he gets right on his heels - and relaxes. He's the last one to get his ass off the ground. So he relaxes... he lags behind, and his controller grabs his brains! - and that's it. If you're new to the business, remember. A rustle or a suspicious breeze... Let a bunny run by... although bunnies are God forbid here... In a word, you have to be ready every second. I've got magazines and grenades at hand and a submachine gun on uninterrupted. If you see something, just take out half a magpie; if something's behind the bushes, hit it too, and then ask. It's a young fighter's course here: they don't give you a warning, they gobble you up before you can make a fart. Yeah, there's a separate story about controllers. Let's say you shoot at a rustle and immediately fall down, in the same second! On your back or whatever. The controller clings if it sees you - it needs to concentrate or something. While you're sunbathing in the shade, listen to both ears to see if there's any rustling, any crap coming towards you. You can quietly flick the magazine, and it wouldn't hurt to have grenades ready... So if everything's quiet, you count to three and... And off you go! Get the hell out of here! Did you suck it? Take care of yourselves every second. It's the only way to survive here.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_5">
		<text>What I'm thinking... I'm not even thinking, I'm just thinking... What if everything here is an experiment on people? Maybe it's some kind of green men... Why? I wonder, if this is some kind of test site, what exactly are they testing here? Checking out which artifacts we drool over the most? Or are they bombs of some kind, huh? They got them all over the world, all over the labs, rich people paying for them... No, that's cool... That's what I'd like to see. You buy some shit under the table, pay a lot of money, like, "We're the best," envy them, and it fucks it up. Oh, great! Oh, I can't believe it. Oh, I don't know what's really going on. Whoever went for the radar can tell you about it. Yeah, maybe they know, but they can't say it. They just moo and drool. Maybe that's why they're drooling. That's why they're drooling. It's not fun at all.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_6">
		<text>So... I remember someone asking me something yesterday, but I forgot... Oh, I remember. So there are those who are curious as to why only our eggheads hang around in the Zone and why foreigners don't show their noses, even though there's about three thousand Nobel laureates... So I'll answer point by point. Firstly, why on earth would they bother to come here when they can give us a grant with such conditions, that he will bring everything you need on a silver platter? Secondly, they have actually been here a lot. It's been the last two years the foreigners are afraid to go to the Zone... one big bummer happened to them. Now they're just buying up materials and information. The pay's pretty good, so a lot of loners work for them, and looters too... What, you haven't heard about this story? You don't say! The whole Zone was on its ear, and you fell out of the sky. Anyway, it was a big deployment. Thirty scientists alone from half the world... all the luminaries, of course, back and forth... They made serious preparations: they were loaded with money, equipment - a mountain. We took a platoon of military-specialists for protection, three of our guides, loaded the shielded BATERs and set off. We returned a week later... twelve men on the dead-beat BATER. We got to the spike at Rottenwood, and there they were... ...looters... Yeah... They don't care where they came from... They got almost all of them. Only three got out of the perimeter - two of ours and one egghead. Impressions made the man go wild in the attic... Well, quickly grabbed him by the scruff of the neck and treated. Now he's writing a book about the Zone. Our guys are all right. Experience helped. Although... they probably went their own way too: one went to the radar and disappeared, and the other went to the Big Land. And the rest were taken by the Zone. Have you heard about the Thirty-two Town? That's where they got caught. At first everything was quiet... well, within limits... They were surveying there, collecting samples, poking at anomalies... And then they went berserk. A mass madness. People started slowly going nuts. Our man, the one who retired, told me... Some started tearing their throats out with their nails, some smashed their heads against the wall, and some simply put a gun in their mouths, and... And then the beasts came. Some of them were in themselves, barricaded themselves in the house. Imagine that, huh? Outside it's night and all the creatures are out there, and inside, people are going crazy one by one. In a word, in the morning, those who were still sane got out. They drove straight back, without the road; they even picked up a few anomalies... We made it to the Rotten Forest... And those who stayed there, they couldn't find anyone. Guys just say there's been a spike in controllers in that area. Yeah... Since then, no one's been going to Town-Twenty-Two, and you can't lure a foreigner into the Zone...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_7">
		<text>So that's what I wanted to say. When they took that illusion, I was there! I just happened to be in the area. My car, my Niva, the right front one broke off. The bolts sheared off in the bump. And there's nothing for spare parts. I swore a lot, and then let me go to the factory to pick up the right ones. It was a kilometre to walk there - a half an hour! And I'd been there before... Suddenly I saw - "a duty"! Not just any patrol, but half a hundred of them. Well, I think it's a bloody mess... He just stood there and fell into the bushes. "If they spot me and start combing through," I thought, "that's the end of me. So I lay down in the hole and tried not to breathe. And here comes the shooting! I'd only heard such gunfire once in my life ... when they took the first base - the old men, remember? So I'm lying there, listening in both ears... It bangs, and then it bangs... Five minutes later it goes quiet and no one comes to me. Well, I got up the nerve, stood up a bit and looked through the binoculars. And they were dragging themselves out of the workshop... battered, dragging a heap of their dead men behind them and the illus on the tarp... only scraps were left of the illus... They ducked into a ravine. Then I hear the engines roar and the sound goes away. I waited a bit longer, nobody seems to be there. I go in. I know you can't find anything after Duty. But it was interesting! I'll tell you, that was something! They almost poked through the walls. Beams across the floor, a piece of roof collapsed. Shell casings up to their knees - a real firing range. Blood, bits and pieces... I didn't find anything useful - just two full cans, and a machine gun lying there, crushed by a beam... I forgot about the bolts... I went back to the car, thought for five minutes, took a bolt off the other wheels... and drove slowly... And if I had gone there a half an hour earlier... Yeah...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_8">
		<text>Yeah, that's how I got to the outskirts of Pripyat. So I decided to look around first thing. I found a place higher up - there was a big boiler house with a chimney. Well, I went carefully... as if everything was all right - there was dust, no traces... I got into the furnace and crawled: there were steps inside the chimney. I crawled in it as if everything was all right - it was petrified. It's beautiful! Half the city in the palm of my hand! I took out my binoculars and looked round... (Small pause) And so on... I was about to slip downwards, but the thought occurred to me: what was going on under my nose and I did not look! I bend over the edge a little, look on one side, then on the other... Well, that's what I was looking at! There's a dwarf walking around the courtyard! The main thing is, I'm almost down there. It's all right that he can't see me yet. But I can't blow his turret off, the Kalash is hanging on my back, and the pipe is too narrow to turn around. Using the Makarov under my arm - shit, it's fifty meters, and the difference in height ... in short, if I do not get right away - and I'm sure I will not - then the end of the world. I'm sitting here thinking. And at the same time, I'm watching what he's doing. He was doing something strange. At first he was so briskly, so light-heartedly, rummaging around in the heap of rubbish - only bits of it were flying off to the right and to the left. And then suddenly he just stood there and froze. He seemed to listen. And then it became a real mess. The rubbish in that pile started to move on its own. Dwarf quickly jumped away, stood like a pillar, put his hands on his head, twisted his palms in a sly way... and it flew at him! From all sides!.. Tin, bricks, roofing felt, branches... He was so over his head. Well, I think that's it. That's it, the kitten won't pee again... No way! For two seconds the rubbish lay there, and then just like that it splashes in all directions! There were some pipe scraps, and they hit the concrete fence. He stood there for half a minute, pondered something, and then turned around and went back to the building. I took a minute to catch my breath. "Well," I thought, "it's a bit of a good thing, let's get out of here. Suddenly there was a puff of smoke. And then it got hot. Go to hell! Someone started a fire from downstairs! In a minute - that was it, there was nothing to breathe. I could manage to reach the edge of the chimney - there was no shelter there, so I sat down and put my feet up... The smoke still eats my eyes, i.e. there was not enough air... in short, i had to leave urgently! I always carried a half-meter of cord just in case of fire... I was sure I was a fireman... So, I halved the cord - it was not too thick - I tied it to the chimney at the best advantage, tore my scarf in two, wrapped it around the belt, and crawled up, praying to all the gods... My only thought was: Better not to fall down! I couldn't find a safety rope, it cut my hands... Of course, by the law of bad luck, I was five meters far from the ground. I had to jump. What to do? Oh, I'm in a jam! I was lucky, I didn't break anything... But I injured myself and my right leg was badly pulled! Then I thought I'd torn a ligament. And then I yanked it so hard, I could have won the gold medal in the race...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_9">
		<text>I couldn't believe my eyes at the time. You'd think there were pretty girls, right? But this one was... she was... Perfect. Yeah. There. Perfect. It felt like the world around her was black and white and blurry, she was the only one in colour and sharpness. The way she moved! I've never seen that before either. I got a lump in my throat. She doesn't need this science! What's she doing here, in the Zone? Yeah, in the Zone. It was late afternoon... There's a separate nine-storey building by the bus station. First something flashed in the window on the ground floor. I took the safety off the "kalash", and then I look - she's coming out of the doorway... I wanted to rub my eyes - what can you expect from the Zone? And she walks up. I'm standing there like a fool, staring... I have my gun ready - it's a habit... She spots me... She smiles... She says hello... I can't hear her, I keep staring at her. She wore a blue jumpsuit, a bright one... but not a hoodie, almost tight... Her figure was something fantastic! It was then that I realized that I was not listening to what she was saying - I stood there and smiled ear to ear... She, it turns out, was from the research group. She asked me if I could help her. She! I'd go into an anomaly for her...! She said that she's working on these, what are they... endemics of the Zone. You know, plants that are only found here. Said she escaped from the guards because there's no leeway with them, and she came here alone. I don't know. I believed it. I agreed to help her - bring her something. Two days later, I showed up like we talked about. Almost got myself killed five times while I was packing it up. As I walked, I had one thought in my head: I'm going to see her again! And nothing. I didn't even see the house where I met her. Just like that... But what was she like! She was glowing on the inside...</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>
