<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	
	<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Freeze! Drop your weapon. You're under arrest. You're coming with me for clarification. They'll figure it out.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_1">
        <text>On my way, soldier. Don't get nervous, I won't run away.</text>
    </string> 
	
	
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_0">
        <text>What a bunch of people! Long time no see, my friend Sawan. It's been a long time! So, tell me how you got here. And where's your friend? Boorland, if I remember correctly?</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_1">
        <text>It started off so well... It was just me, Citizen Warden. Just walking by, not touching anybody. I don't know anything.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_2">
        <text>Yeah, you can tell the prosecutor. This is serious, brother: you're a criminal. And you're here illegally. You're in a secure military facility. You know what you're looking at? 15 years. Or I could shoot you right now if you try to escape. That's another option.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_3">
        <text>Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. How about we make a deal?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_4">
        <text>You offering a bribe? You're out of your fucking mind! I'm on duty. Don't worry, you'll live. Not for long, though. It's a joke. I know why you came here. While you were running around the Cordon, collecting ransom, your friend Borland told me a lot of interesting things. Specifically, about an unusual artifact and its reward.  And where to find it. Thought I wouldn't believe him, that I'd lost my mind. Fool. Too bad he's not with you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_5">
        <text>Oh, man! He didn't tell me about it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_6">
        <text>Of course he didn't! I think he was trying to use you for his own ends. He gave me a phony tip, too, and some of my guys got killed. You think I want to spend 10 years rotting away at Cordon before I'm discharged? And then? A poor Ukrainian pension for the rest of my life? I don't need it! Here, the opportunity comes to me. I got through my channels to find out where they're hiding this artifact. And me and the boys decided to take a chance. We only live once! If you're here too, then my sources are telling the truth.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_7">
        <text>I was hoping to find the artifact in the dungeon where your men caught me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_8">
        <text>It's a false trail. We checked, there's nothing there. Just monsters. And SPEKTRUM fighters who hunt down stalkers who get there and kill them. They patrol the lab constantly. My fighters were just waiting for them to come back upstairs. And here you are. An unexpected surprise. You're lucky you didn't get your ass kicked in the first place. They could have. All right, to the point: According to my intel, the artifact is at the Spectre base in the D.C. building. It's on the other side of the district. We're prepping for an assault. And I could use an extra gun. If you help me, I'll let you go when this is over. You'll be a free man alive. You have my word as an officer.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_9">
        <text>I don't have a choice, do I?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_10">
        <text> There's always a choice. Either come with me on the assault, or I'll put you up against the wall right now. Why so pale? I'm just kidding. Listen to your first mission: we know what frequency SPEKTRUM talks on, but our radio station is an ancient shit Soviet mammoth. In short, we quickly arranged for the necessary radio parts to be delivered from Bolshaya Zemlya to Kordon. This set of parts will allow us to modify our radio station. There was an attempt a few hours ago to get the parts here by chopper. It came under fire. Thank God everyone is alive and the chopper has already returned to base. The pilots said they dropped the cargo and now they have to pick it up. I don't want to send my own fighters, I don't have any extra men. You've come along just in time. You're gonna scout the area, see if you can find a crate of parts. I'll text you the approximate drop zone on the PDA. That's it, you're good to go. You try to mess with me, you'll be surprised before you know it. My snipers will be watching you. An hour for everything.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_11">
        <text>Permission to run, Citizen Warden?</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_0">
        <text>I almost got killed in there! It was an ambush. As soon as I grabbed the box, they fired on me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_1">
        <text>And you thought you were in a fairy tale? This isn't a fairy tale. It's not like shooting wild boars on Cordon! You're still alive, I'll give you that. I see you didn't even get hit. Okay, so we've got the details. Let's start listening to their channel.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_2">
        <text>Any further instructions?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_3">
        <text>Our spy, Sidorenko, came crawling back from his mission alive. I thought he was dead. But he's still moving, it means he's alive. Never mind, he'll heal before the wedding. At least until the next one. Or a funeral. Just kidding, he'll live. Probably.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_4">
        <text>What was his assignment, if not a military secret?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_5">
        <text>Take your time, you'll find out. So here's the deal. By some miracle, the SPECTROMs got an APC. What fucking miracle? I know what kind. The soldiers from Zapolye sold it. They sold it to them for a case of vodka, the bitches! So, the APC poses a serious danger to us.\nThe scout's task was to plant explosives on the APC. We planned to remotely detonate it at the beginning of the assault to confuse the enemy's plans.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_6">
        <text>I guess he didn't plant the explosives, huh?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_7">
        <text>He did. He was ambushed and went off in yards. He couldn't plant the explosives, so to get away, he dumped them somewhere in the playground. Like he said, under some giraffe. There's a lot of playgrounds around here. You need to find the charge and put it on the back of the APC. You're an experienced fighter. You can do this. Do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_8">
        <text>Yes, sir.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_0">
        <text>You did it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_1">
        <text>I never doubted you. While you were gone, we intercepted an important conversation. Early tomorrow morning, SPECTRUM is going to transport their bosses from the Zone, who happen to be here in the city. You get the idea? I think it's for transporting the artefact by air. Two helicopters are booked for this case, which indirectly confirms my point. We need to intercept the artifact. According to our intel, the helicopter getaway will be covered by sniper fire and an APC, which we've already taken care of. Your job is to provide cover for my assault team.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_2">
        <text>You plan to capture the artifact and then sell it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_3">
        <text>You got that right. If everything works out, you'll be free at the end of the mission. And we'll never see each other again.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_4">
        <text>I certainly hope so.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_0">
        <text>Savannah, Savannah, stop! .... Don't kill me. I know what you want!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_1">
        <text>You speak Russian now?! How do you know my name?!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm a Russian German. And I know five languages. If it's so important. I know your name because we know all the experienced stalkers in the Zone. We're a private military company called SPEKTRUM, we planned to take control of the Exclusion Zone and continue the experiments that the scientists of DISSOLUTION didn't finish.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_3">
        <text>This is nonsense. Don't talk back to me. Where's the artifact, bitch?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_4">
        <text>There is no artifact! We're the ones who started the rumor about the artifact. We put out a huge bounty for something that doesn't exist. All so that all the seasoned stalkers would rush out looking for it. And we would hunt them down here and recruit them to guard our labs.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_5">
        <text>I've seen you recruit. Lead in the head. I've seen them. Dead. You just killed anyone who posed a threat to you. For the last time, where's the artifact, asshole?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_6">
        <text>It doesn't exist! Take... Take this case, there's a lot, a lot of money in here. It's a lot more than the bounty we put out on a non-existent artifact. Just let me get out of here alive. Tell me you didn't find anyone here... please! I'll disappear from the Zone forever, just let me go.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_7">
        <text>You got it! Give me the case. </text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_0">
        <text>Show me what you've got.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_1">
        <text>Here, the case with the money in it. I figure it's about 3 million euros in there. Or thereabouts. There you go. The artifact's not in there. So what now? How do we get out of here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_2">
        <text>You're dumber than I thought.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_3">
        <text>What?!</text>
    </string>

    
</string_table>
