<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="labx5_borland_start_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>Well, we're in.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="labx5_borland_start_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>Borland, hurry up.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="labx5_borland_start_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>Take your time, Savannah, you're not leading a squad. You never know what's going on in this lab. If you hear anything suspicious, don't make a fuss. But if you do... Don't forget what you were taught - a spare magazine is always at hand. One more thing: Skidan asked me to look for documents in here. Experimental reports. Promised to pay good money for each one. So keep your eyes open.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_start_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_00">
        <text>Damn, how'd he get me so hooked...</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>What was that?</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>It's the controller. They meet closer to the centre of the Zone. What's he doing here? He's a mind-reader, like a telepath. My head's cracking at the seams. If I was any closer, he'd have taken complete control of me. I'd be a zombie. Thanks for saving my ass.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>You'll thank me later if we get out of here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>If it wasn't for you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx5_borland_second_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>Nothing to talk about. Let's go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_00">
        <text>Looks like we got a problem.</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>What kind of problem?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>There's no power. That's why the lift's not working.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>There's got to be a backup generator somewhere. You stay here, I'll see if I can find it and get it running. Or maybe it's just the breaker that cut the power to the lift. I'll look around, see what I can find.  Keep in touch, let me know when the lift's running.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>Be careful.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_third_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>Mm-hmm.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>You made it, damn it. You're a lively one.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_11">
        <text>What the fuck? I almost got eaten on the way. Did you find the Oakleys?</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>There's no Oakleysman. But the Monolith is. There's an ambush up ahead, I can see it on the monitors. There's video cameras all around. There's Monolith. They're heavily armed. Skidan said they're not in the Zone anymore. No, there aren't. Like dogs.</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>Should we break through? Or are we looking for a way around?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>There is no other way. We're already there, I'm gonna open the door for you. Run straight in, the door will close and lock in two seconds. There's some kind of gas inside, be careful. Your suit's got an insulated breathing circuit, so the gas won't hurt you. Unless you get bullet holes in the suit. Then it's a scarecrow! I don't even have a gas mask, my ass. </text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>Open the door, we'll get through.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_5">
        <text>I'm gonna stay with these computers. I need to find a layout of the interior. If there's a silencer for the machine gun, now would be a good time to put it on the barrel.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_6">
        <text>Why don't you cover it up?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_7">
        <text>Gas, I'm telling you. I'll die of gas.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="labx5_borland_fouth_dialog_talking_8">
        <text>All right, I'll be fine on my own.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
