<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="wiz_foma_about_yourself_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_foma_about_yourself_1">
        <text>What the hell for? I've been trampling this earth for a long time, and I know not to let anyone into my pocket or soul.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_0">
        <text>Maybe you've got a job to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_1">
        <text>Of course I do! Look our collectors told me that the mutants pester them, interfere with them to collect artifacts, and so on. Your job is to pacify these mutants, good it is only by your specialty - hunter! As a reward for mopping up, I'll get you a good artifact, you will be useful, you can be sure!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_2">
        <text>All right, I'll do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_22">
        <text>Some other time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_0">
        <text>Who are you, stalker?! How can I ever thank you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_1">
        <text>They call you Serpent, and you must be the Zhekan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_2">
        <text>Yes, but... How do you know me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_3">
        <text>Come on up, when we get outside, you'll understand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_0">
        <text>That's it, finally justice, and I'd forgotten it even existed! Thank you very much, Serpent!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_1">
        <text>You're welcome, I don't think it's worth sticking around for too long, don't you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_2">
        <text>You're right. Let's go back to camp. By the way, I'll get you something at camp. You've earned it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_3">
        <text>All right, let's go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_0">
        <text>I think it's a good time for an attack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_1">
        <text>You're right, I'll call the guys and let's move. You ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_2">
        <text>I'm ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_22">
        <text>Hang on, I'll get something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_0">
        <text>So Zhekan's still alive, that's good, I think we should try to get him out of the bandits, are you with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_1">
        <text>Since I've already unearthed so much, it'd be stupid not to.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_2">
        <text>Glad to hear it, come to me tonight and we'll head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_3">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>Take your henchman.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>Oh! Found it, well done, I hope it wasn't the only one in the hiding place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_2">
        <text>Not only that, there was also an old man's manuscript, from which I managed to find out where to go down to the catacombs. By the way, what's in this case?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_3">
        <text>Snake, I don't pry into your business, do I? Well, neither should you. Thanks for the job, you're free to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_4">
        <text>All right, be my guest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_0">
        <text>I don't mean to insist, but you said something about a fitting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_1">
        <text>Yes-yes! I remember, here, this is a very good and rare armour, it used to belong to one of the now defunct groups called Clear Sky, maybe you've heard something about them, well, this armour Novikov made himself, as he said: we'll bind everything with blue duct tape - that's it! Take care of him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_2">
        <text>Thank you very much, Rusty. I thought it would be a gun, but here's armour from a group that doesn't exist anymore. Thanks again!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_0">
        <text>Before you die, I want to know what you did to Zhekan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_1">
        <text>It's interesting... an infiltrator, was able to dig up more information than the people who were directly next to him, I didn't expect...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_10">
        <text>So you're also sniffing around with bandits... Scum! Okay, I'll see you in the afterlife...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_2">
        <text>Look, I don't care about you, I'm only interested in information about Zhekan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_3">
        <text>I'm afraid it's too late...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_4">
        <text>Are you sure? You can die quickly, or you can die for a long time, I can arrange that!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_5">
        <text>Are you that bloodthirsty? I don't think so...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_6">
        <text>Shall we test it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_7">
        <text>Fuck it, I'll tell you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_8">
        <text>Just like that...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_9">
        <text>Zhekan is still alive, he's a prisoner of bandits from the village, they're holding him in the cellar, that's all I know. It's not certain he's still alive...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_0">
        <text>Hello, tell me about a stalker called Nazar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_1">
        <text>Nazar? I can't tell you anything, he was an experienced stalker, a collector from God, so to speak. Why do you ask?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_2">
        <text>Just found his body, and a PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_3">
        <text>So? I still can't understand what you want!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_4">
        <text>Nothing, I'm just wondering, how long have you been working with the blues?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_5">
        <text>What do you mean? I don't work with anybody! Are you drunk or something?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_6">
        <text>You don't work? All right, well...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_0">
        <text>Serpent, I told the guys about Kosta's business, the guys are in solidarity with me and also want blood vengeance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_1">
        <text>All right, let's just do it outside the camp and before we kill him, I'll interrogate him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_2">
        <text>All right, shall we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_3">
        <text>Yeah, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_0">
        <text>Rusty, here's the thing...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_1">
        <text>Well? Tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_10">
        <text>What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_11">
        <text>What a bitch! He just sold him out... I don't think Nazar's the first to be tipped off by him, by the way, you didn't catch our leader, Zhekan, did you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_12">
        <text>No, why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_13">
        <text>Zhekan went on a raid with Kosta a week ago, but didn't come back. Our friend Kosta said that he disappeared, but before his disappearance he appointed him as his deputy, and we, of course, were suspicious about it all, but this is the Zone, and stuff happens here, so we trusted Kosta. So I think he killed Zhekan to take his place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_14">
        <text>So what do we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_15">
        <text>I think an exemplary execution is the best solution.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_16">
        <text>I agree, but before we do that, I think it's a good idea to find out what he did to Zekan and where to find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_17">
        <text>All right, I'll call you in a couple of hours. I'll get the word out to the boys, so there's no confusion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_18">
        <text>I'll be waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_2">
        <text>Anyway, remember you asked me to find out what the fuck the blues were doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_3">
        <text>Well, I remember, don't I? Yeah, and you already found out. You said they were looking for some art.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_4">
        <text>Looking for... Artifact is nothing compared to what I've been digging up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_5">
        <text>What is it? Just tell me!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_6">
        <text>When I was tracking the blues, I took out their messenger, he had a PDA, I didn't pay much attention to it at first, so when I told you about it, I went to Ivanych and asked him to unlock the PDA. Ivanych - unlocked, and the PDA was a clue, which revealed that Kosta somehow connected with the blues, so I decided to wait until nightfall and went to their camp, I thought they had already left, but they were waiting for me. They were waiting for me because they were warned by Kosta. I'll text you the confirmation on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_7">
        <text>Costa? Mercenaries? Hell, I could see he wasn't very talkative about mercenaries, but to work with them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_8">
        <text>You read what I just dropped on you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_9">
        <text>[Reads the archive of messages from Crooked's PDA]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_about_yourself_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_about_yourself_1">
        <text>I'm, as you young ones say, an old sovok. Originally from the Donetsk region, I studied, went to the city as a young professional to join a factory and work there all my life. I am an engineer myself. I came here by chance, a job came up and I got cheated on my salary... I met a guy on the Big Earth and he told me about the Zone, saying that I could make good money here, so I came. I've seen a lot of different things here, but I decided to settle down and repair things for the guys, thanks to my education and my hands.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_done_0">
        <text>I got a message from you, did you manage to open it up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_done_1">
        <text>Why not? Here is the device, I'm a cultured technician, so all the information is at your disposal - go for it!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_0">
        <text>Ivanovich, I've got a case for you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_1">
        <text>Business? Spit it out if you're not kidding.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_2">
        <text>I need to unlock a PDA, can you help me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_3">
        <text>I'll help, not for free, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_4">
        <text>How much?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_5">
        <text>Give me one and a half and we'll part like ships at sea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_6">
        <text>Agreed, here's the PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_66">
        <text>I don't have that kind of money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_7">
        <text>Good! I'll contact you as soon as I'm done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_77">
        <text>As soon as I'm done, then come over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_done_0">
        <text>These are the cards you were talking about.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_done_1">
        <text>Good work, Serpent! Here's the reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_0">
        <text>So, how are you feeling after your captivity?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_1">
        <text>I heard from the bandits that there's a fallen helicopter in the vicinity and there's a map of the area with all sorts of markings on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_2">
        <text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_3">
        <text>I want you to find that very helicopter and get those very maps out of it, and I'll pay good money for them. You should be looking for it near the transport tunnel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_4">
        <text>All right, I'll try to find it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_44">
        <text>I'm sorry, but I got a lot on my plate...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_0">
        <text>Got your message, what's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_1">
        <text>Here's the thing... They found the old man, not quite alive...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_2">
        <text>Fucking hell! Now what?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_3">
        <text>Wait a minute! His PDA had information about a cache, here are the coordinates, maybe there's something in there that'll help you, but I'm gonna need one piece of equipment from that cache, and when you find the cache, you'll know what it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_4">
        <text>You got a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_0">
        <text>What can you tell me about this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_1">
        <text>Well listen: we are on the territory of former research institute, but according to some information, the research institute was here before Chernobyl accident, but after the accident the military men settled down here, what were they doing here? Yes, I don't know ... But the fact of their presence here is present, if you go out in the street you can see different equipment.  To the northeast of us, there is an area of some abandoned hangars, something like a repair depot or something like that, or maybe just a bus station, but there is one detail: in one of the hangars, there is a descent to the underground, but no one knows what's in that underground! The doors because nobody's cracked them yet. A little beyond those hangars is an old military base, but the area is closed and there are a lot of anomalies, so I would not advise going there. To the east of us, there's a transport tunnel, our guys guard there, but bandits raid quite often. Further on, there is an old checkpoint where bandits are already settling in - they shoot or gop-stop everybody and everybody...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_2">
        <text>Interesting, though!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_3">
        <text>Wait a minute! That's not all! To the south-west there's an old village where the Sooner brethren live; next to the village are a couple of anomalous clusters; then to the southeast, there's a little campground of the Sooner brethren and a road, but it's strewn with anomalies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_4">
        <text>Wait, so there's no way out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_5">
        <text>What do you mean there's no way out? There is, you came here! That's why we are not getting desperate, our guides know about the paths that we ourselves would never be able to find. There you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_0">
        <text>What's your story?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_1">
        <text>It's been a long time since I was asked that... It's not even customary. Yes, well, particularly there's nothing to tell, and the usual stalker like all here, began as everyone else with Sidorovich orders on Cordon, then stuck to a group of loners who were engaged in search of artifacts on demand, they have so to speak learned me and then began to deal with themselves, but I quickly got tired of it. I have no problems on the Big Earth, but I came to the Zone solely out of interest in what was going on, and there was something here that kept me from getting bored.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_2">
        <text>How did you get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_3">
        <text>It's simple, a group of stalkers led by Zhekan decided to explore new places, so I joined the group and here we are. Zhekan really was strange, but a great leader, but where is he now and will be back or not know ... He even before leaving, appointed me as his deputy and moved to raid, but why and for how long, no one ever found out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_0">
        <text>Oh, here's the weasel who killed our guy. What the fuck are you doing here?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_1">
        <text>[Silence]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_2">
        <text>Are you playing the silent game? The bazaar is a train station! Me and my boys don't have to hurry yet, so we'll wait for you to get your tongue out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_3">
        <text>[Silence]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_0">
        <text>Serpent? What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_1">
        <text>I'm just getting a tan. What about you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_2">
        <text>Us? Same as always! We got the order to fix it, and we got a lead on the blue's camp.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_3">
        <text>All right, all right, Lieutenant, I'll go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_0">
        <text>Lieutenant, I have a question for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_1">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_2">
        <text>You didn't happen to find any keys with the blues' comrades, did you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_3">
        <text>I had one, I'm not giving it away...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_4">
        <text>I don't have much money, I don't have any gear, as you can see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_5">
        <text>Calm down... I don't need any of it. I'm only interested in one thing: Why were you locked up with the blues? Snake, I've known you for a long time, so there's no need to twist and tell tales.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_6">
        <text>On a tip from a stalker - Rusty, who was concerned about the appearance of blues in these parts, so he asked me to sniff out more information. So I sniffed out that the blues had some connection to the local Neutral leader, I learned about it from the PDA of one of these ... So the blues have ordered some rare artifact, they decided not to look for it themselves, they decided to hire a local collector. The collector found the artifact, but instead of paying for it, they just killed him, and since everyone in the camp is silent about the collector, it means that the case is hushed up - the leader. So I decided to collect more evidence to nail the rat to the wall, but instead of collecting evidence, I got stunned... I think they were waiting for me...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_7">
        <text>You think right! Apparently they were warned, which means someone else didn't want you sniffing around here, by the way, there was some correspondence in blue's PDA, you might be interested in it, I dropped the message archive to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_8">
        <text>Thank you Lieutenant, goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_0">
        <text>Lieutenant, got a question for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_1">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_2">
        <text>You didn't find any keys with the blue guys, did you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_3">
        <text>I had one, I'm not giving it away...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_4">
        <text>I don't have much money, I don't have any gear, as you can see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_5">
        <text>Calm down... I don't need any of it. I'm only interested in one thing: Why were you locked up with the blues? Snake, I've known you for a long time, so there's no need to twist and tell tales.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_6">
        <text>Blue here apparently bought the local head of the neutrals, he in turn leaked them an experienced collector of artifacts - Nazar. Stalker this order found some rare art, which in turn, someone ordered the blues, instead of payment for the discovery, stalker killed, so to speak ends in water, I found the body of Nazar and decided to collect more evidence of blue work with the local chapter neutrals. Came here at night, and instead of searching, I just got fucked over the head. So there you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_7">
        <text>Yeah... Sad to hear that neutrals are selling out their own... Okay, here's the key and also Snake, there was one correspondence in Blue's PDA, probably with the leader of these very neutrals, so I already threw you an archive of these messages.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_8">
        <text>Thank you, Lieutenant, I'll never forget it!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_0">
        <text>I think you'll be interested in...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1">
        <text>What do you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_11">
        <text>Nazar's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_111">
        <text>I'm not even gonna ask where you got it. I'll give you 1500 grand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1111">
        <text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_11112">
        <text>May you rest in peace, Nazar...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_12">
        <text>PDA of the mercenary envoy. Found it near the military base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_121">
        <text>I'll give you 1,000 for him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1211">
        <text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_12112">
        <text>Very interesting... Good work, hunter!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_13">
        <text>The laptop from the mercenary camp.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_131">
        <text>I'll give you 2,000 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1311">
        <text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_13112">
        <text>That's it! Interesting... Very interesting!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_14">
        <text>Rezac's stalker PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_141">
        <text>I'll offer 500 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1411">
        <text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_14112">
        <text>As I suspected, nothing of interest...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_rjaviu_about_yourself_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_rjaviu_about_yourself_1">
        <text>Honestly, I don't even know what to say... An ordinary stalker, not a veteran, but not a fixer either, came to the Zone a few years ago, don't know anyone in particular. So there's that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_0">
        <text>Mutant's dead, tell me what you know about the Bison group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_1">
        <text>Been here, didn't stay long though. They bought some grub and some ammo and left. Heard from the main man that they're going to the tunnel, so look for them there. That's all I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_2">
        <text>Yeah... Not much, but thanks for that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_0">
        <text>You wanted something, didn't you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_1">
        <text>Yes, I did! I don't want to beat around the bush, I want information about the catacombs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_2">
        <text>What catacombs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_3">
        <text>Shit... Anyway, I went to the tunnel you told me about. I couldn't find the group there, but I did find traces of their presence and a PDA of one of the group members. Well, the PDA mentions some catacombs that lead the group somewhere, alas more information could not get. That's why I came to you for help again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_4">
        <text>Interesting... I've heard of catacombs, but I thought they were just stories. As it turns out, they're not stories. I can't help you with the catacombs themselves, but there's an old man who hangs around the bar sometimes, and he must know what catacombs are and where they lead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_5">
        <text>Great, where do I find him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_6">
        <text>What I don't know, I don't know. But I can tell you when he shows up again, for a reason, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_7">
        <text>Of course, what do you want in return?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_8">
        <text>Tell you what, I don't have anything worth doing yet to close the payment. So here's what I'm suggesting: When the case comes up, you do it. Deal? By the way, if you don't want to wait for a message from me, talk to the guys, maybe they'll throw you a job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_9">
        <text>Deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_0">
        <text>Hunter? Interesting! Very interesting... What are you standing up for? Tell me why you're here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_1">
        <text>How do you know I'm a hunter? Doesn't matter! Costa told me to talk to you about Bison's band, what can you tell me about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_2">
        <text>About the Bison group? Not much, but you do realize there's a price to pay for information, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_3">
        <text>I know, how much?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_4">
        <text>No, no, no, you don't understand, I'm not interested in money, I have a more productive offer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_5">
        <text>I'm listening...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_6">
        <text>There's a swamp not far from here, and there's a creature there that's been keeping our guys from collecting artifacts from the swamp. It's a business that's very much in your line of work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_7">
        <text>Let's get this straight! I kill the creature, you tell me everything you know about the Bison group, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_8">
        <text>Right, look, this is where the creature is, come back when you're done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_9">
        <text>Okay, stand by.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_0">
        <text>New faces? Interesting! Tell me, who is it? What are you here for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_1">
        <text>I'm the hunter, I'm called Snake and I'm on a case. Anyway, I'm looking for a group of stalkers led by Bison, according to my information, they were supposed to come to your place. What can you tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_2">
        <text>Well, what a hunter is Snake, frankly speaking... I can't tell you anything. You'd better go to Thomas, he's a local merchant, if your fellows have been here, they've been in touch with him. By the way, they call me Kostya, if you need me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_3">
        <text>Thanks, I'll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_0">
        <text>Hey, stalker! I know who you are!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_1">
        <text>Man, you got the wrong guy. I've never been here before. You don't know me...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_2">
        <text>Oh, no! I do! You're a hunter - Snake, if memory serves. Didn't you and Gonta's group, around the Zaton, clear out a den of snarks?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_3">
        <text>Well... I did, why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_4">
        <text>I'm just the stalker that you saved, they call me Rusty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_5">
        <text>Oh, I see, well, it's nice to meet you, then. By the way, how long have you been here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_6">
        <text>Not long, it's only the third week, why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_7">
        <text>Hey, have you met any of the guys from Beezon's band or himself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_8">
        <text>Nah, brother, you better go see the leader or the dealer, they must have seen them, if they've been here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_9">
        <text>All right, I'll talk to them. All right, I gotta...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_0">
        <text>What's the deal with the blues?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_1">
        <text>Nothing supernatural, they were hired in search of a rare artifact, what kind of artifact, I couldn't find out. What I did find out is that they're about to leave. So you don't have to worry anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_2">
        <text>That's all you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_3">
        <text>They didn't look for the artifact themselves, they hired some stalker, he found the artifact, and they smacked him. And the leader of the blues, they call him Krivoy, that's it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_4">
        <text>Not much, but let's hope they bail. Anyway, I'll try to get some info on the blue leader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_5">
        <text>Try it, but something tells me it's a group of one order, people hired, they don't know each other, they'll go their separate ways and that's the end of it. What about my reward, by the way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_6">
        <text>Who knows... Here's your reward, I think that's more than enough!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_0">
        <text>There you are, do you want to make some extra money?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_1">
        <text>Of course, tell me, what do you have to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_2">
        <text>Look, our guys came back from a raid recently and said they saw a small group of mercenaries. They were hanging around near the old military base. The guys waited and saw the blues quietly break through the gate and disappear into the territory. Your job is to find out what the hell the blues are doing here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_3">
        <text>The blues? They are everywhere, they have contracts all over the Zone, and the fact that they came here, no wonder! By the way, did you tell Kostya about the blues? And why do you need to know what the blues are doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_4">
        <text>I did, but he shrugged his shoulders and said it was none of your business, and that it was no good to pry into the blues' affairs at all. I wouldn't meddle, but it's the very presence of blues near our camp that bothers me. So?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_5">
        <text>Kosta's right, we shouldn't pry into the blue's business, but on the other hand... Well, fuck it, I hope the fee will be decent.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_6">
        <text>I won't hurt you with the reward, you can be sure of that!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_7">
        <text>I hope so... Because I'll be risking my ass...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_0">
        <text>Ivanovich, I'm talking about the scanner and the lockpick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_1">
        <text>What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_2">
        <text>The lockpick is dead, he must have been killed by mutants, and the scanner was with him, I installed it in the place you mentioned.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_3">
        <text>Sorry about the stalker, but it's the Zone, nobody's safe from anything...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_4">
        <text>I agree, do you have any other work to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_5">
        <text>Yeah, I do, come back later, I'm busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_6">
        <text>All right, take care.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_0">
        <text>Godspeed, do you have a job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_1">
        <text>Thank you! A job? There's always work, it all depends on what you're good at...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_2">
        <text>What can I do? I've had experience working with scientist technicians, helping them set up equipment and measure anomalous fields. I'm also good at hunting wildlife.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_3">
        <text>Oh, yeah? Hunting doesn't interest me, but experience with scientists is good enough for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_4">
        <text>Well... Don't keep me in suspense, what's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_5">
        <text>Well, I've been working with some scientists for a couple of months, they give me the equipment, I'll put scanners there or find people to study some complexes, so to say the foreman, and it's a lot of money for me and the people. So, about scanners, I've sent one stalker to install the scanner, but I've heard nothing from him for a long time, and last time he got in touch near that anomaly, where the scanner shall be installed. Something tells me that he's dead, but the work anyhow need to do, so find him and take away his scanner, the point where you install the scanner, I'll also mark you, do not worry about the reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_6">
        <text>I hear you, I'm on my way then.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
