<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_0">
        <text>Tell me something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_1">
        <text>So, one time, I was with my team in the Garbage, and we were inspecting an old hangar. Everything was covered in dust and cobwebs. The place looked like shit. Suddenly, our detectors stopped working; our PDAs couldn't even show our own position. We made our usual formation: Sanyok in the front with us covering his back. Everything was going smoothly until all of a sudden, a bunch of metal beams fell from the roof. Sanyok managed to dodge them by some miracle. He fell, rolled back, and without even standing back up, started firing. The others were also scared shitless, and those idiots started shooting everywhere. Then Sanyok started yelling something about a creature sitting in the corner. There was nothing there when I looked, though.\n \nEither way, it was clear that our operation was fucked. What happened after that was a total mess. Everyone panicked, shooting at nothing thinking they saw something. Two of them were really unlucky. One guy was walking on what appeared to be flat ground until he disappeared down a dark hole. The other guy was crushed by a heavy metal door; his spine was turned into mush. After a while, we finally got our shit together, turned on our psy-protection systems and tossed a smoke grenade towards every corner in hopes of luring the creature to the center. Well, it turned out this beast could fly, and while all of us were losing our shit on the ground, that bitch was just sitting up there watching us.\n \nBy the time we figured it out, it was too late. The beast knocked loose a few more steel beams from the scaffolding and splattered four of our guys. In the meantime, Sanyok heard ruffling in the rafters and fired in its direction without a second thought… Incredible reflexes. The beast screeched, and we started shooting where Sanyok landed his shot, bringing the bitch to the ground. Its bloodcurdling screeches left my ears ringing. Even after we ran out of ammo, we kept beating the shit out of the creature with anything we could find while Sanyok finished off the creature with his knife. When we were done, the beast laid splattered all over the floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_10">
        <text>That's one hell of a story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_11">
        <text>You wanna know what I think? Or rather what I'm guessing? Maybe… Maybe all of this—everything around us—is just an experiment on humanity done by aliens. It kind of makes sense when you think about it… more than any of the other rumors people spread about this place. You know what's interesting? Why did the Zone emerge here out of all places? If this place was just some military experiment, then why isn't it better guarded and hidden? Are they checking which artifacts we want the most? What if these artifacts are actually bombs? Think about it: these artifacts are popping up in laboratories all over the world and in the hands of rich people. That would be cool, if some rich asshole would buy an artifact just to have it explode in his face. Ha ha ha!… Anyways, who knows what's really going on? The only people who really know are those who made it past the Red Forest. Yeah… They might know. Too bad they can't say anything. All they do is moan and drool all day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_12">
        <text>Yeah. Anything is possible here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_13">
        <text>We used to have this idiot with us. He was the laziest fuck to ever make it into the Zone. Whenever it was break time, he was the first one near the campfire, but when shit was about to go down, he couldn't be bothered to help out. Eventually, his laziness got him killed. His team spotted a controller, and he couldn't be bothered to get up from the warm campfire to save his own ass. The controller fried up his brains. People forget that this is the Zone, and you can't drop your guard here. Not even for a second. You need to pay attention to every noise, no matter how insignificant you think it is. You need to keep your guns locked and loaded and your grenades ready to go.\n \nAs for controllers, that's a different story altogether. They'll kill you before you even realize it. If you ever see a controller, even in the distance, get to cover immediately. They need to see you in order for them to start frying your brain, and even when they see you, they need a few seconds to concentrate. Once you're in cover, lay down some suppressive fire and throw a few grenades to hold back the controller and distract him. While it's busy figuring where all of that lead just came from, you run… Run as fast and as far away as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_14">
        <text>Thanks for the story. I'll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_15">
        <text>Yeah, somebody told me about something the other day and I can't remember what… Oh, yeah! Even though there's plenty of interesting stuff in the Zone—things that would make any scientist go crazy—foreign scientists won't go anywhere near the Zone. There are several reasons for it: first, why go yourself when you can hire a stalker for a small sum to do your dirty work for you? Second, a few years ago, there was actually this huge expedition from abroad that ended really badly… What, you haven't heard about it? That's strange…\n \nBack when it happened, everybody in the Zone was talking about it. The expedition had thirty scientists from all over the world come here. They all had a shitload of money and the best gear out there. They had a special military unit escorting them, mind you. These weren't just regular grunts. I'm talking elite soldiers. They also hired some of our guides—three very experienced stalkers—to guide the way, and they took a BTR just for the hell of it. When they got back a week later, that BTR was wrecked to shit. It turned out the expedition was ambushed by bandit raiders who killed almost everyone from that expedition save for three people, two of our guides, and one foreign scientist. That same scientist was severely traumatized, and he had to be hospitalized in a mental institution. Right now, he's writing some kind of book about the Zone, and as for our guys, well, they just shrugged it off. Though, to be honest, I think they went through some trauma as well. One guy went off to the Red Forest and disappeared, and as for the other one, well, he just left the Zone. You're probably wondering how such a force could be taken down by a just a bandit ambush. That's not the whole story, though.\n \nHave you heard anything about City 32? They say that's where the people from the expedition started to lose their mind. Some kind of mass hysteria spread from person to person, and everyone started losing their shit at the same time. Some even started scratching their throats out while others bashed their head on the wall. A few just outright shot themselves in the head. To make matters worse, a flock of large mutants showed up at the same time. Anyone who hadn't yet lost their mind fled to nearby houses and barricaded themselves in. Can you imagine the situation? It's midnight and pitch black outside, everyone loses their minds, and at the same time, a flock of powerful mutants is about to have you for dinner. Those who didn't lose their sanity spent the entire night locked in abandoned houses, waiting for morning to come.\n \nAnd when the morning finally came, they tried to retreat. Some died in anomalies on the way back, and the rest encountered those bandits… I already told you how that ended up. Since then, no foreign scientists have dared to set foot in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_16">
        <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_17">
        <text>So I was in the Dark Valley once, and I wanted to scan the area from somewhere high. I found a place where I could climb up: a chimney in a boiler station. So I entered the station, looked around, and the coast was clear. I found the chimney and started climbing up; there was already a ladder inside of it, and it was sturdy and comfortable, so climbing was easy. When I got to the top, I slowly lifted myself on top of the chimney to get a better look. And man, what a beautiful view… It felt like the entire Dark Valley was in my hands. I took out my binoculars and started scanning the area. Everything seemed clear.\n \nJust as I was about to climb back down, it occurred to me that I should check what was happening beneath my feet. So I looked down around the station, and man, what do I see? A burer! Good thing I never went back down; I would've been dead for sure. Luckily for me, he didn't see me yet, or I wouldn't be here to tell you the tale. I wanted to snipe him with my AK, but the chimney I climbed up from was way too thin, and the AK was stuck on my back. As for trying to hit him with my Makarov, that was almost impossible. Plus, if I were to miss—and I *would* miss—the burer would've noticed me right away and killed me. So I was stuck there, thinking of what to do while the burer was messing around in the station, throwing some metal garbage around. This went on for about a minute until he froze in place, like he was listening in on something. Then the garbage started to move on its own, and the burer jumped back and put his hands to his head in a very awkward position. Suddenly, all the metal scrap in the building flew right into the burer, burying him underneath. I thought to myself, “I'm finally saved! That fucker is dead!”\n \nBut no… That pile of trash was only still for a few seconds before it started to move again. Eventually, the crap started to fly around in the air, and then it flew into a nearby wall, smashing it with immense force. Then the burer entered a different building, and I thought, “It's time to get the fuck out of here.” Just as started climbing down, I noticed the smell of smoke and started feeling intense heat. I look below me, and what do I see?… There's a fire inside the fucking chimney! I was starting to suffocate, so I climbed on top of the chimney, where I could at least get some air. Mind you, the smoke was still irritating my eyes. Good thing I always carry forty meter paracord with me, because I knew the only way out was to rappel down the chimney from the outside. I made a knot at the chimney and tied the rope around my waist and legs and slowly started to rappel down. The only thing on my mind was: “Please don't rip.” The rope was cutting into my hands as I made my way down, but it didn't rip. However, just as Murphy's law predicts, the rope was five meters too short, and I had no choice but to cut myself free and fall the rest of the way down. Thankfully, I didn't break anything, but I got torn up bad and busted up my right leg. I thought I ripped a tendon or something. I ran out of there as fast I could despite my leg hurting. Hell, I could've have won a gold medal with that speed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_18">
        <text>Damn. That's intense.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_19">
        <text>Sorry, merc. I'm all out of stories.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_2">
        <text>Interesting story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_20">
        <text>Come back another time. Perhaps I'll have something more interesting to tell you then…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_3">
        <text>Have you heard about Guide? The very first true stalker. He was the one who originally broke into the Zone, and he's still alive. People say he can take you to any place. You just need to name it. Now, finding him's a bit tricky; ain't no flyers around with his address… And he won't go with just anybody, either. From what I hear, he charges quite a bit. But if you find him and have enough cash, you can bet he'll take you where you need to go. Now that's someone I'd like to have a chat with. You can bet he's been beyond the Red Forest…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_4">
        <text>Interesting information. Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_5">
        <text>They say there's this one gang… People call them Shamans or Druids. It's said they don't use any electronic equipment at all; they want to stay close to the nature and stuff… Well, their reason for that is that the Zone reacts stronger to electronics. To all these “electromagnetic emissions” or something… They say it attracts monsters. Basically, they believe the Zone is like a living being, you know. Like, it's no good going into it with all these gadgets. If you're right in your mind, you'll get by fine without 'em. Doesn't stop them from carrying assault rifles, though… Guess the old teeth and nails aren't up to the task, eh? But then again, you don't hear a lot of stories about one of them kicking the bucket. Well, at least no more than us… So, who knows. Maybe they're on the right track there… They seem to be coming from the Belarusian side, though… I'd like to have a look at them one day and check out their pockets for some artifacts…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_6">
        <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_7">
        <text>Have you heard anything about the secret laboratories deep in the Zone? Some say they're still active. Nobody knows how the hell those labs are still operational, considering the fact that people can't survive there due to a lack of resources.\n \nHere's a theory: what if it's not people working there, but ghosts? I talked to this one guy. He hadn't been in the laboratory himself, but he did manage to catch some signals on his radio when he was in Yantar. He overheard a conversation about some kind of laboratory. Another guy swore that he saw some kind of transparent figure when he was in the Red Forest. It had some kind of upgraded SEVA suit, and it told him to get out of there and that he was interrupting some kind of important project, although it was awfully close to the Scorcher, so the whole thing could have been a hallucination for all we know… On the other hand, there are different kinds of mutations. Maybe the Zone turned those lab workers into something else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_8">
        <text>No idea. Anything is possible in this hellhole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_9">
        <text>Merc, you know anything about a group called “Interception”? It's a highly skilled special ops unit that goes on missions deep inside the Zone. They're nothing like the dipshits we have here in the Cordon; these are *real* pros. Not only do they go into the most dangerous places inside the Zone, but they stay there for months. They have a few hidden bases throughout the Zone, and they have plenty of stashes to boot. They also get supply drops via helicopter whenever they need it. Their commander's name is Gromov. I'm sure it's just a fake name.\n \nWhat, you don't believe me?! Belly caught their frequency once, though he turned it off immediately and ran away. This is top secret info, after all, and he could have been shot for just listening in on it. Man… Their pay, though. It's something else. If I had a third—no, a tenth—of their pay, I could just retire somewhere in Sochi. They even have some kind of special device that can locate mutants from afar, no matter what kind. Some say that they even travel into the center of the Zone while others say they've learned how to tame mutants. There are also rumors that these guys aren't military but rather highly gifted stalkers who signed a contract with the government. Duty knows all about those assholes, but they won't talk about them… They say it's all rumors. But trust me, they know better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_0">
        <text>Don't move! Password, now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_1">
        <text>Swordfish. You might want take your finger off that trigger before you hurt yourself, soldier.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_10">
        <text>Almost. Valerian's got a friend by the name of Belly. If he dies, we won't be disappointed, and you'll receive an additional bonus for dealing with him. After you complete the mission, contact me; I'll show you where to meet me again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_11">
        <text>Understood. I'm going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_2">
        <text>You're right. I take it you're Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_3">
        <text>Yep. Let's get straight to the point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_4">
        <text>Let us. You probably know about the stalker base that's by the railroad embankment. Well, we need to get rid of their leader—for good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_5">
        <text>Can't you take him out yourself? I'd think all these soldiers could take on a stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_6">
        <text>We have our reasons. The thing is, we can't kill every stalker in that base. That'll attract too much attention. We need someone to eliminate Valerian without alerting anyone else. After that, the stalker base will fall apart on its own. I don't care how you take him out as long as you do it quickly. This has to been done in no longer than three days.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_7">
        <text>What's the pay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_8">
        <text>Oh, don't worry about that. The pay is good. You'll get it once you finish the job—we don't pay in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_9">
        <text>Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_0">
        <text>Someone must've heard the gunfire… They probably told their men that they were going to inspect the area around this vehicle station. This could cause some serious problems… What are your orders, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_1">
        <text>Don't get too worked up, Raven; these aren't Wolf's people. We already informed the rookie village about our arrival. We should find out who sent those men here. And also: get rid of the bodies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_2">
        <text>I'll figure out what to do with them. Anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_3">
        <text>We need to have a word with Wolf and his brother and see if they know anything about this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_4">
        <text>Leave it to me. I'll talk to the stalkers and see what they know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_5">
        <text>I'm with you. I need to talk to the old nut Sidorovich and make sure he doesn't find out that his contract is just a cover-up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_0">
        <text>Yeah? What's so important? I told you people I was going to sleep and that you shouldn't wake me…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_1">
        <text>Get up, greenhorn. There's a job waiting for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_10">
        <text>Good plan. I'm in. But how am I supposed to gain their trust?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_11">
        <text>Do I have to babysit you? I don't care how you do it as long as it gets done. This conversation is over. After you deal with Valerian, get out of there and head to the bus station near the grain elevator. Got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_12">
        <text>Yes, Beast! I got it. I won't let you down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_13">
        <text>I'm counting on you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_2">
        <text>Oh, is that you, Beast? I didn't recognize you for a second. What's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_3">
        <text>Gaining entry into that free stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_4">
        <text>Okay. I can do that. But what else?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_5">
        <text>Interrupt me again and you'll get a bullet to the face. So, listen: once you're there, you need to assassinate the leader. His name is Valerian.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_6">
        <text>What a “job”… Do I look like I'm suicidal? The stalkers will kill me on the spot if I try anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_7">
        <text>Forgot about your debt already?! Don't you worry: no one's going to hurt you if you do everything right. You wanted to join the Syndicate, remember? This is your chance—the chance to prove you're not a lazy piece of shit, but a real soldier. What's more is that you'll finally pay off your debts and start earning some money. Sounds like a good deal, doesn't it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_8">
        <text>Sounds good. How am I supposed to kill Valerian, though?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_9">
        <text>I'll tell you how. It's not too hard to pull off: you just have to gain the trust of the stalkers at the loner base. The rest is a cakewalk. At night, once Valerian goes to sleep, you'll sneak into his chamber when no one's looking and slit his throat. In the morning, you'll be long gone, and the stalkers will have no clue about who did it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_0">
        <text>Hey, merc. I take it you lead the group at the vehicle station? Thanks for saving us from the bandits. You guys are real pros.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_1">
        <text>I was told that you want to join the Syndicate. Is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_2">
        <text>Yessir. I'm tired of working my ass off for pocket change. I want to make some real money…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_3">
        <text>Very well. First, you have to do a job for me. A test of loyalty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_4">
        <text>What do I need to do? I'm ready for anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_5">
        <text>I need you to make the mechanic leave his workshop. Distract him; lead him away. It doesn't matter how. Just get it done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_6">
        <text>Hmm… I need to think. There might be one way, although he'll only be gone for a short while. I could take him to the bar and get drunk with him. Won't be the first time I get him under the influence. Will that work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_7">
        <text>Yeah, as long as he empties more bottles than he can handle. Do you have enough cash?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_8">
        <text>Yeah, that won't be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_9">
        <text>All right. Get to it. Make sure he's passed out by nighttime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_0">
        <text>You busy right now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_1">
        <text>Not at the moment. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_10">
        <text>Fine. It's your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_2">
        <text>You need a hired muscle? Don't you have anywhere to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_3">
        <text>Do you need something to drink? I have a spare bottle of vodka that I've been keeping for a special occasion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_4">
        <text>Aren't you tired? Don't you want to take a nap for at least an hour or two? I can ask the bouncer to come guard the workshop while you're gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_5">
        <text>Ain't that a strange question… No. I don't need to go anywhere, and if I did, I'd send someone else to do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_6">
        <text>No, thank you. I don't want any vodka right now. I don't wanna sit here drunk off my ass while there's a special contract waiting to be done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_7">
        <text>Hmm… Why do you care, exactly? No. I don't want to sleep. I've already had eight energy drinks, and I have the whole night ahead to work on a special contract.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_8">
        <text>Whatever. It's your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_9">
        <text>All right. It's your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_0">
        <text>Greetings, mercenary. Did everything go according to plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_1">
        <text>Wait. Where's the lieutenant? Or… Are you the one who ordered the contract?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_2">
        <text>Yes. You've understood everything correctly. I wanted to meet you personally today. So, how did everything go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_3">
        <text>Smooth as butter. Valerian and his friends are dead. Here's the proof.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_4">
        <text>At long last; that bastard got what he deserved. Good work, merc. A real pro. Tell me, do you know Scar? He's one of your men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_5">
        <text>No. Don't know him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_6">
        <text>That's too bad. He was a pro too. It's a shame he disappeared somewhere, but no one knows exactly where. I remember he helped me escape when those dirtbags had me behind bars. That Valerian sure caused a lot of problems; to me, to the stalkers, and to Sidorovich. I nearly ended up court-martialed because of that freak. The brass is up our asses to this day, and secret agents are always sticking their noses in everything. Anyway, enough about that. Here's your payment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_7">
        <text>Pleasure doing business with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_11">
        <text>Hey, merc. Keep it down; we can't let anyone hear about this… Jackal has quite a serious mission for you. Don't screw it up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_12">
        <text>So you're Coordinator?… I thought a secretive person like you would be doing something more serious than guarding a bar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_13">
        <text>Spare me the jokes. You have no idea how hard it was to work undercover: for three weeks, I had to act like a regular security guard just so they would start trusting me. All so I could get the necessary info for you to carry out your contract.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_14">
        <text>All right, all right. I get it. Tell me, then, what Jackal has in store for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_15">
        <text>Okay, so, about a month ago, Sidorovich managed to get his hands on a locked black box that was retrieved from a fallen military helicopter, and someone's willing to pay good money for it. Your mission is to steal the black box. Sidorovich keeps it in his storeroom, located in here. Your main obstacle is Van, the technician. He works by the entrance to the storeroom, and you need to get rid of him to get through. Van always keeps consuming energy drinks, and he barely gets any sleep at all…\n \nOh, and one more thing: keep him alive. His death would attract too much attention. You only need to make sure he's passed out long enough for you to get the black box. Meanwhile, I'll make sure the door to the storeroom “accidentally” opens.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_16">
        <text>All right. If that's everything, I'm going to discuss this mission with my partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_17">
        <text>One more thing: this needs to be done tonight. So hurry up and do what you got to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_18">
        <text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_19">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_2">
        <text>How's our mission going? Got the black box yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_3">
        <text>Yep. Here you go. Wasn't easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_4">
        <text>Never said it would be easy. You did your job well; something the Syndicate will take note of. I'll prepare an alibi for you in case Sidorovich gets suspicious. Also, Jackal called: he said that he has another mission for you. Ordered by the military…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_5">
        <text>What's the mission?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_6">
        <text>I have no idea myself. You'll get all the instructions from the client's representative. And remember—this is very important—in order for the military to identify you as their contractor, you'll need to say the password: “Swordfish.”</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_7">
        <text>Understood. Give me the coordinates to the meeting point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_9">
        <text>I've given you everything I have. Got no more info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_0">
        <text>What's up, Creature?! He he… So, how's Sidorovich's contract going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_1">
        <text>Forgot your commanding officer? Call me “Creature” again and I'll snap your neck like a twig.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_2">
        <text>Yeah, yeah. Sure. You should probably remember what Jackal said about that… You remember, right? Anyway, back to the point: I called you here for a reason. You see, Jackal's tired of waiting for you to carry out his personal contract, so you're no longer in charge here. You, Creature, will drop all your current affairs and start executing his mission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_3">
        <text>Just like that, huh? Who'd he put in charge?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_4">
        <text>Me… for now. But once Sidorovich's contract is done, Jackal will pick a new, permanent commander. I just don't understand, though: why the hell did he pick a clown like you in the first place? You couldn't even secure a good place for your team, not to mention how awfully you deal with all your contracts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_5">
        <text>Me… for now. But once Sidorovich's contract is done, Jackal will pick a new, permanent commander. I just don't understand, though: why the hell did he pick a clown like you in the first place? You couldn't even secure a good place for your team, not to mention how awfully you deal with all your contracts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_6">
        <text>That's none of your business, Obscurant. Now tell Jackal that I'll get his contract done. I'll find Vector and kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_2">
        <text>Hey, merc. What's up? Got Sidorovich's package?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_3">
        <text>Yeah. I have it. Pay me first, then you'll get the package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_4">
        <text>Heh, how mindful of you… Don't worry. I'm not like Sidorovich. When I say that I'm going to pay someone, I pay them. Give me the package, and I'll give you the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_5">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_6">
        <text>Okay. Take your money. Take note of the fact that I've paid you twice the amount Sidorovich asked me to; I have my reasons. I have a feeling I'll be stuck here for a while. Valerian has disappeared somewhere, and it's uncertain whether or not he'll return at all. *Someone* has to keep things in order here.\n \nAnyways, our trader needs your help. He asked us to send you over to him. Go talk to him and see what he wants. He should pay you more than I have.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_7">
        <text>Okay, I'll see what he wants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_9">
        <text>Nice to see you, merc. Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_10">
        <text>One of our squads has been radio silent. I fear something happened to them. I don't have anyone else to send, so will you lend me a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_11">
        <text>Of course I can lend you a hand… for a price.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_12">
        <text>God, you mercenaries. Almost forgot who I'm talking to… We don't have a lot of time to negotiate, Beast, so could you find those men ASAP? We'll discuss the payment after your return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_13">
        <text>I'll hold you to it. Where do I need to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_14">
        <text>They went over the hill, toward one of our outposts, but the problem is, that area was overrun with bandits not long ago. I see your gear is quite advanced, unlike ours, so a few bandits should be a piece of cake. I'll mark the area on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_15">
        <text>Got it. I'll head there now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_17">
        <text>Any news, merc? Did you find the missing squad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_19">
        <text>Get out of here, merc!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc. I take it you received my message? I'm Wolf. To tell you the truth, we're not really happy about your presence in these parts… I know you're here on Sidorovich's contract and all, but let's try and make each others' lives easier. Try not to meddle in anything that doesn't concern you or your group in the Cordon. Understood?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_20">
        <text>I'll get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_21">
        <text>Not yet, I'm on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_23">
        <text>Great job! Zokhan told me the whole story about you saving him and his entire squad. I would never have thought a group of mercenaries would rescue our boys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_24">
        <text>No need to thank me. Just pay me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_25">
        <text>No. I feel I should, since mercs don't care about anyone but themselves, from what I've seen. But you're different. By the way, I contacted Sidorovich; he said he's ready to take you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_26">
        <text>All right. Then I'll go see Sidorovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_27">
        <text>Wait a minute. Here's the payment for a job well done. I don't have a lot of money on me, so here's an artifact as well. Hope it'll be useful. Big thanks to you and your men for the help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_28">
        <text>Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_29">
        <text>Yeah. Thanks again for helping us. You can go about your business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_3">
        <text>Understood. I'm Beast, and this is Raven. Thanks for the warm welcome. How's Sidorovich?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_30">
        <text>All right. I'll go see Sidorovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_32">
        <text>Hello, merc. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_4">
        <text>Sadly, the old fart's doing all right, but you'll have to wait a while. He's got some important business to attend to, and he won't let anyone in his bunker for the time being.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_5">
        <text>When can I see him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_6">
        <text>Not anytime soon, that's for sure. Sidorovich likes to take his sweet time with his business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_7">
        <text>We'll be on our way then. Please inform me when Sidorovich has a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_8">
        <text>Wait, wait. Hold up. Can you help me with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_9">
        <text>Tell me what that “something” is, and then we'll see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_0">
        <text>Listen, Beast: I didn't call you here just to chit-chat. Not everyone's happy about the fact that Jackal assigned you as our acting commander, especially Obscurant. He flew off the handle when he heard the news, and he's not the only one who wanted your position. Just be careful—who knows what goes on in that man's head. He's dangerous and unpredictable.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_1">
        <text>Thanks for your concern, but I can handle it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_2">
        <text>Of course. Just be aware of the general consensus. If Jackal made you the commander, he must've had a specific reason despite a number of individuals disagreeing with his decision. A few well-done contracts will help strengthen your reputation, though.\n \nBy the way, our watch is reporting that an unknown group of stalkers is heading toward the base. They've ignored our warnings not to come here. Either way, it's your call on what to do with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_3">
        <text>All right. I'll talk to them. Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_4">
        <text>No. That's not all: the people here won't be happy about our arrival here. If we want to stay on good terms with the locals, we shouldn't poke our noses into everything. The only place we're welcome in right now is the rookie village, but you already know that.\n \nThat's about it. I won't keep you any longer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_5">
        <text>Thanks for the briefing. I'll go deal with our visitors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_0">
        <text>You the one in charge here? What the hell are you doing in the Cordon? Last time I checked, mercenaries weren't allowed around here, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_1">
        <text>You out of your minds? Get out of here while you can. The less you know, the better—ever heard of that saying?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_2">
        <text>Listen up, merc: either you tell me what the hell you're doing here or things are going to get ugly real quick. This isn't your territory, and you don't make the rules here. If I were you, I'd fess up right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_3">
        <text>Is that a threat? What are you three gonna do against an entire group?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_4">
        <text>We'll slaughter you all if it comes to that. Now tell us what you're doing in the Cordon! You're starting to piss me off…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_5">
        <text>And you've already pissed me off. You bastards shouldn't have poked your noses into our business. This is your last chance to get out of here while you're still breathing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_6">
        <text>Don't tell us what to do, you hired gun piece of shit… You come into our territory, snooping around, making these demands, and breaking the peace—and now you want to start bossing us around, too? This is our territory, and you're the ones who are getting out of here!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_7">
        <text>Too bad. I gave you a chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_0">
        <text>Hey, there, merc! What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_1">
        <text>I could ask you the same thing. What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_10">
        <text>A psy-dog, confound the thing. I'm not giving you the tail—it's mine—but you can keep everything else. Do we have a deal, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_11">
        <text>Deal! Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_2">
        <text>Me? I'm hunting a mutant. I've been tracking this creature all the way from the Agroprom, and no matter what I try, it always manages to slip away. This mutant is dangerous, but I'm on a mission from the scientists at Yantar, and I have to complete it. So anyway, I was sneaking up to it here as it was eating a dead stalker and the second it saw me, it ran away. That poor stalker suffered a terrible death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_3">
        <text>I was looking for that stalker. Did you search his body?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_4">
        <text>I searched him. There wasn't much to take, so I left him alone. I'm just here trying to figure out where that mutant went.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_5">
        <text>When you were searching him, did you run across a flash drive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_6">
        <text>So that's why you're here… Sorry to break it to you, but there was no flash drive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_7">
        <text>But?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_8">
        <text>There's a chance that the mutant swallowed the flash drive along with the guy's leg. Since we don't have any better option, I suggest we start looking for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_9">
        <text>Tell me what type of mutant we're hunting here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_0">
        <text>Phew! That thing sure was strong. I can finally wrap up this mission and go see the scientists. How about you? Did you find your flash drive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_1">
        <text>Yeah. You were right: the mutant ate it. Good thing it didn't start digesting anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_2">
        <text>Ha. It takes a long time to digest a flash drive, so I wouldn't worry about that.\n \nI have to get moving; need to haul my ass all the way to Yantar now. Farewell, merc, and thanks for the help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_3">
        <text>Farewell.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_tick_start_dialog_text">
        <text>Yeah? What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_0">
        <text>Wanna chit-chat a bit, while there aren't any clients to bother you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1">
        <text>Sure. What do you want to know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_11">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_111">
        <text>I've been buying and selling shit since before the fall of the Soviet Union. I was one of those “evil speculators,” and I used to buy and sell serious shit; the real deal… until I got caught and thrown in jail, that is. After that, I made friends with some professional crooks in jail. Started running with them when I got out. Got locked up again for another three years, and when I got out, the Soviet Union was already gone. Once I was free, it felt like a totally different world that I couldn't find my place in. For a long time, all I did was small time work, and I was barely able to scrap together a living… Then the Zone appeared, and I found my place here. Everything here is like the old days, and with my experience in trading, I'm always able to make a good living here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1111">
        <text>Cool. Tell me something else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1112">
        <text>All right. I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_12">
        <text>What do you think about Logopedist?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_121">
        <text>I'll tell you this: Logopedist won't stay on top for long. My gut tells me Koba will make him disappear. Logopedist keeps showing off, and by the looks of it, he thinks he's untouchable. What's worse is, he can't notice the fact that a good chunk of us are getting sick of his shit. Remember, though: I'm telling you this because I trust you, and this conversation needs to stay between us. By the way, if you find anything interesting about either Logopedist or Koba, bring it here. In the end, though, it doesn't matter who's in charge. I'll always be here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_13">
        <text>Tell me about the Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_131">
        <text>Yeah, the guys weren't happy about moving to the Garbage. Back then, nobody even thought about going there. They avoided those radioactive heaps of junk like the piles of shit that they are. That was, until a few stalkers decided to start digging through those mounds of junk, and after that, everyone flocked there. At first there was massive chaos there, but then the bandits came, and they put everyone in their place. I think the Zone should be like any other “Zone,” with a clear hierarchy and firm rule, either instilled by cops or by bandits. Hedgehog here also pays to keep the peace around here, and we get a good cut out of everything. We need to eat too. Maybe one day, I'll visit the Garbage myself. Even though this place isn't half bad, there's some serious cash flowing through the Garbage right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_14">
        <text>What's the latest news in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_141">
        <text>I don't like that expression—“latest news.” If I were you, I would stop asking around before the “latest news” becomes your last. Even though the people here aren't that bad, something really fucked up happened not long ago. A stalker came in here. Scared shitless, pale, and his hands were shaking. He and his friend were running away from a group of poltergeists, and they ran into a flock of rodents. I think the waves of hairless rats were so terrible, the guy got scared and shot his friend a few times in the back. So then the rodents, instead of running after him, decided to just eat his dead bro. After coming back, the guy drank his second bottle then started crying his heart out. “Igor, you gave me your last medkit that one time, and I killed you like the last piece of shit on earth.” He was crying all day long, and when the night came, he hung himself on his belt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_15">
        <text>Yeah, not that interesting, really.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_151">
        <text>Whatever you say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_bar_0">
        <text>Why is this place called “Bar number ninety-two”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_bar_1">
        <text>It's simply because the number ninety-two is uranium in the periodic table, which is usually used in nuclear reactors. I think it was Sidorovich's idea… Hey, you gotta admit it's pretty original. Sidorovich and I should copyright this name and sell it to some big shot from Moscow. He'd then open a bar by the same name with some Zone decorations: a few artifacts, a stuffed rodent, some worn out chimes, and a tooth from a pseudogiant. That place would bring a lot of clients. Sid and I would get rich just by getting a small fraction of the business's earnings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_0">
        <text>So, Shaman, is this enough muscle for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_1">
        <text>Yep, this is enough. Thanks for your help. I'll pay fifteen hundred for each guard, just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_2">
        <text>Yep, this is enough. Thanks for your help. I'll pay twenty-five hundred for each guard, just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_3">
        <text>Yep, this is enough. Thanks for your help. I'll pay thirty-five hundred for each guard, just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_4">
        <text>Pleasure doing business with you. Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_0">
        <text>Sidorovich said that you might have a job for me. What problem do you have?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_1">
        <text>Problem? I don't have any problem. I just need some more muscle in my bar. Can you help with that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_10">
        <text>All right. Twenty-five hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_11">
        <text>All right. Thirty-five hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_12">
        <text>No. I won't lower the rent price.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_13">
        <text>In that case, no deal. Forgot about this conversation; I guess I'll have to make do with what I've got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_14">
        <text>Whatever you say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_15">
        <text>All right. that's an affordable price. We need four people with their own gear, since I have none to spare.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_16">
        <text>Deal. They'll be here shortly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_2">
        <text>I can send a few people your way. For some cash, of course. It'll take some time for them to arrive, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_3">
        <text>All right. Money's not a problem. How much for each head?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_4">
        <text>Fifteen hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_5">
        <text>Twenty-five hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_6">
        <text>Thirty-five hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_7">
        <text>Five thousand for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_8">
        <text>Mmm… That's too much for me, merc. Could lower the price a bit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_9">
        <text>Ugh… Fine. Fifteen hundred for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_zone_1">
        <text>Do I look like one of those eggheads? They're the ones who have the Zone under a microscope. Me? I don't know much about this place. I'm only interested in the money-making here, and that's what I'm doing. Hopefully, after a few years, I'll a buy a piece of land near a lake and a large villa.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_0">
        <text>I'd like to rent a bed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_1">
        <text>No problem. It'll be twenty-five hundred for a day. I don't rent them out for any longer than that. If you need it for an additional period of time, come back later and pay me for the next day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_2">
        <text>All right. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_3">
        <text>Nah, I'll pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_4">
        <text>Excellent! The bedroom is down the hallway you came from, to the left. Your bed is located to the right of the entrance. There's also a footlocker by the bed that you can use for storage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_5">
        <text>Whatever you say. It's your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You've just entered the bar with the biggest assortment of food and drinks in the whole Zone. Welcome, and enjoy your stay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Hey, merc. Fancy a drink?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_0">
        <text>Can you turn off the radio?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_1">
        <text>Yeah, sure I can. Just not for free. A lot of people here stay to listen to the tunes, so you're gonna have to compensate them. Five hundred rubles, to be exact.\n \nI'll turn off the radio once you pay, but keep in mind that once you leave the bar, I'm turning it back on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_2">
        <text>Fine. Here are your five hundred rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_3">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_4">
        <text>Pleasure doing business with you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_5">
        <text>Whatever. Your call.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_0">
        <text>Can you turn on the radio?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_1">
        <text>Changed your mind, eh? No problem! Here you go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_2">
        <text>There. I turned it on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_3">
        <text>Listen to your heart's content. I don't mind. But if you want me turn it off again, you're gonna have to pay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_0">
        <text>I'm here to collect my order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_111">
        <text>Here's your Steppe Eagle. It turned out trickier than I thought. Some kind of pistol buff showed a lot of interest, but I barely snatched it in time. See for yourself: a hand-crafted gun. Components are all adjusted with unmatched precision. Ever wonder what a perfect sniper pistol would look like? Well, this is it. You owe me twenty-eight hundred extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1111">
        <text>Okay, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11111">
        <text>There you go. Nice doing business with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have that much on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11121">
        <text>Okay, I'll hold the gun for you a while. I hope you find the money soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1113">
        <text>I don't want to buy this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11131">
        <text>If you refuse to collect the order, I won't be able to rely on you next time around. I'll have to include the risk estimate in the price and ask for a larger advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_111311">
        <text>Still, I will not be collecting this order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1113111">
        <text>All right, suit yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1114">
        <text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11141">
        <text>Sure, that's up to you. I'll hold the gun for you for a while.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_112">
        <text>Here's your ultra high-accuracy Steppe Eagle. You owe me twenty-eight hundred extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_121">
        <text>Behold the Alpine: a real beauty. You can rest assured this pistol is one of a kind in the whole Zone. A unique model, very limited issue commissioned for a single special unit. It wasn't easy to obtain, I even had to involve one of my overseas associates. An expanded magazine, extra hard steel barrel, receiver made of extra strong polymers. Add the remaining twenty-eight hundred and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_122">
        <text>Here's your Alpine pistol with an expanded magazine. Add the remaining twenty-eight hundred and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_131">
        <text>Lookit, this is March. The pistol belonged to a mercenary called Wolfhound. A compact high-caliber shooter with short blowback and a lightened bolt. Wolfhound was one hundred percent scum, but he knew his weapons; gotta give him that. They say his favorite trick was to blow all four of his victims' limbs off and then his head, before it hit the ground. Anyway, that'll be twenty-eight hundred.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_132">
        <text>Here's your rapid-fire March pistol. You owe me twenty-eight hundred extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_211">
        <text>Here you go: Cutter, a submachine gun. Let me say it right off: don't you mind the appearance. It's a brand new model; not in serial production yet. It's a prototype; fresh from the armory. The designers aimed to make a new-generation close-range weapon: a combination of high caliber, rapid fire, and accuracy. So that'll be eight thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_212">
        <text>Yes, here's Cutter, a rapid-fire submachine gun. That'll be eight thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_221">
        <text>Here's a fine specimen: Carabineer. A true army shotgun. Capable of automatic fire while providing good anti-recoil thanks to a balanced, shock-free system. Add eight thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_222">
        <text>Here's Carabineer, an automatic shotgun. Add eight thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_231">
        <text>I reckon this is just what you need. Eliminator, a latest development. The whole batch was supposed to be shipped to Central Africa, but I got a “sample” as a special favor from friends. An automatic shotgun with a large magazine and an excellent rate of fire. Yours for only eight thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_232">
        <text>Sure. Automatic shotgun Eliminator, with an extended magazine. For eight thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_311">
        <text>Sure. Behold Storm, a submachine gun and grenade launcher in one. This prototype is a modified version of a conventional weapon designed for special units operating in the Zone. Technical innovation at its best from our Slavic brothers… Add sixteen thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_312">
        <text>Sure. Here's Storm, a submachine gun and grenade launcher in one with an extended magazine, for an extra sixteen thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_321">
        <text>Here it is: GP37, a new-generation assault rifle. Accurate, reliable, and convenient with a built-in optical scope. It was previously owned by a UN observer. Their group was sent to the Zone to investigate. However, the situation turned for the worse… Sixteen thousand and the rifle is yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_322">
        <text>Here it is: GP37, a new-generation assault rifle. The price is sixteen thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_331">
        <text>Just a sec. Here's a modular FT-200M rifle, the brainchild of Belgian gunmakers. Accurate, all-purpose, handy for both righties and lefties, comes with an optical scope and a grenade launcher. I got it from some unlucky UN observers… That'll be sixteen thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_332">
        <text>Here's a modular FT-200M rifle. That'll be sixteen thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_411">
        <text>Here's Tide. Based on a silent sniper rifle, it was specifically designed for military units to fight zombies. The Tide sacrifices rate of fire in favor of stopping power, allowing the sniper to pick off zombies one by one without disclosing his location. However, it then became clear that stalkers alone would be enough to stop zombies at the Barrier, so the rifle never reached mass production. This baby's yours for an extra sixteen thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_412">
        <text>Here's Tide, a silent sniper rifle with increased stopping power. Add an extra sixteen thousand and enjoy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_421">
        <text>Here. This is an SVU2-A, a short sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire. I bought it off Mac, the legendary Freedom guard. He swore there are no others like it in the whole Zone. It's an exclusive item, at least in these parts. It'll be sixteen thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_422">
        <text>Yeah. SVU2-A, a short sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire. It'll be sixteen thousand extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_431">
        <text>Sure, just look at the Lynx here. Hand-crafted by a local expert. He's deceased now, so there won't be any copies. It looks just like any other rifle, but take it out for some target practice and you'll feel all the difference. It's got a perfect combination of accuracy and stopping power. Add the remaining sixteen thousand and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_432">
        <text>Yeah, Lynx: a sniper rifle with increased accuracy and power. Add sixteen thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_511">
        <text>Look here. I managed to get everything off my list: a CS-3a with a helmet. The helmet is nothing special on its own, but it allows for installing a mobile tactical system, which includes a high-quality night vision system and an active infrared sensor. Now, the CS-3a armor is a real beauty. Excellent protection from bullets and anomalies is a rare feature indeed in a suit as light and mobile as this one. The whole thing will cost you thirty-two thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_512">
        <text>Yeah. A set consisting of a CS-3a suit with a tactical helmet. Thirty-two thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_611">
        <text>Specially for you, a SEVA suit. Everything just like you ordered: a closed-cycle respiratory module, thermal resistant, protective electrical circuit, and outer-surface anticorrosion materials. Plus several built-in artifact containers as a bonus. A must-have suit for any stalker. Toss in twenty-four thousand like we agreed and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_612">
        <text>Here. A SEVA suit. The price is twenty-four thousand, like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_711">
        <text>There it is, a combat exoskeleton as large as life. The best protection you can get in the Zone from bullets, claws or grenade fragments, with the exception of armored vehicles. But it also takes after armored vehicles in that it relieves your weight burden… within reason, of course. Forty-eight thousand and it's yours, warts and all… err… by that I mean batteries and servomotors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_712">
        <text>There it is, a combat exoskeleton as large as life. Forty-eight thousand and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_0">
        <text>I want to place an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1">
        <text>No problem. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11">
        <text>A pistol.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_111">
        <text>Of course. It'll be thirty-five hundred, of which I will require an advance payment of seven hundred.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1111">
        <text>Okay, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11111">
        <text>I'll get in touch with you as soon as the order is ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have the money on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11121">
        <text>Well, please come back when you've got the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1113">
        <text>You know, I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11131">
        <text>Fine. If you finally decide to make an order, I'm always here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_112">
        <text>You're not a very reliable customer, so the pistol will cost you forty-two hundred. And I will require an advance payment of fourteen hundred.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_113">
        <text>I'm afraid the best pistols have already sold out. If you want the regular stuff, Owl's the man to see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_12">
        <text>A close-range weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_121">
        <text>Sure thing. The price is ten thousand, and I'll need two thousand of that in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_122">
        <text>You refused to pick up your last order… So this one will cost you twelve thousand, and I'll need four thousand of that in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_123">
        <text>Hrm… You know, I probably can't help you there. The demand is too high.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_13">
        <text>An assault weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_131">
        <text>Something high-caliber and with rapid fire capability, okay… The regular price is twenty thousand, with a four thousand advance payment. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_132">
        <text>You're a tough customer. I'll have to charge you twenty-four thousand and I need eight thousand paid in advance. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_133">
        <text>Right now is a bad time… the military are making things hot at the Cordon. Someone attacked their outpost the other day, which made them even more difficult to deal with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_14">
        <text>A sniper weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_141">
        <text>For you, I can get the best for only twenty thousand, but you'll have to pay me four thousand in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_142">
        <text>Working with you entails a certain amount of risk… I can try to arrange your order for twenty-four thousand, but you'll need to make an eight thousand down payment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_143">
        <text>Sorry, this type of weapon is hard to come by right now. My contact for sniper stuff is… let's say he's indisposed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_15">
        <text>An armored suit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_151">
        <text>Yeah, I can think of something… suitable. It'll cost you forty thousand, but you'll have to pay me eight thousand in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_152">
        <text>Yeah, I can think of something… suitable. You refused to collect your last order, so the price will be forty-eight thousand and you'll have to pay me sixteen thousand in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_153">
        <text>I won't be able to do any better than the last suit I got for you. That one was both unique and top of the line.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_16">
        <text>A suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_161">
        <text>That's a tall order… Won't be easy to obtain, not by a long shot. I can try to get one of these babies for thirty thousand, but I have to ask for a down payment of six thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_162">
        <text>You let me down on the last order, so I have to think twice this time. I can try to get one of these babies for thirty-six thousand, but I have to ask for a down payment of twelve thousand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_163">
        <text>I bent over backwards to get the last one. Don't think I'll be able to repeat that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_17">
        <text>A mercenary exoskeleton.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_171">
        <text>You must have given this choice a lot of thought. I can get my hands on a combat version, but it'll cost you sixty thousand. Expensive, I know, but well worth it. Keep in mind I'll need twelve thousand of that paid right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_172">
        <text>You didn't treat me very nicely on the last order, so this one'll set you back seventy-two thousand. Keep in mind I'll need twenty-four thousand of that paid right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_173">
        <text>No way. Since they closed the manufacturing plant, vacant exoskeletons are typically found only on corpses… That's just not my method.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_18">
        <text>Nothing right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_2">
        <text>Sorry, my shop is closed at the moment. Temporary difficulties with order shipments…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_11">
        <text>Hello there, Beast! If you need any weapons or gear, you've come to the right place. I offer you rare models, prototypes, and unique weapons in addition to some elite equipment; namely, some recent combat suit designs. Each order is handled by me personally, so high quality is guaranteed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_12">
        <text>Hello. Would you like to place an order?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_13">
        <text>Hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_14">
        <text>Your order will be delivered very soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_15">
        <text>The order is finished. Please come to collect it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_10">
        <text>Sidorovich asked me to find this courier. I didn't expect to find him dead. My sympathies, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_11">
        <text>Damn… He was one of the good ones; I went through a lot of shit with the guy. You'd think this would be the last place he'd die… The Cordon is the safest place in the Zone, and yet here he is…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_12">
        <text>Did you see who killed him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_13">
        <text>Did you find anything else interesting, hunter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_14">
        <text>Did you search his backpack?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_15">
        <text>All right. Did you know this stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_16">
        <text>I found a PDA in his backpack, but it's locked. Do you know anyone who can hack it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_18">
        <text>Nope. I don't know, nor have I seen who did it. I accidentally caught his signal when I was walking by, and he wasn't answering. I came here to check it out. I thought he might've pressed the SOS button by accident or something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_19">
        <text>Yeah. This is a sad turn of events, but what's done is done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_2">
        <text>Those bastards! Why would somebody do such a thing? Fuck… I told him not to take that damn job—that it was too risky—but, no, he just had to go and get himself killed… Ugh… Anyway, what do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_20">
        <text>No. I haven't searched his backpack yet. I doubt there's anything valuable there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_21">
        <text>Yeah, I knew him well, and I used to help him with his courier jobs from time to time. He was a good, kind-hearted stalker. I don't know why someone would kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_22">
        <text>I don't know for sure, but I think Van could help with that. You should ask him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_23">
        <text>Well, I'll go search him. He might have something that I need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_24">
        <text>Gotcha.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_25">
        <text>All right. I'll ask him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_26">
        <text>All right. That's all I needed to know. Good luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_3">
        <text>Did you know this guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_4">
        <text>Yeah, I knew him well, and I used to help him with his courier jobs from time to time. He was a good, kind-hearted stalker. I don't know why someone would kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_5">
        <text>Who could have done this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_6">
        <text>text in default</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_">
        <text>?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_1">
        <text>Sidorovich, some say you trade valuable information. Is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_10">
        <text>Yeah… Never mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_11">
        <text>What can you tell me about Shaman?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_12">
        <text>Five hundred rubles, and I'll tell you everything I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_13">
        <text>Okay, here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_14">
        <text>Shaman's a good guy. He used to be in some kind of special forces unit or something… He is nowhere near like Wolf, but he still knows his way around the Zone, and he's been around for more than a year now. Most stalkers can learn a lot from him, especially new ones. He's a real leader, and he keeps all the stalkers here in line and makes sure that they all watch each other. He's also a good strategist. He always knows how to solve problems, even very complicated ones. All in all, he's a good stalker, and I'm glad he's here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_15">
        <text>Do you know anything about Mark?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_16">
        <text>Any whim for your money. It's five hundred rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_19">
        <text>What do you know about Borland?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_2">
        <text>Depends on what information you're looking for… Tell me what you need to know, and then I'll see if I can help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_20">
        <text>My price for such information is always the same: five hundred.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_21">
        <text>Got change for a thousand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_22">
        <text>According to rumors in the Zone, Borland wasn't a soldier, nor was he a scientist. Rather, he was a thirty-two-year-old professional racer. Due the ongoing mess in his home country, every race track and stadium was closed, and Borland was forced to find something else to do with his life. He was quick to grasp that the only place for him is the Zone. All of his talents are useful here. His dexterous eyes and hands, his ability to remain cool in dangerous situations, and his stamina all serve him well here in the Zone. Borland had the ability to find the solution to any problem on the fly—no matter how tough—and he had a great sense of time and distance. Really, the Zone was nothing new for him; it was all the same, except the stakes were higher.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_23">
        <text>I heard about this guy named Fang. You wouldn't happen to know anything about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_24">
        <text>Oh, Shroud! That's a really good question! I just so happen to know a lot about him. Give me five hundred rubles, and I'll tell you something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_25">
        <text>I am all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_26">
        <text>Fang is a legendary stalker. He was part of Strelok's group. You could say he was the “muscle”; he would take care of anything combat related. He was a terrific shot, and more than that, he was also very capable in engineering various gadgets. He upgraded his own exoskeleton and made it the best piece of armor the whole Zone. Too bad he disappeared somewhere. Nobody knows the exact location. Some say that he died, while others say that he simply left the Zone. I can't tell you for sure. I simply don't know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_27">
        <text>Do you know anything about Strelok's group? How about Ghost?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_28">
        <text>Five hundred rubles…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_29">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_3">
        <text>What do you know about Wolf? Who is he, and how did he get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_30">
        <text>Ghost was something of a spy: he could sneak anywhere without anyone catching even a whiff of him. He wasn't called Ghost for nothing. Too bad he died in the underground laboratory beneath Yantar… He was a good stalker. Perhaps even one of the best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_4">
        <text>Information is a precious commodity. Pay five hundred rubles, and I'll spill the beans.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_5">
        <text>Whatever you say…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_6">
        <text>Don't you think that's a tad too much? I'll pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_7">
        <text>Sergey Yekimov—Wolf, that is—and his family were always in a bad shape. His wife left him around the same time that he got fired from his job. He'd spend days drinking his life away at some pub, but after his brother, Peter, found himself in some trouble too, things changed. Peter was beaten up by some local gang. Got beaten to a pulp, just barely clinging on to life. As you might've guessed, Wolf didn't just stand idly by. He tracked down the ones resposible for the attack, and just a week after the beating, he shot every single gang member dead. After that, Wolf fled into the Zone and started building up his reputation. He used to conduct deep raids into the Zone, but chose to stay in the Cordon later on, where the atmosphere is much calmer, with only the military patrolling the border and rookies waiting to be trained. That's how Wolf became the legendary rookie leader we all know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_8">
        <text>Do you know anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_9">
        <text>All right. Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_2">
        <text>All right, Beast, what are your orders?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_4">
        <text>Hey. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_5">
        <text>I need you to patrol the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_6">
        <text>Sit back for a while. I don't have any work for you right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_7">
        <text>Get back to base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_8">
        <text>Never mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_0">
        <text>I want to hire some extra security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_1">
        <text>Tell me where you need the guard so I can assign him his post right away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_10">
        <text>Excellent. Some extra guards have been sent from the nearest outpost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_11">
        <text>I want to hire some extra security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_12">
        <text>Very well. The price for the soldier is twenty-five hundred, and you'll have to pay out of your own pocket since you're the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_13">
        <text>Very well. The price for the soldier is twenty-five hundred, and you'll have to pay out of your own pocket since you're the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_14">
        <text>Very well. The price for the soldier is twenty-five hundred, and you'll have to pay out of your own pocket since you're the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_15">
        <text>Yeah. Here's the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_16">
        <text>Yeah. Here's the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_17">
        <text>Yeah. Here's the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_2">
        <text>Administration building, second floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_3">
        <text>Near the tunnel leading to the Dark Valley.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_4">
        <text>Yard, south entrance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_5">
        <text>Yard, north entrance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_6">
        <text>All right, I need to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_7">
        <text>Very well. The price for the soldier is twenty-five hundred, and you'll have to pay out of your own pocket since you're the leader. So, what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_8">
        <text>Yeah. Here's the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_9">
        <text>No. I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_11">
        <text>Hey, Beast! What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_12">
        <text>Coordinator will be waiting for you in Bar ninety-two. Jackal never described his appearance to me, but he did say that he'll approach you first. Man, this mission is probably going to be worth it. This contract that Jackal's giving us is serious.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_13">
        <text>What types of jobs did you do before this one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_14">
        <text>Small shit, for the most part. Nothing too serious. The pay wasn't that good, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_15">
        <text>All right. I'll go meet this Coordinator. The more info I can get about this mission, the better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_17">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Got any work for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_18">
        <text>Yes. Contact Jackal and ask him to send four fighters our way. Tell him we need the soldiers for a security job at the bar and that if it goes as planned, our pay will be good. In the meantime, though, we won't be paying for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_19">
        <text>Jackal won't be too happy with sending troops without an advance payment, but he'll go through with it as long as the pay is good in the end. What about the briefing? What should we tell the troops?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_20">
        <text>They just need to guard the bar in the rookie village. Just send them there when they arrive here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_21">
        <text>All right. I'll do that. Once the mercs arrive, I'll contact you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_22">
        <text>Right, then. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_24">
        <text>Hey, Beast! What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_25">
        <text>No. I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_26">
        <text>Excellent. Jackal just dispatched a few extra guards from the nearest outpost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_27">
        <text>All right. I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_3">
        <text>Hey, Beast. There aren't many of us in the Cordon right now. Jackal's refusing to send us reinforcements without some extra payment, but if you want, you can hire some more people for a small fee. They'll be here to protect our temporary base, and we'll need it. Who knows what the stalker bastards will try next… So, if you provide the funds, I can radio Jackal and get us more men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_4">
        <text>Hey, Beast! What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_6">
        <text>Greetings, Beast! Bizon told me that Sidorovich transferred the money for the contract. Any news about it? Is there any work for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_7">
        <text>There is. Radio Jackal and tell him that the trader needs two men to guard his bunker. I have no manpower to spare. I think he'll understand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_8">
        <text>I'll get on it right away. Oh, by the way, I almost forgot: Jackal told me that Coordinator's ready to meet you and that he has a new job for us. He told me you should see him personally.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_9">
        <text>That's probably the secret mission Jackal told us about… All right. Where is this Coordinator waiting for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_0">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Vulture told me you've talked to Coordinator. So what's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_1">
        <text>We need to “borrow” something from Sidorovich's warehouse, but to get there, we have to neutralize the mechanic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_2">
        <text>All right. I'm sure we'll come up with something… Also, I found out about our three guests that visited us a while ago. They were Valerian's men, and they were sent to observe us and collect intel. I guess they were too cocky for that job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_3">
        <text>I see. That means they weren't here on Sidorovich's orders. We don't need more problems.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_4">
        <text>At least we tried to negotiate with them. Not our fault they were so aggressive… Oh, the stalker we saved at the bandit outpost, Raccoon, asked to join the Syndicate. I turned him down; gave him the regular “you're too green” response.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_5">
        <text>You did the right thing. Though, having a mole in the rookie village wouldn't be a bad idea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_0">
        <text>Why would we pick *that* stalker? He could compromise our whole operation, and we would have to spend days unfucking the mess afterwards.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_1">
        <text>Relax. I have a plan. Raccoon could help us with our current mission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_2">
        <text>And what would he do? He won't even do so much as touch Valerian. He'll just get shot down by the guards… What the hell are you thinking?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_3">
        <text>We just need to force Valerian out of the base. We could easily ambush them and finish the job quietly. Easy as that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_4">
        <text>So you want to use that rookie as bait?… Ah. I get it now: Valerian will find out that we sent an assassin after him, after which he'll try to escape. Then we kill him while he's away. That's actually a good plan. This could totally work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_5">
        <text>Exactly. Tonight, we'll see if my plan works out. I've told Vulture to send two men to keep an eye on the stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_6">
        <text>All right. And what will you do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_7">
        <text>I'll head back to base and wait for a signal from the recon team. Until then, we won't be making any move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_0">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Got new orders?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_1">
        <text>Raven, I need you to take two fighters and get to the tunnel leading to the Dark Valley ASAP. Valerian took the bait. He's going to try and escape through the tunnel, and we're going to ambush him there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_2">
        <text>Got it. Heading out now. You with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_3">
        <text>Yes. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_10">
        <text>Not now. I'll stay here for a bit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_12">
        <text>You should probably talk to the hostage first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_13">
        <text>You're right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_2">
        <text>This checkpoint is ours. The guys will hold it until we… well, *you* decide what to do next. We can head back to the village now. What about those stalkers? Can they walk?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_3">
        <text>Yeah. They're fine. Listen: my sniper rifle needs some adjustments. When we get back to the village, take it to the technician. See if he can do anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_4">
        <text>Gotcha. Are we heading back to the the village?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_5">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_6">
        <text>Just wait for a moment. I need to check something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_8">
        <text>So are you ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_9">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_0">
        <text>We're in position, Beast. Another group of ours just arrived in the Cordon; they'll be joining us in the assault. Everyone's ready to go. The bandits won't know what hit 'em. Before we strike, though, can I ask you a question?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_1">
        <text>Excellent. Ask away, Raven.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_2">
        <text>Are you sure it's worth it? Risking our guys for a couple of nobodies? I doubt Wolf is paying us a fortune for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_3">
        <text>I'm not really sure, but this is our best option at the moment. By carrying out this contract and saving those men, the people around here will start to trust and recognize us. We need a good reputation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_4">
        <text>Got it. So, we're doing this… How's the sniper spot I picked? I thought it matched your request. Plus, I couldn't find anything better, so…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_5">
        <text>The position is perfect, Raven. Ideal for trying out my new sniper rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_6">
        <text>I'm glad it suits you. Now let's go over our plan one more time: I help our guys distract the bandits while you snipe them off one by one from up here. That right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_7">
        <text>That's our plan, all right. Now let's do this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_0">
        <text>I need medical assistance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_1">
        <text>Let's have a look…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_11">
        <text>[continue…]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_111">
        <text>That's better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_2">
        <text>Let's have a look… Well, your liver is bigger than I'd expect, but that's an occupational hazard, right? Apart from that, you're as healthy as a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_0">
        <text>Can you refill my canteen with water?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_1">
        <text>Of course, merc. No problem. It'll cost you a thousand. The price may be high, but keep in mind that it's hard to filter out radiation out of water. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_2">
        <text>Okay. Here's the canteen and money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_3">
        <text>Nah. Changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_4">
        <text>Let me hold on to your canteen for now; I'll fill it up later. In exchange, I'll give you this full canteen I have right here. When you run out of water again, come see me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_5">
        <text>All right. Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_0">
        <text>I found a PDA belonging to this Final Day group… Wanna take a look at it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_1">
        <text>Really? Is it encrypted?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_2">
        <text>Only partially.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_3">
        <text>I'll pay ten thousand for it. No more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_4">
        <text>Sure, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_5">
        <text>Here's your cash, merc. Now let's take a look…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_10">
        <text>He's always alone; I doubt anybody hangs around him. I know his type like the back of my hand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Where can I find him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_12">
        <text>That's a bit more difficult. I have no idea where he went, but I might have a solution: I'll part with a beacon, you place it where I tell you, and then we'll be able to track him down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_13">
        <text>All right. Give me that beacon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Grab it from the storeroom and plant it on the bridge. I'll send you the exact coordinates on your PDA. Now go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_15">
        <text>All right. I'll go get the beacon. Tell your guard to step aside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Merc, don't forget that you need to set up that beacon before I can find where Klim's hiding.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_18">
        <text>Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, merc. Let's get straight to business: I take it you already know that you were hired for more than one job, right? Good. Not only have I managed to make a lot of enemies in the long time I've been here, but there are many other things that need taking care of.\n \nBefore we begin, let's establish a few rules that will keep you and your men from getting into trouble: first of all, you know that stalker base by the railroad embankment? Don't go there, because Valerian despises mercenaries. Second, don't do any business behind my back. Third and final, all of this remains between us. Are we clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_20">
        <text>So, merc, have you found the flash drive yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Yeah. Here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_23">
        <text>Excellent. Give it here. And don't bother me with the details… Tell me, though: the guy that was carrying it; is he dead?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Take the flash drive. And yeah. You won't have to worry about him ever again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_25">
        <text>That's good to hear… And that son of a bitch thought he could rip me off. All right. Let's not waste any more time. You're free to go for now. I'll message you when I'll need you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_26">
        <text>And now it's time to do your part of the deal. Give me the payment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_28">
        <text>Hey, merc. Listen: I didn't call you for a job. I have a different offer for you instead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Yeah? And what sort of offer would that be?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_3">
        <text>So, it's true what they say about you. I understand. Now hear out my only rule: I get paid on time right after the job is finished. No exceptions. Are we clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_30">
        <text>Well, I need you to send me two of your men to guard my bunker. I've been getting some extra heat recently; some people don't like the way I do business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_31">
        <text>Sure. I could probably get you a couple of guards… depending on how much you'll pay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_32">
        <text>Merc, have you forgotten that I've made a contract with your superiors? I can remind you the hard way. Either way, I want two guards near my bunker as soon as possible. You got that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_33">
        <text>Not a chance. All my soldiers are already occupied. Besides, I'm not paying my leader with *my* money to hire *you* any security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_35">
        <text>I don't loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_37">
        <text>You're right. I didn't call you for that… Did you hear about what happened last night?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_38">
        <text>No. What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_39">
        <text>Something very strange… Last night, Valerian ran off somewhere with some of his most trusted men, and they haven't been seen since. His PDA has gone completely silent, and no one, not even in his own base, knows where he went.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_40">
        <text>Okay. And why are you telling me this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_41">
        <text>I wanted to share the news with you, you know. Thought you might know something, but clearly, you don't. Either way, Orest will take over in the absence of Valerian. He's an experienced stalker who just came back from the Agroprom, and he'll be residing in the stalker base temporarily. I need you to deliver something to him. I've already talked to them; they'll let you into the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_42">
        <text>I'm not some delivery boy running around the Zone… If you don't have any *real* work, then I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_43">
        <text>Listen here, you scoundrel: either you do as you're told or the contract will be canceled. Are we clear here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_44">
        <text>Fine, trader. Give me the package and let's get this over with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_45">
        <text>I hope we've cleared everything up.\n \nHere's the package. Give it to Orest personally. I told him you'd come. Also, Shaman was looking for you; he has a job for you. He's in the bar right now. Go and pay him a visit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_46">
        <text>Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_48">
        <text>I don't loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I don't loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_50">
        <text>Merc, don't forget that you need to set up that beacon before I can find this Klim guy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_51">
        <text>All right. I'll go get it. Tell your guard to let me through.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_52">
        <text>Fine. I'll pay for your guys. Five thousand for both of them. No more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_53">
        <text>That's better. I'll send them right away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_54">
        <text>Thanks for the guards, merc! With this protection, I can rest easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_55">
        <text>I doubt you contacted me just to thank me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_6">
        <text>We're clear. If we're on the same page, we can get on with your first assignment: a while back, a guy came in and wanted to sell me some valuable information, but the price he demanded for it was astronomical. And it wasn't even worth the price. The stalker's name is Klim, and he keeps the info in his flash drive. He always has it on him. Your job is to get me that flash drive and kill the stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_7">
        <text>All right. What does this guy look like? Is he heavily armed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_8">
        <text>No. He's just some random stalker with subpar gear. He wanted to play wise guy, and I won't let that slide. When he came here, all he had was sawed-off shotgun, and I doubt his assortment has improved since then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Does he have any friends? Does he work in a group?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1">
        <text>I always liked to work alone; by myself, for myself. But when I heard that the stalkers organized their own base, I knew I just had to join in. I've been in many places in the Zone, and to me, being among independent stalkers is the best. There are only regular stalkers here. You feel me? They don't have any codes, rules, or anything else that other factions have. They're just regular dudes trying to make a living, and that's the way it should be.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11">
        <text>Good spare parts are very scarce in the Zone… How do you manage to work with what you have?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_111">
        <text>Well, it's not like I upgrade Gauss rifles over here, but I can manage to get some decent work done. I've been doing this for many years now, and I'm good at what I do. That's pretty much it. Most stalkers don't bring anything that complicated; mostly regular guns and armor that needs fixing. From time to time, a stalker asks for an upgrade to his suit or weapon, which I can carry out with ease. You can also take a look at what upgrades I can install. You might find that interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1111">
        <text>From what I understand, you've traveled around the Zone quite a bit. Have you seen anything unusual on your trips?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11111">
        <text>Unusual? I came here from the Agroprom when the big emission hit; you know, the one that changed everything. The things that happened after can only be described as miracles. A place that was once totally empty became a total shitshow; part of the land there was all messed up with parts of it rising up—it was like a Salvador Dali painting—and the radiation there was so strong that you couldn't get anywhere near it without getting a lethal dose. Later on, the guys told me that the anomaly was one of the most dangerous in the Zone but that it had the rarest artifacts. If you ever find yourself near that area, beware…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_0">
        <text>Woah… Man, if it wasn't for you guys, we'd be dead right now! Raccoon and I are very grateful. It's a good thing you came by when you did… Who are you? Why did you risk your lives for us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_1">
        <text>We're mercenaries. We were hired by Wolf to look for your squad. We found Zokhan, who gave us your location.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_2">
        <text>Zokhan's alive?! Oh, thank God! I thought these bastards killed him for sure; I'm really happy to hear that!… I want to ask you one more thing: where are you going now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_3">
        <text>Don't worry. We'll escort you back to the rookie village. After that, we'll be on your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_4">
        <text>Good to hear. Those damn bandits took all of our gear, so we're left with nothing… and walking around in the Zone without a gun isn't exactly the smartest thing to do. So, are we heading out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_5">
        <text>Hold on a sec. I need to talk to my partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_6">
        <text>Hold on a sec. Let me tell my guys where we're headed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_7">
        <text>Yeah. Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_1">
        <text>I'm a trader… who's just starting out. When we came here not that long ago, Shaman said that everyone can be whoever they want. So I wanted to be a trader. I have the talent for this job; I've been buying and selling things since I was a kid. Back in school, I used sell those old electronic games; you know, the ones where there's a wolf that catches eggs? I'd hand them to my classmates for ten kopecks per game… I have a knack for it, you understand? Yeah, those were the days… Right now, I'm just trying to figure out how things work around here… I get most of my products from Sidorovich, so there's not that much profit, but hey: slowly but surely, I'm starting to get my own clients, so there's that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_111">
        <text>Man, right now, we are living like in God's pocket… The military won't steal our loot anymore, so now all of our earnings will remain ours. After a deep raid, we can actually rest easy in the Cordon, and we can actually get a hold of some quality gear here. Hell, we can even start making real money. Not like before when the military would shake down a stalker the moment they spot one… Maybe one day, we will drive out these jarheads completely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_2">
        <text>What do you think about the life in the Cordon right now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_3">
        <text>Man, right now, we are living like in God's pocket… The military won't steal our loot anymore, so now all of our earnings will remain ours. After a deep raid, we can actually rest easy in the Cordon, and we can actually get a hold of some quality gear here. Hell, we can even start making real money. Not like before when the military would shake down a stalker the moment they spot one… Maybe one day, we will drive out these jarheads completely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_10">
        <text>Fine. I won't tell anyone. What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_11">
        <text>Usually, bandits don't poke their noses in that place, meaning that they had a special reason for being there. They must've been looking for something, and we ran into them by accident. Their behavior was also really strange; I saw one of them drop a blue notebook when they were there, and then I heard a few shots. After that, my vision went black, and when I woke up, I saw you. They must have taken the hostages and left.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_12">
        <text>Okay. And what do you suggest we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_13">
        <text>Could you go back there—where you found me—and look around again? Maybe you can find something. I have a feeling that those bandits were there for a reason. Don't worry; I'll pay up. You know me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_14">
        <text>All right. I'll see what I can find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_15">
        <text>I have better things to do than waste my time looking for something only God knows.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_16">
        <text>Merc, I'm counting on you here. Please; if you can, find some free time for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_17">
        <text>Fine… I'll go there and see what's what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_18">
        <text>All right, but not right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_2">
        <text>You're back… Thank you. You saved those guys' lives. If not for you, they would've been dead; the bandits don't hold hostages for long. Also, thanks for the medkit. It truly saved my life. Was it hard facing off those scumbags?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_20">
        <text>So, Beast, have you finally found some time to help me out? I'll pay up good. You know me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_21">
        <text>Fine… I'll go there and see what's what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_22">
        <text>Fine… I'll go there and see what's what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_24">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_26">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Have you found the notebook?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_27">
        <text>Yeah. I found the notebook, and I lost twenty-five grand in the process. Now, I need that money back and your payment for the job, which will amount to thirty grand in total. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_28">
        <text>Yeah. I found the notebook, and it held the coordinates of a meeting that was supposed to take place. Over there, I found a note that led me to the tunnel under the embankment. In the tunnel, I got jumped by some guy, and he demanded twenty-five grand from me, so I iced him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_29">
        <text>What? How? What exactly happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_3">
        <text>It was easy. I'm used to these things.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_30">
        <text>There isn't that much to explain. I went to the tunnel and there was a bandit who tried to rob me, so I shot him down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_31">
        <text>That's impossible. There's a stalker base nearby, so how would a bandit get anywhere near there? The bandits that hang around the northern checkpoint know full well not to go anywhere down south… This was done by someone else, I'm telling you. Did he tell you why he wanted twenty-five G's? And how the hell did you know to get to that tunnel anyway?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_32">
        <text>I found that notebook you mentioned before, and it contained the coordinates for a meeting. When I went to the meeting place, it was empty, save for a note that said someone would be waiting in tunnel at night. I went there, and it turned out to be a trap. The guy stuck a gun to my chest and demanded twenty-five grand for some case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_33">
        <text>We need to see what's inside that case. Do you have it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_34">
        <text>I have the case, but it's locked, and there's no way we're opening it without a professional lockpicker. Besides that, the case is really light, like it's empty… I doubt there's anything noteworthy inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_35">
        <text>All of this is very strange… I need the contents of that case. It might have some valuable info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_36">
        <text>Fine. I'll take care of cracking the case. And you need to come up with the money that you owe me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_38">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_39">
        <text>That's impossible. There's a stalker base nearby, so why would a bandit go anywhere near there? The bandits that hang around the northern checkpoint know full well not to go anywhere down south… This was done by someone else, I'm telling you. Did he tell you why he wanted twenty-five G's? And how the hell did you know how to get to that tunnel anyway?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_4">
        <text>Too bad you guys didn't come by earlier; you would have saved a few more lives… Either way, though, you saved some lives today.\n \nHere, take this artifact. I found it in the Garbage. Never seen anything like it. I wanted to sell it to Sidorovich, but you've earned it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_40">
        <text>That cash must've been payment for the case; the one he had on him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_41">
        <text>We need to see what's inside that case. Do you have it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_42">
        <text>I have the case, but it's locked, and there's no way we're opening it without a professional lockpicker. Besides that, the case is really light, like it's empty… I doubt there's anything noteworthy inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_43">
        <text>All of this is very strange… I need the contents of that case. It might have some valuable info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_44">
        <text>Fine. I'll take care of cracking the case. I won't be giving away everything inside for free, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_5">
        <text>Hey, thanks, man. If you ever need my help, you know where to find me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_7">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_8">
        <text>Thanks. You said you needed to talk to me about something. Is it the reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_9">
        <text>No, Beast. I need to talk to you about something else, but you have to promise me that you'll keep it between us. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_10">
        <text>Damn… Dude, I already told you everything I know… Please… Give me a medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_11">
        <text>Thanks a ton, man… Whew. Feeling better already. You saved my life… Wait. Why are you here, anyway?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_12">
        <text>Wolf hired us to check up on your squad. I take it you're the only survivor?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_13">
        <text>No. Two of us were taken hostage by the bandit attackers. I heard one of them say they need hostages for something, but I don't know what the hell they're planning. I'm fairly sure our guys are still alive, though, so maybe there's still a chance to rescue them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_14">
        <text>Where did they take them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_15">
        <text>The northern checkpoint; the one that leads to the Garbage. They set up a small base and everything, the bastards.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_16">
        <text>Got it. We'll try to save them. You return to Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_17">
        <text>No… I can't just sit on my ass while my friends are in danger. I can shoot my gun, and I'm already feeling better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_18">
        <text>Not a chance. Get back to Wolf. You're wounded, and you won't be of any use to us during the fight. We can handle a few bandits on our own, no problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_19">
        <text>Ugh… Fine. Just make sure you bring everyone back alive! I'm counting on you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_20">
        <text>Go see Wolf and tell him what happened while we prepare the assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_3">
        <text>Dude, help me… I'm bleeding here. Please…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_4">
        <text>After you answer a few questions. Then I'll see what I can do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_5">
        <text>Are you kidding me?… I… I can't hold out much longer… Gimme a medkit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_6">
        <text>No. I'm serious. Tell me right now: who the hell are you, and where is Wolf's squad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_7">
        <text>I'm Zokhan… As for the squad… you're looking at it… We were ambushed by bandits, and they killed everyone… They left me for dead… We… We managed kill a few of them… but it wasn't enough. There was too many of them… Dude, please, just give me a medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_8">
        <text>All right. Here's your medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_9">
        <text>I don't have any medkits… Sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_10">
        <text>Uh-huh. It seems true to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_100">
        <text>First time I'm hearing about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_101">
        <text>It's a well-known fact by now that what we call “zombies” are just people who have completely lost their sanity and intelligence, and yet people still endanger their minds in hopes of finding better loot. That's human greed, all right. Duty, for example, doesn't even go anywhere near controllers, always keeping a kilometer between them and that dangerous mutant. They'd rather not risk their mental health; it's just not worth it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_102">
        <text>Yeah, scary shit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_103">
        <text>So a Freedom stalker heard about Duty's well known zoo…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_104">
        <text>Promising start…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_105">
        <text>God knows what was going in that Freedomer's head, but he got into his mind that he must see those mutants that were held in the Duty zoo. Even though that guy was a good dude, it always seemed like he was too good. His honesty and loyalty had no limits, and it was clear that it was only a matter of time before he was about to do something really stupid. That's why nobody was really surprised when the stalker said he was going to infiltrate the Duty base and attempt to free those mutants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_106">
        <text>What was he thinking?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_107">
        <text>Since it was Freedom—the faction of the anarchists—as long as nobody does anything to harm the faction itself, everyone can do whatever they want. So they let the deluded Freedomer continue with his crazy plan. Everybody said their goodbyes to him, because they knew he was done for, but our hero wasn't as simple as he looked. I don't know how, but he managed to catch a live rodent so he could use it as “payment” for the ticket to Duty zoo. So what do you think Duty did?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_108">
        <text>I doubt they invited him over for tea…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_109">
        <text>I don't know whether it was because the guards were in a forgiving mood or because the Freedomer appeared totally harmless, but they let him through. However, when he finally got to Duty's zoo, shit hit the fan!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_11">
        <text>Too bad they couldn't enjoy their victory for long. They were struck by a psy-field! It's like the Brain Scorcher was a living creature that suddenly realized they were there and wanted to get rid of them. When the psy-field hit, only one of the guys was zombified. The other had a suit with a strong psy-protection system, so he managed to survive that wave while his friend's brains were fried for good. Some say this happens a lot; where not everyone gets zombified at once. The guy whose brains were intact tackled his friend and dragged him to the Red Forest in hopes of saving him…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_110">
        <text>Plot twists. That's good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_111">
        <text>It turned out that the Freedomer was crazier than everyone thought. When he entered the zoo and saw the state the mutants were in, he lost his shit. The animals were locked in small cages with barely an inch to move, and they were so starved that they looked like scarecrows. The sight drove our hero mad, so he started screaming at the top of his lungs and jumped on the zoo keeper, Inquisitor, and started beating the shit out of him. At the same time, though, Inquisitor wanted to put their newly obtained rodent into the rodent cage, so its door was open! Once the Freedomer started assaulting him, all the rodents escaped. The Dutyers, of course, shot the Freedomer almost instantly…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_112">
        <text>Too bad… Poor fellow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_113">
        <text>He did manage to follow through on his plan, though. He exchanged his own life for the freedom of those rodents who escaped. They ran between the soldier's legs without them noticing, until the rodents finally found their way out of the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_114">
        <text>Not a bad story, all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_115">
        <text>Did you hear about the village; the one near the army warehouses that's inhabited by bloodsuckers? Even though everyone knows about that hellhole, I bet you don't know why all the bloodsuckers flock there in first place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_116">
        <text>Can't say that I do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_117">
        <text>Way back before the big blowout that created the Zone, that village was inhabited by the military. Keep in mind, though, that these were no ordinary soldiers. They had some kind of different uniform with its own strange emblems. They were some type of special unit. No one knows for sure what their mission was, although it doesn't matter much for our story. Anyway, when the big blowout hit, almost all of the soldiers died instantly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_118">
        <text>Sounds interesting, but what does this have to do with the bloodsuckers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_119">
        <text>However, a few of those soldiers managed to survive in that same village by hiding inside the cellars, in which people used to store all the pickled goods in the old days… You know how our people are. We love our pickled shit, and we can't have enough of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_12">
        <text>I doubt he could accomplish anything, but that's some loyalty…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_120">
        <text>Well, they had to come out sooner or later, didn't they? They had to eat, after all. It's not like there was an unlimited supply of food in those cellars.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_121">
        <text>Yeah, you're right. They had to come out of there at some point, and they did. The soldiers would come out of the cellars from time to time to find some food and other supplies, grabbing whatever they could get their hands on. They didn't have any detectors, so they had no idea when they were walking through a radioactive field, and the amount of radiation they took was enormous. But they had no other choice due to food supplies running low.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_122">
        <text>Hell, I wouldn't know what to do either…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_123">
        <text>When they ran out of food completely, the soldiers resorted to cannibalism. What ensued was a total nightmare! Those guys were so starved that they ate the people who were too weak to go on; their own friends, no less. But that's not the crux of this story. Believe it or not, things get even weirder.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_124">
        <text>I've completely lost my appetite, and now you're telling me things are going to get even weirder… What else was I supposed to expect in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_125">
        <text>Yeah. The Zone is an unpredictable place, and some even say that it's a living creature. In the Zone, some things don't die out, but rather adapt to it, revealing their ugliest form in the process. That's what happened to our beloved soldiers, who, instead of dying, turned into the bloodsuckers we now all know and love. The first generation of these mutants would wear a special soldier uniform; the same one as the guys that were stationed in the village. To this day, bloodsuckers flock to that place… Maybe they feel it's their home? Who the hell knows what goes on in the heads of those overgrown ticks…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_126">
        <text>Man, I don't even know what to say…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_127">
        <text>Yeah, trying to figure that out is a waste of time. Moral of the story, though, is that sometimes, it's better to just accept your death instead of turning into a complete monster. The latter is a fate much worse than death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_128">
        <text>Yeah, maybe you're right… All right, I gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_129">
        <text>There was a time when the Barrier was totally unprotected and nobody was around to guard it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_13">
        <text>Fate had more hardship in store for those two. All that noise attracted the attention of a Monolith squad that was patrolling the area and happened to see the two stalkers. They opened fire the second they noticed them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_130">
        <text>I like stories about the old days, keep going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_131">
        <text>Back then, huge waves of monsters would run through the Barrier and travel all the way to the Garbage. That's why most stalkers preferred not to set camp anywhere near the Barrier, and the farthest place you could see stalkers camping was in the bloodsucker village. But that village was no less dangerous, as it was always occupied by packs of… well, bloodsuckers. That's how the place got its name. Nobody really knows why those bloodsuckers flock to that village, but that's a story for another time… Back to what I was telling: because of the danger, stalkers would still in sleep in the houses of that village with one eye open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_132">
        <text>Sounds like a story about me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_133">
        <text>So, this one time, a certain screwball decided to spend the night on top of the tower located at the edge of the village. He climbed up, opened a bottle of vodka, and slowly started chugging it it whilst gradually falling asleep at the same time. Then, all of a sudden, he saw a human silhouette in the distance, rustling around in the bushes. The stalker at the tower grabbed his rifle and his binoculars and got in better position to take his shot. For all he knew, it could have been a bloodsucker or a snork looking for some fresh prey, or even worse: a controller. However, it turned out be a regular stalker who was looking for a place to sleep through night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_134">
        <text>He got lucky…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_135">
        <text>Our hero was happy to see another stalker in the area, so he started throwing stuff from the top of the tower in hopes that the other guy would see him. The stalker wandering around the village finally realized what was going on and went straight to the tower. But was this wasn't an ordinary stalker. No, he was an experienced bandit with some serious gear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_136">
        <text>Damn…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_137">
        <text>He was probably looking for a place where he could set up an ambush. Our hero wasn't beating around the bush, and the minute he saw it was a bandit, he opened fire on him. A serious firefight ensued between the two. The stalker threw a few grenades from the top of the tower, but the bandit was a tough one, and he avoided those grenades like a pro. After that, the two started shooting each other from behind cover, and the fight lasted for hours. Finally, after a long night of shooting, the bandit fell on the ground…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_138">
        <text>I am guessing the bandit was dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_139">
        <text>No matter how you spin, the stalker had a better position in that tower. After he shot down the bandit, he went down to check on the body. When he went inside the building the bandit was hiding in and saw the body, he froze from shock. It turned out that the bandit didn't die from a bullet. When they were busy shooting each other, a bloodsucker snuck in and broke the guy's neck. Before the stalker could even close his mouth, the bloodsucker killed him as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_14">
        <text>That was some luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_140">
        <text>The bloodsucker got a two for one deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_141">
        <text>If only those two would have just put their differences aside, they would have lived to fight another day. Instead of everyone going their own separate way in the morning, we could all just enjoy our time at a cozy campfire… But that's too much to ask for; we can't help but shoot at each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_142">
        <text>Hey, sometimes people can help. Just not in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_143">
        <text>Man, have I got a weird story for you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_144">
        <text>Things are weird enough already, but I guess it can't hurt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_145">
        <text>A stalker went to the Zone to search for his beloved girl, who was known to the people of the Zone as The Snow Maiden. I don't know how she got that nickname. She was average in the looks department; nothing special. Although some say she had a nice personality. The guy looking for her, on the other hand, was a total scumbag, but that's how it usually is: the good ones always fall for the bad ones.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_146">
        <text>Yeah, I think we've all seen that happening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_147">
        <text>The two finally found each other and went to the bloodsucker village. You know, the one near the army warehouses. Bloodsuckers would always flock to that place for some reason, but it was possible to survive there. That village had a group of stalkers there who would loot the dead bodies of veteran stalkers from unsuccessful assaults in the center of the Zone. A real bunch of assholes… The Snow Maiden and her boyfriend were members of said group. Despite the fact that the girl felt sick from the whole thing, she stayed, because she wanted to be with her boyfriend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_148">
        <text>She was an idiot…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_149">
        <text>Hey, what can you do? You can't pick who you love. Anyway, one time, this band of looters had a disagreement about what loot to share. As for our heroine, it was the worst day of her life. The looters took out all of their frustration out on her by torturing and raping her. Thinking about it makes me sick. She was locked up in the water tower all day and night. However, strange things tend to happen in the Zone…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_15">
        <text>Just as it seemed the stalker and his friend were done for, things turned for the better. While the stalker was exchanging fire with the Monolith, his zombified friend stood up, and instead of attacking the stalker, he just stood and looked at him for a second, and after that, covered his friend from enemy fire with his own body, thus saving him. The Monolith were shocked when it happened! Zombified stalkers under the influence of the Brain Scorcher are supposed to be their allies; yet, this one wasn't!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_150">
        <text>Hopefully, it would be something that would aid our heroine. Poor woman, being tortured like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_151">
        <text>A controller had entered the village and he had killed the majority of the group in a matter of seconds. The few that remained climbed up the tower and barricaded themselves from within. That didn't help much, obviously. The controller broke through the barricade and slaughtered everyone inside, but do you know what's even weirder?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_152">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_153">
        <text>The controller didn't touch the girl! It makes no sense, but that's what happened. He just left her there, and the horde of zombies following the controller didn't touch her either. Nobody can explain why that happened, but maybe the Zone decided to save the girl. Either way, it's a true miracle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_154">
        <text>I'm at a loss for words…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_155">
        <text>The only thing we can know for sure is that this forsaken place doesn't just destroy people, but it helps the poor and the tormented from time to time. Still, it is a mystery how the Zone works.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_156">
        <text>Risking your life for answers isn't always the best solution. Some things are meant to remain a mystery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_158">
        <text>Sorry, I don't have anything interesting right now… I… I ran out of stories… Awkward, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_16">
        <text>Yeah, that is very unlikely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_17">
        <text>The zombie just kept covering his friend while his buddy was crawling towards the trees. When the stalker got to the tree, they looked at each other for a second, and they both knew it was their last moment together. The stalker ran away and managed to get back to the Barrier. Since then, that stalker never harms any zombies, but instead just passes them by.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_18">
        <text>Yeah, I understand that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_19">
        <text>As for his zombified friend, some say that he wanders around radioactive forests to this day and protects any lost stalkers he comes across. And that meeting him is a sign of great fortune to come.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_2">
        <text>Hello, good sir. What brings you here? Everyone calls me Storyteller, because I like to tell various stories from all across the Zone, with a bottle of vodka in my hand. If you give me a bottle, I might just tell you something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_20">
        <text>Even though the story ended with a bit of hope, it was still very depressing. Well, I've got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_21">
        <text>There are some people who have special talents and abilities out there. There was a stalker here who was completely immune to psy-emissions. He could walk right through fields with out a scratch whilst others would lose their minds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_22">
        <text>Let's say that's somehow possible…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_23">
        <text>One might think that this stalker was some kind of a zombie, but that couldn't be further from the truth. In reality, this stalker was actually clever, and used his gift well. He respected the Zone's boundaries, and he would never go to places he wasn't supposed to. Sometimes, he wouldn't go past the Brain Scorcher at all despite being able to without taking any damage. He would bring unique artifacts from his raids into places others have never been to, which would earn him a lot of money. He never hesitated to help out a fellow stalker, and so earned respect of most people, even though he had his fair share of enemies. But he was a good fighter too, and he always had good gear on hand. Most people just avoided getting into a fight with him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_24">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_25">
        <text>He was also very cautious. Despite being well equipped, he would rather stay away from conflict. That's why he made camp in one of the abandoned hangars in Yantar. The psy-emissions there were on full throttle, and anybody who would go there would become zombified in the flick of a switch; unless it was our guy, of course. I have no idea how he protected himself from the wandering mutants and zombies, though. But he lived there pretty quietly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_26">
        <text>Seems the guy was living a good life…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_27">
        <text>Everything would have been good and well, except one time, a controller came to those same hangars. Of course, try as it might, the controller couldn't take control of the stalker, but it still made his life miserable. Nobody knew for sure what went down there… He only mentioned his problem a few times, saying he tried to kill the controller a few times, but that it got away. That's not the main point of the story, though…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_28">
        <text>What's the point, then? I'm dying to know here…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_29">
        <text>At a later point in time, a group of experienced stalkers was moving through Yantar, and they ran into that same controller! They were all good fighters, so they decided to get rid of the creature for good. They carefully backed the controller into a corner, and you know what happened then? That same stalker who was living in Yantar started shooting at the group from his sniper rifle. He managed to kill half of them, and the rest escaped. No one knows why he did it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_3">
        <text>All right. Here's a bottle. Tell me something interesting…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_30">
        <text>That stalker must've lost his mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_31">
        <text>The stalkers who traveled to Yantar have told stories about those two. They said that, even though the controller and that stalker were at each other's throats all day, they would protect each other when there was an outside threat. Nobody could find an explanation as to why this was happening, and thus it was just considered another mystery in the Zone. After a while, the duo disappeared somewhere, and nobody has seen either one of them since.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_32">
        <text>A mystery indeed. I don't even know what to think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_33">
        <text>Here's what I think: If you have a nemesis who you've had a conflict with for a very long time, then you get used to them, and then ending that relationship becomes very difficult.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_34">
        <text>I doubt that's the case, but it's possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_35">
        <text>I'll tell you a story. Not necessarily scary, but it's definitely creepy. I take it you've heard about the “concentration camp” down in the Garbage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_36">
        <text>Yeah, I've heard about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_37">
        <text>I'll tell you what: the Garbage was always a god-awful place. Even back before the incident in '86, the place was used as a dump where all the unneeded radioactive waste was thrown and buried. Near every junk heap, there was a station where the workers would dump the trash. However, the only station that I still remember to this day is the one we call the junkyard. Many people died there due to various accidents, and those that didn't were too afraid to talk about it, fearing that they would themselves be killed in an accident for talking too much. That's why you don't really hear about it. Anyway, after the incident at the CNPP, the Garbage was just left like that, with all the junk and tools intact…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_38">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_39">
        <text>Even back then, there were death traps on every corner: ammunition exploding, gasoline in cars catching fire, sometimes even huge metal parts fell on workers from out of nowhere, killing them. Nobody could explain what was happening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_4">
        <text>I'm not in the mood for stories.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_40">
        <text>Okay…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_41">
        <text>When the Zone emerged, everyone flocked to the Garbage immediately, either just for the artifacts or because it was a good strategic point. At first, Duty tried to take over the place and make it a safe haven for regular stalkers, getting rid of mutants and such. They would also deal with any bandits who were robbing or murdering passing stalkers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_42">
        <text>That's very decent of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_43">
        <text>Only, it didn't last for long. Duty made a small base inside an old bunker and would hide there during blowouts. Only, one time, when a blowout was coming, they all ran inside their bunker to wait it out, only to find out they were trapped. The blowout changed the positions of all the anomalies in such a way that they would block off every entrance to the bunker. All the Duty members there died of starvation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_44">
        <text>That's a brutal way to die. Wouldn't wish it on my worst enemy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_45">
        <text>What followed was no less brutal. At first, Freedom tried to make a base in the Garbage, but the constant mutant attacks at night prevented them from doing so. Regular loner stalkers also tried to establish something of a base for anyone who was coming back from a long raid to the Zone and needed to quickly resupply, get some sleep, or to sell off some unneeded gear. But like everyone else, they didn't last for very long. One guy came back with a mutated virus that he caught somewhere deep in the Zone. Even though the stalkers figured out quickly that an epidemic was among them, the base still had to be turned into a quarantine area where no one could get in or out. As for the sick, they all died there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_46">
        <text>Fucking horrifying…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_47">
        <text>Yeah… No matter what happened or who came over to this to the giant dumpster, it always ended badly. As of now, the bandits are occupying the Garbage and the junkyard they call the “concentration camp.” Little do they know that the ones who are going to die soon are not only the stalkers they are holding prisoners but they themselves as well. They're total assholes, but I still feel sorry for them… They are people, after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_48">
        <text>Sure… All right, gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_49">
        <text>Even though women aren't exactly common in the Zone and most stalkers only catch glimpses of them in porn mags, you can encounter a woman here from time to time. Not that you can expect anything good from them coming here; only problems. I have a story about a woman stalker…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_50">
        <text>All right, I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_51">
        <text>The Garbage—which is now controlled by bandits—was once a place where experienced stalkers would go to get some rest after a long journey and resupply. The trader there was a chick named Matryona. She would sell gear and food to those same stalkers. Although her prices were through the roof, that only scared off the rookies. Other than that, though, her business was doing very well, and she would always cash out with a smile on her face. But under that big smile was a very staunch alcoholic… She would empty multiple bottles of vodka a day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_52">
        <text>A guilty conscience, perhaps?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_53">
        <text>Anyways, one time, a guy was unlucky enough to fall in love with her. He ran after her all day and night, bringing her gifts and shit… Sometimes, he would even serenade her with his guitar during the evenings. It annoyed everyone else; they made him wrap it up quickly. It was obvious that the guy was totally obsessed with her.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_54">
        <text>Yeah. Not the first time I'm hearing about a guy losing his head over a chick… What about Matryona?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_55">
        <text>She would only wink at him from time to time with her green eyes and milk him for all his goods. Everyone felt sick just watching it; even the bandits felt bad for the guy. But what can you do to help a guy in a situation like that? Not much. Everyone just shook their heads and waited until the mess would reach its awful conclusion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_56">
        <text>So what was the conclusion?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_57">
        <text>Things ended badly. One time, she was drunk as usual, wandering around in the Garbage, but the thing was, she was so drunk she couldn't even see a vortex right in front of her. She couldn't even realize what was going on before the anomaly ripped her to shreds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_58">
        <text>Can't feel much sympathy for her… What about our Romeo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_59">
        <text>He completely lost his mind. He wanted to find the Wish Granter and wish her back, so he went past the Barrier. After a while, a few Freedomers saw his zombified ass marching back from the Barrier alongside a Monolith squad and some other zombies. All that was left of him was a shell of all of his humanity drained from him, like anyone else who tried to go past the Barrier before him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_6">
        <text>Hello, young man. If you share a bottle of vodka with me, I'll tell you an interesting story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_60">
        <text>Yeah, poor guy. All right, I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_61">
        <text>I'll tell you a story about two guys who met up in the “concentration camp” in the Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_62">
        <text>I'm all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_63">
        <text>The stalkers who end up in the concentration camp are usually those who have enough courage to visit the Garbage but not enough money to pay the bandits. Because these stalkers can't pay their “debt” for entering the bandits' territory, they're forced to work their asses off looking for anything valuable in the junk heaps. This, of course, stops eventually, when the bandits decide to kill their prisoners off. To this day, that death prison is full of stalkers who didn't have enough money to pay off the bandits. However, one time, two individuals met up inside that camp. If they were anywhere else, they'd just be fighting each other…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_64">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_65">
        <text>The two dudes that I'm talking about were a Dutyer and a Freedomer! I don't know why nobody was sent to rescue them. Perhaps it was because everyone thought they were dead or something. It's not that hard to believe, considering how many people go missing in the Zone every day. But that's not the gist of this story…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_66">
        <text>So what is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_67">
        <text>Those two decided to put their differences aside and plan an escape. They were the only two capable stalkers in the camp, and nobody expected that they would help each other. Strangely enough, they managed to form a pretty tight bond between each other… After a while of planning, the duo managed to escape from the bandits while they were doing another one of their archaeological digs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_68">
        <text>So how did they manage to escape?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_69">
        <text>I don't know for sure, but I heard that they used an artifact as weapon. They found it in one of the junk piles and did something to it that made it turn into an anomaly. They say that if you spin an artifact in your hand the right way and poke it in the right places, it will turn into an anomaly in which it was created. I can't say for sure because I have no idea how to do that, but I do know people who are experts in artifact handling.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_7">
        <text>I have a cool story for you. It starts with two good friends going into the Red Forest to look for very rare artifacts and to hunt some big game.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_70">
        <text>That's too bad…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_71">
        <text>Anyway, both of them managed to escape and ran off to the nearest Freedom outpost. They could see the light at the end of the tunnel, but alas, fate played a cruel trick on them. A Freedom sniper saw the Dutyer and took him out with one shot, a real tragedy. The Freedomer was devastated, and instead of running further away from the bandits, he just sat there crying and mourning his dead friend while the bandits were getting closer and closer. But you know what happened then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_72">
        <text>Stop making me guess. Just tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_73">
        <text>Everyone died except for the Freedomer who was on the run. The bandits and the Freedomers at the outpost started fighting until they killed each other while our escapee was weeping over his dead friend. When the smoke cleared, everyone was dead expect for him. I guess the Zone spared him for some reason. After that, he left Freedom and became a total hermit who now spends his time exploring caves and other abandoned places in the Zone. Who knew things would turn out this way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_74">
        <text>Yeah… Anyway, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_75">
        <text>Have you heard anything about the Duty zoo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_76">
        <text>Not much. I know it exists, but that's about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_77">
        <text>It's a really weird and creepy place. Stuffed mutant carcasses gawk at you with their empty eyes, all lined up one after the other. The guy who organized this zoo, Inquisitor, isn't exactly normal as well, as one might guess. I don't know how much you know about that zoo, but I bet you don't how and why that guy organized that zoo in the first place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_78">
        <text>All right, then. Tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_79">
        <text>Legend has it he had a very expensive old watch gifted to him either by his granddad or great granddad. I don't know for sure how he got that watch, but it's not that important. What's important is that this watch was very valuable, and therefore, the Inquisitor would carry this small little personal treasure with him at all times so that no one could steal it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_8">
        <text>Great start.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_80">
        <text>What does this have to do with the zoo, exactly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_81">
        <text>If you would stop interrupting, I would explain. So, one time, the guy ran into a bloodsucker in some forest, and he barely managed to fight it off. He survived, but so did the bloodsucker. Though, it managed to drag away the Inquisitor's watch in his teeth… Or rather his tentacles… Or even swallowed it whole… Heh, who knows… Either way, the Inquisitor lost his most valuable item that day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_82">
        <text>That's kind of funny…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_83">
        <text>He got really pissed that time; spent a few days with his shotgun searching for his lost watch. He was so angry he committed a bloodsucker genocide; killed at least a dozen bloodsuckers and sliced each of them open in hope of finding his lost wristwatch. He couldn't find anything, though, no matter how many he tracked down and killed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_84">
        <text>Shit happens…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_85">
        <text>However, since then, that guy had developed a knack for capturing and dissecting mutants. It's like he found some kind of a hidden talent. Some say that, to this day, he's looking for his lost watch, but no one knows for sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_86">
        <text>You know, if he would've put out a decent reward for that watch, then stalkers would've found it in no time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_87">
        <text>Well, after all these years, I do know for sure that sometimes, the bad things in life are fate's way of setting us on the right path. Just like the Inquisitor, who, after losing his watch, instead found his new talent.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_88">
        <text>I doubt that. Bad shit happens to me all the time, and it hasn't yielded any benefit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_89">
        <text>Have you ever been to the Duty zoo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_9">
        <text>They got pretty far, and they've collected a lot of good loot along the way, but greed got the better of them and they decided to keep pushing further. They went further, inch by inch, until, suddenly, they wandered right into the Brain Scorcher! You can be sure that those two were paralyzed from fear when they saw those antennas over the horizon…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_90">
        <text>I've heard about it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_91">
        <text>It doesn't matter that much, to be honest. The important part is that the zoo doesn't have a controller's stump in it, and by the looks of it all, it never will. Obtaining the intact body of a controller is just way too dangerous, and there's no way the general will allow to hunt such thing after the last incident.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_92">
        <text>So what's the point of this story?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_93">
        <text>The point is that, one time, Duty tried to obtain an intact carcass of a controller; the first one they could find. They wanted to shoot him with a sniper rifle between the eyes, thus leaving most of his body intact. They knew of a controller lair not far from their base in a nearby forest. The mutant was living in a small cave, and it would only come out at night to hunt for food. So the Dutyers decide it's an easy target and sniping it from far away wouldn't be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_94">
        <text>Yeah, I've hunted a few controllers for a few clients.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_95">
        <text>Then a squad of Duty soldiers made camp on top of a small hill not far from the controller's lair. Their plan was simple: wait for the controller to come out of his cave and then have the sniper shoot in the head. However, despite them waiting for a few days straight, the controller didn't come out of his lair; it's like he knew they were there. Slowly but surely, the squad was running out of food and water; however, the Dutyers didn't want get back to base empty-handed, so they decided to advance closer to the lair and try to lure the controller out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_96">
        <text>Bad move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_97">
        <text>That's for sure. They couldn't get into position in time when the controlled popped out. The poor bastards had their minds broken… The controller turned out to be an experienced one, and could easily sense that he was being watched by a group of stalkers. Everyone was zombified except for one guy who barely managed to escape, and even *he* suffered some serious brain damage. Since that hunting trip, that guy can't even speak normally. He constantly stutters; can't even finish a sentence.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_98">
        <text>Well, we all have our battle scars.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_99">
        <text>The gist of this story is that one of the stalkers that were zombified on that hunting trip was the brother of Krylov, the founder of Duty! When Krylov found about this, he strictly prohibited anybody from going anywhere in that lair. Truth is, Krylov doesn't want anyone killing his brother, because he's hoping that one day, the scientists can find the cure for zombification and save his sibling.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_0">
        <text>I'm here for the tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_1">
        <text>What about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_2">
        <text>I used to bring tools for Van.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_3">
        <text>Well, I don't have everything I need. If you find anything, bring it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_4">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_0">
        <text>I brought some tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_1">
        <text>Great… So, which ones are for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_11">
        <text>The ones for basic work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_111">
        <text>Great! Now I just need tools for fine work and calibration…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_12">
        <text>The ones for fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_121">
        <text>Great! Now I just need tools for basic work and calibration…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_13">
        <text>The ones for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_131">
        <text>Great! Now I just need tools for basic work and also ones for finer work…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_14">
        <text>Nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_141">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you'd bring tools for calibration, I'd be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_151">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you'd bring tools for fine work, I'd be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_161">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you'd bring tools for basic work, I'd be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_171">
        <text>Wow! Where the hell did you find them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_0">
        <text>If you need any tools, I can get them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_1">
        <text>That would be awesome. At the moment, it's like working in the Stone Age. The only difference is that the soldering iron has replaced the shaman's staff… If I had tools, I could do some top upgrades, and you better believe there'd be coin in it for you, too…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_11">
        <text>Okay. I'll look for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_12">
        <text>I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_3">
        <text>Good idea. I can do upgrades and you can earn cash…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_1">
        <text>Hey, you still need those tools?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_2">
        <text>Of course I do! Show me what you got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_3">
        <text>I've got tools for basic work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_4">
        <text>Great. Now I can start modifying weapons and armors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_5">
        <text>I've got tools for fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_6">
        <text>Great. Now I can start working on advanced upgrades.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_7">
        <text>I've got tools for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_8">
        <text>Excellent! Now I can turn your guns into killing machines… Ones that would put Sidorovich at your mercy. He he.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_9">
        <text>Nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_0">
        <text>Sidorovich, turn off the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_1">
        <text>All right. I'm sick of it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_2">
        <text>Sure. What, you've got a headache?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_3">
        <text>What, you don't like my music? So be it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_0">
        <text>Sidorovich, turn on the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_1">
        <text>You want some music? Sure, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_2">
        <text>All right. I'm also in the mood for some music.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_3">
        <text>Sure, here you go. Listen to your heart's content.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_0">
        <text>Anything interesting around here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1">
        <text>Not really. This place is mostly for rookies and people who come back from long trips looking to sell their loot. There's the army outpost south of here, so beware of them. North of here, there's a road leading to the Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11">
        <text>Tell me about the rookie village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_111">
        <text>There's not much to say. This is where most rookies start off, but after gaining some money and experience, they move further north. This place is sort of the main starting point for stalkers. Once they gain some experience and can earn a bit of cash, they move up north. There are some idiots who stay here because they can't handle themselves anywhere else in the Zone, but that's about it. From time to time, you can see an experienced stalker walking through here to sell their loot to Sidorovich and to get some rest in a quiet place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1111">
        <text>How about the military? Do they give you any trouble?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11111">
        <text>Not really. We have a non-verbal agreement: we don't bother them and they don't bother us. They say themselves that they'd rather not risk their lives fighting with stalkers who will mostly likely die in anomalies anyway. And it's the same for us: we'd rather not get in their way. When the military is on a raid or looking for something, we stay out of their way and let them do their job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_22">
        <text>Tell me about Sidorovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_222">
        <text>He is the go-to trader in the Cordon. His main clients are rookies and newcomers to the Zone. He has a lot of connections in and out of the Zone. They say he started trading in his youth, selling in college. He's highly respected by stalkers for his honest business, but at the same time, he's disliked for his greed and selfishness. One thing's for sure: he's given a lot of stalkers an opportunity to survive, and without him, they would probably be dead. He also has the richest business in Zone. If Sidorovich doesn't have something, then you're not going to find it anywhere else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_1">
        <text>I'm sort of the leader here. I teach the rookies how to live and survive in the Zone. As for why I'm here, I had enough time to wander around the Zone, and I'm sick of it. I came here to the Cordon to leave the Zone a long time ago, but since then, something's been holding me here. Like I'm under a spell or something. Every time I try to leave, something gets in the way; either the military is doing a raid or a blowout starts at the wrong time. Sometimes, I get offered a job so good, I can't refuse it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>Right now, we're in the Cordon. Down south, there's an army outpost, guarding the entrance to the Zone. Further north, there's a road leading to the Garbage. This place still somewhat resembles the outside world, since there are barely any artifacts or anomalies here. You can see some wild boars or dogs here every now and then, but other than that, it's totally quiet. Well… Quiet in comparison with the rest of the Zone, that is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This place is mostly for rookies and people who come back from long trips looking to sell their loot. There's the army outpost south of here, so beware of them. North of here, there's a road leading to the Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_8">
        <text>Lead the way.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
