<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>You scared me, Beast… You were out like a light for so long. We’re in deep shit right now…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>The hell… What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>I’m not sure, but it’s nothing good… That creature’s gotta be messing with us. We shouldn’t have gone there. The second I sent you that message, I got knocked out, and then I woke up here. I think this might be its den. I got excited at first because I thought I was finally out of that damn anomaly, but according to my PDA, we’re still in it. Just underground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>That’s sad news. But what kind of creature are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>I saw it a couple of times, but I didn’t say a word about it to anyone. They’d think I’m insane. But I’m not… Physically, it kind of looks like a bloodsucker, but it acts and talks like a normal human being, and it even wears clothes… I also saw an entry in my contacts named “Stronglav.” But it can’t be a human. And that’s not even the worst part: I tried to kill it, but as soon as I opened fire, it just laughed at me again and straight up vanished! It laughed at me, Beast! I just don’t know what to do…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>I saw it too; thought I was just seeing things. We need to find a way out of here, Markus, and we will find it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>You think I haven’t tried finding a way out?! There’s a ladder further into the cave, but if you try to climb it, there’s something that holds you back… Wait… You feel that?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>What am I supposed I feel?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_8">
        <text>That smell… It’s like something’s burning. It’s the same smell from when I first saw the creature. Don’t move! I think the resident of this lair is coming back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_9">
        <text>Fantastic…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_0">
        <text>You gave away our position. And you managed to grab the attention of those things…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_1">
        <text>I don’t know. I was just trying to kill it, but… What is even going on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_2">
        <text>How should I know? We have to get out of here fast. It’s gonna return soon…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_3">
        <text>Agreed. We’re done for if we just sit here. Let’s go look for a way out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_4">
        <text>I’m not in any condition to go exploring. It’s better if you go look for an exit while I cover you in case it comes back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_5">
        <text>Sounds good to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_6">
        <text>All right. Keep an eye out for the exit. Message me if you find anything. Don’t worry about me; I’ll make it out on my own. Now hurry!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_7">
        <text>Okay. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_0">
        <text>Beast, what was that? What is even going on?! It’s gone, but I fear it’ll be back soon…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_1">
        <text>I can’t give you an answer to that. I have no idea what’s going on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_2">
        <text>It laughed again. It might’ve seen us. We need to get out of here fast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_3">
        <text>Yeah. We can’t waste any time finding a way out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_4">
        <text>I’m not in any condition to go exploring. It’s better if you go look for an exit while I cover you in case it comes back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_5">
        <text>Sounds good to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_6">
        <text>All right. Keep an eye out for the exit. Message me if you find anything. Don’t worry about me; I’ll make it out on my own. Now hurry!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_7">
        <text>Okay. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_0">
        <text>Hey, Knucklehead, how are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_1">
        <text>Could be better… but I’ll hold up for now. Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_10">
        <text>Unfortunately, I have two doses of medicine left but three patients to treat. I decided to give one dose to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_11">
        <text>Beast, no. Don’t give it to me. The others have their whole lives ahead of them… I’ve already lived mine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_12">
        <text>I’ll find more medicine. We still have time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_13">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. Thank you for everything. But… we may as well say our goodbyes here. This may be the last time we speak.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_14">
        <text>No. It’s too early to say goodbye. I will find a cure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_2">
        <text>I’ve found some more medicine, but it’s not much.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_3">
        <text>Sorry, Knucklehead, but I’ve already given it to someone else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_4">
        <text>Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_5">
        <text>Beast, don’t worry too much about it. Each to his own fate. If I’m to die here, then so be it. You can’t blame yourself for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_6">
        <text>I’ll find more medicine. We still have time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_7">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. Thank you for everything. But… we may as well say our goodbyes here. This may be the last time we speak.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_8">
        <text>No. It’s too early to say goodbye. I will find a cure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_9">
        <text>That’s good to hear. But is it enough for everyone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_0">
        <text>How are you feeling, Markus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_1">
        <text>I wish I could say I’m feeling good, but that would be a load of bull. I’ve never felt this shitty in my life. I feel like I could die any minute… Did you find any medicine?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_2">
        <text>Yes. I’ve found a dose for you. It’ll help alleviate the symptoms.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_3">
        <text>Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_4">
        <text>Well, at least I have a fighting chance now. Give me the medicine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_5">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_6">
        <text>Thank you for trying to save my life, Beast. It means a lot to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_7">
        <text>It’s all I can do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_0">
        <text>How are you feeling, Cutter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_1">
        <text>Eh. I’ve been better… What’s up, though?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_2">
        <text>I’ve got some medicine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_3">
        <text>Never mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_4">
        <text>Oh, that’s music to my ears. How much did you find?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_5">
        <text>Only two doses. I’m giving one of them to you. That’s all I have, unfortunately.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_6">
        <text>So that means, after I take the dose, I either die or join the ranks of the healthy once more. Still, thank you, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_7">
        <text>Get well, Cutter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_10">
        <text>Well, there’s not a lot from choose from around here, so we’ll have to change up your usual diet. Go shoot down a few boars, then cook their meat at a campfire. I know it’s not exactly gourmet stuff, but at least you won’t be wandering on an empty stomach.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_11">
        <text>Need something, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_12">
        <text>All right. I guess that’s how it is… Is there anything else you wanted to tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_13">
        <text>We’re out of supplies. Savage said you’d be able to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_14">
        <text>This might be news to you, but we’re out of edible food. You had some canned food and sausages on you when you came here, but we’ve already eaten through all of it… And now we’ve had to resort to eating the local wildlife again; namely, boars and pseudodogs. Of course, there’s a chance of food poisoning, but if you cook it up right, it won’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_15">
        <text>Never imagined myself eating the wildlife of the Zone, but we don’t have much of a choice…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_16">
        <text>So how do I prepare the meat properly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_17">
        <text>I’ll tell you what: go cook a piece of meat. I’ll check it out myself and tell you if you did anything wrong. Also, keep some of the boar fat; it’s one of the tastiest parts from the animal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_18">
        <text>Okay, Knucklehead. You got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_2">
        <text>Wait. I know you… You’re that mercenary, right? The one that helped me hunt down that psy-dog in the Cordon?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_20">
        <text>Got some cooked boar meat yet, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_21">
        <text>Yep. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_23">
        <text>Well… You did good on cooking this. Perfectly edible. There’s pretty much no chance of getting poisoned from this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_24">
        <text>Thanks for the comment. I’ll keep it in mind. Getting this meat should be a lot easier than other types of food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_25">
        <text>Don’t mention it, merc. I hope you’ll remember how to cook meat properly. It’ll be useful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_26">
        <text>I’ll remember; don’t worry. I’ve got to go now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_28">
        <text>Need something, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_3">
        <text>Yup. Small world, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_30">
        <text>Need something, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_4">
        <text>Sure is. You guys sure caused some mayhem back there… My lips are sealed, though, so don’t worry about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_5">
        <text>I was only doing my job. Nothing more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_6">
        <text>If you say so… Well, anyway, I won’t take up any more of your time. See you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_7">
        <text>Yeah. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_9">
        <text>Need something, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_0">
        <text>I’m ready to hunt the chimera.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_1">
        <text>Excellent. We can move out right now. The chimera should be in the bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_2">
        <text>Hold on just a second. I told you the chimera only goes inside the bunker at nighttime. It’s too early right now. Come back around two in the morning.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_3">
        <text>Let’s go, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_4">
        <text>I’ll return to you later, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_10">
        <text>Okay. That’s all I needed to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_11">
        <text>The chimera only enters the bunker at nighttime, so we may as well go right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_12">
        <text>Then come see me around two AM. That’s when the chimera tends to be there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_14">
        <text>Let’s go now, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_15">
        <text>All right. I’ll talk to you again at night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_17">
        <text>There. We can finally stop worrying about that thing sneaking into our base. Thanks for the help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_18">
        <text>Don’t mention it. Another dead mutant is good for all of us. You can bet I’ll be sleeping easier tonight, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_19">
        <text>Yeah. By the way, I bet you’ve noticed that our food sources are running out fast. However, I’ve been trying out a new food source for about a week; haven’t told the others about it yet. They’ll probably be disgusted at the thought of trying it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_2">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Heard you found Scavenger… Sucks that he turned out to be such a piece of shit, but at least that’s over with. Anyway, I needed to talk to you about something important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_20">
        <text>Well? Get to the point. What’s this food source of yours?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_21">
        <text>Well, while the others have been eating their canned goods, I’ve been eating the local wildlife. Naturally, there’s a chance of getting poisoned at any moment, but if you cook the meat the right way, it shouldn’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_22">
        <text>Nothing wrong with that. A mutated boar’s not exactly as tasty as a stuffed rabbit, but it’s edible. Wouldn’t be the first time I try it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_23">
        <text>I had a feeling you’d get me, Beast. But there’s more than just the boars: I’ve been trying the dog meat lately. Very different taste; it’s also nowhere as hard as boar meat. Listen, how about we try to change your diet? Go shoot down a few boars, then cook their meat at a campfire. I know it’s not exactly gourmet stuff, but at least you won’t be wandering on an empty stomach.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_24">
        <text>Yeah, sure. I was getting hungry anyway.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_25">
        <text>Listen, you mind bringing me a piece as well? All this hunting’s got me feeling pretty hungry. Also, keep some of the boar fat; it’s one of the tastiest parts from the animal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_26">
        <text>Sure thing, Knucklehead. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_28">
        <text>So, Beast, you bring some of those cuts of meat yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_29">
        <text>Yeah. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_3">
        <text>Let’s have it. I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_30">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_31">
        <text>Great. Oh, you cooked it right. Just what we need right now. Thanks!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_32">
        <text>Thanks for the advice. Around here, meat is one of the easier food sources to get a hold of.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_33">
        <text>By the way, Markus told me to tell you to see him. When you have a free moment, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_34">
        <text>All right. I’ll go talk to him. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_36">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_37">
        <text>By the way, Markus told me to tell you to see him. When you have a free moment, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_38">
        <text>All right. I’ll go talk to him. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_4">
        <text>We’ve got a serious problem on our hands. A couple of days ago, I saw a chimera near our base. I was by myself and had almost no ammo on me, so I didn’t shoot. Good thing it didn’t see me. It’s a dangerous creature, and tracking it down will be difficult. And just imagine what’ll happen if it wanders into our camp at night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_5">
        <text>So what do you suggest?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_6">
        <text>We need to kill it. We’re more likely to do any damage during nighttime, when the mutant goes to sleep in the northern bunker. The two of us can handle it without a problem; it won’t know what hit it. What do you think of my plan? Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_7">
        <text>Just the two of us? Wouldn’t it be safer with more people?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_8">
        <text>We’re the only ones with enough ammo for the job. The others are short of any rounds. Don’t worry; I’ve dealt with with these creatures before. We’ll do fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_0">
        <text>About your gun…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_1">
        <text>So? Do you have it or not?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_2">
        <text>Yeah. I have it. Also, I ran into the bloodsucker that scared you earlier; it was waiting there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_3">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_4">
        <text>It didn’t scare me… It’s just that things screwed up. Had no choice but to run.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_5">
        <text>Spare me the excuses. I don’t care whether it scared you or not. Here’s your gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_6">
        <text>Thanks. Now I can go on raids with the guys and not stay behind. Plus, it’s a lot safer here when you have a gun. Here’s a small reward for your good work. I don’t need the money anymore, but maybe you’ll need it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_7">
        <text>Thanks. I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_0">
        <text>So, soldier, tell me: where’d you drop your gun? Can you at least estimate its location?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_1">
        <text>I can show you the exact place, actually. I know where the gun is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_2">
        <text>So, what’s the problem, then? You can go get the gun yourselves. You’d already be done by now, and you wouldn’t be taking up my time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_3">
        <text>See, here’s the thing… I didn’t lose the gun. I threw it away.\n \nWhen I was scouting, I was attacked by a bloodsucker. I fired at it, but then, my gun jammed. I had no time to reload it, so I threw it at the bloodsucker, then shot it with my pistol a couple of times and bolted. I can’t tell the general I ran away from a mutant, and taking one of those things on with a pistol is suicide.\n \nHelp me out here, stalker, and return the rifle to me; I’ll owe you greatly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_4">
        <text>Well, what can you do? All right. I’ll look for your rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Stop right there! Who are you? What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Take it easy, lieutenant. I’m a mercenary—callsign Beast—sent here to restart a transformer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hmm. Let’s say I believe you… How’d you open the cage door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Someone helped me open it. What about you, though? How long have you been stuck here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_4">
        <text>You think I’m gonna tell you everything just like that? Go talk to the general. Maybe he’ll talk to you…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Okay. I’ll speak to your general, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey, merc… Give me… some water. I won’t last much longer without some water…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_1">
        <text>What the hell? I can’t. I can’t walk up to you; something’s teleporting me back. What’s happening here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_2">
        <text>Most likely an anomaly… Just really small. I can’t get out of here, and I’ve run out of food and water. And the guys… One of them disappeared somewhere—and I hope he was able to get out of this damn trap—but the rest… Seems the colonel lost his mind. He started shooting the others, and then shot himself in the head. And now I’m left alone…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_3">
        <text>Hold on a second. I was here with you just a moment ago, and everything was fine. You sent me a message just a moment ago. How did all of this happen so quickly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_4">
        <text>A moment ago?… It’s been almost a week since the moment I sent you that message. After that, I tried to make contact with somebody, but my PDA was unable to send anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_5">
        <text>Almost a week?! What the fuck is going on in this cursed Zone? How’s that possible? What is going on around here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_6">
        <text>Right now, that’s the last thing I care about… Get out of here, merc. Leave me alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_7">
        <text>Goodbye, general.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Well, hello there, stalker. Say, do you have any food you could spare? We’re all tired of eating the radioactive mutant meat around here. Some *real* food would be nice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_12">
        <text>No, general. I could eat a horse myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Yeah. Didn’t expect you to give it for free, so I have a suggestion: we were on a raid and found a couple of artifacts. Our intention was to give them to the scientists, but we’ll trade them for any food: canned goods, sausages, bread; doesn’t matter as long as it’s real food. But we need no less than eight different pieces. That should suffice. Do we have a deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_14">
        <text>All right, general. I’ll try to find some food for you. I’ll be back soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_15">
        <text>No. Can’t help you with anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_17">
        <text>So, Beast, are you gonna help us with our food situation?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_19">
        <text>So, found any rations?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, stalker. What the hell is going on in here? Where are we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_20">
        <text>Here you go, general. Had to pull my socks up to get a hold of this stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_21">
        <text>I can imagine that. Right; you’ve held up your end of the bargain. Good work. You can make some pretty good profit off of them if you ever get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_23">
        <text>Wonderful. Though I’m not so sure we’ll ever get out of here… Now goodbye, general.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Hold on, stalker. We’ve got something else for you. During our last sortie, Bunchuk lost his rifle. Help him find it; you understand that things are hard for a soldier without his weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_25">
        <text>Sure. Where did he drop it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Go ask him. He’ll tell you everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_27">
        <text>Okay. I’ll go ask him for the details.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Hello, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_3">
        <text>I’d love to know that myself. Looks like we’re trapped in some sort of anomaly… Do you remember how you got here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_4">
        <text>What kind of anomaly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_5">
        <text>A spatial anomaly. You’re not the only ones here: there’s a group of stalkers nearby. They’ve been inside the anomaly for a while now; over two months. So, do you remember how you ended up in here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_6">
        <text>God damn it. Another “gift” from the Zone… Just what we needed. All I remember is that we were walking through the Agroprom, searching for some artifacts. We saw a bright light, and then, we woke up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Okay. Well, I’ve gotta go find a way to turn the electricity back on around here. I’ll talk to you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Hello, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_0">
        <text>Finally starting to see how grave your situation is, are we? I’m only gonna ask you one more fucking time: where is the Compass?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_1">
        <text>God damn it! You know me, you psycho. I don’t lie; especially not about things like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_2">
        <text>Times change, and so do people… And now your only friends are a bunch of rotten stalkers who got stuck inside the spatial anomaly. I don’t even know what to expect from you anymore. I’ve had enough of you; Obscurant is gonna take you out to get some fresh air. Good night!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_3">
        <text>Hold on! I’m not done yet…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_0">
        <text>Rise and shine! Welcome back to the real world, dickhead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_1">
        <text>What the hell is going on? What are you doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_10">
        <text>Wrong answer. I’ll give you one more chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_11">
        <text>I’m telling you: we don’t have the artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_2">
        <text>I came here to check up on you. Jackal was beginning to worry where you’d gone off to.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_3">
        <text>Surely, you understand what you’ve gotten yourself into? How are you going to get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_4">
        <text>Why would we want to leave? We just arrived. This place is pretty nice, I’ve gotta say. We might stay a while. But if we don’t, we’ve always got this handy scanner to lead us right out. Oh, before I forget, I’ll nab yours so you don’t try anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_5">
        <text>Why the hell did you even come here? To save me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_6">
        <text>You think too highly of yourself, Beast. Think: why would we save you? We’re on a mission here: to retrieve the Compass from you and your friends. *Then* we’ll get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_7">
        <text>What are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_8">
        <text>The Compass is an artifact. Don’t act like you don’t know about it. You should’ve found it long ago. So, you hand over the artifact and you can live out your days here in peace.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_9">
        <text>But we don’t have that artifact. And if we did, we sure wouldn’t give it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_0">
        <text>You need any help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_1">
        <text>Glad you asked, merc. The gasoline in our generator is running out, and there’s nothing left in our jerry cans. No fuel means no electricity, which means no light in our base… and no light means we’re dead if any mutant or hostile stalker decides to pay us a visit at night. Try to find us some gas; in exchange, I can give you a couple of bandages and a medkit. I’d give you more, but you know how bad our conditions are.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_2">
        <text>Sure. I’ll try to find some gasoline.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_3">
        <text>Sorry, but I’m occupied right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_4">
        <text>I need gasoline for the generator. No fuel means no electricity, which means no light in our base… and no light means we’re dead if any mutant or hostile stalker decides to pay us a visit at night. Try to find us some gas in exchange, I can give you a couple of bandages and a medkit. I’d give you more, but you know how bad our conditions are.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_5">
        <text>All right. I’ll try to find some gasoline for the generator.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_6">
        <text>Sorry, but I’m still busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_7">
        <text>I don’t really need anything right now, but thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_10">
        <text>If you can befriend a Dutyer, a mercenary shouldn’t be a problem…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_11">
        <text>Snake’s a good guy. We’ve found some common ground, and places like this force you to work together with whoever’s around. I’m far more concerned with getting out of here than fighting in some endless faction war.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_13">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m listening…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_15">
        <text>Find the fuel yet, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_16">
        <text>Yup. Actually managed to find a fuel canister here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_17">
        <text>Not quite yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_18">
        <text>Best news I’ve heard all week. At least now we won’t have to worry about electricity for a while. Give it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_19">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_2">
        <text>Focus on the zombies, merc. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_20">
        <text>Thanks, merc. That’s more than enough. You saved us big time. Like I promised, here are two bandages and a medkit as a token of appreciation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_21">
        <text>No need to thank me. We’re all helping each other out here. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_23">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m listening…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_24">
        <text>All right. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_3">
        <text>Okay. I’ll be on my way, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_5">
        <text>Go get some sleep or something, merc… I’m not really in the mood to talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_7">
        <text>Hello, merc. I’ll introduce myself… The others call me Sledgehammer. I was a member of Freedom before I got stuck here; not anymore, though. After some time here, I’ve had a different outlook on life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_8">
        <text>Ah. Well, my name is Beast, but I assume you already know that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_9">
        <text>I’m not going to lie: I’m not exactly enthusiastic about you being here. Your people were a constant threat to us. Had you been here a few months ago, we wouldn’t be having this conversation… but like I said, this place has changed me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_0">
        <text>Where the hell were you, merc? I was tired of waiting for you all by myself…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_1">
        <text>Where are the others?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_2">
        <text>They left early. I stayed behind to wait for you. Where are those Duty soldiers you told us about? Aren’t they coming with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_3">
        <text>Well… They’re dead. Where is the exit taking us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_4">
        <text>Darn it. Rest in peace… We don’t know where the exit’s going to drop us. Anyway, are you ready to leave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_5">
        <text>As ready as ever. Time to leave this godforsaken anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_6">
        <text>Just a heads-up: people tend to pass out when they leave these things. Just warning you; you need to be ready for anything. Now follow my path exactly and everything should be fine. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_7">
        <text>Okay. Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_0">
        <text>Thank you, young man. I’m getting too old for this shit… but more importantly, wildlife in the Zone has been going absolutely crazy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_1">
        <text>Don’t mention it, old man. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_2">
        <text>I’m Forester. I reside in the Red Forest—have you heard of it? I got your requests for help on my receiver, so I came out here to help you, using my Compass. Are you the one who called for help? Or is there anyone else here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_3">
        <text>Wait. You came here to save us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_4">
        <text>That’s right, sonny. That’s why I brought the Compass with me. It’ll help you get out of this trap, along with anyone else, if there are more people here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_5">
        <text>I’m not the only person stuck here. There’s a hideout full of stalkers nearby, further to the north, and a squad of Duty members stuck underground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_6">
        <text>Then lead me there so I can meet the rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_7">
        <text>Sure. Follow me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_10">
        <text>All right. Well, enough about that. We’ve gotta bury the bodies from the bunker and pay our respects to Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_11">
        <text>Yeah. Let’s get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Who’d you bring this time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_14">
        <text>This is Forester. He’s going to guide us out of this anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_15">
        <text>Are you serious?! I need to talk to him right this instant. While I do that, though, there’s another signal I need you to check out. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_16">
        <text>Another one?… From where?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_17">
        <text>It’s around the same place you were before. I’ll send you the coordinates now. Go there and check it out. I’ll go talk to Forester.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_18">
        <text>Right. Send me the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_19">
        <text>Okay… There. You should have them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_2">
        <text>Excellent work, Beast! Now we have light. How did it go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_20">
        <text>I’ll be going, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_22">
        <text>Beast, let’s talk later. Go check out the signal first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_24">
        <text>Hey, Beast, any news? Did you find any medicine that’ll help our guys? They’re not in good condition; if they don’t get any help, they’ll probably be dead within a couple of days.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_25">
        <text>I did find some medicine, but only for one time, which won’t be enough for three people. I only have two doses, and they may or may not have any effect… All because we’ve been eating mutants. We should’ve known it was a bad idea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_26">
        <text>The important thing right now is not to give up. Right now, more than ever, we have to keep fighting. But… I could never choose who gets to live and who gets to die. Can you make that decision?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_27">
        <text>All right, Savage. I’ll hand out the medicine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_28">
        <text>Thank you. I couldn’t do it myself. Those of us left are Knucklehead, Markus, and Cutter. Think about it and make your decision, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_29">
        <text>I’ll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_3">
        <text>When I was in the underground tunnels, I found a squad of Duty members. Five men…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_31">
        <text>Did you give them the medicine yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_32">
        <text>Not quite yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_34">
        <text>You’ve been gone for a few days. Where did you go for so long?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_35">
        <text>I’ve been looking for a cure the whole time. I even slept in the barn just in case I found more survivors…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_36">
        <text>I’m sorry: you weren’t able to save everyone. Knucklehead passed away last night. We buried him not far from the base…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_37">
        <text>And I never even told him goodbye…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_38">
        <text>Neither did I. The whole time, I was hoping he’d get better…\n \nNow, you said you were looking for medicine. Did you find any more ampules? Markus and Cutter are both feeling better already, although they still need treatment. Oh, and before I forget, we found this when searching through Knucklehead’s stuff. I think it’s for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_39">
        <text>Sadly, I didn’t find anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_4">
        <text>Jesus Christ… Do you know how long they’ve been down there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_40">
        <text>That’s unfortunate. Let’s hope that one vaccination will be enough to get rid of the sickness. Now, you should get some rest. I need some alone time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_41">
        <text>Yeah. See you around, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_5">
        <text>No. They only arrived in the anomaly recently.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_6">
        <text>Did you tell them about us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_7">
        <text>I did, though I didn’t suggest cooperating with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_8">
        <text>Well, if they don’t want to join us, then I see no reason to ask them. We just need to make sure they don’t try anything once they run out of provisions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_9">
        <text>I wouldn’t worry about that. We fought the mercenaries, and we’ll fight these guys if necessary.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_0">
        <text>How are you, Beast? How’s Screw? Is he all right? I’m guessing Marcus already told you what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_1">
        <text>Yeah. Everything’s all right. I took out the mercenaries in the barn. Screw’s safe; he’s with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_2">
        <text>Sucks that Hatchet got away with his men. I think they’re out of the anomaly by now. We’ll make them pay for what happened to Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_3">
        <text>The son of a bitch got my decoder, too…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_4">
        <text>So you found it after all? But it doesn’t make much of a difference now… Okay, listen. I have an idea. Already discussed it with the guys, so now I’ll take it up with you: it’s best for us to move inside this bunker. The door will keep us safe from any emissions. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_5">
        <text>Good idea. After what happened, we’d be mad to return to the barn.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_6">
        <text>Glad we’re all on the same page. By the way, those mercenaries from earlier tried to make an escape. We had to kill them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_7">
        <text>They made their choice. Did Markus tell you that he found the key to the storage room? We now have ammo.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_8">
        <text>Yeah. He told me already. That’s like music to my ears. We have something more important to talk about, though:\n \nWe have to find a way to turn on the electricity. When you turned off the lights in the barn, you must’ve shut them off here, too. I’ve already messaged Screw and asked him to turn the lights back on, but it didn’t work. There must be a transformer around here somewhere that needs restarting. Cutter and I looked around and found some blueprints; we found that there’s a transformer not far from the barn, underground. I’ll leave you to turn it back on.\n \nThe door to the underground is locked, but Screw assured me that he’ll pick the lock. He’ll be waiting for you there, so you should go and meet up with him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_9">
        <text>Sure. I’ll get right on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>What the hell happened here? Did you kill these guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>It wasn’t me. It was that Stronglav thing. It made them shoot themselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>Fuck, man! It can do that?! We’re lucky to be alive… We have to free the other guys. I have a plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>And what’s your plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>The mercenaries captured a few of our guys, and they’re holding them in the barn. First, we need to regain control there. Then, we return here and free the rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>Yeah. I don’t think we have any other options. Also, how did you manage to get out of the hole?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>Simple: I followed you after you climbed out, and I managed to break free. I was so happy I could die… But enough about that. Let’s focus: first, we need some ammo, and I know where to get it. Follow me; I’ll explain everything when we get there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>Okay. Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_2">
        <text>All right. This place is an old army weapon stockpile. I don’t know how long these weapons have been stored here, but let’s hope that they’re all in good condition.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_3">
        <text>How are you gonna open that door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_4">
        <text>I found the key while I was inside Stronglav’s lair. I’ve already taken some stuff for myself. You, too, should take a look inside; find yourself something useful.\n \nHere’s the key. Take whatever you need, and I’ll wait out here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_5">
        <text>Got it. Wait for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_7">
        <text>Get a move on, Beast. Take whatever you need, and I’ll wait out here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_8">
        <text>Got it. Wait for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_0">
        <text>So, you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_1">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll let you have the key back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_2">
        <text>Okay, so, listen up: most of the mercs are in the barn. They’re holding Screw hostage; no idea why. But we’ve gotta save him. The best option we have right now is to cut the power to the barn and take them out in the darkness. How’s that? And can I ask you something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_3">
        <text>That’s a pretty solid plan. Though, I don’t think this is the best time to be asking questions…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_4">
        <text>It’s about what we’re doing right now. Are you sure you can take on a group of mercenaries, considering you know many of them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_5">
        <text>I can. I didn’t make friends in the Syndicate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_6">
        <text>That might be the case, but we have no choice. We have to do this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_7">
        <text>Hmm. All right, then. Well, we’d better get going. I’ll go help the rest. You tackle that barn problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_8">
        <text>You’re right about that… Well, we’d better get going. I’ll go help the rest. You tackle that barn problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_9">
        <text>You got it. I’ll join you when I’ve finished up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_10">
        <text>When you’re ready, talk to Snake. He’ll send you the coordinates on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_13">
        <text>No time for chit-chat, Beast. Let’s focus on the flesh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_15">
        <text>Hey, Beast! I’ve noticed you’re quite the detective: you tracked down the chimera with Knucklehead, you found Scavenger, and you discovered all the nasty things he was up to behind our backs.</text>				
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_16">
        <text>What’s your point?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_17">
        <text>We need your help. Before Savage started leading the group, we had a leader whose callsign was Shell. He was a good man, but he went missing…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_18">
        <text>How long ago did he go missing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_19">
        <text>About a month ago. It’s foolish to believe that he’s still alive, but I caught his PDA signal a couple of days ago, though it disappeared after a split second. It was near the abandoned shelter. I looked everywhere inside the basement for him, but there wasn’t a single trace of him there. Maybe he was using teleporters inside this place like how Scavenger was. He might be looking for a way out, if there’s even an exit… Try to find him, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, this is important shit! Those zombies are closing in, and you and Mosquito are the only ones who have any ammo. Kill those braindead creatures and we’ll talk afterwards.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_20">
        <text>Hmm… And you think he could survive on his own?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Maybe. He was the toughest guy we had, with an exoskeleton and a PKM. He had plenty of supplies with him on the trip he disappeared on, too. Shell had a silver tongue and a knack for getting people to put their differences aside. He helped us found our group; an impressive feat, considering most of us were from opposing factions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_22">
        <text>All right. I’ll keep an eye out for Shell. Maybe he’s somewhere around here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Hello, merc! I haven’t had the chance to introduce myself: I’m Markus. We’re really glad you helped us out. At least now we have some ammunition to spare, which is amazing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_25">
        <text>Nice to meet you. The people around here call me Beast. But you should know that already…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Yes, I do. This place we’re stuck in—is it a “spatial anomaly”? There should be to be a way out of here, and it’s up to us to find it… Anyways, if you’re not too busy right now, do you think you could help me with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_27">
        <text>I’m free. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_28">
        <text>Sorry. My hands are full right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Nothing too difficult. I need a Wrenched artifact. It can cleanse radiation from any organism. It comes from gravitational anomalies, which there are a lot of nearby. I’m almost out of ammo, though, so I don’t want to tempt fate. I have another artifact here I can give to you as a reward; it’s radioactive, but it has some useful properties to it as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_30">
        <text>All right. I’ll go look for a Wrenched.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_32">
        <text>So, are you free or still busy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_33">
        <text>Not any more. What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_34">
        <text>Yeah. I’m busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_36">
        <text>So, Beast, how’s your artifact hunt going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_37">
        <text>I found it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_38">
        <text>I haven’t found one yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_39">
        <text>That’s great! Now I won’t have to worry about antirads anymore… It’s been two weeks since I ran out of them. The artifact is gonna do a better job at it. Thanks, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Me and a few of the other guys were gonna go looking for some food. We need your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_40">
        <text>Here: your artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_41">
        <text>And this is for you. I’m very grateful for what you’ve done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_42">
        <text>I’m glad to help anytime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_44">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_46">
        <text>Beast, you get any leads on where Shell’s been?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_47">
        <text>Yeah. I found Shell. He was zombified, though. Had to put him out of his misery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_48">
        <text>Not quite yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_49">
        <text>God… If only he had brought someone else with him. He’d probably still be alive by now. How did you even manage to take him down? Wasn’t he clad in an exoskeleton?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_5">
        <text>What exactly do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_50">
        <text>It wasn’t easy, but I did it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_51">
        <text>Was he carrying anything of note?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_52">
        <text>Just this dog tag. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_53">
        <text>Yup. That’s it, all right… Thank you for your help, Beast. Here’s a reward for the hard work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_54">
        <text>I try to help out whenever I can. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_56">
        <text>Hey, Beast! What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Right, so, Cutter told me he saw a herd of flesh nearby. Since we’re out of food, I thought we might hunt them down and cook them. Will you help the guys take them out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_60">
        <text>All right. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Sure. I’ll help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_8">
        <text>You’ll be going with me, Snake, and Sledgehammer. First, though—real quick—I’ve gotta go to another area, but once I’m done, I’ll meet up with you. Make sure they don’t fight each other in the meantime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Okay. Send me the coordinates to these flesh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_10">
        <text>I’ll help. Don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_11">
        <text>So, Beast, have you found that SVD ammo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Yep. Here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_13">
        <text>No. Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Wow! Didn’t think you’d find it around here, but you’ve proved me wrong… Great work, Beast!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_15">
        <text>And what about the reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_16">
        <text>Here, just like I promised.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Great. I’ll go now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_19">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Listen, Beast: thanks for clearing out those zombies. But uh, are you busy right now? I kind of need your help with something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_4">
        <text>I’m free right now. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_5">
        <text>So, are you free or still busy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Not any more. What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Well, I have an SVD stored nearby. It’s a good rifle, but I have no ammo for it. Could you find some ammo for it? Just one pack is enough for me right now. In exchange, I’ll make it worth your while with an AK magazine with some cash on top. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_8">
        <text>Yeah. I’m busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Sorry. My hands are full right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_0">
        <text>Well, look who it is!… Hello, Creature! What the fuck are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_1">
        <text>I could say the same god damn thing to you, you moron. Do you even know just how much you’ve fucked up by coming here? If you don’t get out of my way right now, you’re a dead man. I have nothing to lose.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_2">
        <text>Well, someone’s acting tough, saying all this hard shit… But you’ll be singing a different tune in just a second. Oh, and before I forget, the Syndicate says hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_3">
        <text>Oh, you mother—</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_0">
        <text>Thanks for saving my ass as usual, Beast. Are these guys really here just for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_1">
        <text>No. They’re here for some special artifact called the Compass; they think we possess it. Those motherfuckers killed Sledgehammer because of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_2">
        <text>Fuck this, man… That means there are more mercs out there. They must be holding our guys hostage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_3">
        <text>Yeah. Marcus is setting up for a plan to free the rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_4">
        <text>Then you should go help him with that. Those guys screwed me up pretty bad, so I’d better just stay here. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_5">
        <text>Okay. Stay here. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_0">
        <text>Oh, you’re finally here. Did Savage fill you in on what you need to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_1">
        <text>He did. Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_2">
        <text>Then let’s get started. I’ll open the entrance for you and head back to base on my own.  Unfortunately, I’m not going down with you into the underground; there’s no telling what’s down there. You’ll do fine without me. You ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_3">
        <text>Yeah. Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_10">
        <text>I’ve been tasked with finding a battery for a similar radio transmitter. Give it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_12">
        <text>Yeah, merc? What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_13">
        <text>Then give the battery to the soldier. I’m gonna catch my breath in the meantime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_14">
        <text>All right. I’ll be going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_2">
        <text>Thanks for the help, man. I think we can talk now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_3">
        <text>You said mercenaries were after you. How come?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_4">
        <text>Well, basically, I was given an assignment by the scientists. They want me to try out a radio transmitter. Let’s see if I remember their words correctly: “Just try it out and see if you pick up anything.” I gave the thing a twist and happened to pick up a mercenary channel… and man, they were having some serious negotiations. I heard it all; my jaw was on the floor. Didn’t move a muscle. Then, the mercs finally got that someone was listening in on them, and ordered everyone to sweep the area. So that’s when this whole shitstorm started. The place was crawling with mercs within minutes, all because of my screwup. I randomly happened upon an anomaly; good thing it wasn’t a whirligig or anything… No, it was some kind of space anomaly. And now I’m here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_5">
        <text>Do you still have the transmitter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_6">
        <text>I have it, but it looks like it broke when I was sent here. When I was running away from the mercs, I threw it into my backpack. When I left the anomaly, I landed on it. Now the transmitter is more of a puzzle game than a working machine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_7">
        <text>Are any of the parts salvageable?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_8">
        <text>All right. Let me have the battery for now. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_9">
        <text>A couple of busted microchips… and a battery that I could give you, if you have any use for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Who the hell are you, God damn it? Tell me or I’ll shoot!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Calm down. I came here to help. Name’s Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_10">
        <text>Don’t get hysterical. Calm down or I’ll put you down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_11">
        <text>You’re dead meat, merc… All of you are dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Your choice…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_2">
        <text>“Here to help,” huh? I don’t need to hear that bullshit from you! What the hell do you mercs want from me, anyway? I didn’t hear anything! Go away!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_3">
        <text>“You mercs”? I’m the only mercenary in here. I’m alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Let’s say you’re not lying… Wait. You said “in here.” What do you mean by that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Oh, man, you sure are unlucky. You’ve ended up in a spatial anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_6">
        <text>What? Damn it! I have to get out of here right now! Those mercenaries are gonna come back! They must’ve seen where I ended up…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Don’t panic. There’s a safe space nearby. Let’s go there and talk everything out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_8">
        <text>Is it far? Are there other stalkers there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Like I said: we’ll talk about it when we’re there. Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_0">
        <text>You are very fortunate that the phantom didn’t take you with it, mercenary. Had you not passed its trial, it would’ve stopped you from ever waking up again. Phantoms are very deceptive, but that which fuels them is much more dangerous.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_1">
        <text>Wait. What are you saying? Who are you, even?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_2">
        <text>That is not important right now. You must stay away from any phantoms; interacting with them is tempting fate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_3">
        <text>What’s happening here? What phantoms?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_4">
        <text>What you saw here last night was a phantom. They are the souls of dead people or animals. They appear at the site of their death, or close to their dead body. They normally aren’t dangerous, but the phantom you saw was made specifically to lure people into a trap…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_5">
        <text>The other person must have failed, then. Though I escaped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_6">
        <text>Fortune favors you, mercenary, but fate has its eye on you now. You must be vigilant and rely on your skills and intuition more than your luck. Do not let yourself be fooled once more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_7">
        <text>How do you know all of this, old man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_8">
        <text>I know many things. Heed my advice, as you are already in danger. Stay alert.\n \nFarewell, mercenary. I hope we see each other again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_9">
        <text>What?! Hey! Wait! How are you going to leave the anomaly?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_0">
        <text>I… I can… do it… This th—iiing…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_1">
        <text>Hey, man, are you all right? What’s going on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_10">
        <text>I can’t remember much… The Red Forest, scary. Scary place, so we took a shortcut through the Red F-Forest… Hole in one of the fences let us sneak past the Monolith patrols. First went Savage; next, good old Spotty; and finally, Hunchback, God bless him. Wait, wait, Hunch, can you get through?! Wait, can you…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_11">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_12">
        <text>I-I don’t… remember… The voice! The voice, it it it spoke to me! It got right in my head! A terrible voice spoke directly to my brain, saying stuff… Hot voice. Scorching all of my brain. Terrible… Terrible… Terrible! You cannot go there! A wild pain reminds me, sounds like that bastard at the bar… You… You can’t go there! I go where I want…! But you, you can’t. The wild pain will crush your skull and squeeze your b-brains out like lemonade…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_13">
        <text>All right, all right. I won’t. You’re safe here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_14">
        <text>Whispers, whispers, creak of swings… It’s in my head, over and over… the voice w-w-wants me to become… one of those… monsters! *I won’t!* I… can’t… please. Take this. B-Before I… lose it… give it to Baldy. Make sure it… gets to my wife and my kids. My beautiful kids… Tell them I love them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_15">
        <text>I will. Rest easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_2">
        <text>I-I’m fiiiiine… I can hold it together… Right…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_3">
        <text>Hey, can you hear me? Is everything okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_4">
        <text>No! NO! I won’t let it be with me!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_5">
        <text>Jesus Christ…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_6">
        <text>My skull! It’s being ripped out of my fucking head! Ahhh!… Sp-Spotty… That’s what… They called me. Spotty. Hunchback! *Hunchback!* He died! The radiation finally got to him…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_7">
        <text>Hunchback? Who was that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_8">
        <text>A stalker… A friend. Savage, Hunchback, and good o-ol’ Spotty went near the Scorcher. Scientists told us about cert-aiiIIINNN!!… times… we could pass through… AH! SKULL! S-Skull…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_9">
        <text>What did you do there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_10">
        <text>First, we have to clear out the zombies nearby, or else they’ll take us with them. Do you have any ammo for a Kalashnikov?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_11">
        <text>Yeah. Had some on me before I woke up here…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_12">
        <text>Share two packs with me. I’ll give them to Mosquito; he’s a good shot. With him at your side, you’ll get out in one piece.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_13">
        <text>Okay. Here’s the ammo.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_14">
        <text>Yeah… This is bad.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_15">
        <text>We have to find Scavenger. We won’t last long here without him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_17">
        <text>Welcome back from the world beyond, buddy… Nobody was thinking you’d be coming back to your senses; you were unconscious for four whole days.\n \nHmm… That blowout messed you up bad. Nobody would’ve survived that. But you’re alive. I don’t know whether that’s a good thing or a bad thing. The fact remains that this is very strange, though. Very strange indeed.\n \nBut enough about that. You seem all right, but I don’t like your merc attributes. Whose side are you on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_18">
        <text>I’m Beast. I’m a mercenary… What is this place, and who are you?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_19">
        <text>Hmm. A mercenary? Looks like I was right…\n \nWell then, mercenary: answering your first question is going to be difficult, because I myself don’t know where exactly we are. This place here is mystical; we’ve been here for a long time, and all the while, the Zone’s been playing tricks on us.\n \nAs for me, though: I’m Savage. Nice to meet you. By the way, though, the guys aren’t very happy about having a mercenary around here, so I’m going to ask you to behave yourself. We’re all in a rather difficult situation, so be tactful. We all try to get along so we can make it out of here in one piece.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_2">
        <text>Merc, your help would be much appreciated right now… Zombies are heading straight for our our base. We have to take them out, or this place is going to be overrun within seconds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_20">
        <text>What do you mean? What makes this place “mystical”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_21">
        <text>I don’t know, merc. There’s no way out of here… You go anywhere, you always end up back at this fucking barn. We barely make ends meet around here, living another day without dying of starvation or being hunted down by any of the mutants here. Lost a lot of munitions, too, and the mutants aren’t making it any easier on us. Only God knows how they find their way here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_22">
        <text>Damn… What have I gotten myself into? How long have you been here? And where’s my equipment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_23">
        <text>One of the stalkers and I have been holed up in here for about seven months. The rest of us, about one to three months.\n \nAs for your equipment, we’re not quite sure. Around four days ago, one of our scouts was scavenging for supplies and found you conked out outside. All you had on you was a pistol, a few magazines, and your suit, which was starting to look like a floorcloth.\n \nBut anyways, we can’t really make you follow orders. But I suggest you become a part of our group, so you last longer with us than you would without us. Furthermore, we’d be glad to have someone with your skillset. I hope you’ve heard me loud and clear; otherwise, you’ll have a few more problems on your hands.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_24">
        <text>I understand. I have no ill intentions toward you and your men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_3">
        <text>Is there nobody else who can help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_4">
        <text>There’s no time to chat. You need to help Cutter. He’s the one who you brought you here, even if not all of us supported his decision. Now it’s your turn to repay the favor.\n \nAnd I noticed a few Kalashnikov mags in your uniform. If you hand me two of them, I can send someone with you. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_5">
        <text>I don’t even remember how I ended up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_6">
        <text>Damn this place! What do we do? Without rations or munitions, we won’t last a week! It’s been almost two months since we last saw any new stalkers. Usually, they die in anomalies, and we live off their possessions, but now… On top of that, Scavenger’s gone off somewhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_7">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. Don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_8">
        <text>Who’s Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_9">
        <text>Scavenger? If it wasn’t for him, we’d all be worm food right now! He scouted the area and gathered any valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and didn’t return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_1">
        <text>Yeah. I think so. The worst has come to pass; his wounds don’t look fatal any more. He should be able to move soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_10">
        <text>Beast, if it wasn’t for Scavenger, we’d all be worm food right now. He combed the whole area and gathered any valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned… He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him—Cutter and Mosquito—but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you. Here’s what I don’t get, though: how did you manage to survive in the first place? There were blind dogs no further than ten meters from where you were found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_11">
        <text>I don’t know how I’m still alive, but it’s important I stay that way. Anyway, I’ll go check out the area. Maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_12">
        <text>I don’t know how I’m still alive, but it’s important I stay that way. Anyway, I’ll go check out the area. Maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_13">
        <text>It’d mean a lot to us. No one can really replace Scavenger; he was able to gather so much stuff in a single day, and we can’t even match half of his efforts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_14">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_15">
        <text>It’d mean a lot to us. No one can really replace Scavenger; he was able to gather so much stuff in a single day, and we can’t even match half of his efforts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_16">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_17">
        <text>Speak to Knucklehead on that matter. He’ll help you solve the issue. Oh, also: Snake wanted to see you about something important. When you’re done with all of that, come back to me. I’ve got something else for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_19">
        <text>Well, this is great. I thought this was going to be our ticket to freedom. This anomaly doesn’t want to let us go… How’s that soldier? Is he going to live?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_2">
        <text>That’s great. I think this used to be some sort of military complex before the anomaly. Maybe he can give us some info about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_20">
        <text>All right. I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_22">
        <text>Hey, there, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_24">
        <text>I need your help with a little something… We had this stalker called Scavenger. He went missing two days ago, but I don’t want to think that he’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_26">
        <text>Hey, there, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_28">
        <text>Hey, there, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_3">
        <text>Maybe so, but in his current state, he can barely even stand. Let him rest a bit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_4">
        <text>Yeah. No need to bother him right now. I’m quite sure we have enough medicine to get him on his feet eventually. If only we had a trained medic… By the way, I see you’re looking much better than before. Some time in that bed did you good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_5">
        <text>Yeah. I feel better; at least my headache’s over… I’ve got some provisions. Do you guys have any rations?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_6">
        <text>That’s great, Beast. Remember when I told you about Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_7">
        <text>The looter? Yeah. I remember him. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_8">
        <text>What about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_9">
        <text>Yeah. Scavenger combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned. He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him—Cutter and Mosquito—but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you. Here’s what I don’t get, though: how did you manage to survive in the first place? There were blind dogs no further than ten meters from where you were found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_0">
        <text>So *that’s* where the damn zombies came from. And the root of it all showed up at our doorstep… Well, we can finally stop worrying about them. Thanks for your help, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_1">
        <text>I scratch your back, Savage…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_10">
        <text>It’ll mean a lot if you find him. Scavenger was a good stalker. He’s been great help to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_11">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_2">
        <text>All right. We should get out of here, or else pseudogiants will start showing up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_3">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. There has to be an exit somewhere. Do you have anything else for me to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_4">
        <text>Yes, Beast. Remember I told you about Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_5">
        <text>The looter? Yeah, why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_6">
        <text>I remember him, but I don’t know who he is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_7">
        <text>Yeah. Scavenger combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned. He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him—Cutter and Mosquito—but they found you instead. You offered to share your ammunition and you helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller. For that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_8">
        <text>Beast, if it wasn’t for Scavenger, we’d all be worm food right now. He combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned… He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him—Cutter and Mosquito—but they found you instead. You offered to share your ammunition and you helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller. For that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_9">
        <text>No need to thank me. I’ll go comb the area; maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_0">
        <text>So, what did you find there, merc? Did you clear out all of the zombies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_1">
        <text>Yes. The zombies have been neutralized. Mosquito’s fine as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_10">
        <text>Hmm. A spatial anomaly, you say? Does the note have any clue about an exit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_11">
        <text>No. I have a question, though: how did zombies end up here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_2">
        <text>The zombies are down, but… they got Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_3">
        <text>That’s good news, merc! Did you find anything useful on those poor fellas?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_4">
        <text>What? How? Ugh. I’m sorry for the guy… But what’s better: staying around here waiting for starvation or leaving for the afterlife?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_5">
        <text>Yeah. I found that they were a Duty squad. One of them carried a note.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_6">
        <text>Yeah. And I forgot to mention: the zombies were the remnants of a Duty squad. One of them had a note in their backpack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_7">
        <text>What’s it say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_8">
        <text>What’s it say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_9">
        <text>The note describes the place we’re in: it’s some kind of anomaly. The Dutyer described this anomaly as a spatial anomaly. I’ve heard about it before…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_0">
        <text>Damn. My head… What the hell was that?! Okay, at least we know how the zombified stalkers ended up here. The root of it all showed up at our doorstep… Hey, I wonder: why didn’t you fall under its influence like everyone else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_1">
        <text>I don’t know. One of those mutants managed to control me in the past. It very nearly managed to zombify me, but then Fish saved me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_2">
        <text>That Fish is certainly a good man. Anyway… Good thing you managed to steer clear of that controller’s influence, or else we’d all have been on a leash. What was I thinking?… With our level of security, anyone can waltz in here without a problem. What scares me the most is that those zombies were wandering around the barn for a while, and that probably means that the controller was snooping around under our noses, too…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_3">
        <text>Right now, we need to get your guys some more ammo. Otherwise, we’ll have nothing with which to protect ourselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_4">
        <text>As important as that is, our key issue here is that our food supplies are dwindling. Our drinking water supplies are also getting dangerously low. Morale is dropping lower and lower every day because of it. Several of our men are saying that there’s no way out of here and that we’re all going to die of starvation. I admit, I those kinds of thoughts get to me as well, but I try to keep them at bay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_5">
        <text>I’ll do everything I can in my power to find a way out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_6">
        <text>I just hope we can still find a way out. I don’t want to die here, trapped like an animal. This was the worst present that I could get from the Zone… I just want to go back home and see my wife and daughter. Why did this Zone do this to me?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_7">
        <text>Yeah. It’s not easy around here… Do you have anything else for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_8">
        <text>Listen, Beast: you look like hell. You spent a lot of time in that bed, blacked out, but I can see it didn’t help you nothing. A face-to-face meeting with a controller isn’t the best treatment, either. Go get some shut-eye; it hurts me seeing you in your current state. We’ll talk more in the morning; the guys and I are going to dispose of the controller.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_9">
        <text>Yeah… I think some sleep will help ground me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_10">
        <text>Just a sec… Okay. The marker should be on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_12">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_13">
        <text>Let’s go, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_14">
        <text>I’m listening, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_15">
        <text>Hey. Were you looking for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_16">
        <text>Yeah, Beast. As you might’ve noticed, our lack of food and munitions isn’t our only problem: our supply of drinking water is dangerously low. The only water source here is the well outside the barn, but all the water in there is radioactive. Drinking it without purifying it beforehand is out of the question.\n \nBut there is one way I’ve been thinking about that would definitely make safe drinking water: from time to time, you can find an anomalous plant inside this anomaly. At one point, I was helping the scientists at Yantar, and, by using such a plant, they were able to effectively purify water.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_17">
        <text>You’re saying you want me to go flower picking? That’s not my style.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_18">
        <text>No, Beast. You won’t have to pick anything. Cutter spotted a few such plants from a tower, and he sent me their locations. I just need you to follow me and cover me. This place is crawling with mutants, and I don’t have a lot of ammo to deal with them on my own. Do you think you could help me out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_19">
        <text>All right. I’ll cover you. When are we heading out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_2">
        <text>We can have a chat later, merc. Right now you really need to focus on clearing out those zombies with Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_20">
        <text>Right now. If you’re ready, of course…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_21">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_22">
        <text>Wait just a moment. I need to check my gear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_24">
        <text>I’m listening, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_26">
        <text>We’re back, safe and sound, and I have the plants. Now I’ll be able to work with purifying the water for the men. Thanks for covering me, Beast. These plants should last us for some time. If you need more drinking water, come see me, and I’ll make you some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_28">
        <text>You ready to pick some flowers, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_29">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_3">
        <text>Then I’ll go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_30">
        <text>Wait a moment. Not quite ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_31">
        <text>No problem. I’ll come by if I need any water.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_33">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_34">
        <text>My canteen is empty. Can I get some water?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_35">
        <text>No problem, Beast. Hand it over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_36">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_37">
        <text>Right now, I’m busy purifying that water for you. Waiting for it to cool down. I’ll message you when I’m done. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_38">
        <text>All right. I’ll wait for you to message me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_40">
        <text>Here’s your canteen. The water’s all cool and clean. You can drink it right now if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_41">
        <text>Thanks, Snake. You’re a big help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_42">
        <text>Here’s the thing: I haven’t purified the water for you yet. We’ll deal with the flesh later. Once it’s done, I’ll give you a message. ’Kay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_44">
        <text>The water’s still contaminated. Drop by a bit later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_46">
        <text>’Kay. I’m ready to go. I purified the water; here’s your canteen. Now let’s go hunt some flesh so we can make some dinner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_47">
        <text>Thanks for the water. Put a marker and let’s take them out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_48">
        <text>Just a sec… Okay. The marker should be on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_49">
        <text>Let’s head out, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_50">
        <text>All right. The flesh are waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_51">
        <text>All right. I’ll go later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_53">
        <text>Here’s your canteen. The water’s all cool and clean. You can drink it right now if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_54">
        <text>Thanks, Snake. You’re a big help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_6">
        <text>Hey, there, Beast! So, you ready to shoot down a few radioactive pigs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_7">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s head out right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_8">
        <text>Great. Now let’s go hunt some flesh so we can make some dinner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_9">
        <text>Put a marker where the flesh are at and let’s take them out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_0">
        <text>I’m out of water. Do you think you could purify some more for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_1">
        <text>No problem, Beast. Hand it over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_2">
        <text>Here’s my canteen.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_3">
        <text>Right now, I’m busy purifying that water for you. Waiting for it to cool down. I’ll message you when I’m done. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_4">
        <text>All right. I’ll wait for you to message me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_0">
        <text>Tell me about your group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_1">
        <text>Well, who do you want to know about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_10">
        <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_11">
        <text>Cutter’s a strict man. He’s hard to understand, but he doesn’t cause a lot of conflict; on the contrary, he helps break up any conflict in the group, if it ever arises. He’s been here for about two months, and at first, he struggled to adapt to the way this place works. He’s gotten used to it now, and his primary role here is reconnaissance, which used to be Scavenger’s thing. All in all, he’s a decent guy, but as of late, he’s been pretty down; he keeps talking nonsense about us being stuck here forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_12">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_13">
        <text>Sledge? Well, he went through thick and thin in his days. He’s not even a man; he’s a god damn force of nature. I knew him before the whole fiasco with the anomaly. Back then, he worked with Freedom at the military warehouses. He was just about everyone’s favorite person back then. When he came here, things changed, though. He found friends among enemies and generally became a kinder person. He’s been with us for about two and a half months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_14">
        <text>Hmm. So this place has some value to it. Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_15">
        <text>Young dude who, in his own words, “made the mistake of joining Duty.” If he gains some experience, he might become a very good fighter one day, but if he gets out of here, he probably won’t be joining up with his faction again. He made friends with Sledgehammer, though they both got pretty hot-headed when they first met, with the Duty–Freedom stuff and all. He’s been here for almost over a month.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_16">
        <text>Markus is the musician here. On top of that, I guess you could call him my right hand man. If there’s ever something I can’t quite deal with by myself, he’s always there to help. He was part of the original group that ended up here… Well, there was a third guy, but I’ll tell you about that another time. You could say that we brought some order to this place, if you can call it “order.” Eventually, some new stalkers came along, including yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_17">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_18">
        <text>Thanks for the info, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_19">
        <text>Mosquito used to be a marksman; hence, his accuracy is practically supernatural. If you need help from a good shooter, he’s the one to talk to. He’s kindhearted and quite talkative, and he doesn’t let the anomaly faze him. He’s been with us for about three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_2">
        <text>Tell me about Cutter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_20">
        <text>Mosquito was a marksman; hence, his accuracy was practically supernatural. He was kindhearted and quite talkative, and he never let the anomaly faze him. He was with us for about three months… It’s unfortunate that he died here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_21">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_22">
        <text>Without Knucklehead, we’d have been much worse off. He’s a hunter and a looter. After Scavenger came here, they’ve both been helping the group by supplying us with mutant meat. Things around here just wouldn’t work without him. He’s been with us for over three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_23">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_24">
        <text>Not much I need to say about Screw. He’s the heart of our group. Without him, we wouldn’t be able to maintain any of our equipment, and without equipment, we wouldn’t last very long. The guys give him all sorts of random stuff that he buys for money, and then, using that stuff, he fixes our gear. I mean, he doesn’t do it for free, but that doesn’t matter to us. He got here about a week ago or two after us, and since then, he’s been a steady helping hand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_25">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_26">
        <text>I won’t take up too much time talking about myself. I ended up here during the assault on Limansk. At the time, I was in a detachment together with Markus and Shell. Everyone here ended up at the same time, and not all of us have stayed alive up to this point. Shell was the leader of the detachment, so, naturally, he became the leader here too… well, until he disappeared, that is. After that, I assumed his position.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_27">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_28">
        <text>Not at all. If you want me to share more about anyone else, just ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_3">
        <text>Tell me about Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_4">
        <text>Tell me about Snake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_5">
        <text>Tell me about Markus.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_6">
        <text>Tell me about Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_7">
        <text>Tell me about Knucklehead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_8">
        <text>Tell me about Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_9">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_0">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. Did you need anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_1">
        <text>Markus should’ve returned by now, but there’s no trace of him… Do you know where he went off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_2">
        <text>Hmm… Nope. He didn’t tell me anything. Wait just a minute; I’m gonna try pinging his PDA signal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_3">
        <text>Go on. I’ll wait.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_2">
        <text>Beast, I think I’ve picked up Markus’ signal… or rather his last signs of activity. Head over there at once. I can tell something’s not right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_3">
        <text>Understood, Savage. Send the coordinates and I’ll head over there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_5">
        <text>Beast, not now. Go to Markus’ last known location and find out what happened. We have to find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_0">
        <text>I have info on that SOS signal incident.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_1">
        <text>I’m listening. Did you talk to the sender?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_10">
        <text>Most likely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_11">
        <text>I’m listening. Did you talk to the sender?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_12">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_2">
        <text>Yeah. The stalker who sent the signal is already here; I’ve led him into the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_3">
        <text>I think you did the right thing, Beast. In a place like this, you need to stick together. Having another soul here won’t hurt. He does know where he is, right? Have you told him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_4">
        <text>Yeah. When I met him, though, he told me he was being pursued by a mercenary group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_5">
        <text>Well, that’s no good… but I doubt they’re reckless enough to jump headfirst into a spatial anomaly. Can you ask him for more information about himself? We need to know if he can be trusted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_6">
        <text>Sure thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_7">
        <text>I’m listening. What happened there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_8">
        <text>The stalker who sent the signal was killed. I wasn’t able to bring him back to the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_9">
        <text>Sad to hear. But the Zone is merciless. I’m sure you did everything in your power to save his life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger. He’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_1">
        <text>How is he dead? Where’d you find him, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_10">
        <text>The stalkers Scavenger was looking for weren’t always dead. He killed them himself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_11">
        <text>Strange. He never told us anything about that. Beast, we need to find that decoder; right now, it’s probably what we need the most.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_12">
        <text>Don’t worry. I’m set on finding it, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_13">
        <text>Great to hear that, Beast. As soon as you get more info about it, come back to me and we’ll discuss it. What else was on Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_14">
        <text>Hmm… Well, that’s very much like him. I’m glad he tried to help us somehow. If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll figure out what to do with it, and it’s not like he needs it anymore. Did his PDA have anything else on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_15">
        <text>So that piece of shit took all the good stuff and let us use the grimy ammo and eat mutant meat? Wonderful. If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll figure out what to do with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_16">
        <text>Are you serious? That motherfucker! If I knew about this earlier, I’d have him pulverized… Good thing he’s gone now. That’s what he deserved.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_17">
        <text>Yeah. He was a slippery type, but now he’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_18">
        <text>God damn it… And I trusted him, too… Thanks for opening my eyes. Did that rat bastard have anything else on his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_19">
        <text>Nope. That’s everything. You can have it if you want. It’ll describe everything in more detail.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_2">
        <text>Behind the fence. Seems he was using the northern teleporter to get around; that’s how I found him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_20">
        <text>Yeah… What a slippery bastard he turned out to be. Ready yourself to look for that decoder; right now, it’s probably what we need the most.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_21">
        <text>Don’t worry. I’m set on finding it, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_22">
        <text>Great to hear that, Beast. As soon as you get more info about it, come back to me and we’ll discuss it. What else was on Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_23">
        <text>Hmm… Well, that’s very much like him. I’m glad he tried to help us somehow. If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll figure out what to do with it, and it’s not like he needs it anymore. Did his PDA have anything else on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_24">
        <text>I’ve already found his stash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_25">
        <text>Oh? Good work, Beast. What was in it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_26">
        <text>Ammo, medical supplies, and also a locked container. No key in the stash, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_27">
        <text>Uh-huh. Hand over that container. I’m gonna give it to Screw; maybe he’ll manage cracking it without a key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_28">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_29">
        <text>I’ll call you as soon as Screw’s done opening it. What else was on the PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_3">
        <text>Yeah… Sad. That guy was sharp as hell. Saved us many times…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_30">
        <text>Yeah. Turns out we didn’t know much about Scavenger at all… Anyway, Knucklehead was looking for you, and that army guy also wanted to see you. Go talk to them. I need some space to sort things out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_31">
        <text>All right. I’ll talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_4">
        <text>Scavenger was sharp, but not that sharp. By the way, he had a PDA on him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_5">
        <text>What do you mean, Beast? And throw that thing away. There can’t be anything useful on it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_6">
        <text>Quite the opposite: it does have quite a few interesting entries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_7">
        <text>Yeah? And what did you find out from Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_8">
        <text>There’s an entry about some kind of decoder that’s supposed to provide an exit out of the anomaly. It was stashed away somewhere, but there’s no information on where.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_9">
        <text>Scavenger kept his most valuable findings away from you and hid it all somewhere, but I don’t know where.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_0">
        <text>Hey, uh, when did Scavenger go missing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_1">
        <text>Scavenger went missing two days ago. He picked up an SOS signal nearby and went to go check it out but never came back. When I sent Cutter and Mosquito to find him, they found you instead. Not that that’s a bad thing; I’m glad you showed up. You helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller, and for that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_2">
        <text>No need to thank me. I’ll go comb the area; maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_3">
        <text>It’ll mean a lot if you find him. Scavenger was a good stalker. He’s been a great help to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_4">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger’s stash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_1">
        <text>Oh? What did you find?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_2">
        <text>Ammo, medical supplies, and also a locked container. No key in the stash, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_3">
        <text>Uh-huh. Hand over that container. I’m gonna give it to Screw; maybe he’ll manage cracking it without a key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_4">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_5">
        <text>I’ll call you as soon as Screw’s done opening it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_6">
        <text>Understood, Savage. I’ll come by later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_10">
        <text>Can I ask you something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_11">
        <text>Can you? Go ahead, seeing as it interests you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_12">
        <text>What do you think about the other guys here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_13">
        <text>Do you think we can really get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_14">
        <text>Who were you before you came here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_15">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_16">
        <text>I’ve gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_17">
        <text>It’s not like I have any radical opinions on them. They’re all right people. We’re all different, but the tragedy of this situation applies to us all; we’re stuck in this mess together, like pebbles stuck in cement.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_18">
        <text>I don’t know, but even if we do find a way out, not everyone will make it. That’s for sure. I’m still amazed that we’ve been able to hold out for this long. Not only do we barely have any grub or munitions, but we have more dangerous concerns.\n \nI left the barn the night before yesterday to get some fresh air, and I could smell something burning. I thought, “Maybe something’s on fire…” but then I saw a huge pillar of smoke, and I could make out a person standing in the center of it. I looked through my binoculars to see who it was, but I couldn’t see shit in the darkness. I decided to take a closer look, and, suddenly, there was a laughter. All the smoke was gone, and so was the figure inside it.\n \nI don’t know what the heck that was, but it sure wasn’t anything good for us. It didn’t bode well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_19">
        <text>I’m a stalker; a loner. I made a living working under Sidorovich, and after that, I set off to Yantar for science. They’ve got regular-paying jobs and medical supplies, and the army doesn’t sniff around there more than they have to. What sucks, though, is that those eggheads tend to send you to places so bad that even boar shit looks good in comparison. Before I ended up in this anomaly, I remember how I went up to an anomaly by myself at Yantar to gather a few specimens, and then, all I saw was a white flash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_2">
        <text>Oh. It’s you, merc. Looking better than you did before. Thanks for clearing out those zombies earlier.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_3">
        <text>Well, I owed you for saving my hide. Say, do you remember where you found me? Maybe some of my equipment was left behind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_4">
        <text>Of course I remember. How could I not? You won’t find anything there, though. I scouted that place far and wide to try and find your stuff on my own. I also looked at the possibility of an exit from this hellhole, but as you can see, I’m still here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_5">
        <text>Send the coordinates anyway. I want to check the area myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_6">
        <text>Be my guest.\n \nThere. You should have it. Check your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_7">
        <text>Thank you. Time to go find my backpack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_9">
        <text>So, merc, what’ve you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. I’m glad you’re okay. I’m basically the local technician. I’ll buy any busted shooters off of you, though my repairs and modifications aren’t free of charge; I’m getting out of this place someday, so I try to make whatever money I can. I also need to get hold of intact guns in exchange for any weapon parts. By the way, if you find any sets of tools around here, bring them to me. I’ll find a way to make use of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hi, merc. Need anything repaired or improved?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Well, come see me if you need anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_0">
        <text>Make any progress on Scavenger’s container?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_1">
        <text>I opened it. Turns out there are quite a few goodies inside; even a set of tools, which means I can now work on additional upgrades, but let’s leave that for later. As I told you in my earlier message, you can take some of the loot for yourself, and I’ll share the rest with the others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_10">
        <text>I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_11">
        <text>I don’t need that. What else is there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_12">
        <text>That’s everything. Not much else is left in the container; only medical supplies and bullets, which I’ll be giving to Savage. He’ll distribute it amongst the others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_13">
        <text>No problem. Here’s your shooter. And by the way, have a few rounds for it, as a bonus. They were also in the container. It’s a rare caliber; a type used by no one around here. Other than that, there are two packs of 5.45x39 mm military armor-piercing ammo. Very useful against armored targets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_14">
        <text>That’ll come into handy. Give it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_15">
        <text>No. I don’t need ammo right now. What else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_16">
        <text>All right, here. Next up is a rare artifact, called the “Black Angel.” Not bad in its qualities. It helps you withstand the pressure from psy-fields. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_17">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_18">
        <text>I don’t need that. What else is there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_19">
        <text>Here. Take the artifact. Not much else is left in the container; only medical supplies and bullets, which I’ll be giving to Savage. He’ll distribute it amongst the others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_2">
        <text>Then show me what’s inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_20">
        <text>Inside are two packs of 5.45x39 mm military armor-piercing ammo. Very useful against armored targets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_21">
        <text>We also have a Black Angel artifact. Not bad in its qualities. It helps you withstand the pressure from psy-fields. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_22">
        <text>Great. See you later, Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_3">
        <text>Right. First thing is a 1PN58 night vision scope. Very useful item. Contains a built-in night vision device, which’ll help you spot targets in the dark. You attach it to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_4">
        <text>I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_5">
        <text>Don’t need it. Show me more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_6">
        <text>Mm-hmm. Here’s your scope. Next up, we have a decent pea-shooter: the FN FNP-45. Not exactly up to date, but its destructive capabilities won’t be disappointing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_7">
        <text>I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_8">
        <text>I don’t need that. What else is there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_9">
        <text>Got you. Next up, we have a decent pea-shooter: the FN FNP-45. Not exactly up to date, but its destructive capabilities won’t be disappointing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_0">
        <text>Here. I found a toolkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_1">
        <text>You found tools for basic work? They probably won’t be of much use for any fine work, but they’ll come handy nonetheless. Thank you very much, merc. I’ll lower my prices for repairs and upgrades for you. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_2">
        <text>Deal. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_10">
        <text>Find those fucking assholes!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_12">
        <text>Hey, Beast, you still busy? Can you help me out with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_13">
        <text>What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_14">
        <text>We need to fix this radio transmitter. A battery and two rolls of copper wire should do the trick. The copper wiring should be real easy to find, but the hard part will be finding a battery. Since we ended up here in the first place, I wouldn’t say our chances are too high…\n \nIf you find anything resembling a wire or a battery, bring it to me. I might actually be able to fix this thing, and then you can try to send a signal that’ll reach outside the anomaly. Someone will surely get the signal and help us in some way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_15">
        <text>You have me on board. If I find anything like you described, I’ll bring it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_16">
        <text>I’m busy right now. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_18">
        <text>So, what’s up, merc? Find anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_2">
        <text>Hey, merc. See, I’m recovering in here. Decided to move into the basement so I don’t keep being an eyesore up there. It’s better for everyone this way, including myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_20">
        <text>Found a battery after all. Another “lucky” stalker ended up in the anomaly and shared what he had with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_21">
        <text>I’ve found two rolls of copper wire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_22">
        <text>Sad to hear about the stalker, but he’s doing us a big favor. I’d even say I’m glad he ended up here. So, hand me the battery. You sure it’s in working condition?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_23">
        <text>Here you go. It’s hard to say whether it works; he took it from a broken radio transmitter, but let’s hope for the best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_24">
        <text>Here you go. It’s hard to say whether it works; he took it from a broken radio transmitter, but let’s hope for the best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_25">
        <text>Okay. Let’s see…\n \nYeah. That should do it. It’s just that, even if this thing works, I can’t get it to restart just yet. I just need some rolls of copper wire so I can replace what got fried. Try to find two rolls, and then we’ll try to put this pile of trash into operation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_26">
        <text>Okay. Let’s see…\n \nYeah. That should do it. If everything works out and the transmitter successfully restarts, I can send a signal for help beyond the anomaly.\n \nCome back to me in about twenty minutes. In the meantime, I’ll try to replace all the fried wiring.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_27">
        <text>Okay. I’ll come back in twenty minutes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_29">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. Let’s talk later, you and I. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_3">
        <text>Well, that’s relatively good news. Savage said you needed me for something. Is that right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_30">
        <text>All right. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_32">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_33">
        <text>Ah. It’s you, merc. Got any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_34">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_35">
        <text>Nope. Haven’t found anything yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_36">
        <text>Excellent, merc. Hand me the wiring. Too bad that I can’t do much without a battery…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_37">
        <text>Here you go. Regarding the battery, I’ll try to figure something out, though I’m starting to think that we won’t be able to find anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_38">
        <text>Well, in any case, keep me updated. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_39">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll be going now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_4">
        <text>Yeah, merc. Got a very delicate task for you. I’ve found out that the radio transmitter in this basement is fixable; I’ve had my moments with these devices before.\n \nWhat stands out is its broken battery. On top of that, some of the internal wiring is fried. I could use a couple of rolls of copper wire and a new battery. Once I have all that, I might be able to bring the thing to life.\n \nIt might just save the day. If we get it working, we could send a signal beyond the borders of this forsaken anomaly, and if anyone gets it, they might be able to help us get out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_40">
        <text>Excellent, merc. Hand me the wire and come back to me in about twenty minutes. I’ll try to replace the battery and the fried wiring.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_41">
        <text>Here’s the wire. I’ll come back in twenty minutes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_42">
        <text>All right. I’ll try to find some wiring for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_44">
        <text>Come back in a little while, merc. I’m still trying to get this thing working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_46">
        <text>I managed to fix the damn transmitter after all. Now we need to find someone that we can broadcast the signal to. That’ll be my job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_47">
        <text>Did you pick up on any outside signals while you were testing it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_48">
        <text>Nothing interesting. I’m hearing a few sentences here and there along with some unintelligble jabbering, but they’re probably just some old broadcasts. I’ll keep scanning for more signals. Thanks, merc, for helping me repair the transmitter. Who knows? Maybe it’ll help us get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_49">
        <text>No need to thank me. We’re all together in this. I’ll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_5">
        <text>Good idea, but where am I going to find a battery, and one that still works, at that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_6">
        <text>Well, I’m kind of busy right now. Let’s discuss that later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_7">
        <text>Well, merc, I’m just putting some options out. It’s gonna take some persistence and luck to find a battery in these parts, but since we were unfortunate enough to end up here in the first place, I wouldn’t say our chances are too high… Two rolls of copper wire should be pretty easy to find somewhere, but without a battery, this thing won’t work…\n \nStill, if you find anything resembling a wire or a battery, bring it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_8">
        <text>You have me on board. If I find anything of note, I’ll bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_9">
        <text>What kind of help did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_2">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_3">
        <text>Ah. It’s you, merc. Got any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_4">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_10">
        <text>Damn… Man… Give me a medkit, or I’m riding the pale horse…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_11">
        <text>We’re here… Thanks for the help. Who knows what would’ve happened if you didn’t come. I’m feeling a bit better now.\n \nCan you tell me where we are? What is this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_12">
        <text>Well, have you ever heard of a space bubble?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_13">
        <text>Well, I’ve heard things, and I know what it does in general terms. What about it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_14">
        <text>Congratulations: you’re in a spatial anomaly right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_15">
        <text>Well, then… Sucks that they sent us to fly today of all days… And most importantly, how the hell did we even end up here? This place never appeared on any of our maps.\n \nWhatever. What’s done is done. I take it you haven’t found any way out of the anomaly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_16">
        <text>Nope. So far, not a thing. Where are the other soldiers from the helicopter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_17">
        <text>Just great… The chopper crew was most likely torn apart. Me, though… Seems like I got lucky. God damn aerial anomaly… It fried all the electronics in a split second.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_18">
        <text>Yeah. Well, get better, soldier. We’ll be needing your help soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_20">
        <text>All right. I’ll see if your shooter’s still around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_23">
        <text>Hey, there, merc. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_3">
        <text>I’m finished… Man… Man, end it. I won’t last…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_4">
        <text>Just you wait. I might be able to help you still.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_5">
        <text>You think I still have a chance? This pain is giving me hell… I can’t handle it… Ease my suffering…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_6">
        <text>You’ll live. I’ve seen worse. First, we need to get you a medkit so you can come with me to the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_7">
        <text>Alright… Do whatever you need to… Just… Just make this pain stop… Give me your medkit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_8">
        <text>Here. Use this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_9">
        <text>I don’t have any medkit right now, but I’ll find one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="super_0">
        <text>default text</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
