<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_self_0">
<text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_self_1">
<text>I am professor Ozersky. Engaged in the study of anomalous formations in the CZE. Previously, I worked at the perimeter on this topic. But I decided to be, so to speak, closer to the source. After the super-emission I moved here in the valley. Conditions aren't bad, the place is secure... \nTo be honest, they're offering me to work closer to the center - near the Jupiter plant. That's why I'm thinking. Maybe in the future I will agree to the offer. But in the meantime there's plenty of work here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_upgr_0">
<text>Tell me what kind of artefact modifications you can perform.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_upgr_1">
<text>The most widely demanded one - removal of the radioactive component. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_vofka_0">
<text>I found a stalker's corpse - he's called Vovka.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_vofka_1">
<text>Vovka died? That's a pity. Do you have his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_vofka_11">
<text>Yes. In one of his notes he mentioned that he had finished your task.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_vofka_111">
<text>I'll give you 7500 for the PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_about_vofka_1111">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_guard_open_door_0">
<text>Open the door - I'm leaving.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_guard_open_door_1">
<text>Alright, goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_trader_start_11">
<text>Greetings. It's nice to see a new face around here. If you wanted to change an artifact's properties, you've come to the right place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_trader_start_21">
<text>Your order is ready. Collect it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_atr_trader_start_31">
<text>Yes, yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_0">
<text>Have you met these stalkers, by any chance - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_1">
<text>Of course - they've been around here. I even know where they are. But do you wish to help to kill a beast first - only then I'll give you the info. If you accept... We'll go hunting, but then I'll tell you everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_11">
<text>Good, I agree to help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_111">
<text>Another thing... That thing only comes out at night. We can go now if you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_112">
<text>That thing only comes out at night. Come here to the shed when it's two in the morning - me and my friend will be waiting there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_12">
<text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_121">
<text>Then think and think... Like some darn professor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_about_stalkers_2">
<text>Of course I have. I even know where they are. I'll tell you all I know only after the hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_dialog_1_0">
<text>I'm ready to go hunting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_dialog_1_1">
<text>Now that's real men talk. Ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_dialog_1_11">
<text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_dialog_1_2">
<text>Come here when it's two in the morning - this thing comes out only during the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_11">
<text>Hello. I don't think I've seen you here before. Arrived recently?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_111">
<text>Yes, not a long time ago.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_1111">
<text>There's a deal worth money - are you interested?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_11111">
<text>Tell me about it and then I'll see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_111111">
<text>Generally speaking, there's an abandoned camp nearby. There's some talk that a creature has appeared. During the day it sleeps, but when it's dark, the mutant goes out to hunt. Local stalkers go around this place, fearing it. Well, me and my friend here decided to go and kill this thing. There's moral satisfaction and a money equivalent from the stalkers... But going there with only two men is foolish. That's why we're looking for another one. As they say - will you be the third one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_1111111">
<text>Good, I don't mind to do some hunting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_11111111">
<text>Well, then wait until it's two in the morning. The mutant leaves its den only during the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_11111112">
<text>Come here when it's two in the morning - the beast shows up only during the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_1111112">
<text>Not now. I have more important things to deal with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_11111121">
<text>Well, if you change your mind, come to the shed. Me and my friend are resting there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_21">
<text>Oh, it's you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mudak_start_31">
<text>Well, did you change your mind about the hunt?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_dolg_0">
<text>Where did you get a "Duty" suit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_dolg_1">
<text>You see, I'm a retired "Duty" soldier. That's all from old times... When I found out why and how "Duty" was formed, all the great ideas vanished from my mind. Me and the guys decided to become free stalkers and came here. The men here are from my squad, well, from the one that's no more. The equipment remains as a reminder of our wrongdoings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_mudak_0">
<text>Two people from your base have tried to rob me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_mudak_1">
<text>Now that's some news. Who were they?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_mudak_11">
<text>Ilya "Mongrel" with his friend. Here's his PDA. All is detailed in there. As you can understand - he's dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_mudak_111">
<text>Those idiots. I would understand if they mugged those who were returning home with the swag. But these guys... They're definitely dumbasses... But you're a fine man - saved many from such a headache. Here, take your modest fee.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_place_0">
<text>What can you tell me about the nearby places?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_about_place_1">
<text>What can I tell you? Before the great blowout this place was a wasteland, now you can see what's happened. Stalkers flooded in looking for artifacts. Found a pile of junk here and built a shelter. We thought that it'd always be like this... For some reason the emissions ended and now every artifact is worth gold. There's barely any loot and the stalkers started to bite each other's throats like blind dogs. So keep your eyes open and do not turn your back even to neutral stalkers.\nStrictly speaking, this is the rookie camp. After us, all the stalkers go onwards, later they return back here. Tough guys go deep in the valley, but the rookies stay here to gain experience.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_11_0">
<text>Okay, I'll get the flash drive. Where can I find this Vasya?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_11_1">
<text>Take the approximate coordinates. And do not wait with this case, but then get back here as long as your eyes can see... You'll be able to turn him in later...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_12_0">
<text>And what's on the flash drive? Is there some sort of a compromise?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_12_1">
<text>That's none of your business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_12_2">
<text>As a good friend of mine, now dead, said: "I always knew too much."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_13_0">
<text>Why don't you solve your problems yourself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_13_1">
<text>Making stalkers die near my base is bad for my reputation. Go and show yourself later, how's it all like. But you're a new guy here and, as I can see, you haven't been here for long. There will be no questions about you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_0">
<text>Take the flash drive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_1">
<text>Thanks, you did a good service. What's with Vasya?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_11">
<text>He's dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_111">
<text>Well, that's the end of him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_12">
<text>It's nothing. I'll give the flash drive myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_14_121">
<text>Hmm... Strange.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_15_0">
<text>Here's the flash drive. Vasya "Mail" is dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_15_1">
<text>Wow... I see that you already were able to talk to the locals.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_0">
<text>Hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_1">
<text>Good to see you. What are looking for in these parts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_11">
<text>I am looking for these buddies - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_111">
<text>Strange, people usually come here looking for loot, not to find friends.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_1111">
<text>Well, they went looking for the "Heart of Oasis" artifact, but didn't return back on time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_11111">
<text>Yes, many hunt for these artifacts, but apparently no-one has seen them. And I remember your stalkers. But I'm not some sort of a manual, so I cannot help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_111111">
<text>And how much do you want for the information?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_1111111">
<text>I don't need your loot, but a service won't hurt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_11111111">
<text>What's the deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_111111111">
<text>There used to be a stalker called Fyodor with us, he went to the center of the valley in search of meaty artifacts. Except that he disappeared; so he gave me a flash drive with valuable information. But Vasya "Mail", that louse, decided that he can keep it for himself. Such a theft cannot be left alone. You see what I'm getting at?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_11112">
<text>Of course, many hunt for these artifacts, except that no-one has seen them. But I remember your stalkers. But I'm not some sort of a manual, so I cannot help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_63">
<text>What about the deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_71">
<text>That's none of your business. So, do you accept?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_1_72">
<text>Making stalkers die near my base is bad for my reputation. Go and show yourself later, how you're really like. But you're a new guy here and, as I can see, you haven't been here for long. Well, do you accept?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_0">
<text>Well, what about the stalkers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_1">
<text>They were here. The guys were swift, all eager to go to the center of the valley for artifacts. So I sent them to Maximilian's base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_11">
<text>Yeah, not a lot of information. Where can I find this Maximilian?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_111">
<text>Well, finding him is not hard. Except that he won't talk to you just like that. He's overly cautious - a lot of scum keep on appearing all around, but there are not many reliable people. But there is a way...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_1111">
<text>Go on...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_11111">
<text>A package was being brought to him from Skadovsk not too long ago. The stalkers who carried this delivery were pushed in by bandits. Simply put, right near their base. And the package, well, disappeared. Maximilian is visibly upset. But there are currently no people who can help him deal with the bandits. So deal with this problem - I think that your talks will be easier then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_111111">
<text>Probably.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_1111111">
<text>Anyhow, take the coordinates of Maximilian and the location where the stalkers perhaps were robbed. But deal with the rest yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_12">
<text>Yeah, not a lot of information... If I were with him, I obviously wouldn't have asked.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_121">
<text>Well, brother, those are your hardships... But... Alright... Take a compensation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_dialog_2_13">
<text>Wait a minute... I already know all of this... I thought you were going to tell me something new.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_start_dialog_11">
<text>Ah, a new face.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_mutny_start_dialog_13">
<text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_0">
<text>The plant that you talked about, I can bring it to you if the pay will be good enough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_1">
<text>If you'll bring the plant, I'll pay 3000 - that's a good price for it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_11">
<text>That'll be miniscule...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_111">
<text>Well, as you wish... Otherwise I have no choice at all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_12">
<text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_agree_121">
<text>So, let's see how you're like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_11">
<text>Oh, one more dolt in the valley... Alright... What do you want to do? Buy? Sell?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_111">
<text>What's with you, someone pissed in your morning coffee? You're losing all of your clients like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_1111">
<text>Where are you going? Don't you need sausages for food or a pack of ammo after travelling here from Zaton... Stalker... Me too... Do you want to complete a simple task for the smart guys - everyone else has been an ass...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_11111">
<text>What, someone failed a task?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_111111">
<text>Yes, I had an order from the scientists to get an anomalous plant. I figured out its approximate location, then I commissioned two imbeciles to search that area. So they barely had arrived when they heard some sort of a growl. Damn rookies, screw their mothers... And why did they flood in to the Zone? Did they think that chicks grow here on trees? Tourists, damn it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_1111111">
<text>If the pay will be good enough, I'll forget your talk about idiots and will bring the plant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_11111111">
<text>If you get the plant, I'll pay you 3000 - it's a good price for it... And I'll take my words back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_1111112">
<text>Do you have the plant, by any chance?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_11111121">
<text>Well, I take that back... You cheered me up... Take 3000 - it's a good price.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_1111113">
<text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_21">
<text>Greetings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_31">
<text>Well, what's with that plant?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_311">
<text>I'm in the process...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_3111">
<text>Well, well... All is clear... There already were two in such a process...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_312">
<text>Take your plant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b1_trader_start_41">
<text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_11">
<text>Snorks, foul creatures... I hate them...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_111">
<text>What, you hunted snorks recently?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_1111">
<text>Like I hunted them... More like they hunted me... Listen, help me with one thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_11111">
<text>What's the matter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_111111">
<text>We went with some guys to comb anomalies for artifacts. All was well, I even found an artifact. Suddenly, snorks... Well, we began to shoot at them... I only remember that they first got Vadik, then Romka... And then I ran like hell... Barely escaped...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_1111111">
<text>And what do you want from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_11111111">
<text>You see, me and the guys are childhood friends - we grew up in the same house. We previously wrote letters to our families on flash drives - we knew where we were going. And we agreed that in the event of death, the survivor will take them to their destination... And I can't make it to that place anymore... If you'll get the flash drives, I'll give you all what I have - 2000 RU plus an artifact for this darn stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_111111111">
<text>It seems that I've been there. Here are your friends' flash drives.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_1111111111">
<text>Now that's a save for me. Now I can safely get out of this fucking Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_111111112">
<text>Alright. I'll try to get the flash drives.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_1111111121">
<text>Thank you, friend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_111111113">
<text>I don't have time for that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_21">
<text>Well, did you get the flash drives?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_211">
<text>Yes, take this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_212">
<text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_31">
<text>Eh, if only someone helped...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_artur_start_41">
<text>Hello...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_siut_0">
<text>Radik told me to pick up a mercenary outfit from you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_siut_1">
<text>Here you go... There's a stalker standing there - Lyoha "Moose". He's sad over there, wants to help Radik. If an extra pair of hands does not hurt, take him along with you. The guy is kind of smart.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_0">
<text>Maximilian promised me equipment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_1">
<text>Maximilian died. What fucking equipment, man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_2">
<text>Alright. What do you prefer - sniper or assault?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_21">
<text>Sniper.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_22">
<text>Assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_221">
<text>Take this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_222">
<text>Take this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_barman_give_weapon_3">
<text>You were late, mate, Maximilian already went to the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_gonets_talk_0">
<text>Good to see you, man. I heard that you were sent to go to Radik. I want to help, I've stayed here for far too long. It's always more fun to go together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_gonets_talk_1">
<text>Good, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_gonets_talk_2">
<text>I haven't finished the deal here. I'll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_merc_0">
<text>What are mercenaries doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_merc_1">
<text>Yes, it's a mystery. Looks like someone doesn't want for stalkers to poke their nose around the center of the valley.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_mutny_0">
<text>I must inform you about Turbid, it's related to the rookie base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_mutny_1">
<text>What about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_mutny_11">
<text>I found out that he robs stalkers when they're leaving the valley. And there's no other exit other than the one near the rookie base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_mutny_111">
<text>Now that's some darn news! I'll go to round up my men - we need to deal with this louse. And a thanks to you. Go to the base and ask the trader for a reward, I'll warn him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_mutny_2">
<text>I know... We were informed already... We already got a group ready to get rid of that bastard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_0">
<text>What can you tell me about the nearby places?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_1">
<text>Well... There was a wasteland here... Until the big blowout shook the whole place. Back then artifacts were like acne on a teenager's face when they appeared. That's why stalkers came here for a permanent residence. They took all what was in arm's reach. They built outhouses and makeshift shelters - thought that it'd always be an artifact Klondike here. But... The emissions for some reason stopped and the artifacts quickly ran out. So soon stalkers will leave this place and it will become a wasteland again, just twisted by emissions and befouled by stalkers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_11">
<text>Yes... How did stalkers manage to get so much of their junk here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_111">
<text>They got here by military helicopters...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_1111">
<text>The soldiers have been ordered to get rid of the stalkers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_about_place_11111">
<text>Eh, brother... For the high ranks the Zone is one thing, for the grunts - another. You can never know when to expect danger, either you'll vanish in an anomaly or monsters will tear you apart. And you have to spend the night in some darn pocket... That's why the grunts warn what has been seen, how much of it has been spotted and what kind of monster activity has been sighted in an area. They were ordered to sweep the helicopter and ammunition. In the truth the stalkers had the chopper chartered and, evidently, there were no monsters in that area. Transportation for the stalkers, money for ammunition for the soldiers, who later get it from the trader. Such is the economy, brother.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_0">
<text>Greetings. You seem to be the chief here. Tell me about one thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_1">
<text>I don't have time for your questions, I already have plenty of problems for myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_11">
<text>Ever heard about reciprocity? I will help you and you will help me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_111">
<text>Maybe... Listen. Two stalkers were bringing me a parcel from Skadovsk. But they didn't bring it here. They most likely got robbed by bandits. Since you came here, you probably saw them. But the case is important. Can you take the box?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_1111">
<text>Okay, I'll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_11111">
<text>You haven't wasted any time. Thanks for the package. If you have any questions - ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_11_1112">
<text>I happened to pass by the bandits and take their blue box. Is it yours, by any chance?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_12_0">
<text>Here's your package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_12_1">
<text>That's nice. Thank you... If you have any questions - ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_0">
<text>Greetings. I'm here from Turbid.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_1">
<text>Oh, it's you... Turbid told me that you sorted out the matter with the package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_11">
<text>Yes, here it is. I had to kill the bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_111">
<text>Well then, that will discourage others. Turbid told me that you're looking for someone here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_1111">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_112">
<text>Yes, less and less reliable people around. Turbid told me that you're looking for someone here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_113">
<text>Come on, don't waste time. You'll do the deal, then we'll talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_12">
<text>Here it is. I had to buy it because the couriers lost it in a card game.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_1_13">
<text>I am in the process.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_0">
<text>I'm ready to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_1">
<text>Here's the deal - the path is not short. And anything can happen. So don't go too far away from me, it'd be a shame to ruin the operation at this stage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_11">
<text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_2">
<text>Hmm... You haven't take the equipment from the trader yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_21">
<text>I'll take it now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_22">
<text>Like I need that shit! If anything, I'll knife them all in the noodle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_21_221">
<text>Well, it's your deal... So, here's the deal - the path is not short. And anything can happen. So don't go too far away from me, it'd be a shame to ruin the operation at this stage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_0">
<text>I'm looking for these stalkers - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. Have you seen them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_1">
<text>I remember them, they were here. Guys were pretty normal. They were looking for the "Heart of Oasis" artifact, that's why they burst to the center. But it wasn't peaceful for them. Mercenaries, screw their mothers, sprung up. So if you want to find your guys, you'll need to go with us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_11">
<text>Go on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_111">
<text>They went away with Radik's group. Some time later there was neither noise nor life from their side - I thought that the guys kicked the bucket. But recently we received a signal from Radik. They are stuck there with no food and ammunition. They can't go forward nor backward. The only known path to the center of the valley that's known to us is controlled by the mercenaries. We're going to attack their camp. My guys are already in place. Your help would be most welcome. All the more so, you can help out Radik and your interests. So, decide, are you are with us or by yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_1111">
<text>Yeah, I'm with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_11111">
<text>No time to think, brother. Make up your mind now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_111111">
<text>Then you can take equipment from out trader. And when you'll be ready - talk to me. Just watch out, I'm not going to wait long for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_1112">
<text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_1113">
<text>Like I fucking need you - I'll handle it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_222222">
<text>Well, then I'm sorry, buddy, you did help me with the package, but in the way of conspiracies you'll have to wait here until we'll finish there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_2222222">
<text>Damn, I was just pulling your leg. Of course I'm with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_2_222223">
<text>Frets. I'd rather sit here all day and rest rather than be there with you and eat bullets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_11">
<text>Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_1111">
<text>Oh, it's you... Turbid said you sorted out the matter with the package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_21">
<text>Speak...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_23">
<text>(Text here was missing and contained only a "P")</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_31">
<text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_32">
<text>Well, listen now. The plan is simple as that. The guys laid explosives at the entrance. We blow up the gate, break in and put them all in their places. Are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_321">
<text>Always ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_322">
<text>I'm still taking a look around here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_3221">
<text>What the fuck? Say "Ready" and let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_32211">
<text>Okay, ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_33">
<text>Before some accident happens... If something happens with me, find Radik's squad. I already sent you their last coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_331">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_34">
<text>Not for you now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_41">
<text>Wow, you're a master. Take a modest reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_411">
<text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_4111">
<text>I will tell Radik about your deeds. So he'll help you out as much as he can. But do bring him some food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_41111">
<text>Good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_42">
<text>Not bad, not bad. Take a small fee.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_43">
<text>As a fighter you were, of course, weak, but... You helped. I'll tell Radik about your deeds. So he'll help you as much as he can. Just bring him some provisions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_44">
<text>Frankly, you're a crappy fighter. You didn't finish off even one mercenary. Well, that's your problem - all the fun is past you. So, will you bring Radik provisions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_441">
<text>Come on, I've been wanting to go to him all this time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_442">
<text>I'm not a camel to you that carries all sorts of crap on his back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_maxim_dialog_start_51">
<text>Greetings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_job_0">
<text>Hey, do you have a job for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_job_1">
<text>There is one little thing. There was a stalker with us - Gena Non-Understanding. He took my box of tools. He left the base. If you find him, take my stuff. I will not stay in debt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_job_11">
<text>Alright, if I'll find him, I'll take it back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_job_12">
<text>Another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_job_2">
<text>I had a deal with one stalker. Except that someone recently murdered him. And, as Stalin said: "No man, no problem."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_0">
<text>I found Fierce's PDA. It seems that there's something for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_1">
<text>How? Fierce is dead? Sorry for the guy. Where did you find this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_11">
<text>In a cave, not far from the bandit camp.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_111">
<text>Yeah... Misfortune... Here he wrote that he dropped a gun when he ran away from mutants. The deal is that he asked me for my modified shotgun when going out for a trip... Yeah - it did not help him and he didn't return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_1111">
<text>What, a valuable gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_luty_11111">
<text>The gun itself is not bad. But it is valuable to me for other reasons. Look, here are the coordinates for the place where he dropped the gun. If you're going to those places, check it out. I will not stay in debt. Take the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_mutny_0">
<text>I have to report an accident related to the rookie base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_mutny_1">
<text>What happened there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_mutny_11">
<text>It became apparent to me that Turbid mugs stalkers when they're leaving the valley with loot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_mutny_12">
<text>Now that's damn something! Thanks for the warning. We have long been suspecting that something wrong is happening in these places - we have lost contact with many stalkers who have went home with artifacts. I think that for such info you deserve a reward from the communal funds - go and speak with the trader. And this is from me, personally.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_about_mutny_2">
<text>I know... News quickly travel around there. Thanks for the information. Take this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_0">
<text>About your shotgun...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_1">
<text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_10">
<text>I found it. Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_101">
<text>Thank you, you helped me out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_11">
<text>I'm not going to look for it, I have other things to deal with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_111">
<text>No questions. I'll ask someone else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_cancel_wpn_12">
<text>It's nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_0">
<text>This may interest you. Here's Mishka "Tesla"'s manuscript. Looks like his own work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_1">
<text>Let me take a look... Wow... But how did he do this? Hmm... Interesting...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_11">
<text>What about translating it to normal human chatter? Are there any practical applications?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_111">
<text>It looks like Mishka has done a great job. It's a pity that he didn't choose another team... Okay. \n There are such anomalies - transporters, as they're called. I've heard about one of them - people go in it like it's a bubble and wind up God knows where - one returned damn long ago. And it seems that in Mishka's writing there are also "Unstable teleports" which are mentioned...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_1111">
<text>Can you make it simpler?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_11111">
<text>To be short, bring a "Svarog" detector and a "Compass" artifact here. I can adjust the detector so that it will detect these anomalies. If you need them, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_111111">
<text>Why do I need this detector? I'm going to leave the Zone with the help of the devil.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_1111111">
<text>Well, if you change your mind, talk to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_111112">
<text>I'll keep that in mind. So a "Svarog" and a "Compass"...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_1111121">
<text>Uh-huh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_111113">
<text>Take the "Svarog" and the "Compass".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_1_1111131">
<text>Well, you're a hoarder, now you have all you need. Come back later and you'll be able to take the detector.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_2_0">
<text>Is the detector ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_2_1">
<text>Yes, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_2_2">
<text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_3_0">
<text>Take the "Svarog" and "Compass".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_detector_3_1">
<text>Well, you're thrifty, that's all you need. Come back later and then you'll be able to take the detector.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_gena_dead_0">
<text>I found your Gena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_gena_dead_1">
<text>Did he take my box?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_gena_dead_11">
<text>No... I had to kill him but he didn't have the case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_gena_dead_111">
<text>Yes... Gena wasn't a fool with the whole deal of lugging around the loot. Well then... I'll have to order new instruments.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_0">
<text>Here, take your case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_1">
<text>Thanks for that. Take the pay... By the way, what happened to Gena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_11">
<text>I wasted him... There's no place in the Zone for people like him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_111">
<text>Well... That's what he deserved.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_12">
<text>I let him go wherever he wishes to, but the rest is his own problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_121">
<text>To hell with him...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_13">
<text>What's the difference... The case is with you and all is well...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_have_stuff_131">
<text>Well, do you wish to have a chat - do you need...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_told_about_loh_0">
<text>I found Gena, he wanted to buy back your tools but disappeared with the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_told_about_loh_1">
<text>Now that's damn something! Probably the old trick with the note?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_told_about_loh_11">
<text>Yeah...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_told_about_loh_111">
<text>Damn, the thing you've done there... Ha, don't throw the note away so that you don't forget about it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_0">
<text>Do you happen to need damaged guns for repairs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_1">
<text>I do need that. Do you see the box left of me? Throw the unnecessary scrap there. I'll dig through it in my free time and will pick what I need. I will not give a lot of money, but, on the other hand, you'll get rid of all the junk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_0">
<text>So, did you pick something from the scraps that I left?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_1">
<text>Yes, take the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_mutny_0">
<text>I have to report the accident related to the rookie base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_mutny_1">
<text>And what has happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_mutny_11">
<text>I found out that this guy, Turbid, robs stalkers when they're leaving the valley with loot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_mutny_111">
<text>Now that's damn something! Thanks for the warning. We have long been suspecting that something wrong is happening in these places - we have lost contact with many stalkers who have went home with artifacts. And thank you for the information. Take this award.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_mutny_2">
<text>Yes, I've heard about it... Thanks for the information. You deserve something from the communal funds. Here, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_0">
<text>Do you know Novikov? He's a scientist who works at Yantar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_1">
<text>I know. Is this related to the group of stalkers who performed measurements for his task?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_11">
<text>Yes. Andrey, the one who was taking the measurements, died. I have his flash drive with the results of the readings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_111">
<text>Hmm... I'll give you 3000 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_1111">
<text>Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_about_ucheny_1112">
<text>Another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_1_0">
<text>You sent a message. What's the deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_1_1">
<text>I was asked by the personnel of a scientific laboratory about research in the valley. They need help carrying out measurements in the anomalous zones. I was asked to find reliable people. They pay well. So, if you need extra income, talk to their lead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_2_0">
<text>I agreed to help the eggheads. We need explosives - they said that you're aware of that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_2_1">
<text>The explosives were left for us from the mercenaries at the containers. I already spoke with Ivan, he'll give them to you. \nAccording to the coordinates, the caves are located near the place where Semyon "Cowboy" is at. Now take the explosives and go directly there. But a guide for the guys I'll find by myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_3_0">
<text>There's a pay for me from the eggheads.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_nauchny_3_1">
<text>Ha. Yes, there is. Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_0">
<text>Is there a job for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_1">
<text>I will not go into details, but... There was a time when the military came here with choppers to slack off - offered us all sorts of junk. Of course, I also had to deal with them. But the last two wind riders did not fly away... Either they were shot at or they stepped foot in an anomaly - hell if I know. One fell near the rookie camp, so there's nothing left to take. But the other one died somewhere close to the center of the valley. And that's when he had my stuff on him - a couple few weapons and some other junk. But the most important thing is the laptop, I've been waiting long for it. Generally speaking, find my notebook - I'll owe you... Well, you can also take the junk, I may buy it off from you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_11">
<text>Yeah, damn... Previously I never could have imagined that the military did such business here. Interesting, did they get away with it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_111">
<text>Of course not. Half of the officers dealt with the cancer in the grunt ranks. It sucks... There's no more scrap being sent to us by air... Let's get to the deal. So, will you find my notebook?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_1111">
<text>Alright, if I'll find it, I'll bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_1112">
<text>I saw your chopper lying around near the containers. I also found your notebook.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_11121">
<text>Now that's something! Found it? Here, take 7500 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_111211">
<text>I accept.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_111212">
<text>No... This is my find. I won't sell it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_1112121">
<text>You shrewd guy... Alright, take 15000 and we make it a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_11121211">
<text>Now that's something different. Deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_2">
<text>Rumour has it that you killed Maximilian... This, of course, has not been proven, but... You don't have my trust.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_1_3">
<text>I don't have trust in you, man, which means that I have no work for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_2_0">
<text>I found the notebook.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_notebook_job_2_1">
<text>Now that's something! Found it? Here's 7500 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_0">
<text>I think you'll be interested.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1">
<text>What have you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_11">
<text>A mercenary's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_111">
<text>Hmm... Interesting... Take 2000 - there's nothing else to say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_17">
	<text>Fyodor's Flash</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_171">
	<text>Hmm... Interesting... Take 1000 - there's nothing else to say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1711">
	<text>Okey dokey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_12">
<text>Look at what a plant I found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_121">
<text>Wow. It seems that it's the plant that the scientists promised 6000 for... You can understand that I cannot give you the full sum, but 5000 - now that's a great price. The price is my own part of it. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1211">
<text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1212">
<text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_12121">
<text>Well, think about it, think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_13">
<text>I found Petya "Saiga"'s corpse. Do you know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_131">
<text>Darn. Saiga is dead? I thought so. He had to give me some sort of  information. But then he disappeared. Poor guy... Do you have his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1311">
<text>Yes, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_13111">
<text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_14">
<text>Mishka "Tesla"'s manuscript.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_141">
<text>I'm not interested. For that go and ask our technician, Valeriy Palich. They used to know each other until Mishka went away and joined "Freedom".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_142">
<text>I already told you - go to Valeriy Palich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_15">
<text>A bandit's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_151">
<text>I will give 1000 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1511">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1512">
<text>No, I'll hold on to it for now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_16">
<text>Vovka's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_161">
<text>Let me see. Hmm... Here it says that Vovka completed some sort of a task for Ozersky. He's a "full-time chef" when it comes to artifacts.  West of our base there is a cave where Ozerksy and his assistants live... I can buy this PDA from you for 1500 roubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_1611">
<text>Will do.</text>
    </string>
<string id="sad_b2_trader_sell_stuff_17">
<text>No problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_about_bomb_0">
<text>Rockefeller said that you have explosives.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_about_bomb_1">
<text>Yes, they remained from the mercenaries. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_about_ucheny_0">
<text>Andrey had to leave money for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_about_ucheny_1">
<text>Uh-huh. Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_0">
<text>Those prices you have... God damn...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_1">
<text>Shipping is expensive - there's your price. And the previous delivery disappeared with the stalkers who were carrying it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_11">
<text>What, a stalker betrayed you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_111">
<text>No... Vanka "Susanin" didn't betray me... Although, if there was a deal, he'd have a conversation with a squad of bandits in a nearby anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_1111">
<text>What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_11111">
<text>Vanka found short trails everywhere, which is why he worked faster. So he found a cave which, when used, could reduce the path from here to the exit of the valley. However, stalkers do not go that way - there's an anomaly which makes your brains boil. But Vanka bragged that he had found an artifact which made him able to not fear those anomalies... \nThe last time he told me on the radio that he's on his way. But then the connection was lost... Just in case I'll give you the coordinates of the entrance to the caves. If you find Vanka, take my stuff from him - I will not stay in debt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_111111">
<text>Okey, i do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_1_111112">
<text>Don't know. Maybe next time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_2_0">
<text>Take your goods. Vanka was killed by zombies in the caves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_trader_dialog_2_1">
<text>Yes... You can never know where to expect trouble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_arrive_home_0">
<text>All necessary measurements have been made. We're going back to the base. Ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_arrive_home_1">
<text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_0">
<text>I got your message... Who are you and what kind of a job is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_1">
<text>My name is Andrey, my partner's - Stepan. We were hired by scientists who have a base in Yantar. They were interested in the local anomaly fields. We are asked to make measurements in a couple few places. Some measurements we have made, but... During the past few days the mutant activity has become excessive, that's why going further to the center only as a pair is suicide. We met with Novikov - he's our direct customer - and he gave us the green light to hire stalkers to help take the measurements. Three already have agreed, but we want to have another one in the group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_11">
<text>I agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_111">
<text>Good. Let me know when you're ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_12">
<text>I don't have time for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d1_121">
<text>Well, if you change your mind, we'll kindly invite you... If we won't find anyone else for that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d2_0">
<text>I'm here regarding the measurements. Is there room for another one in the squad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d2_1">
<text>You're right on time. There were a couple few doubters around. But you've been to those places, so your help will be useful. Let me know when you're ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d3_0">
<text>I'm ready to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d3_1">
<text>Well, then, I'll warn you right away - we're not going on a picnic, so stock up on equipment. Also, we'll move as a group. If you'll move far away from the group, then you'll be automatically kicked out of it and you won't see the dough. Not a single person will be able to see the cash in the case of my death simply beacause I'm the only one who can take these measurements. Well, got it all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_d3_11">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_start_11">
<text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_start_21">
<text>You were of great help. Take the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b3_ucheny_start_31">
<text>Yes, yes...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_0">
<text>I'm dying, brother...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_1">
<text>Take the medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_11">
<text>It won't help... My time has come... I lived like a dog and will die like one... I have only one request... Give me a gun and one round.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_111">
<text>Okay, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_112">
<text>Why did you become so limp, buddy. Get it together! We'll stumble to the doctor. He'll put you back on your feet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_1121">
<text>I have my own grievances with life, brother. Don't play the hero here. So give me a gun or get out of here...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_fedor_talk_11211">
<text>Farewell...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_0">
<text>Hello, brother. I've heard that stalkers curtailed you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_1">
<text>Yes, by surprise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_2">
<text>I suppose you are itching to finish off that louse. I'm all for it. I don't see why the fuck do you need him alive. But, well, an order is an order. Excuse me, brother, don't take it to heart.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_3">
<text>Where's the other one? There were two of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_4">
<text>What's with you, brother, have you been living under a rock? Or... There's something fishy about this. Come on, tell me the code word!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_41">
<text>Hell if I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_42">
<text>Abrakadabra?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_43">
<text>Syaski-masyaski?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_jail_guard_44">
<text>Bambariya kergudu?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_first_meet_0">
<text>I don't understand, why are you alone? Where are the men?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_first_meet_1">
<text>Well, damn, we ran into a squad of stalkers - the guys are no more, I'm the only one left.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_first_meet_2">
<text>Well, shit. Go to the leader... The stalkers are flooding in like flies to honey. Something needs to be done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_first_meet_3">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_11">
<text>Hello. I already heard about your "achievements". It's a shame - the stalkers kicked your asses.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_111">
<text>They caught us by surprise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_1111">
<text>Alright, I'll talk with you later. You can go now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_11111">
<text>Good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_21">
<text>What else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_killer_glavar_211">
<text>Nothing... I'm going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_11">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_111">
<text>What will you do next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_1111">
<text>Nothing will be done here. Soon we'll go to the containers. And we'll stay there. If you decide to come with us, tell me, we'll leave immediately. It's always more fun together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_11111">
<text>Alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_21">
<text>So, are you ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_211">
<text>No, I'm still taking a look around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b4_talk_after_212">
<text>Yes, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_0">
<text>I'm here thanks to the swag that your crooks took from the stalkers some time ago.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_1">
<text>Oh, it's a small box, so blue...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_11">
<text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_111">
<text>No, I haven't heard of it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_1111">
<text>Stop playing the fool, this is Maximilian's item. Have you heard of it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_11111">
<text>I don't give a damn who's doing well. Two guys got drunk here and lost the swag in a card game. To be honest, the box is locked away so that my brothers don't knock each others teeth out for it. In short, give me ten grand and you can take it. That's like a darn "Wheel of Fortune" here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_111111">
<text>Okay, take the dough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_1111111">
<text>Well, come back when you will.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_111112">
<text>I don't have 10000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_111115">
<text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_1_2">
<text>You know the price - decide before I haven't changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_start_21">
<text>What do you want, stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_start_22">
<text>Why did you drag yourself here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_dialog_start_23">
<text>Dragged myself... Fuck you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_0">
<text>Where are you going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_1">
<text>Well, damn, I'm thinking about joining in with your band.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_11">
<text>I don't think that Kostyan "Frock Coat" will allow a sucker like you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_111">
<text>I was just joking, I have a deal with Kostyan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_1111">
<text>Well, come in, just don't fool around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_11111">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_2">
<text>I'm from the Canadian company. I want to sell cosmetics to your group's leader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_22">
<text>The hell, we've got a joker around here? We can quickly deal with that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_221">
<text>Okay, okay, don't get mad... I have a deal with your leader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_222">
<text>Well, give it a shot, risk with your own health.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_2222">
<text>Come closer, you joker, just don't fool around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_22221">
<text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_22222">
<text>Come closer, you joker, just don't screw around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1_3">
<text>We had an argument with stalkers that I get you in the basement. So get out of the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1b_0">
<text>Fuck off, stalker. You don't have anything to do in here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1b_1">
<text>Understood, I'm going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ban_bandit_guard_1b_2">
<text>For such words I can punch you in the mug.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_merc_0">
<text>Where are the mercenaries here from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_merc_1">
<text>It's not my business. They don't let us get to the center, which means that someone needs what's there. And if they have enough dough to pay for mercenaries, we don't have a need to wage war with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_mutny_0">
<text>Did you hear the news about Turbid?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_mutny_1">
<text>What about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_mutny_11">
<text>It turns out that he robs stalkers on the way back from the valley. Warn your guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_about_mutny_111">
<text>Well... Anything can happen... As they say - don't blame the swordsman, but blame the one who holds his sword.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_dialog_1_0">
<text>"Tesla" said that you have a hundred grams and dough for anyone who kills Oleg...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_dialog_1_1">
<text>Say what? You know where this louse is hiding?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_dialog_1_11">
<text>I do know... In hell... I sent him there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_dialog_1_111">
<text>That's good news. Take this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_11">
<text>Good to see you. What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_111">
<text>I'm searching for stalkers - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. Have you seen them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_1111">
<text>Yes, they were here. They were searching for an ordered artifact. Craven stayed here, he wanted to check out one place for artifacts, but Bonehead and Seasoned went away to some sort of a stalker container. We agreed to meet on the way back. But I haven't seen them ever since. And do you understand what's the deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_11111">
<text>The guys didn't return back on time. I was hired to find them and obtain their artifact... So, well... Did Craven find the artifact?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_111111">
<text>Well, listen... You won't get on the plateau where the artifact may be at that easily. And there's no direct exit to get back out of there. Generally speaking, you can get there only if you hunt down a spatial anomaly. Our mechanic, Mishka "Tesla" built a special scanner that finds such anomalies. However, the thing isn't stable, but Craven decided to take the risk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_1111111">
<text>Go on...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_11111111">
<text>Craven didn't wait until "Tesla" checked everything - he relied on chance. Generally speaking, he teleported to somewhere. And then the connection was lost. And no sound or life. Either if he's alive or not, we don't know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_1111111111">
<text>Ha... My guys didn't go here to kill themselves... But...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_21">
<text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_81">
<text>Are you no longer trying to get to the plateau?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_cowboy_start_811">
<text>No... We are currently content with easy loot. Yes, and there are no "heroes" amongst us who can bounce around anomalies. If you're willing to take the risk, talk with Mishka "Tesla" about the scanner. I'll alert him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_11">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_21">
<text>There's nothing for us to talk about, you're on your own now. Go your own way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_211">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_22">
<text>You wanted to and said that you're on your own, but you still kind of helped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_31">
<text>Oh, it's you... We called you to come here and talk, we wanted to invite you to capture the camp, but you ignored us. So, go your own way - we have nothing to speak about when it comes to that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_32">
<text>Damn, man, me called you to attack the camp together, but you ignored us... But you helped. Thank you for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_41">
<text>Ah, hello... Well, what can I say to you? You didn't do a darn thing to help us... If only you killed just one bastard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_42">
<text>That's it - Turbid is no more. Now I'll stay here to monitor what happens next.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_43">
<text>Hello... Eh, I feel grief about Grisha, he was a good stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_431">
<text>Anything can happen - we're not here to rest like it's a resort.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_after_fight_4311">
<text>And that is true... Although Turbid is no more... And now I'll stay here to monitor what happens next.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_0">
<text>I received a message that you need help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_1">
<text>The deal is about Turbid. After you reported about his foul deeds, stalkers, of course, went to his place to get rid of him. And this nit managed to put together a band with his friends - former "Duty" members - and killed all the rookies at the base. Generally speaking, Turbid has nowhere to go, so he's on the defense at the rookie base. We're going to kill the bastards. Are you with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_11">
<text>Yeah, I'm with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_111">
<text>Well, when you're going to be ready, talk to me. Just don't take long, we won't be waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_12">
<text>No, these are your own problems. I'm staying out of this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_0_2">
<text>There's been a sabotage at the novice base. Not too long ago Turbid was accused of robbery by stalkers who were returning from the center of the valley with loot. The rookies didn't wait for us and went to him to get rid of the guy. And this nit managed to put together a band with his friends - former "Duty" guys, and killed all the novices... Generally speaking, Turbid now has nowhere to go, so he's defending at the rookie base. We're going to kill the bastards. Are you with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_grisha_dialog_1_0">
<text>I am willing to be nominated.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_maxim_about_cowboy_1_0">
<text>Here's the deal... Generally speaking, I was robbed. Yes, it's stupid, I feel dumb for saying this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_maxim_about_cowboy_1_1">
<text>Well, fuck. Who has done that here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_maxim_about_cowboy_1_11">
<text>There's that bastard - Semyon "Cowboy".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_maxim_about_cowboy_1_111">
<text>Yes, brother, business... You, come to the base. There you'll find Volodya "Big". I'll warn him, he will help you. As for the equipment, address the technician and the trader, they may have some sort of a job ready for you. And one more thing... Take the key for my personal box at the base, I left all sorts of stuff there - it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_0">
<text>Rockefeller said that you need help. What are you researching?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_1">
<text>According to our theory, there are some sort of anomalous formations underground. Perhaps they provoked the powerful local emissions, which reshaped the whole valley. We sent stalkers to the valley with specially configured detectors that can detect such anomalies. One of these stalkers found a place where the detector's sensor went off the scale. But he died on the way back to us. Rockefeller sold us his PDA. So now we have the coordinates of the place. According to the stalker's PDA entries it's a cave that's littered with stones. It is unknown what's in this cave. Therefore, we need men for support.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_11">
<text>Have you, by any chance, hired mercenaries to protect these places from "bad" pathfinders?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_111">
<text>No. Our financial resources do not permit that. But we're not the only ones trying to find the anomalous formations here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_1111">
<text>I agree to help. What is the plan of action?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_11111">
<text>First, you need to get the explosives, which would clear the entrance to the cave. Talk with Rockefeller - he is aware of the situation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_1_1112">
<text>I don't have time for that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_2_0">
<text>I took the explosives.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_2_1">
<text>Excellent. Ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_2_11">
<text>Yes, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_2_12">
<text>I need some more time to prepare.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_2_13">
<text>I have a small job - entertaining tourists. I'll deal with them and then we'll go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_3_0">
<text>Done. I set the charge.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_3_1">
<text>Well, then detonate it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_3_11">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_0">
<text>What was in the cave? What laboratory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_1">
<text>I can't say anything specific. I have always considered the presence of underground laboratories here to be a myth. But, as we have seen, they do exist. In any case, there's not enough data right now. One thing is for sure - the mercenaries are guarding these secrets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_11">
<text>You are going to investigate this matter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_111">
<text>Most likely - yes. But not around these parts. There was nothing planned about disclosing the secrets of the Zone in this episode. And you have other tasks to do for now. Maybe someday you will return to the valley and will investigate this same question. Who knows, maybe everything here will be different.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_1111">
<text>Darn, you're such a ratface. This complication was planned and you just turn your back to it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_4_11111">
<text>It's not me, it's the upper ones.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_start_11">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_start_12">
<text>You've been very helpful. In any case, I left the reward for you at Rockfeller.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_nauchny_dialog_start_13">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ran_guard_first_talk_0">
<text>What do you want, stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ran_guard_first_talk_1">
<text>I am looking for stalkers, they may have been here. Who's your leader, I need to talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ran_guard_first_talk_11">
<text>Well, I consider that you've been past face-control. The leader's name is Semyon, he's on the second floor. Go. Just be polite - do not fool around with guns.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_ran_guard_first_talk_111">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_gonets_dialog_0">
<text>Greetings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_gonets_dialog_1">
<text>Did you bring the outfit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_gonets_dialog_2">
<text>Yes, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_gonets_dialog_3">
<text>Take it easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_0">
<text>What do you want, stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_1">
<text>I am here from Maximilian.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_11">
<text>Go, just don't fool around with weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_111">
<text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_2">
<text>I am looking for someone. Who's in charge? We need to talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_31">
<text>The chief's called Radik. Go, but if you're here to do business, don't screw around with your weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_guard_311">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_1_0">
<text>I brought you food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_1_1">
<text>Thanks for that. Well, tell me, what do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_0">
<text>I'm looking for these stalkers - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. Maximilian said that they went with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_1">
<text>Yes, we met on the way and teamed up. Only one of them - Craven, broke off before the containers. He's, like, going to go and look for artifacts. We agreed to meet on the way back. All was well then. \nBut we moved onwards. Then we ran into a squad of mercenaries. There wasn't a detachment, it was a darn army; to hell with them. Seasoned with Fyodor went ahead. They only managed to warn us before they were captured. The fight there was no showing off. We rushed back. One of my guys "went to sleep", but Bonehead fell in a Springboard. Later, we went there. Here, take his PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_11">
<text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_111">
<text>Don't even think that we abandon our guys. We simply had no choice in this situation. All have perished there. Now we're going to free Fyodor and Seasoned. Are you with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_1111">
<text>Yeah, I'm with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_11111">
<text>Then let's delve in this. A head-on attack is impossible, the guys will most likely get killed. Here it's necessary to perform a trick. We need to give them a "trojan". Got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_111111">
<text>Tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_1111111">
<text>We need to get a mercenary's outfit and a PDA from one of their guys. Then you will get to their base in disguise, you'll find the guys and you'll give us the signal. In the meantime, we will attack the camp while you will protect the boys. Such is the plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_11111111">
<text>Not a bad plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_111111111">
<text>Well then, go to the base. Take the mercenary's outfit from the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_1111111111">
<text>Damn, where did he get such a suit from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_11111111111">
<text>This is from the time when I contacted Maximilian on the radio and asked him to order one copy, just in case. It came in handy, as you can see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_2_1112">
<text>That's not fucking necessary - I'll go on my own.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_3_0">
<text>I took the PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_3_1">
<text>That's nice. Now all is set. Let me know when you're ready. We'll move immediately.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_4_0">
<text>I took the suit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_4_1">
<text>Excellent. Now all what remains is to get a mercenary's PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_4_2">
<text>Any ideas?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_6_0">
<text>I'm ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_6_1">
<text>Chances are mercenaries blocked the passage to their base. But the explosives will do the trick. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_6_11">
<text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_about_merc_0">
<text>What are the mercenaries doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_about_merc_1">
<text>Hell if I know. One thing is clear - their customers don't want for stalkers to poke their nose around the center of the valley.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11">
<text>Who are you? What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_111">
<text>I am here from Maximilian.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_1111">
<text>Ah... He informed me that you brought food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11111">
<text>Yes, I did. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_111111">
<text>Thanks for that. Well, tell me, what did you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11112">
<text>I brough it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_1112">
<text>Yes, he talked about you. A conversation with us won't happen as long as my men are hungry. Bring us provisions, then we'll talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11121">
<text>Alright, I'll bring that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11122">
<text>To hell with you - find the food yourselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_1121">
<text>Wait a minute... Maximilian told me about you. You, like, refused to help him. So I don't want to talk to you. Understood?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11211">
<text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_114">
<text>I'm looking for these friends - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. I was told that they had went with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_1141">
<text>Yes, they were here. We won't be able to have a conversation as long as my men are hungry. Bring us provisions, then we'll talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_11411">
<text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_114111">
<text>Thank you for that. Now, tell me, what did you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_21">
<text>Damn, my stomach is growling... Did you bring the provisions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_2111">
<text>Text in default.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_212">
<text>I'm in process of that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_22">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_31">
<text>Go your way, dude.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_311">
<text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_radik_start_51">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_tech_start_11">
<text>Greetings. I'm kind of a mechanic. Serious upgrades I can't perform, but if you need a gun repaired, talk to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_tech_start_12">
<text>Greetings. I'm kind of a mechanic. Serious upgrades I can't perform, but if you need a gun repaired, talk to me. For now that'll be for free.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_tech_start_21">
<text>Well, what have you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sher_tech_start_22">
<text>Well, what has happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_11">
<text>It seems to have ended. Radik died - now I'm over it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_111">
<text>What's next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_1111">
<text>Next change to a mercenary's outfit and go straight along the path to their base. Look for our guys there... And then we'll get there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_11111">
<text>Welcome.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_21">
<text>It seems to have ended.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_13_after_31">
<text>Well... What are you waiting for? Go to the merc base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_1_0">
<text>Now, look at that, what people are here! Gena Non-Understanding! And I was looking everywhere for you. The technician at the base, Valeriy Palich, actually, they all missed you... And then there's your box.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_1_1">
<text>That's our own private matter with him. By the way, I stashed away the box. Just in case you decide to be a fool. So, mind your own business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_1_11">
<text>We'll see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_0">
<text>Help...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_1">
<text>Eh, no, mate... First, tell me where did you hide that box. And I'm thinking about either giving you the medkit or not.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_11">
<text>Okay. I buried it not far from here. Give the first aid kit, and I'll take you to the place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_111">
<text>Okay, take the medkit...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_112">
<text>I don't have a medkit. Lie down here, I'll go and look.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_2">
<text>Now look at that, what people are here! Gena Non-Understanding! And I was looking everywhere for you. The technician at the base missed you... And then there's your box. So, do you want to live?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_3">
<text>Argh, you got here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_7_gena_dialog_2_4">
<text>First, I will finish off your buddies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_about_merc_0">
<text>Where do the mercenaries come here from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_about_merc_1">
<text>Mercenaries? Ah, the ones who have a base nearby?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_about_merc_11">
<text>Well, yes...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_about_merc_111">
<text>No, I haven't heard...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11">
<text>Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_111">
<text>A stalker. I walk, I travel. And there's a concert - you and the monsters. Here I stayed for the intermission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_1111">
<text>You're a rather bad hunter... How did you even get here? I do not understand... Well, go and practise. When you'll be experienced, come and talk to me... But now I have nothing to talk about with you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11111">
<text>Okay...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_1112">
<text>Yes... You, hunter, bless you! You shot the monsters... What are you looking for in these parts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11121">
<text>I'm looking for a "Compass" artifact... Do you know where I can find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_111211">
<text>Eh, you... Artifact - shmartifact... The Zone will be covered in another blowout, like last time... Who will want them? Okay... I have a "Compass", take it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_1112111">
<text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11121111">
<text>Well, go... And I need to get some sleep...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_111211111">
<text>Goodnight...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11122">
<text>Many are looking for that. For an example, the "Heart of Oasis" artifact... Have you heard of such a thing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_111221">
<text>Eh, you... Artifact - shmartifact... Here the Zone will cover another area in a blowout, like last time... Who will want them? Okay... I live here as a hermit, but I do undestand something when it comes to artifacts... So, take the "Compass" artifact... Intuition tells me that this will help you find the "Heart of the Oasis"...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_11123">
<text>Of course, I wanted to go and shoot some monsters...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_111231">
<text>Well, shot some? But go now... I need some sleep...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_112">
<text>I've seen him... I'm a stalker...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_1_2">
<text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_2_0">
<text>Listen, do you have a twin brother in Zaton?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sim_9_noy_dialog_2_1">
<text>All men are brothers. In Zaton or here - it's the same everywhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_11">
<text>Well, hello... You see how it's like... Then there was Vovka, now there's no Vovka...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_111">
<text>What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_1111">
<text>You see, there, that's an anomaly. There's a cave. No-one has ever returned from that cave. It is said that there's some sort of a grandiose artifact. And that's where the reckless heads go off to...  Vovka also decided to risk... Now Vovka is no more...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_11111">
<text>Yes, this is not a resort... Also, I'm looking for my friends - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. Have you met them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_111111">
<text>No, I haven't seen them. Go and ask Turbid. If someone has disappeared here then he hasn't been past his base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_1111111">
<text>Thank you. Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_start_men_dialog_21">
<text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_0">
<text>Hi, I'm here from Semyon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_1">
<text>Ah, you're here for the scanner? There are two problems. The first one - to make the detector stable, a "Compass" artifact is needed, which I don't have. And without the "Compass" there is no guarantee that teleportation will be correct.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_11">
<text>And the second one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_111">
<text>There was a stalker with us - Oleg "Motaliga". We didn't really develop a relationship with him. He always wasn't satisfied about something - then there was the wrong upgrade, then the detector was not properly configured... At one point, he removed the microchip from the scanner and flung it to an unknown direction. In general, made a nasty end. By the way, not only for me. Semyon put a bounty on his head. \nThat's why I've stopped work on the scanner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_1111">
<text>If I get a "Compass" and the microchip, the scanner will work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_0_11111">
<text>Where did he go? Personally, I'll go with you, and I'll follow the operation of the scanner, if you decide to make the jump.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_1_0">
<text>I brought the missing parts for the scanner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_1_1">
<text>Bring them here... Setting up the scanner will take some time. But during this time you'll have a job to deal with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_1_11">
<text>What's the matter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_1_111">
<text>You see, I have to go with you to monitor the operation of the scanner. But that place, to say the least, is... Dumb... More mutants have appeared - just don't cry for your mother. Go and clean up the place. I already gave you the coordinates... Also, take this gun - it'll come in handy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_2_0">
<text>All is clear - the mutants have been killed. We can advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_2_1">
<text>That's good... I configured the scanner... A difficult thing, that bitch... You can understand it yourself - it's your own burden. Well then, are you ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_tesla_dialog_2_2">
<text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_cmon_0">
<text>Follow me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_info_health_0">
<text>Take the medkit and heal yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_info_health_1">
<text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_0">
<text>Greetings. What are you doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_1">
<text>You see, tourists have arrived. Do you wish to lead them around such a haven?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_11">
<text>How much?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_111">
<text>They have plenty of cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_1111">
<text>What needs to be done?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_11111">
<text>Guys are looking for thrills - beasts to shoot, taking a look at the anomalous areas. They need someone who knows the local sites.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_111111">
<text>I agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_1111111">
<text>Try not to kill the mutants, just injure them. That's because your pay depends on the amount of mutants that the tourists have killed. Guide them to the local anomalies - let them look around. And don't forget to periodically treat them after a fight - if one of them dies, then the amount of money you'll get will be barely worth a damn. When you'll be ready, come here and talk to me - I'll be waiting here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_11111111">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_1_12">
<text>I do not have time for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_2_0">
<text>That's it - lead them to Zaton.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_2_11">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_2_111">
<text>Okay, I'm taking these along. Maybe there'll be more the next day. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_locman_2_1111">
<text>Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_stay_here_0">
<text>Wait here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_step_back_0">
<text>Move away, friend, you're blocking the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_0">
<text>Listen carefully - I'll give everyone an introduction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_1">
<text>I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_11">
<text>Do not attack until I do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_111">
<text>Understood. But if we'll get shot at, we won't just stand there - we're not soldiers and we won't fulfil your orders without asking questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_12">
<text>Ignore the fighting if the enemy is far away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_121">
<text>How far?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_1211">
<text>30 meters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_1212">
<text>50 meters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_15">
<text>If I run away, it means that there's something bad. Ignore the enemies and run after me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_151">
<text>We will try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_16">
<text>Hang up the "Run after me" command.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_161">
<text>Understood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_turist_vvodnaya_19">
<text>I cancel all previous statements. If you see an enemy, just shoot it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_uni_about_stalkers_0">
<text>I'm looking for these stalkers - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned. Ever seen them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_uni_about_stalkers_1">
<text>No... I haven't seen them. Go and ask Turbid - he's a veteran. Many stalkers go to his base. Here are his coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_dialog_11">
<text>Thank you, friend, you rescued me. I already thought that was it - the end of me. In return I'll tell you a secret - closer to the center are a bunch of containers, you can't miss them, there's a tree there right in the middle. At this tree is a backpack with good loot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_dialog_11121">
<text>Walk somewhere further away from here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_dialog_111211">
<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_dialog_21">
<text>Ah, the saviour.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_flesh_dialog_0">
<text>Do you have Fyodor's flash drive? If so, give it to me without any additional questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_flesh_dialog_1">
<text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_stalkers_dialog_0">
<text>Hey, have you come across these stalkers - Craven, Bonehead and Seasoned?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_vasya_stalkers_dialog_1">
<text>No, I've never met them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_after_11">
<text>Well, now we'll be there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_after_12">
<text>It's a shame that Volodya died... He was a good man...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_after_21">
<text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_1_0">
<text>Greetings. I am here from Maximilian.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_1_1">
<text>Yes... After "Cowboy"'s hooligans?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_1_11">
<text>Uh-huh... I went to an anomaly and found an artifact. But when I went back, they caught me in an ambush.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_1_111">
<text>Well, brother, you can't be so trusting here... Well, let's get to the point. Me and the guys have long been itching to kick some ass, but we're sitting here like in some sort of a sanatorium - darn boring. Especially because this is a good place for that. Now we have a reason to poke around there. Tell when you are ready, we will move immediately.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_2_0">
<text>I am ready to advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_3_0">
<text>Good. You'll be the one in charge here now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_3_1">
<text>I would not say so. But if any problems arise, talk to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_3_11">
<text>Yes, I was robbed by "Cowboy" and his pals. Now I want to take over their base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_volodya_dialog_3_111">
<text>Well, a deal... Me and the guys have long been itching to kick some ass, but we're sitting here like in some sort of a sanatorium - darn boring. Especially because this is a good place for that. Now we have a reason to poke around there. Tell when you are ready, we will move immediately.</text>
    </string>

	<!-- SAD_ATR_DIALOG -->

	<string id="atr_actor_start">
<text>I want to change an artifact's properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_trader_start">
<text>What kind of changes would you like to make?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_actor_exit">
<text>I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_radiation_general">
<text>Remove the radioactive component.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_mixer_general">
<text>Mix artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_power_general">
<text>Strengthen its properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_next_time_general">
<text>Some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_radiation_trader_1">
<text>To perform this procedure, I need the local radioactive mushroom. Do you have it? No...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_radiation_trader_2">
<text>As I understood, the radioactive mushroom is with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_radiation_trader_3">
<text>Let's see which artifacts of yours I can, so to speak, pump up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_radiation_trader_4">
<text>Let's see... Hmm... Unfortunately, you do not have any artifacts whose properties I could change.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_mixer_trader">
<text>In the local context, I can not do any soldering. Let's see what you have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_mixer_trader_x">
<text>In this given order it is impossible to mix them together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_power_trader">
<text>I can't strengthen every artifact. Let's see what you have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atr_trader_come_later">
		<text>Come back after three hours. If you want to, you can lay down on the couch.</text>
	</string>

   <string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_0">
    <text>Hello, Beard, what's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_1">
    <text>Hello, Max. Problems have arisen. A request has come in for one artifact - called the Heart of the Oasis. I started looking for information about it, and I was told that it may be located in the Valley of Whispers. This is a territory full of cracks that formed after the Big Emission. So, for this serious request, I sent my friends: Coward, Fool and Veteran, but they disappeared.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_2">
    <text>Yes, business. What are you going to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_3">
    <text>Organize a search, need to find my friends and the artifact itself. Will you take the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_4">
    <text>Yes, I'll do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_41">
    <text>No, I have too much to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_5">
    <text>Too bad. But come by if you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_51">
    <text>Okay, I'll send all the info to your PDA. Go talk to the Harbor Master, he'll take you to the Valley of Whispers and give you a lead on who you can ask about my friends there.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_6">
    <text>The Harbor Master, you say? Okay, I'll go talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_oasis_0">
    <text>Beard, I found the artifact you requested. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_oasis_1">
    <text>Amazing thing, I've never seen anything like it. Here, take your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_oasis_2">
    <text>Thank you. If you have more work, let me know.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_pda_0">
    <text>Beard, I have news. I found your friends - they're all dead. It's a dangerous place, you shouldn't have sent them there.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_pda_1">
    <text>Oh... how could this happen? They were the best stalkers, they performed all dangerous tasks flawlessly and without losses!</text>
</string>
 <string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_pda_2">
        <text>Yeah, those guys were unlucky. The places there are wild, and the people are scum, ready to betray for a penny. Here, take their PDAs. Maybe you'll find something interesting there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_pda_3">
        <text>Okay, thanks for the job, stalker. Here's your reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_sad_give_pda_4">
        <text>Thanks, Beard. If you need anything, just let me know.</text>
    </string>

   <string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_sad_0">
    <text>Hey, Pilot. Beard sent me to you. I need you to take me to the Valley of Whispers. He also said that you will give me information on who I can talk to there.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_sad_1">
    <text>So you need to go to the Valley of Whispers? Beard already transferred everything to my PDA, I know what you're looking for. Ready to go? It'll be two thousand from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_sad_2">
    <text>Agreed, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_sad_21">
    <text>I don't have that much.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_sad_3">
    <text>Come back when you have it.</text>
</string>






</string_table>
