<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>Halt, who is this!? What were you doing there? I wouldn't recommend lying.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>My name is Savannah, freelance stalker. I had a partner with me, Borland. He got out before I did. Skidan, the trader from Cordon showed us the way to the X5 lab.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>You two are idiots. And so is Skidan. Your partner's got severe poisoning. Must have been gassed. And there's no guarantee you didn't ingest it, too. It's toxic gas, why are you dumbasses in there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>It's not so poisonous as long as we're still alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>If you live till tomorrow at least, you're lucky as hell. Nobody knows what the gas is, but every time it's killed a digger. They get out alive, then an hour later they die. In terrible agony.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_5">
        <text>Did they all die?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_6">
        <text>One of them seems to be alive, but nobody knows how he did it. If you can find him, you can help yourself and your friend Borland.</text>
    </string>
	 <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_7">
        <text>Where do we find this digger survivor?</text>
    </string>
	 <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_8">
        <text>Hell if I know. Somewhere. At the junkyard.</text>
    </string>
	 <string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_9">
        <text>See ya.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_101">
        <text>I don't feel so good, Sawan. I think we've been breathing some special shit in the underground. I've had two whole army first-aid kits pumped into me, but it's no use. I'm getting worse and worse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>I know, Borland, I feel like shit too. But the longshoreman said there's a digger who's been dealing with this poisoning. You wouldn't happen to know about that, would you? Where can I find him on the Dump?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>I heard there's a rubbish heap near the tanks. Well, I heard it's in that area somewhere. A lot of people have tried, but no one's found his lair.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>We don't have much choice. If you can't go, I'll find it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>Come on, you're our only hope. But there's no time left, I'm afraid the Zone is going to eat me. Goodbye, maybe I won't see you again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>Hold on, I'll be right back.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>Shroud, I knew you'd keep your word.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>All right, Borland, here's the antidote.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>You just get yourself up, and I'll have a word with the local authorities.</text>
    </string>	
	
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_00">
        <text>You smell that, Savannah? A blowout of unprecedented power is coming. A super-blowout. The scientists have issued a warning. The only place to hide from it is in the dungeons of the Bar. If you don't want to die, follow us to the Bar for cover. Decide now. If not, we're closing off the Junkyard Bar, so the mutants don't come after us. There's no survivors here in the junkyard.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_0">
        <text>The Bar is the only place to survive? Are you sure?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_1">
        <text>You don't joke about that sort of thing. If you've noticed, the dump is already deserted. Everyone who cares about life has already evacuated.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_2">
        <text>How far is Bara from here? Can we make it? I don't know the way. It's my first time here. Borland, my partner, probably knows the way...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_3">
        <text>No time to talk. Sensors are going off the scale. Make up your mind. Are you coming with us?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_4">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="gar_a2_dolg_guard_dialog_0">
        <text>Hurry up, it's about to start! We'll wait for another Quad and follow you. In short, on the road all the way and on the run. Let's go!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_a2_dolg_guard_dialog_1">
        <text>Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    
</string_table>
