<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_text">
    <text> I don't lend money! What do you want? </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_text">
    <text> Hey, Savan. </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_bandit_logoped_start_dialog_text">
    <text> What do you want, buddy? </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_bandit_tick_start_dialog_text">
    <text> So, what's up with you? </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_0">
    <text> Stop right there! Who are you? </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_1">
    <text> We're scientists under contract... </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_2">
    <text> Do you know the procedure? Papers for inspection! Slowly. If anything, I'll shoot without warning! </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_3">
    <text> Here you go. </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_4">
    <text> Let's see... Stamp and signatures in place. Seems to be in order... But why are you on foot? Where is the escort? Where's Major Polischuk? </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_5">
    <text> Our car broke down, and he stayed with it. It's not far, just a couple of kilometers. We decided to walk, since we can't drive any further anyway. </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_6">
    <text> When are they going to replace this piece of junk? What are they thinking, for God's sake? They should be sent here for a day... Okay, here are your papers. You may pass. </text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_7">
    <text> Thank you. </text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_8">
    <text>What's that! What did you smear your hand with, ink? Stop! Hand it over. Give me that!. The stamp is smudged! It's a forgery! Well, pray, scoundrel!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_9">
    <text>No! Don't shoot!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_about_zone_0">
    <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_about_zone_1">
    <text>I found the right person to ask! Ask the eggheads instead, they examine it under a microscope and put it in an X-ray. But I know a little bit about the Zone... It allows me to earn enough money to buy my own plot of land with a vineyard on the seaside in two years - that's it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you, brother! You saved me - I won't forget it! Sorry, I don't have any money right now. But I'll pay you back later! And now, let me give you the coordinates of the stash. I hid a good sawn-off shotgun there on my last trip. Whatever you find is yours. I owe you my life, Savan. I'm in your debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, come on, don't mention it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_3">
    <text>Believe me, not everyone would risk their life for someone they barely know. Here in the Zone, it's usually every man for himself. Anyway, I'm heading to the ATP, I've got some business there. See you later, I think. Take care! </text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_4">
    <text>You too, take care!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are. We've searched the entire camp. So, are you alive and well?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah. I met some new people. From the swamps.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you talking about Dima? Well, we've known each other for ages, just haven't seen each other for a while. And here - a pleasant surprise. So, let's go to the village and discuss our business? I found something in Logoped's notes that I think you'll find interesting. By the way, keep your stuff, I can't carry it forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go quickly, I'm starving - I have no strength left.</text>
</string>
 <string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Good thing everything worked out. They could have killed you. I warned you not to ask about the Freedom member directly. Anyway, let's not dwell on that. I found out a lot of things here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>For example?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_10">
    <text>There's a local resident here, an old man who's obsessed with clocks. He's supposedly a master of clockmaking. They say he's been living in this village since its founding, even before the first disaster in 1986, can you imagine? And he survived the second disaster too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_11">
    <text>What good is that to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_12">
    <text>Just listen. Logopedist had some blueprints of old communications in his laptop: pipes, tunnels, ventilation shafts. I figured out that one of these tunnels passes right under this Clockmaker's house.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_13">
    <text>What are you suggesting? Break into the old man's house and search it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_14">
    <text>Are you an idiot on Saturdays or what? Why break in? We won't break in. We'll ask him nicely. Maybe the old man needs something and we'll bring it to him, like a glass of water or something. Can you go and talk to the Clockmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_15">
    <text>Why me? I'm no negotiator, I'm just a grunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_16">
    <text>I know you're no diplomat, that's for sure. But I need to go to Shaman's urgently, to give him Logopedist's laptop. There's still a lot of useful information for the free stalkers on it. I can't trust anyone else with it, not even you. No hard feelings. Don't worry, I deleted all the information about the catacombs from the laptop. So now, nobody knows about these underground passages except us.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_17">
    <text>Okay, I'll talk to the old man. Damn you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>I found out where they caught the Freedom member. Can you believe it? The bandits took him almost right near the rookie village.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>So, right here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Almost. There's an iron hut on the hill. That's where they took him. Can you imagine, the bandits have never ventured so far into stalker territory before. It seems they had been tracking the freelancer for a long time. He was very important to them for something.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_5">
    <text>What kind of hut is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_6">
    <text>Just an ordinary hut, like a transformer or something. Only there are no electrical wires running to it, which is strange. God knows why it was placed there. Maybe for ventilation? It's impossible to find out, the door is welded shut.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_7">
    <text>So, what's in it for us?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_8">
    <text>Now here's where it gets interesting. Do you know Clockmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_9">
    <text>Who is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are. So, did you find out about the dungeon from Clockmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, and not only did I find out, but I also got the key to the room that has the entrance to the dungeon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
    <text>Excellent, I didn't expect it to be so easy. What did he ask for in return?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
    <text>Nothing. He just gave me the key out of the kindness of his heart. So, Borland, do you want to explore the dungeon?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
    <text>You're asking. Of course!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
    <text>Savan, you're alive?! You're something else! I've never seen a performance like that, not even in the circus. How did you manage to fall?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh... alive, alive... What can I do? I twisted my leg.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, you're a lousy climber. How can you be so clumsy... Wait! I heard something.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
    <text>Um, what?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
    <text>Shh! Follow me. Don't make any noise. Get your weapon ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's go ahead, I'm behind you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_0">
    <text>What? This is the first time I've heard of such a thing as an inverted artifact. Do you think it's true, Savan?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you asking me? Who's the experienced stalker here, huh? I don't know about the artifact. Maybe it exists, maybe it doesn't. But I have heard the story about the Marked One before. In a different place, at a different time, with less detail. I thought it was just a pretty fairy tale. Looks like I was wrong... Something serious is going on here. And I don't like Skidan, he's clearly hiding something from us. He wants to use us blindly. Is that what we want?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, come on, Savan. Aren't you interested? This is a once-in-a-lifetime chance to touch the main mystery of the Zone. Agree! Do you know how much this artifact is worth? A number with five zeros. In dollars.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_3">
    <text>You're right. We came to the Zone for money. If this artifact is really as valuable as Skidan says, then I can go back to the Big Land with a lot of cash.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, that works too. Money is as good a motive as any. So I understand you. My motive is different - to get to the heart of the Zone's secrets.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, let's go further into the laboratory. According to the plans, there's a sealed door with a code lock ahead. We need a key-card and a code. Skidan probably has it, but I don't want to ask him. He won't just give it to us, he'll demand something in return, like a favor or money. Wait here, I'll ask the Watchmaker for the key-card. He must have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh wow! I see you're dressed up. Skidan didn't skimp. Top-notch gear. He also gave me some nice equipment and a good gun.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Can you imagine, someone broke into the Clockmaker's house and stole his access keycard to the laboratory. So, we won't be alone down there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_2">
    <text>Who cares? We'll kill everyone if it comes to that. Everyone should be afraid of us now, we're like two terminators. Follow me!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_0">
    <text>Here we are, at the Cordon. I told you you wouldn't get lost with me. I know every trail here blindfolded. It's not my first time. Now, the most important thing: don't joke around. The military doesn't understand jokes. They'll shoot first and won't even ask for your name. Let's approach calmly, show our documents and leave. You haven't forgotten the cover story, have you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_1">
    <text>I can repeat it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_10">
    <text>Hold on a minute. Let me check your documents. Damn, the ink on your pass hasn't even dried yet. If it smears during the inspection, we're done for. Alright, try to be careful, don't touch the stamp with your fingers. Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_11">
    <text>Ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_2">
    <text>No, that's unnecessary. And remember: if something goes wrong, these fake passes will lead us straight to the cemetery instead of the Zone. Or to prison. I don't know which is worse.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_3">
    <text>Do you think they'll notice?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_4">
    <text>They shouldn't, but anything can happen. The fact that the military didn't open fire right away is a good sign. But if push comes to shove, they might shoot. And then say that it was justified. It's not uncommon here, even stalkers with real passes have been killed. Like "good morning". The Zone will cover it up.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_5">
    <text>Is there any hope? I'm scared.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_6">
    <text>There's always hope. But, as they say, the odds aren't in our favor.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_7">
    <text>Are there any other options? I don't like the idea of going to prison, let alone the cemetery.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_8">
        <text>Well, there is another option. If the soldiers don't turn out to be completely frozen, they will demand money. Which we don't have. So keep your face simple and don't wander with your eyes. Look ahead, but don't stare. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_9">
        <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_0">
        <text>What are you looking at, ugly? Thought you were the smartest? I've seen a dozen like you in the past month.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_1">
        <text>Don't shoot. Please, don't shoot! Let me speak!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_2">
        <text>What can you say, you monster? Why did you try to sneak into the Ecological Disaster Zone through a guarded perimeter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_3">
        <text>I wanted to earn some money. Let's make a deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_4">
        <text>You want to make a deal, huh? Then give me the money - and we'll make a deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_5">
        <text>How much do you need?</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_6">
    <text>How much are you willing to pay for your life and your friend's life? Let's say, 15.000 rubles each, that's still a good deal. He will stay with me for now. But if you ever think of betraying me, I will cut off his head and send a message to the free stalkers about who sold him. Then the Zone will seem like a dead end for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_7">
    <text>I will try to earn the required amount. I can do it! How much time do I have?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_8">
    <text>Maybe you can. If you don't mess around, you can earn it in a couple of days, I think. Just don't bring any junk here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_9">
    <text>I will bring the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_0">
    <text>I brought the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_1">
    <text>Oh, our sponsor has arrived. We have been waiting for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_10">
    <text>Well, too bad. That means your partner will stay with us. We will make him pay every last penny. And if not, I will personally get rid of him. I will get an exceptional vacation for that. Or a medal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_11">
    <text>Wait, please! Don't touch Borland! Maybe there are other options?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_12">
    <text>Hmm. There are a couple of options! Either you give your equipment to the regular army, or you do a couple of missions "and we're even," as Skidan says. What do you choose?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_13">
    <text>All right, take the equipment. I hope we never see each other again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_30">
    <text>I'll do your tasks, no problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_31">
    <text>So, rookie, we lost one of our lieutenants. And some valuable documents that were on his PDA. The investigation showed that he was last seen in the north-west tower area, and at that time a Chimera attacked the outpost. We've been tracking this fast beast for several days near the swamp, but we can't catch it. Maybe it has a den nearby, and it's possible that it took the lieutenant with it. Your job is to retrieve the documents and kill the Chimera.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_32">
    <text>Sending me to certain death?</text>
</string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_33">
    <text>You're a stalker! You came to the Zone to die anyway! So let's get to it without talking. Or have you forgotten who you're dealing with?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_34">
    <text>I remember, I remember... I'm going.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_2">
    <text>As agreed, here are 30 pieces.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_22">
    <text>I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_3">
    <text>Bringing the money is good. But while you were away, the price went up. Your friend wanted to escape. He broke the sergeant's nose and tried to take away his gun. But he didn't succeed in anything. So now it's not 30, but all 40 pieces from you. As compensation for the losses.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_40">
    <text>Bringing the money is good. But while you were away, the price went up. So now it's not 30, but all 50 pieces from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_4">
    <text>Oh, you... Alright, here's another 10,000, to take them. Are you satisfied?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_41">
    <text>Oh, you... Alright, here's another 20,000, to take them. Are you satisfied?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_5">
    <text>Of course! It's nice to deal with a conscious stalker, unlike some. Well, if you're passing by - come in.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_6">
    <text>No-no-no. Once was enough. I wish I never saw you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_7">
    <text>Well, suit yourself. You're free to go! By the way, don't forget your gear - it's in a box on the first floor. And if you decide to come back, you won't forget where to find us! Ha-ha-ha! I'll warn my guys, they won't touch you, so come in if you need any work, we really need our own stalkers in the Zone.</text>
</string>
   <string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_8">
        <text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_9">
        <text>But that's all I have! I don't have anything else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_0">
        <text>Stop! Drop your weapon! Hands up!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_1">
        <text>I'm here to see the Colonel. I have an appointment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_2">
        <text>Stay still and don't move. Take off your backpack and gun - you'll get them back on your way out. The Colonel is waiting for you in his office. And mind you, no funny business!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_3">
        <text>Don't put your things too far away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_4">
        <text>Who do you think you are telling me what to do? Our commander has been found! I'll teach you a lesson...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_5">
        <text>That's enough, calm down!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_0">
        <text>Why are you so scared? What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_1">
        <text>Guys, help me out! I urgently need money! Can you lend me 30,000? I'll pay it back, I swear! It's urgent, right now. A matter of life and death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_10">
        <text>Ha! Of course. You're running around like you're on fire. Alright, enough talking. So, shall we start earning?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_11">
        <text>Let's start! What do we need to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_12">
        <text>We have a hothead here - they call him Dubolom. He's a promising guy, but as impulsive as diarrhea. He wants to do everything faster than anyone else. When it comes to killing mutants, he's in the front lines. When it comes to searching for artifacts, he's indispensable. He hasn't been here for a week and he's already gone to the Dump. He thinks he's experienced, but he's still very green.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_13">
        <text>Well, I just arrived from Big Land myself. Isn't it too early for me to go to the Dump? Especially since I don't even know where it is.</text>
    </string>
   <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_14">
        <text>Don't panic ahead of time. Nobody is sending you to the Dump. This stalker guy is already here, at the Cordon. A couple of hours ago, he sent me a message that he's returning to the camp. He wrote that he found something interesting at the Dump and wants to sell it to Skidan, a local trader. And I still haven't heard from him, even though it's only a twenty-minute walk.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_15">
        <text>What do you need from me? Find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_16">
        <text>Yes. Preferably alive and unharmed. But if something happened to him, at least bring back his backpack or any other belongings.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_17">
        <text>Where should I look?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_18">
        <text>In his last message, he wrote that he wants to cut through the "electric train," our local attraction. Start your search from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_19">
        <text>I'm not familiar with the area yet. Where is it, approximately?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_2">
        <text>Hold on, calm down! Tell me what happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_20">
        <text>First, you need to overcome the railway embankment. Since you're new here, it's better for you to go through the tunnel to the west of the elevator. Just be careful, there are some tough guys there - they collect a fee from everyone who passes through.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_21">
        <text>Tough guys? Bandits, you mean? How much do they charge?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_22">
        <text>It depends on who's passing through. They have nothing to take from you right now, so let's try to negotiate with them. The guys at the tunnel like to take newcomers by the collar, so here's a bottle, or two bottles of vodka, just to be safe. If you give it to them, I think they'll let you pass without any problems. You can return through the "electric train" - just climb onto a wagon and jump over the barbed wire on the other side.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_23">
        <text>Are there any other options? I don't really want to meet with bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_24">
        <text>Of course there are other options! You can walk under the bridge. But even experienced stalkers are afraid to go there, let alone someone like you. It's so hot down there that one wrong step could be your last. And if you don't get burned, you'll turn into a golden crust in no time. So it's better to go through the tunnel - you'll be safer.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_25">
    <text>And the bandits won't touch me for sure?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_26">
    <text>No, they won't touch you. Are they complete idiots to kill the hen that lays golden eggs? We stalkers are their only way of making money. They don't look for artifacts themselves, but they take their cut from us. Those are the rules here, it's easier for stalkers to pay for passage than to get into conflicts. And don't call them bandits, they'll get offended.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_27">
    <text>Yes, it's an unpleasant situation. Anyway, I'm going.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_28">
    <text>Wait! Where are you going without any gear, fool? This is not an amusement park - people even carry weapons to the toilet. Here, take this beginner's kit for free. It'll be enough for a while, and then you can get your own stuff. Do you know how to handle a weapon?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_29">
    <text>I had some experience in the army. Thanks for the gun! I'm going to look for your lost friend now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_3">
    <text>I'm in trouble! I mean, we are. Me and my partner got caught at the checkpoint - our papers are fake, the ink blurred while the soldiers were checking. Now they're demanding money, or they'll kill my partner. And then probably me too...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_4">
    <text>How much are they asking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_5">
    <text>Like I said, 30,000. 15,000 per person. So, are you going to lend us the money?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_6">
    <text>We're not going to lend you anything, this is not a bank. But we'll give you a chance to earn the money yourself. When did they say you should bring the money?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_7">
    <text>You have to do it within 48 hours, or... I don't even want to think about what will happen.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_8">
    <text>Don't worry, everything will be fine! But you shouldn't delay, you never know what they'll do to your friend. I see you're new to the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_9">
    <text>Yeah, is it that obvious?</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_0">
    <text>What did you find?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_1">
    <text>I found the backpack. I didn't find the stalker. Honestly, I didn't have much time to search - there are wild boars there. So, I guess Dubolom was killed by the boars. Sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_2">
    <text>He's alive, Dubolom is alive! He rode up about ten minutes ago. His eyes are worth five rubles - he can't say anything coherent. We sent him to the basement to heal with vodka. And you're a hero! On such an occasion, take a bonus from me. Also, while you were away, I talked to a local trader. He's offering some work. The pay is not great, but it's stable. So, go see him if you haven't already. His name is Skidan, and he lives in a bunker behind the village. If you have any more questions, come see me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_3">
    <text>What should I do with the things?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_4">
    <text>Just give them to Dubolom. Although, if we were being fair, we should teach him a lesson and not give him his things back. But never mind, he has already punished himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_5">
    <text>Thanks for your help, Pooch. See you!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_6">
    <text>There's nobody there. I found a torn backpack near the fire. But it's empty. Apparently, the boars took all the things. I didn't see the stalker either. Most likely, the boars got to him too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_7">
    <text>That's too bad. But don't worry about Dubolom - he's back. He's scared and muttering something. But never mind, it's his own fault. He won't be showing off for no reason again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_8">
    <text>Right. So, are you taking the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_9">
    <text>Oh yeah. Here, take this for your efforts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_x">
    <text>Hello, Pooch. I went to the "electric train".</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, hero! I brought your things. You left them in the backpack near the "Electric Train".</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, another one. I'd take a look at you if you were taking care of business and a boar came out of the bushes at full speed. I wouldn't have time for my backpack then. I don't even remember how I got on that train. The animals went crazy. Can you imagine? When I was walking from the Garbage, some creature jumped out of every bush at me. I could barely run. Wolf told me about you. Thanks for going on the search, I respect that. And leave my stuff, I don't need that junk anymore. I'll buy myself some new gear - you won't believe it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_2">
    <text>Glad to see you're okay. Thanks for the gear.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_3">
    <text>No problem. Hold on, let's exchange numbers. Here are the coordinates of my stash - there's an automatic rifle and spare ammo hidden there. Take it, for honesty!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_4">
    <text>Wow. Well, thanks. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey man, did the explosion get you? Sorry, my guys went too far.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, my head... What a day. Thanks for not killing me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_10">
    <text>Are you kidding me? You're a funny guy. The Shaman called us for help. We were just thinking of moving to your location at the Cordon. We also took care of the bandits and freed you. Aren't you happy?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_11">
    <text>Happy? Of course! Thanks for saving me, I won't forget it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>Kidding? That means you're alive. What's your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>They call me Savan. And you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
    <text>Smoke.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_5">
    <text>And who are you guys anyway? I've never seen you around here before.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, not many people have heard of our group, even during its heyday. And now, no one knows us at all. Some call us the "Swampers," but we're really all that's left of the "Clear Sky" group. A scientific research group. It was... and then it was gone. But now it's coming back. And we're going to finish what we started.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_7">
        <text>How did it "sink"? Where did it sink? What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_8">
        <text>Well, I don't even know what happened back then. We still can't figure it out. Don't bother yourself with it, you'll just break your head. People smarter than you thought about it, but didn't come up with anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_9">
        <text>So, what brings you here? Just passing by? From the village of Shishigino to Monte Carlo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_">
        <text>?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_1">
        <text>I heard you trade information, is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_10">
        <text>Alright, forget it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_11">
        <text>What can you tell me about the Shaman?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_12">
        <text>500 rubles and I'll tell you everything I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_13">
        <text>Alright, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_14">
        <text>The Shaman is a decent guy, used to be a special forces or something like that. Of course, he's no match for the Wolf, but he's been roaming the zone for many years and can easily outperform many stalkers with his 100 points ahead. He's a true leader and stalkers rely on him like on a rock - he won't abandon them in trouble and will share his last piece of bread. He's an honest, straightforward guy with a reasonable head on his shoulders - a real genius of tactics and strategy. The operations he carries out are amazing! In short, he's a trustworthy guy and a real stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_15">
        <text>Do you know anything interesting about Mark?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_16">
        <text>For your money, anything you want. Give me 500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_19">
        <text>Do you know anything about Borland? I'd like to find out more about him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_2">
        <text>That's an overstatement, I just sell a little bit. What do you want to know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_20">
        <text>For that kind of information, my rate is always 500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_21">
        <text>Will you give me change from a thousand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_22">
    <text>Borland was a famous stalker. Didn't know that? He-he. He was a former motorcycle racer and street racer. He played guitar like a god. He was memorable for many things in the Zone. He killed the leader of marauders nicknamed Lavash. There was a lawless man here that old-timers remember. After that, the entire gang of marauders fell apart. It's hard for jackals to live together. Borland fought against the Monolith faction, not alone, of course. The "Horizon of Events" operation. Haven't heard of it? Many legends are still told around the campfire about it. Anyway, he spent 7 years in the Zone and then left everything behind. Probably got tired. \nAnd now, apparently, he's back. Why, don't ask me, I don't know. Former stalkers rarely return here, very rarely. Because the reason for returning to the Zone must be very serious, you know. They also say that Borland had a rich stash on the swamp near Agroprom, and apparently, he left it untouched when he left the Zone forever. So, the question is, why? If you don't need it, give it away for free or sell it. It's a matter of business, of course. Although, if he planned to come back, then it makes sense.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_23">
    <text>I don't know who else to ask. Can you tell me about the Zone? You've been here for a long time, you must have understood something about this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_24">
    <text>Oh, Savan, that's what you need to ask about. Give me 500 rubles and listen.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_25">
    <text>All ears.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_26">
    <text>So, with the Zone, it's like this: if you return with loot - it's a miracle, if you return alive - it's good luck, if a stray bullet misses you - it's a stroke of luck, and everything else is fate. You know what they say - the further into the Zone, the closer to heaven. Haven't heard that? Well, everything is ahead of you. You're a stalker, and stalkers are allowed into paradise without standing in line. The Zone is alive, it lives its own life, and we're newcomers here - we're just pulling chestnuts out of the fire. Artifacts, it doesn't matter... And it all depends on whether we're lucky or not. For the planet Earth, the appearance of the Zone passed without a trace, in general. Of course, it's not excluded that by randomly pulling chestnuts out of this fire, we will eventually pull out something that will make life not only here, but also on the whole planet simply impossible. That would be bad luck. However, it's always been a threat to humanity. Although... I've long since stopped speculating about humanity as a whole...</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_27">
    <text>Can you tell me something about the Strelok group? About Pripyat, for example?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_28">
    <text>Give me 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_29">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_3">
    <text>Tell me about the Wolf: who is he, where is he from?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_30">
    <text>The Ghost was a born spy - he could sneak into anywhere unnoticed. No wonder he was given such a nickname. It's just a pity he died. He went into the laboratory under Lake Yantar and never came back out. Ah, what a shame - he was a skilled stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_4">
    <text>Information, Stalker, also costs money. Give me 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_5">
    <text>Oh, well of course. Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_6">
    <text>Wow, isn't that a lot for a simple conversation? I don't have that kind of money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_7">
    <text>I started writing my memoirs in my spare time, and there's a whole chapter about the Wolf. Let me read it to you: "Sergei Yekimov (the Wolf) and his family were always unlucky. His wife left him when he was fired from his job. He drank heavily at first. But one day, when his younger brother Peter Yekimov got mixed up with a bad crowd and was severely beaten, breaking his nose and arm - the Wolf snapped. He took his father's old shotgun, found his brother's attacker, and shot him. After some thought, the brothers left for the Zone. At first, Sergei didn't have a nickname, and he was constantly called "Grey" until one of the experienced stalkers made a joke and recited a rhyme: "Grey Wolf, Grey Wolf, at the bread bin - click." And so Sergei became the Wolf. As time went on, his experience grew, and the respect of the stalkers for the Wolf grew as well. He became a mentor to newbies in the village. He walked all over the Zone and was considered almost a legend of the Zone." Well, what do you think? Can I put letters into words?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_8">
    <text>Do you know anything else? You're trading valuable information, huh?</text>
</string>
   <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_9">
        <text>Oh, I see. Well, thank you for the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey there, Stalker. Ready to go on a safari with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_1">
        <text>Sure!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_2">
        <text>Then don't lag behind and cover the rest of the guys. Ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_3">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_0">
        <text>Can I join the clan of the free Stalkers now? Will you take me in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_1">
        <text>Of course! I liked you from the start... but, you know how it is: trust but verify! Well, after what you've done, I'm ready to accept you into our clan without question. Ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_2">
        <text>Always ready! What could be better than the life of a free Stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_3">
        <text>Well, for example, Smoky beer and hot sand on the beach by the ocean. Ah, never mind... I hope I don't need to tell you about the Stalker's code?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_4">
        <text>It's better if you tell me, so there won't be any questions later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_5">
        <text>It's simple. To be a Stalker means to be human. To help a comrade in a difficult moment, not to be a sneak, not to commit treachery. Share a medkit or a piece of bread, cover each other's backs in battle, share a night by the campfire. And our main enemy right now is the bandit scum, who only parasitize on our Stalker brethren. We are neutral towards other clans in the Zone. \nWe don't have an army structure, but a community of free people. You are free to decide what to do at any given moment. And no one gives you orders, not even me. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_6">
        <text>No questions, everything is clear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_7">
    <text>Then I won't bother you anymore. Congratulations to everyone present on the arrival of our new comrade in our friendly community! No claws, no anomalies for you, stalker Savan!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_8">
    <text>Okay then. I'll go about my stalker business...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_9">
    <text>I'll think about it. I'm not sure if I need this.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_0">
    <text>How can I join your clan?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_1">
    <text>Easy! If I see that you are a good person and can be trusted, I will call you one of us. You know, they say a friend is known in trouble. Well, we're full of troubles right now. Help us out and consider it a test passed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you have a minute?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>What do you want? Just make it quick, time is money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>I've heard rumors that your freedom fighter brothers took someone down recently. They were taken here, in Korodon. I want to know where exactly.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>Did Ramses mess up? Are you insane, do you understand where you are and who you're talking to? Are you immortal or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
    <text>Sorry, my mistake. I'll leave now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm here. Did you call for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, it's you. I have an offer for you, kid. Will you join our brigade? We're desperately short on fighters now. You're new to the Zone, so it's either us or the free ones. Basically, it's chaos out there: everyone kills whoever they want. But we live by certain rules, and we teach others, for which we take our fair share. Everything's in order on the Dump, now it's time for the Cordons. We've already taken over half of it. To completely control this territory, we just need to drive out the stalker base at the ATP and show who the real boss is. And the newbie village - there are only wimps there. Look at them sternly, and they'll lay down for us themselves. So it's profitable to join us. I'm not pressuring you, think it over. So, what do you say?</text>
</string>
   <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_10">
        <text>I've sent you his coordinates on your PDA, and you have the equipment, so there should be no problems.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_11">
        <text>Okay, I'll do it right away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_12">
        <text>I wouldn't mind working with you, but don't call me to join your team, I prefer to work alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_13">
        <text>That's too bad, but I won't force you. However, I always have some work for you if you need it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_14">
        <text>Go ahead, I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_15">
        <text>We need to take out a stalker who's carrying a valuable item through the Dark Valley. If you do it, you can keep the item, and I'll even pay you extra. Are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_16">
        <text>Sure, no problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_17">
        <text>I've sent you his coordinates on your PDA, and you have the weapon, so there should be no problems. I'll be waiting for good news.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_18">
        <text>I'll be done quickly, just wait for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_2">
        <text>No, sorry, I prefer to work alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_3">
        <text>You're making a mistake, kid. But it's your decision. Leave now, while I'm still feeling generous.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_4">
        <text>Okay, I'm leaving now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_5">
        <text>Yes, I've always dreamed of this kind of adventure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_6">
        <text>Great, then you'll need to pass a test, a real one with blood. I happen to have a job like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_7">
        <text>I'm all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_8">
    <text>You'll have to take down the Stalker, he's carrying contraband from the Dark Valley. Take him out and you can keep the contraband for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_9">
    <text>No problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_0">
    <text>I took out that Stalker and kept the contraband for myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_1">
    <text>Job well done! Here's a small monetary reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_2">
    <text>If you need anything else, just let me know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_0">
    <text>I took out that Stalker and kept the contraband for myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_1">
    <text>You did the job well, no questions asked. But it all went too smoothly, which makes me suspicious. So, you go ahead and wander around the Zone while I make some inquiries. If everything checks out, I'll contact you on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>I need medical help.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Come on, let me take a look...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>[Continued...]</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>Alright, you're all good now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Let's see... Your liver is naturally enlarged, but that's professional... Otherwise, you're as healthy as a Burer!</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_moskit_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello, dead man! Empty your pockets and hand over your bribe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_moskit_dialog_1">
        <text>I don't understand! What do you want from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_moskit_dialog_2">
        <text>What's there to understand? Hand over the bribe or die!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_moskit_dialog_3">
        <text>Alright, here you go. I only have this artifact worth 1300 rubles, but remember, it won't be easy for you to sell it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_moskit_dialog_4">
        <text>Alright, leave me alone and let me live.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_0">
        <text>Stop right there. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_1">
        <text>I'm from Skidan, with payment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_2">
        <text>Alright, come on in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_3">
        <text>Here's the bag. The seal is intact, just as we agreed. You can count the contents if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_4">
        <text>Great. Let me check the number... all good. I won't count it again - Skidan always keeps his word. So, are you coming with us or staying here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_5">
        <text>You start moving and we'll see. Don't worry, I won't get in your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_0">
        <text>How's it going with Shmyga?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_1">
        <text>You arrived just in time - the mercenaries are already on their way. Did you get some rest?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_10">
        <text>I'll figure things out once I get there. So, can I go now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_11">
        <text>Hold on. If everything goes smoothly, I'll give you a generous 10,000 rubles. It's worth it for a job like this. Alright, go ahead now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_12">
        <text>You're quite generous, Skidan. I'll go do my job now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_2">
        <text>We'll get some rest on the other side!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Nice to hear from you! So here's the situation: there will be some mercenaries waiting for you near the camp of those degenerates, Shmyga's buddies. I'm paying them good money for this job. Here, take this bag of money. Deliver it to the leader of the group. And be careful not to mess things up! The bag has a seal on it, and I've already sent the mercenaries the number. If anything goes wrong, they'll shoot you on the spot. So be cautious with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>But they won't kill me for sure, will they? They'll just take the money and say they did the job.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>No, Savan, mercenaries are serious people. If they take on a job, they'll do it well. Otherwise, no one will ever hire them again. But if you ever come across them in the Zone in the future, it's best to stay away. If you interfere with their contract, they'll shoot you without a second thought. Do you understand what I'm saying?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay. But if it's so complicated with the mercenaries, why didn't you ask some free stalkers? They're closer, and they won't ask for as much money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_7">
    <text>Everything should go perfectly, and no one but professionals can be trusted with that. Stalkers are a friendly bunch, but they can't keep their mouths shut. Okay, enough talk. The hired guns will be waiting for you near the rocks not far from Shmyga's camp. You'll give them the money, and you don't have to fight. The most important thing is to find Shmyga and take my case from him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_8">
    <text>Are you sure there will be a case there? What if Shmyga has already opened it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_9">
    <text>He hasn't opened it. I'm sure. It has a tricky lock that only one master in the Zone can pick. But I've already informed him about the theft, so Shmyga won't try to break it himself. Although he might hide the case somewhere nearby so that it's always within reach. So if you don't find the case with Shmyga, look for it in the camp.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Well, Skidan, celebrate! I dealt with Shmyga.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Where's the case?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>Here, here! Take your suitcase, Scrooge McDuck. Hehe!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Oh! Praise the Black Stalker! Well done, Savan! Take your hard-earned reward. Ah, now we'll live!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Well, I won't interrupt your joy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_0">
    <text>What about the bandits?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_1">
    <text>So, how did everything go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_2">
    <text>They didn't even have time to be surprised.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_3">
    <text>Nothing happened yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_4">
    <text>You're not dragging your feet, alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_5">
    <text>Thanks a lot! Here's your reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_0">
    <text>Shaman sent me. Need any help?</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_1">
        <text>Need help? Yes, we do. You see, we've just set up our base and haven't had the chance to clear the area around it yet. Bandits are everywhere, robbing stalkers who bring me supplies. At this rate, I won't have anything left to trade. Just yesterday, another group of bandits appeared. Brazen, they set up camp right in front of our base! Could you take care of them for us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_2">
        <text>No problem! Everything will be taken care of.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_3">
        <text>You know what, maybe some other time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_0">
        <text>Can I help you with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes, we have a problem. Ask our trader, he'll explain the situation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_2">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_0">
        <text>Phew, I brought your equipment. It's heavy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_1">
        <text>Great, Savan. We'll set it up now. The main thing is that it works.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_2">
        <text>Can I help with anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_3">
        <text>Yes, Savan, but later. For now, you can take care of your own business. Just don't go too far, we'll need your help soon. Stay in touch.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_4">
        <text>Got it. I won't go far from the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_0">
        <text>What's the urgent matter? Stepa told me about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_1">
        <text>Sit down. It's a serious matter. Pathogen told me about our dead contact. I don't know if Logoped knew about it, or if Shpala did it himself, but I'm sick of this. It's time to end these scumbags. Are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_2">
        <text>Of course. What do you need me to do?</text>
    </string>
   <string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_3">
    <text>Actually, we don't need much. We have plenty of weapons, enough ammunition and armor for everyone. But we're really short on people. As you can see, there aren't many of us here at the ATP. I'm not counting the newcomers from the village, they're all inexperienced. To deal with the bandits once and for all, we need allies. The military won't help us, they're too proud. The Duty faction doesn't care about our problems, they're fighting mutants. The Freedom faction doesn't even know what's going on here, and they're neutral with the bandits. So, we're completely alone against these thieving bastards.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_4">
    <text>So, what should we do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_5">
    <text>I have an idea of who could help us. Can you go to Skidan and get something for us?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_6">
    <text>Sure, no problem. What exactly do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_7">
    <text>Skidan knows about it. I'll contact him now, and he'll give you what you need. And of course, don't tell anyone else about this. We need to keep this a secret to maintain the element of surprise. Alright, you can go now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_8">
    <text>Got it. My lips are sealed. I'm on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Skidan, Shaman sent me to get something. I'm not sure what it is, though.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, I know what it is. Here's your box. Are you trying to make friends with the swampers or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>What are you talking about? I have no idea. Wow, this box is heavy. And who are the swampers?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, if you don't know, I won't spoil the surprise. You'll find out when the time comes. Hehe. And be careful not to drop the box, there's valuable equipment in there!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll try not to drop it too often.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_0">
    <text>Thank you so much, Savan. I'll tell everyone in our camp how you helped me. Go see Shaman, he'll reward you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_1">
    <text>Alright, but how about you? Are you okay?</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_2">
        <text>It will heal like a dog, the medkit worked. I feel a bit better. I think I'll go to the medic and get my wounds patched up.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_3">
        <text>Take care of yourself, Leshy. And consider changing your profession.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey there. I thought you weren't coming. Did they send you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes. So, you must be the best hunter around here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_2">
        <text>Correction - the only hunter. They call me Leshy. Listen to me carefully - everything I say, you do unquestioningly: if I say stand, you stand; if I say lie down, you lie down; if I say kiss a boar on the ass, you kiss a boar on the ass.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_3">
        <text>Wouldn't you go, old man?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_4">
        <text>Just kidding! Don't get angry. Just try not to make noise and follow me step by step. Let's go hunt a boar. There's one here that's as strong as a bear. He's already killed several people. We need to calm him down. Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_5">
        <text>A boar's a boar. Show me the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_hanter_dialog_0">
        <text>We last saw the boar not far from the train tracks. There's a small hollow there - it's always damp, even on sunny days. Most likely, the boar's there. When we get closer, you go up the hill on the right and I'll go on the left. When you see the boar, drive it towards me - I'll stop it with my shotgun. And be on the lookout - there could be mutants there too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_hanter_dialog_1">
        <text>Good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_0">
        <text>Damn it, damn it, damn it! It hurts like hell, like they've ripped my stomach open. It's killing me. Do you have a medkit? I'll die otherwise.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_1">
        <text>Here's a medkit. You're not cut out to be a hunter, Leshy. You're as useless as a turd. You need to change your profession while you're still alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_2">
        <text>Sorry, I don't have a medkit.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_3">
        <text>"Thank you for the medkit, Savan. I underestimated my strength... It's good you were nearby. Listen, I can make it to the camp on my own, no problem. But I'm not much of a shooter right now. Can you take me to the ATP? There might still be some beasts lurking in the bushes."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_4">
        <text>"No problem. Hang in there, Leshiy, we're almost at the camp."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_0">
        <text>"Well, well, look who we have here, Savan."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_1">
        <text>"Any problems?"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_2">
        <text>"No problems, Savan. I just wanted to talk to you as the leader of the stalkers in the Zone. Officially, you know. I'm the elder around here, although among free stalkers, it's just a formality, as you can imagine."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_3">
        <text>"Speak, Shaman, I'm listening carefully."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_4">
        <text>"Petya thinks highly of you. And now I see for myself that you're not just any guy - you helped Leshiy in a tough moment. Here's a small reward for you."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_5">
        <text>"Thanks for the shotgun - I've been dreaming of one for a long time."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_0">
        <text>"Borland! Glad to see you alive and well! How did you manage to shake off the military?"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_1">
        <text>"There are still good people in the world. Shaman's stalkers bailed me out. I knew right away that you wouldn't be able to gather that much money in two days. And Koljazin isn't stupid. On the second day, when the deadline was approaching, he came to me and started asking who else could pay the ransom for me. You can always count on being put up against the wall, but you can't make that much money that fast. So, I sent a message to Shaman, and he sent a messenger with the ransom. But Koljazin is still angry at you, so don't mess with the military anymore. And be careful, you never know what might happen."</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_10">
        <text>"Alright, I'll go chat with someone. See you later!"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_2">
        <text>Oh, what a disaster. I had almost gathered the necessary amount, but I fell short. And Kolyazin kept sending me threats on my pager. And then he wrote that they fed you to the mutants, and now it's my turn. Well, I got scared and backed off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah, it's an unpleasant situation. The Colonel will now make it his business to get to you - he's stubborn. Watch your back more often now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_4">
        <text>That's true, but let's not dwell on the sad stuff. How are you doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_5">
        <text>I'm doing fine, even though I got shot a couple of times by the soldiers. It's nothing serious, I've been through worse. Why did I call you? Will you be my partner? I've been in the Zone for many years, you won't get lost with me. Experience, as they say, is something you can't buy! My previous partner decided to quit the Zone and go somewhere else, maybe to the States or somewhere. He got tired, you know. And he made enough money here, enough for the rest of his life and even for his grandkids. I even wanted to go to America with him, but at the last moment I changed my mind - I can't live without adrenaline! So I decided to come back to the Zone and find a new partner somewhere here. And then I saw you crawling through the hole in the fence, and there was a minefield. I thought, well, that's it - the cat's done for. And me too, because they'll send me to the outpost for the explosion. That's why I decided to rescue you. It was just a coincidence. And now I see that you're not a total idiot, you pick things up quickly, and you're good at adapting to situations. And most importantly - you don't whine. I'll teach you a few tricks of the trade, and you'll become an excellent stalker. So, are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_6">
        <text>I'm not against it. You seem like a reliable guy. Do you have a plan for what's next? I've had my fill of the Cordon and realized that there's not much money to be made here. Should we head north together? Or maybe towards the center of the Zone? I've heard different things about the center, don't know if they're true. But apparently, everything there is made of pure gold. Or something like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_7">
        <text>Hold on a minute, what kind of Zone center can we reach with our ragtag group? First, we need to get some gear and better weapons. There's no gold in the center of the Zone, but we can strike it rich there. And make flippers there too. Even faster than striking it rich. That's why we need good... </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_8">
        <text>So, what's your plan?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_9">
        <text>My plan is a clean thermonuclear bomb! Just kidding. I do have a plan. I'm going to chat with Skidan. He asked me for some service, to go somewhere or something like that. I can't refuse - he'll get offended. But I'll try to bargain with him for some cheap gear in return. So, I might be gone for a day or two. Don't just sit around doing nothing. Go see Pathogen and Shaman, they started something but it didn't work out. Maybe they need some help. Who knows, you might even earn a bit. Every penny counts for us now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_frend_0">
        <text>Hello buddy! How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_0">
        <text>Where have you been?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_1">
        <text>You can't even imagine what happened to me!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_10">
        <text>Let me try. So... Mm-hmm... Wow... Is that all? That's interesting... What kind of artifact did they snatch from the Monolith? And I've never heard about a lab near the Cordon. There are some service tunnels here, but no one knows where they lead. And the strangest thing is that the Monolith agent was wearing a Freedom mask. Nobody will believe it if you tell them!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_11">
        <text>Do you think what's written in the PDA is true? I mean, about the artifact and the lab?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_12">
        <text>If there was an artifact, someone has probably already found it and sold it to Skidan or someone else. But I wouldn't mind checking out the information about the lab. Can you imagine if no stalker has been there yet? You can gather so much stuff there! And we won't need any artifact Klondike.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_13">
        <text>So, what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_14">
        <text>I'll try to find out about the catacombs from Skidan. He's been sitting in his basement for so long, he's practically one of the first stalkers. He must know something. And your mission, bro, is the most responsible - go see Logoped. You haven't had a falling out with him, have you? Do you talk normally? Try to get something out of him about the Freedom captive. The bros still don't know that they had a Monolith guy in captivity. Try to find out where they caught him, maybe the entrance to the catacombs is nearby. Just be careful, don't mess with the bros...</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_15">
        <text>I'll do my best.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_2">
        <text>Were the mutants causing trouble? Or did the bandits rob you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_3">
        <text>No way! Someone tried to smash my skull on the elevator! Somebody crept up behind me and hit me straight on the head. It's still ringing. I was unconscious, but they didn't take anything. Everything is still with me, can you believe it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_4">
        <text>Weird. What were you doing on the elevator?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_5">
        <text>I was looking for Stepka there, he was supposed to unlock the Stalker PDA for me. And I found him. But it was too late - Stepka was killed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_6">
        <text>Wow! Who killed Stepka? And what was in the PDA? Tell me everything in order.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_7">
        <text>I freed a Stalker from the bandits captivity, and instead of saying "thanks", he just shot himself in the head. I took his PDA and searched for Stepka to unlock it and see what's inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_8">
        <text>And?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_9">
        <text>Here's the PDA. I didn't understand a damn thing. Some kind of encryption, I didn't understand half of the words. Maybe you'll be able to figure it out?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_0">
        <text>I heard you're offering work?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_1">
        <text>I heard they milk cows in Limansk! Ha-ha! Well, I have some problems. Can you help me figure them out? I'll pay you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_10">
        <text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_2">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
</string>
   <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_3">
    <text>Shaman and I decided that we can't afford to lose people in clashes with bandits anymore. Even the stalkers are tired of fighting, and not everyone can pass through the "Bakery". So we decided to make a deal with the gang - they let our people pass through the tunnel freely, and we give them a percentage of our earnings once a week. The negotiator seemed happy with the terms. We sent our contact person with the agreement, but he never made it to Logoped. I have no idea where he could have gone - he vanished into thin air. We don't want to jump to conclusions about the gang too soon, especially since it's in everyone's best interest to honor the agreement. But our contact person has disappeared, so what happened to him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_4">
    <text>Why did you send him without any protection?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_5">
    <text>That's the thing - we didn't expect any foul play. I've known Logoped for a long time, we crossed paths a few years ago. He may be a bandit, but he keeps his word. However, he and our Shaman don't get along - they had a falling out. That's why I handle all the negotiations with Logoped. And he's clearly not involved in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_6">
    <text>Could Logoped have enemies among his own people who want to set him up?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_7">
    <text>That was also a possibility - someone really doesn't want us to make a deal with the gang. And I have a hunch about who that might be.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_8">
    <text>And who is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_9">
    <text>They have a real piece of work in their camp named Shpala. He threatened to kill all the free stalkers, but Logoped keeps him on a short leash. This Shpala could have pulled something behind his boss's back. Here's the plan: I'll give you Shpala's radio frequency. Our technician Stepka has golden hands, he's already hacked into all the gang leaders' radios. They don't have their own technician, so they call Stepka whenever something breaks. And Stepka isn't dumb - he's already cracked their frequencies and codes, so we can monitor all their movements at any time. So, keep an eye on Shpala: what he's doing, where he's going, and who he's talking to.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_0">
    <text>I've been keeping an eye on Shpala.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_1">
    <text>Do you have any leads on our contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_2">
    <text>Yes, but the news is bad. Our contact is dead. The bandits killed him, but I don't think it's as simple as it seems.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_3">
    <text>This is what I feared. Did Shpala decide to betray the Speech Therapist? Or did the Speech Therapist know everything? But then why did they kill our guy? There are many questions, but no answers. Here, take this as payment for your work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_4">
    <text>That's not all. Besides your contact and the bandits, there was another stalker there. Judging by the patch on his armor, he was from the "Freedom" clan. But he was completely frozen - I killed the bandits, and this "Freedom" guy picked up a gun from the ground and shot himself. Can you imagine? He put the gun to his head and pulled the trigger without saying a word.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_5">
    <text>What? You're kidding me. He shot himself? Yeah, right. Don't lie to me. We haven't seen anyone from "Freedom" around here for a long time. What are they doing here? And I definitely don't believe he shot himself. Maybe they like to smoke weed or something hallucinogenic, but to commit suicide - you're a storyteller. Anyway, here's 500 rubles for your interesting story, go buy yourself a flag. I'll take care of serious matters - the bandits can't get away with killing our contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_6">
    <text>You're wrong, Patogenych, that's exactly what happened. Anyway, it's your business. Goodbye for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_0">
    <text>I've been watching Shpala.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_1">
    <text>Did you find out anything about our contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_2">
    <text>I'm not 100% sure, but he's probably dead. I didn't get too close, but I saw a dead stalker there. Most likely, that's your contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_3">
    <text>What if it's not him? Although, who am I kidding. That dead guy is probably our contact. Poor guy. But the bandits can't get away with this, whether or not the Speech Therapist knew about it. Those bastards need to be punished. Here's your payment - thanks for keeping an eye on things.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_4">
        <text>Hang on, Pathogenic, there's more. The sleeper and the bandits are holding some stalker captive near that house. I can't be sure, but the patch on his armour says "Freedom". I saw it through the binoculars.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_5">
        <text>Now, that's interesting. Freedom, huh. Why would a freedom fighter stray so far from his base? They've never been seen here before... We're at peace with Freedom. We're supposed to be allies. You want to settle up? Me too. I'll pay you for any information. Or a solution.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_6">
        <text>I'm curious myself. I don't want to leave a man prisoner in the hands of these scumbags.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_7">
        <text>I don't tell you what to do. If you rescue him from captivity, bring him to us. Just run, before the bandits slap him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_8">
        <text>He's on the run.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_0">
        <text>Pathogenic, I don't know how to say it. This is bullshit. The freedom fighter shot himself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_1">
        <text>What do you mean, shot himself? By himself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_2">
        <text>That's what it means! I cut the bandits off, I walk up to the freedom fighter, and he picks up his gun off the ground and shoots himself in the head. Without saying a word. I didn't even have time to get my bearings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_3">
        <text>Oh, man... "That's the last thing we need in Cordon. And what the hell do the bandits need him for, they're supposed to be neutral? Why did he shoot himself? Was he stoned? What a story. Riddles in the dark. If you learn anything new, stop by.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_4">
        <text>I will.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello to the hammer and screwdriver men! Can you unlock a PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_1">
        <text>Forgot about the soldering iron. Hi. Give me your PDA, I'll see what's up. Why is it locked? Did you steal it or take it off a dead guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_2">
        <text>What's up with you? I didn't kill anybody. He was already dead. I mean, the owner. Can you believe I saved him from bandits and he just shot himself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_3">
        <text>Oh, man. Well, it's none of my business. I can unlock the PDA, but it's gonna take a while. Come back in a couple hours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_4">
        <text>All right, I'll be right back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_5">
        <text>Wait, you should go see the Rainmaker, he's got an emergency, maybe you can help him out, and I can unlock your PDA for free.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_6">
        <text>It's a deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_0">
        <text>Have you seen Steppe? I asked him for a favor and he took off somewhere. That's weird.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_1">
        <text>I have no idea where he might have gone, he doesn't tell me. Wait a minute, though. Sergei came back from a job five minutes ago and said something about Stjepka. I think he almost knocked Sergei down at the bus stop, running somewhere towards the grain elevator. You look there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_2">
        <text>Thanks, I'll run and have a look.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_0">
        <text>Have you seen a stalker named Shmyga around here lately? Or anyone like him? Or anyone suspicious at all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_1">
        <text>Haven't seen Shmyga in two or three days. He's kind of gone missing. Skidan's been searching for him, I don't know why. Sounds to me like he's a scumbag and nothing to be sad about if he dies. And suspicious... Let me see. I didn't see it myself, but the lads at the campfire were talking about some strange types at the Grain Elevator. Maybe that's where Shmyga's hiding.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_2">
        <text>Could be. I'll go ask somebody else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_3">
        <text>Ask Pussy, he's always sticking his nose in. Maybe he'll tell you something. He's in the village now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_4">
        <text>I'll ask him. Thanks, Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_0">
        <text>Listen, have you seen any suspicious characters at Cordon the other day?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_1">
        <text>Every other face around here is suspicious. Yours, for instance, is very suspicious. Be more specific - who are you looking for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm looking for Shmyga. You know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_3">
        <text>Well, I know him. He's a bad man. It was a couple of days ago. We were sitting around the fire, and this Shmyga was bragging about how he'd soon get rich and get out of the Zone. Then he disappeared. We thought he'd gone. But yesterday Romka saw him near an abandoned house across from the farm behind the bridge. Shmyga had a fight with some brothers, and they were arguing very loudly. Romka decided not to interfere and avoided it. Anyway, you go and see the sketch artist at the ATP. That guy knows all the rumours: who, what, where, where and why. He's like a word-of-mouth radio and Argumenty i Fakty newspaper, but in one person. If he doesn't know, nobody does.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_4">
        <text>Thanks for the tip.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_0">
        <text>They say you can share a rumour? Do you know anything about the stalker Shmyga?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_1">
        <text>I know your Shmyga. He's a nasty piece of work. But if you're looking for him, then you came to me for nothing - I don't know where he hangs around, he doesn't report to me. But if he's on Cordon, there's only a handful of good hiding places where he could be: the Grain Elevator, the Farmouse behind the bridge, and the Roadblock to the north. Look around those places and see if you can find Shmyga there. If he's still alive, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_2">
        <text>Well, thanks for that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_3">
        <text>Thank you doesn't butter my bread.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_4">
        <text>Here's one for your red caviar sandwich. Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_5">
        <text>Don't worry, you won't starve.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_0">
        <text>What do you want, you little punk?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_1">
        <text>Guys, I don't want any trouble. I'm just looking for someone here. You wouldn't happen to know Shmyga, would you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_2">
        <text>Who are you? What do you want with him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_3">
        <text>I've got a message for him, just a few words. So, you know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_4">
        <text>Listen, messenger, you better get out of here while you still can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_5">
        <text>I'll go, no problem. Just tell me, is Shmyga here or not?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_6">
        <text>Don't you get it?! I'll blow your head off if you say another word about our bumpkin!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_7">
        <text>So is Shmyga your bumpkin?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_8">
        <text>That's it, you bastard, you're in trouble! Get him, boys!!!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_9">
        <text>Oops!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_0">
        <text>Stalker Savan is here to do his job!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_1">
        <text>Oh, you're so fast! Well done! Here's your candy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_10">
        <text>Don't sweat it, Skidan, I'll do my best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_2">
        <text>Glad you could make it! All right, joke's over. What's up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_3">
        <text>Oh, Savan, I'm not in the mood for jokes myself. Anyway, there's this stalker named Shmyga. It's a silly name, no doubt about it. But who am I to say?. Anyway, this guy owes me a lot of money. A lot. He volunteered to mediate between me and some... You don't need to know. Who they are doesn't matter, but I needed their connections badly. That's beside the point, too. Anyway, I did a couple of tests on this Shmyga. He seemed all right. He passed all my tests, did everything without a hitch. So I trusted the stalker and asked him to pass the payment on to these people. In the end, I got the goods, but the money never reached the customers. I always have a little stash for a rainy day, so I somehow managed to pay the suppliers. But my pockets are now empty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_4">
        <text>I don't know what you're talking about. What happened to Shmyga? Did he die or escape?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_5">
        <text>At first I thought he was dead. But hell no, he's alive and well. Only they don't call him Shmyga anymore. He changed his name. I don't know his new name. But I do know that he's been hanging around Cordon somewhere - the local lads saw a guy like him recently. So I have a very important task for you: find this stalker. But don't kill him, he might not have any money on him. Your job is just to find him. The rest is up to me. Will you do the search?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_6">
        <text>What is the pay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_7">
        <text>I'll give you $10,000. And a discount on my merchandise. Savan, if you really need it, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_8">
        <text>All right, I'll find your friend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_9">
        <text>Remember, do not under any circumstances kill Shmyga or his cronies. If he dies, my money goes to the grave with him. And if he escapes to the north of the Zone, you'll never find him there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
        <text>I did your job. I haven't seen Shmyga himself, but I know where his camp is. He and his buddies are camped out at the northern roadblock. I think they've formed a new gang there. And he's become a bogeyman. His friends are very aggressive. They almost put a bullet in my head. The only thing that saved me was that I'm a fast runner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
        <text>Well done, Sawan! You did the right thing. Don't worry about Shmyga and his gang, they'll be handled by professionals. But I could still use your help. You get some rest, I'll have a word with someone. Come back in an hour, I'll have a special assignment for you. You're gonna have to shoot, so stock up on ammo and first-aid kit, just in case things turn out badly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
        <text>Great, I can't wait to teach these bastards a lesson.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_0">
        <text>I got those ghouls, friends of Shmyga's. Only he wasn't there himself. He must have slipped away. Sorry, Skidan, but they started it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_1">
        <text>"First ones"? What are you, a kid making up excuses like that? Oh, you, Savannah. You ruined the whole thing. Who asked you to be a hero? I told you in Russian not to kill anyone! And you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_2">
        <text>What me? I told you, they shot me first! What was I supposed to do, stand around and catch bullets? You taught the bastards a lesson. Next time it'll be better for your Shmyga.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_3">
        <text>There won't be a next time! Now Shmyga will go to the centre of the Zone, and then you'll have to look for him. That's the end of my money. Here, here's your payment for the freaks, five grand will do you good. The rest will be forfeit. Oh, Savan, Savan... You were so hopeful. Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_4">
        <text>I... that's... I didn't do it on purpose, Skidan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_0">
        <text>I tracked down Sawyer and found out where he's hiding the loot. Here are the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_1">
        <text>All right, Savannah, here's your reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_2">
        <text>What are you gonna do to him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_3">
        <text>Stake him! Just kidding. We have clan rules, and he broke them. So we have to punish him. Take him somewhere in the woods, give him a gun and one bullet. That'll teach him a lesson, if he makes it out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_4">
        <text>Tough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_5">
        <text>Rules are nothing if there's no punishment. Can't let him get away with this, that's why I'm the leader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_6">
        <text>All right, well, good luck with that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_0">
        <text>You got a job for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_1">
        <text>There's a job for someone like you, Sawan. I need someone new, from the outside. You see, there's a rat on the ship. Some of the guys are starting to lose things. Sawyer's the suspect, but he ain't been caught red-handed, and nobody can prove it's him. We should follow him, but don't make any noise. Just look where he's going and then show me where he's going. Just keep a low profile and don't take him to vigilante justice, we'll teach him a lesson.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_2">
        <text>We'll just give him a dark one, that's all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_3">
        <text>We can always do that. Except we can't get the stolen goods back that way. That Sawyer's a stubborn man. I'm texting you the coordinates to his PDA. Look where he's going again. Just keep a low profile.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_4">
        <text>All right, I will.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_0">
        <text>Whew! You scared the shit out of me, man. Why are you sneaking up on people?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_1">
        <text>So this is where you hide your stolen goods.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, man, take it easy! That's my stuff. Who the hell are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_3">
        <text>The Rainmaker sent me to find out where the rat's hiding his supplies. I know everything now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_4">
        <text>Shit! Man, please don't give me to the Rainmaker! He can't prove anything without this stuff. Don't turn me in! I'll give you money. How much are they paying you? Two thousand? Five? I'll give you 10,000 to keep you from giving me up. And you'll tell the Shaman the false coordinates - that's where Vasky Lyutogo's stash is. I'll plant a couple of stolen things there, and everyone will think of him. Say yes!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_5">
        <text>All right, I'll take the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_6">
        <text>Here's the money. Get your PDA, I'll text you the coordinates of Vasya's stash house. That's it, it's done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_7">
        <text>I advise you to run from Cordon. Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_0">
        <text>What are you, Skidan's mailman? You got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_1">
        <text>Sure did. Here's your box. It's heavy, man. All safe and sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_2">
        <text>Well, thanks for the favor. We don't have much time left, we're going on a trip with the men. We've ordered all sorts of stuff, but no one to send for the goods. Here's a bonus from me for the speed of delivery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_3">
        <text>Wow, thanks! If you need anything else, call me Savan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_0">
        <text>What's the job? How much do you pay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_1">
        <text>I thought you'd disappeared. Heh-heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_10">
        <text>I wish you'd just come in here and make a confession. All right, give me your package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_2">
        <text>I don't get the humor. What'd you call me for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_3">
        <text>You need more work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_4">
        <text>Of course I do. Then why do you think I'm here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_5">
        <text>Well, maybe you came by to check on a sick old man. You might have brought some oranges or something. You can't even get a nice word out of your brother, let alone oranges. You always don't like us traders. And you think our life is chocolate? It may be the same colour, but it tastes different. I'm going to go to the mainland. I'm going to the south to rest. Then you'll remember who Skidan was and what he did for you. I've been killing my health here for you lummoxes. My liver's fucked up, my back hurts, my knees hurt. I should go to a sanatorium, to the healing waters. Or a spa. If you think about it, a spa is even better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_6">
        <text>Are you done talking? Can we talk business?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_7">
        <text>Oh, come on. You don't have the spark of God in you. I don't want anything to do with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_8">
        <text>Then why the hell did you call me, you old fart? If you got a job, you do it. If not, I'm out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_9">
        <text>Wait, Savannah, I'm sorry. I'm going somewhere. Don't be offended, the weather must be affecting me. I got a job for you. You don't even have to work hard - I have to deliver a package to a stalker at the ATP. The stalker, nicknamed Chesnok, will be waiting for you at the entrance. I'll pay you 3,000 rubles for the job. After delivery, of course. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
        <text>It's all right. Delivered the package in the best condition. That stalker Chesnok even gave me a bonus for speed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
        <text>Well, since he paid you off, I'm not paying you anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
        <text>What a jerk!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
        <text>Are you insulting me? I'm just kidding! That's my sense of humor! And you say "asshole". Oh, you young people, you don't know anything about life. And here, in the Zone, neither do you. Here's your money - I always keep my word.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
        <text>You're a joker. Petrosian's at his leisure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_5">
        <text>Of course I am! There's nothing without humor here! Heh-heh-heh-heh!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_6">
        <text>What's that, "Anschlag" in the basement. All right, you got any more work to do, call me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_0">
        <text>Skidan, what the hell is going on?! Why didn't you tell me you had a bunch of cops hanging around? They took your package! Oh, my God! I barely made it out alive myself. I almost got shot. Give me compensation for the risk!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_1">
        <text>Get out of here, you bastard! You think you can fuck me over like this?! You think I'm gonna take your word for it like a little kid?! That stalker you split the package with, he works for me!!! You fucking idiot! That was a test.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_2">
        <text>Skidan, I...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_3">
        <text>Get the fuck out of here before I feed you with buckshot! Look who you're trying to throw, you bastard! I don't want to see you again!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_4">
        <text>Yes, I... Don't be angry, Warden.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello, tramp. We have business, let's talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_1">
        <text>Well, hey, if you're not joking. What business?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_10">
        <text>I was, I was, let's get that lock open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_11">
        <text>Now we're talking! Now, just a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_12">
        <text>Well, what is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_13">
        <text>Wow, there's a lot of stuff in here! Wait a minute, we'll divide it up fair and square. Here, see what you're taking: The Kalash or the helmet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_14">
        <text>Give me the helmet, at least I'll cover my head. Otherwise there's all kinds of shooting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_15">
        <text>Give me the kalash, you can't do without a gun here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_16">
        <text>Here. So, let's see what's next. What's your choice: a Soviet submachine gun or a foreign sight?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_17">
        <text>Give me the scope, I'll bolt it somewhere. I was the best marksman in my company.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_18">
        <text>Give me the grenade launcher. I like this kind of thing. One shot and they're all gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_19">
        <text>All right, take it. Oh, there's guns too! What do you want, an Italian rifle or an English rifle?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_2">
        <text>I hear you got a package on your way to the TSA. How much did Skidan promise you for it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_20">
        <text>Give me the rifle, I don't like those guns.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_21">
        <text>Of course a shotgun's a killer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_22">
        <text>Now, there's a couple of other artifacts here. I think I'll take them. I've earned them. And here's a suit for you - the Freedom Winds. Good stuff, I'll tell you that. Freedom's got a knack for lightweight armor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_23">
        <text>It'll do the trick. That's it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_24">
        <text>Yeah. You happy now? It's definitely more than 5 grand worth of gear. You'll have to make a deal with Skidan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_25">
        <text>I will. Bye-bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_3">
        <text>What business is it of yours? Keep your nose out of other people's business. Go where you're going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_4">
        <text>Whoa, whoa, whoa, easy! Don't be impertinent, my heart! I'm trying to help you and you're cursing. If you don't want it, just say so.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_5">
        <text>I didn't ask for your help. I don't know you. Get lost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_6">
        <text>Ew, how rude! Do you even know what's inside the package, huh? I can see you don't. Well, I do - there's about 30 grand worth of merchandise in there! Trunks of trump, rigging and all kinds of stuff. Skidan's only giving you five. Or less? Less? What a cheapskate. So here's my proposition: We split the parcel in half, and you tell the dealer it was stolen by some hoodlums. That happens all the time around here. I can give you a black eye to prove it. What do you say? Say yes! You've got a lot of work to do for this kind of stuff. And here you'll get it all at once.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_7">
        <text>Why don't you fuck off, uncle!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_8">
        <text>Oh! Well, if you don't want to, fine. Don't look at me like you're nervous. My job is to offer, your job is to refuse. Just keep in mind that without special equipment, you can't open the lock on the box. And I happen to have that equipment. If you're thinking about it, I'll be waiting here. You think about it, think about the upside. Skidan won't be poor, he's got a percentage for shrinkage, shrinkage and broken glass in all his prices. You understand, Zone. Well, think about it, I won't rush you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_9">
        <text>Yeah, look for fools!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_0">
        <text>Grandpa, where can I find a dealer around here? Some skidane. They said to look in this bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_1">
        <text>Ha-ha-ha! Grandpa?! Ha-ha-ha! You made it! Ha-ha-ha! Oh, I can't!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_10">
        <text>Come on, man. I got it, I'm not stupid. I'll find you that... what's his name? Afrikat schmartifuck. Anyway, I'll get you your miracle crap. Just don't get angry. I'll be there soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_2">
        <text>What's so funny? Are you Skidan? I got a message from you. Are you offering me a job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_3">
        <text>Wait a minute with your job, ha-ha-ha! Oh, here you are, the kids are calling you a grandpa. Oh... It brings tears to my eyes. What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_4">
        <text>I'm looking for a job, I told you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_5">
        <text>What's your name? You don't look familiar. Are you new here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_6">
        <text>It's my first day here. The name's Savan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_7">
        <text>Tell you what, Savan. That's an awful nickname, I'm sorry, God damn it. Whatever. Before I give you a proper job, I need to make sure you're capable. For starters, it's standard. Bring me an artifact of some kind. Preferably something from the bakery, cause my lower back's been bothering me lately. For such a favor, I'll give you... let's say... one thousand evergreen rubles. Agreed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_8">
        <text>Grandpa, are you kidding me? It's not funny. I need 30 thousand in two days, and you're offering me one thousand. That's not serious. Let's do it another way: you lend me 30,000 rubles, I pay off the soldiers and free my partner, and then I come back to you and work off the debt. So it's a deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_9">
        <text>Kid, is there something you don't understand? You either accept my generous offer and find me some fire artifact, or you get the hell out of here. And I'll make sure you never make another penny in the Zone. It's your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
        <text>It's about the Afrikat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
        <text>You got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_10">
        <text>There's a funny little thing here. Check it out. This?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_11">
        <text>Well done, Sawan. And here's your well-deserved reward, as promised. It's a good start, but you're not cut out for serious business yet. You go around, check out the neighborhood, talk to people. I'll text you if I need you. Well, good luck, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_12">
        <text>Don't get sick, Skidan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
        <text>No, I haven't found it yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
        <text>So why are you here, then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
        <text>I just came by to see what's up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_5">
        <text>Skidan, it's like an oven in there! I tried it on one side and on the other... I mean, I almost burned my trousers. There's no way to get near it. I don't even know what to get you - what does this Afrikat of yours look like? There's a lot of junk in there, I don't know what to take. Anyway, I'm empty-handed. Let's do another job, easy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_6">
        <text>You've upset me to no end. Oh, you, rookie. I'm done with you. I don't have any more work for you, I'm sorry. But if anything comes up for you, I'll be sure to text you. Get out of my sight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_7">
        <text>All right, bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_8">
        <text>Found a piece of crap. Looks like rock crystal. Only it glows in an unusual way. How's that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_9">
        <text>Look, I don't know if it is or not. Here, here's a balloon for you. It's warm. There wasn't anything else weird in there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_0">
        <text>I want to pick up my order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_111">
        <text>Here you go. "Steppe Eagle! Took me a while to get it... A collector was interested in it, so I snatched it from under his nose. Take a look for yourself: handmade, with jewel-like precision. Have you heard the joke about the sniper pistol? Well, it's not a joke. This is it. Yeah, that'll be another 2,800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1111">
        <text>All right, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11111">
        <text>There you go... Thanks for the order!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have that much money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11121">
        <text>Well, I can hold on to the merchandise for a while. I hope you can find the money soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1113">
        <text>I don't want to buy it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11131">
        <text>If you refuse to take your own order, I can't count on your word next time. I will have to include the cost of risk in the price and increase the deposit amount.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_111311">
        <text>Nevertheless, I won't be taking this order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1113111">
        <text>Well, that's up to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1114">
        <text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11141">
        <text>As you wish, of course... I'll hold on to your merchandise for now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_112">
        <text>Here, Steppenwolf! A super precision machine, for a second... That'll be 2,800 more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_121">
        <text>Look, it's an Alpine. I can safely say there's only one such gun in the whole Zone. It's a unique model. It was made in small batches for one special unit. It wasn't easy to get, but I got some of my friends overseas on board... Enlarged magazine, extra-strength steel barrel, extra-strength polymer receiver. The remaining 2,800 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_122">
        <text>Here's the Alpine, a pistol with a larger magazine capacity. The remaining 2,800 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_131">
        <text>Look at this -- this thing's called a Marsh. Belonged to a mercenary called the Dogcatcher. Compact, large-caliber, short-stroke, lightweight breech-loading cannon - you can tell the former owner was a rare bastard, but he knew his way around a gun... They say Dogfather's favorite joke was to shoot a man in all four limbs and then, as he fell, his head... Yeah. All right, that'll be 2,800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_132">
        <text>Here, a Marsh gun. That'll be another 2,800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_211">
        <text>Look: a Fraser submachine gun. Let me tell you right off the bat, it's a brand-new weapon. Not even a production model - a prototype, straight from a gun shop, completely handmade! Those engineers designed a pretty good melee weapon: large caliber, excellent rate of fire and accuracy. That'll be another 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_212">
        <text>Uh-huh, a high velocity Fraser submachine gun. That'll be another 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_221">
        <text>A fine specimen, the Carabiner! It's a fine army shotgun. It can fire automatically, and it doesn't hit the host with the recoil - there's a balanced shockless system inside. You owe me the remaining 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_222">
        <text>Here, an automatic carbine shotgun. That'll be the remaining 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_231">
        <text>I believe this is exactly what you need. "The Carabiner, one of the latest developments! The whole lot was supposed to go to Central Africa, but I got an acquaintance to send me one sample. It's an automatic shotgun with a high-capacity magazine and excellent rate of fire. 8,000 and you can have it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_232">
        <text>Of course. Automatic shotgun "Blowback" with a high-capacity magazine. 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_311">
        <text>Sure. Here: The Storm automatic grenade launcher system. Prototype is a modification of the usual weapons, made strictly for special units operating in the Zone. A miracle of technical thought by the Slavic brothers... 16,000 and take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_312">
        <text>Of course. Here's one: the "Storm" grenade launcher, with a high-capacity magazine, for the missing 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_321">
        <text>There it is, the GP37, the next-generation assault rifle! Accurate, reliable, comfortable, with built-in optics... Belonged to one of the U.N. Observer Team - they were sent here to investigate the situation... and it goes critical. For 16,000, it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_322">
        <text>Here it is, GP37, the next-generation assault rifle. That'll be 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_331">
        <text>Wait a second! Here it is: The FT-200M modular rifle, the brainchild of Belgian gunsmiths. Accurate, versatile, fully reversible - so it doesn't matter if you're right-handed or left-handed... and the optics and grenade launcher, of course. I got it from the U.N. Observers. You owe me another 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_332">
        <text>Here's an FT-200M modular rifle. That'll be another 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_411">
        <text>Here's the Priboy. Designed for military units, specifically for zombie combat, based on a silenced sniper rifle. It has a reduced rate of fire, but increased killing power, so zombies can be hit one at a time without giving away their position. The only thing that did not go into production is after they found out that the zombies can be stopped on the barrier anyway. It'll be yours for the remaining 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_412">
        <text>Here's the Surf, a silent sniper rifle with increased killing power. For the remaining 16,000, you can have it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_421">
        <text>Here, this is SVU2-A, a shortened sniper rifle with increased rate of fire. Bought it from Max, the legendary guardian of the Freedom faction. So Max swore it was the only one of its kind in the whole Zone... even if he was lying, it's definitely exclusive in these parts. That'll be another 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_422">
        <text>Mm-hmm. SVU2-A, a shortened sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire. That'll be another 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_431">
        <text>Sure. Here, look, it's a Lynx. Hand-built by a local expert... now deceased, so there won't be another one like it. It doesn't look any different from the usual model, but in action, you can feel the difference at once: just the perfect ratio of accuracy to killing power! The remaining 16000 and it will be yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_432">
        <text>Yes, the Lynx is a sniper rifle with increased accuracy and power. You owe me the remaining 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_511">
        <text>Check this out. I managed to get what I had planned - a set of CH-3a and a helmet. The helmet itself isn't anything special, but it's a good base for setting up a mobile tactical system with good night vision and infrared scanner. But the CHN-3a is a special talk. Good protection from bullets and anomalies at lightness and mobility is not often found. All together, 32,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_512">
        <text>Yeah. A set of CHN-3a armor and a tactical helmet. All together, 32,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_611">
        <text>Specially for you, a SEVA jumpsuit. Just like you ordered: closed-circuit breathing, plus heat resistance, electrical protection circuit and corrosion-resistant exterior coating materials. As an added bonus, there are integrated artifact containers. Indispensable for a stalker...! That'll be 24,000, as agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_612">
        <text>Here you go. SEVA jumpsuit. As agreed - 24000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_711">
        <text>Here he is, a beauty! Combat exoskeleton, one piece! The best protection against bullets, claws, and shrapnel that can be found in the Zone - well, with the exception of armored vehicles, of course... However, like armored vehicles, it takes the weight of your gear - within reason, of course. For 48,000 you can have it in one piece - I mean, with the battery and servo motors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_712">
        <text>That's a combat exoskeleton, one piece! 48,000 and you can have it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_0">
        <text>I want to place an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1">
        <text>No problem. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11">
        <text>A gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_111">
        <text>Easy. The gun will cost 3,500. Of that, I need 700 as a deposit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1111">
        <text>All right, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11111">
        <text>I'll contact you when the order's ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have any money right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11121">
        <text>Well... If you get the money, I'll let you know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1113">
        <text>You know, I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11131">
        <text>All right. Well, if you do decide to order something, you're welcome to it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_112">
        <text>You know, you're not a very reliable buyer, so the gun will cost 4,200. Of that, I need 1,400 as a deposit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_113">
        <text>I'm afraid the best guns are already sold out. And you can get some of the cheap stuff from Sych.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_12">
        <text>Weapons for close combat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_121">
        <text>Easy. It'll cost you 10,000, and I'll need 2,000 right away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_122">
        <text>The last order you turned down... So this one will cost you 12,000, and you'll need 4,000 right away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_123">
        <text>Mmm... You know, I probably can't help you with that. There's too much demand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_13">
        <text>Assault weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_131">
        <text>Large caliber, high velocity... The usual price is 20,000, 4000 of which is a deposit. How's that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_132">
        <text>You're a hard man to work with. For you, the price would be... Yeah, 24,000. 8,000 of which is the deposit. You in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_133">
        <text>That's the problem right now: The military is on the rampage at Cordon... Someone attacked their roadblock recently, so it's hard to negotiate with them now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_14">
        <text>Sniper weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_141">
        <text>I can get it for 20000, but 4000 of it will have to be paid in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_142">
        <text>Working with you carries a certain amount of risk... I could try to arrange an order for 24,000, but I'd need 8,000 of that up front.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_143">
        <text>Sorry, it's a tight squeeze. The sniping supplier has certain... ahem... health issues.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_15">
        <text>Armor protection.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_151">
        <text>I got something in mind... Costs 40,000, but 8,000 of that's up front.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_152">
        <text>I got something in mind... But you didn't pick up the last order, so this one will cost 48,000. And 16,000 of that will have to be paid up front.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_153">
        <text>I can't get anything better than the last set... And that was a one-of-a-kind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_16">
        <text>A suit with a closed-circuit breathing system.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_161">
        <text>It's a rare order... I don't know. I could try to get one for 30,000, but then I'd ask for 6,000 as a deposit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_162">
        <text>You let me down with your last order, so I don't know... I can try to get one for 36,000, but then I'll ask for 12,000 as a deposit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_163">
        <text>I got the previous one with a lot of trouble. I'm afraid I can't find another one of those now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_17">
        <text>Exoskeleton.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_171">
        <text>That's a serious choice. I suppose I could get a combat version, but that would cost 60,000. It's not cheap, but it's worth it. Mind you, I'm gonna need 12,000 of that right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_172">
        <text>You didn't do too well with your last order, so this one will cost you 72,000. Keep in mind, I need 24,000 of that right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_173">
        <text>Not a chance. Since the factory shut down, exoskeletons are now mostly taken off dead bodies, but that's not my method.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_18">
        <text>Nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_2">
        <text>Sorry, not working right now. I'm having a little trouble shipping orders...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_start_11">
        <text>Greetings. I'm the Draughtsman. I buy weapons in any condition for cheap and sell information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_start_12">
        <text>Greetings. Anything you want to sell?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_start_13">
        <text>Greetings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_start_14">
        <text>Your order will be fulfilled shortly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_start_15">
        <text>Your order has been fulfilled. You can have it now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_0">
        <text>Can you answer a few questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_1">
        <text>Ask me what you want.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_22">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_221">
        <text>I'll tell you what I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_222">
        <text>One thing I've been wondering since day one, is it true what they say about the Zone expanding all the time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223001">
        <text>What do you think? Of course it's true. The Zone used to be much smaller. When it first appeared, its boundary was north of where Bara is now. I can't tell you exactly where, and no one will, but judging by the presence of anomalies, the Zone started at the abandoned army depots.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223002">
        <text>And how fast is it growing? There are quite a lot of anomalies here now, was there less before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223003">
        <text>Believe it or not, a year ago, there were many times fewer anomalies here at Cordon. And there were no anomalous fields at all. And five years ago there weren't any anomalies in this area at all. The military maintained a protective perimeter around the current northern roadblock on the Junkyard. But then the Zone started getting bigger. I don't know why, ask some scientists, maybe they know something about it. The Zone grew in leaps and bounds, and for no reason at all. This enlargement was usually accompanied by an explosion. They used to be extremely rare, once every few months. But every year the expansion slowed down. The outbursts became weaker, but more frequent. Now it thunders almost every 24 hours, but no anomalies have been seen beyond the Cordon. But the military have begun to build a new barrier, now ten kilometres from the current one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223004">
        <text>And what will happen to the current barrier? I take it this isn't the first perimeter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223005">
        <text>That's right, Sawan, it's not the first barrier. Now, let me see... That roadblock with the wall in the south of Cordon is the third. They started building it when the Zone first expanded. A lot of people died on the perimeter back then. Some got hit, but most got mauled by mutants. Nobody had ever seen such large numbers of those things, there were dozens or even hundreds of them! All the nearby units were alerted. Oh, what a massacre that was! Mortars, helicopters, tanks, APCs - everything was fired at once. There were even requests for bombardment sent over the radio, but by then everything had calmed down. After that incident, they began to take the Zone seriously. They decided not to rebuild the old barrier, and quickly built minefields in the south of the Dump. But they did not stop there either. They decided to build a second line of defence in case the first failed. The current roadblock to the south is the former second line. Now it's on the front line.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223006">
        <text>Why does the military roadblock look so weird? I mean, it doesn't look like a fortified defensive position. And this wall is weird, why is it built so that some of the structures are inside the perimeter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223007">
        <text>A roadblock confuses you? It's not a roadblock. There weren't any military buildings here before. Before the accident in '86, there was a service station here. And even afterwards it was still used, refuelled and repaired the equipment that worked at Chernobyl. And after the emergence of the Zone the military settled down. No wall was even meant to be here at that time. They began to build it after the first breakthrough, when this roadblock was declared the second line of the Chernobyl Abnormal Zone barrier. But the engineers got it wrong in a hurry, or for some other reason, but they started building the wall to the south of the roadblock. After it had been built, all the buildings would have been inside the Zone. Someone at the time was kicked in the butt for their oversight, and they decided to turn the wall around, so that it would at least cover some of the buildings. And that's how it got so fucked up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223008">
        <text>Where's the gate? I didn't see it there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223009">
        <text>They're gone, torn down. Mutants went for a breach a couple of months ago. What's noteworthy is that it wasn't there that day. Just in a flash, hordes of dogs, wild boars and flesh-eaters appeared from somewhere in the north, tore down the gate, trampled a few soldiers, and moved on to the Big Land. And as the helicopters arrived and began to iron the mutants, something strange happened - all the creatures in a single rush turned around and raced back to the centre of the Zone. No one understood what it was, nothing like it had ever been seen before. They decided not to rebuild the gates, they would soon finish the second line anyway, and then the soldiers would be taken out of here. You're from the south, by the way, aren't you? Have you seen the second line? It's beautiful, isn't it? All the rules of fortification: flamethrowers, mortars, fortified trenches and pillboxes with redoubts. A minefield of sorts, no Turk could get through. They have poured billions of money into it. Europe has nothing to spare on security, the sponsorship is top-notch.</text>
    </string>

	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2231">
        <text>Thanks for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_224">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_225">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2251">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_226">
        <text>Question 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_227">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2271">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_228">
        <text>Question 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_229">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2291">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_230">
        <text>Question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_231">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2311">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3">
        <text>Anything in particular you are interested in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_33">
        <text>Tell me something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_331">
        <text>Have you heard the story about the American spies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_332">
        <text>No, what's the story?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_333">
        <text>Well, listen. Last year, Skidan got an offer to organize a camping trip through the Zone for three foreigners. The money was good, so the salesman agreed. But he's a sneaky guy, checks everything out. In general, he ran through his channels information about these foreigners, and found out that they are not tourists, but the agents of the CIA. Skidan didn't want to lose the money, but he didn't want to set the stalkers up either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330001">
        <text>So what did he do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330002">
        <text>He came to me, explained everything to me. We had a heart-to-heart talk and found a solution - to send Ilya Muromsky as a guide. You know, the nickname is appropriate. The giant is over two meters tall, with a length of his shoulders and a tremendous amount of strength. He once snapped a boar's neck with his bare hands. So he can stand up for himself if anything happens.</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330003">
        <text>And then?</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330004">
        <text>At the appointed time Ilya met with the "tourists" and took them to the densest places of the border locations. The "tourists" wanted to see some mutants from afar, take pictures of them and, if they were lucky, even shoot some. But Ilya did not know English well enough to understand even a tenth of what his charges told him. The accumulated baggage of knowledge was enough only to understand that the guests want to beat the mutants, and Ilya decided to do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330005">
        <text>I think I'm beginning to guess.</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330006">
        <text>Listen, this is only the beginning. For three days Ilya dragged the poor Americans with him. They had seen and seen what they had not seen during that time. In the dungeons of Agroproma, a bloodsucker attacked them and nearly killed one "tourist. Ilya "accidentally" forgot to warn the foreigners about zombies on Amber, and when one half-decayed corpse begins to rise on its feet in a meter from the spy going to the bathroom, the latter went to the bathroom right there. I do not speak about several packs of wild boars, blind dogs and carnivores, on which Ilyusha, again "accidentally", led the group. And on the third day, on the way back, Ilya proposed to spend the night in an unfinished complex in the north of the Dark Valley. Of course, he was silent about the Burer again. I do not even know who was more afraid that night - American spies, who saw so close the smelly and dirty midgets in tattered robes, or the Burer, who met the "tourists", shrieking with horror. When Ilya recounted it all, we nearly burst out laughing.\nBut that was not all. The next morning, the "tourists," with their trousers full of memories, returned to the Cordon to Skidan to get them across the roadblock. The post was lively that day - some bigwigs had arrived from abroad. Kolyazin asked Skidan to arrange special conditions for the new arrivals. The foreigners turned out to be three CIA agents, officially sent to the Zone to undergo a special training programme. Skidan was puzzled as to why the CIA would first send some of its agents as "tourists" and then officially send three more agents. He shared these thoughts with the "tourists", to which they explained with horror in broken Russian, which they had managed to learn during these three days with Ilyukha, that they were not spies at all, but usual tourists, they simply came to see the Zone and paid dear money for the vouchers. They had nothing to do with the CIA.</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330007">
        <text>Holy shit! Does this mean that your Ilya Muromsky was dragging the real tourists around the Zone, scaring them in every possible way by thinking they were spies?  You guys are unbelievable! Ha-ha-ha!</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330008">
        <text>Yeah, that's the story. Almost got people killed. By the way, Ilyukha and I sent the official spies along the same route. The burers in the Dark Valley were so happy. Hehe!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330009">
        <text>Thank you, you cheered me up.</text>
    </string>	
	
	
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3331">
        <text>Thanks for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_334">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_335">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3351">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_336">
        <text>Question 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_337">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3371">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_338">
        <text>Question 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_339">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3391">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_340">
        <text>Question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_341">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3411">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_4">
        <text>Where are you from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44">
        <text>I was born in the glorious city of Okha on Sakhalin. I hope you know where it is. Because these days, young people aren't interested in anything, let alone their own country.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44001">
        <text>About Sakhalin? Of course I know, it's an island in the Far East, not far from Japan. Wow, where did you come from? What did you do there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44002">
        <text>It's a working-class town, lives mostly off oil and gas. And there's a place for the old trades as well, logging and fishing. So there was always plenty of work. But ever since childhood I had an urge for adventure, I could not sit still in one place. I had to explore all the mountains and forests around me. But that wasn't enough for me. So as soon as I turned eighteen, I was happy to go to the enlistment office. In my case, it was the only way to get off the island and see the world.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_441">
        <text>Thanks for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_5">
        <text>How did you get into the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55001">
        <text>I still do not know whether it was a chain of coincidences or the Zone itself brought me here. In general, I proved myself well in the army. I have been good at sports since I was a baby, so even two years in the Special Forces was not too much for me. Although I did manage to get through the Afghan war, I was lucky not to take part in fights. Then, on the recommendation of the headquarters, I was sent to military training. While I was studying, I started a family. I did not have any children, but it turned out to be for the best. After graduation I was dragged around the garrisons, I had no time for children. Then I was sent to Chechnya. That's where I lost my Marishka... Why the fool did I take her with me, they said it was dangerous at the base, Dudayev's guerrillas could attack. And I... idiot... I didn't keep it safe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55002">
        <text>Sorry, I didn't mean to remind you... Sorry, I didn't know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55003">
        <text>Forget it, it's my fault, my past, my cross. I have to live with it till the day I die. Maybe that's why the Zone brought me in, don't you think? There was a lot more after the first Chechen war, I can't tell you everything. But I remember the appearance of the Zone like I remember it now. It's impossible to forget such a commotion. In the first hours no one even knew what had happened: a reactor exploded or a meteorite fell, or maybe a war had broken out. In Moscow there was no less excitement than in Kiev. Then our troops were sent to the Zone, as agreed. I'll never forget that day, the Zone did its best. I lost almost my entire squad because of the staff rats. They had to find out how anomalies affect people. Bastards. And no one even asked us. How Sergey, Dimka and I got out of there, I have no idea. It was like the Zone itself was leading us between the anomalies. As soon as I got into the headquarters, I shot the general between the eyes. I was about to take my gun out of my holster, but I got caught. I would have been in jail for a long time if it hadn't been for my friends who helped me out of the cell. After I left the camp, I had no choice: either try to survive in the Zone, or try to exist outside the Zone. So I chose my own path - it's better to live a little in the Zone than to exist for the rest of my life in prison.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55004">
        <text>Yeah, that's the story. Don't you long for home, for your homeland?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55005">
        <text>You know, at first I didn't feel it at all, I didn't have time for it. Now the Zone is more or less settled, everywhere you go you're bound to run into someone. But back then there was no one here at all. Even though I'm a combat officer, I've seen enough horrors while in the service, but when you watch the well-known laws of physics being broken and see your true comrade vanishing in agony right in the air, you've got no sense of self-control, fear replaces all the feelings. But you can't lose your knack, so somehow I managed to survive. Then, over time, when I gained experience in the Zone, thoughts of the future began to arise. Now I really want to go home. To see my parents, if they're still alive. To see my hometowns. Believe me, I'd even be ready to go to court if they'd let me spend at least a day in my homeland. Ah...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_551">
        <text>Thanks for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_6">
        <text>Question 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_66">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_661">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_7">
        <text>Question 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_77">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_771">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_777">
        <text>I have already told you everything I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_8">
        <text>Question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_88">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_881">
        <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_999">
        <text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_9990">
        <text>text in default</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
        <text>That's it, you fella, dry your paddle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
        <text>What's going on?! Why is everyone hitting me on the head?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
        <text>You're lucky to be alive. I guess the Speech Therapist has plans for you. Heh-heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
        <text>My head hurts so bad. Listen, bro, why don't we make a deal? I can pay you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
        <text>What are you gonna pay me? You ain't got nothing! And I don't want to deal with the speech therapist later. I don't want that kind of trouble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_5">
        <text>My partner's got money. He'll pay! Whatever you say, he'll pay. His name is Borland.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_6">
        <text>Borland, you say? It's a familiar name. I've heard of him. A stalker in authority. This one might pay. Well, you stay here and think about your sins, and I'll talk to your mate. Don't go anywhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_7">
        <text>I can't get out of the cage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
        <text>Ugh! You scared the hell out of me! What the hell are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
        <text>Skidan?! What a meeting! What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_10">
        <text>Shroud, come clean. I can see right through you, you can't hide anything from me. Borland will tell you that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_11">
        <text>We... we're... kind of...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_12">
        <text>Just tell it like it is, don't pull your balls out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_13">
        <text>Did you hear about the Liberty stalker case?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_14">
        <text>The suicide case? Of course I heard about it, but the whole Cordon is worried about the Libertines coming here to investigate. Can't really prove to them he shot himself. You're the only witness. So what's wrong with this stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_15">
        <text>He wasn't a free man. He was an undercover agent for the Monolith.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_16">
        <text>Oh, really?! No way. Are you drunk or something? Monolith, heh. That's a hell of a thing to say. Where'd that come from? Their faction's long gone, their puppeteers all dead. There's no Monolith, not anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_17">
        <text>What are you talking about? What puppeteers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_18">
        <text>I'll tell you later. It's a long story. You tell me about the agent first. You didn't bring him up for nothing, did you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_19">
        <text>Well, the monolith had a PDA on him, but it was locked. I asked Stjepka to unlock it. That's when I came to you for the walkie-talkie. When I came back from your place, I went to Stoepka's booth and he was gone. I went looking for him... and I found him. I wish you hadn't.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
        <text>None of your damn business. That's the third time this week they've broken the alarm. Where do you get off being so smart?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_20">
        <text>So? Don't drag it out, tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_21">
        <text>Stoepka was killed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_22">
        <text>So that's where he disappeared. And the whole camp has been looking for him for 24 hours. Why didn't you say anything before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_23">
        <text>Wait, Skidan, let me finish. When I was leaning over Stoepka, someone hit me in the head. I was unconscious on the elevator for hours. When I woke up, Stoepka was as dead as if he hadn't been there. And who would believe me that I didn't kill him if there wasn't even a body?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_24">
        <text>Well, you got that right. Wait a minute, where did you say you found Stjepka, at the grain elevator?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_25">
        <text>Yes, yesterday. Why? Do you have any idea who might have knocked me out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_26">
        <text>Yes, but I can't tell you. All I can tell you is that yesterday I arranged a meeting for very serious people at the grain elevator, and that meeting fell through. Apparently, because of you and Stjepka. But who could kill the technician remains a mystery to me. Although...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_27">
        <text>What? Skidan, come on. Stupeka's been murdered, it's not about privacy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_28">
        <text>All right, all right, this is serious. I sent a stalker to the grain elevator. He found an interesting container on the Dump the other day, which my clients from the centre of the Zone have been looking for. It was their money that Shmyga stole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_29">
        <text>What kind of container? What's inside? And who's the stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
        <text>Skidan, what alarm? What's the third time this week? It's our first time here, honest to God.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_30">
        <text>Who the hell knows what's inside the container. I didn't open it, just looked at the numbers on the lid and knew right away it was the container my clients were looking for. The stalker's name was Dubolom. He was delighted when I told him about the deal. I didn't dare buy the container back from him myself, so I arranged a meeting. But now I don't know what happened there - the clients didn't get the container, the stalker disappeared, and you and Stoepka. My clients couldn't have attacked Stoepka - it's not their style. And I don't think the stalker would dare do that, either. I can't vouch for him, though. That leaves someone else. Bandits, maybe?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_31">
        <text>A douche bag? Oh, wow! I know him, Wolf asked me to find this stalker the first time we met. He seemed strange to me even then, he obviously didn't care about his loot. But he's up to no good. Maybe he killed Stoepka. And then hit me over the head as a witness?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_32">
        <text>Maybe he did, though he seemed like a normal guy. Why would he kill Stoepka? I don't know. That's a really strange story. And I don't know where to find Dubololok now, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_33">
        <text>Yes, that's it... Where was I? Oh yes, I remember. I found an unlocked monolith's PDA at Stjepka's place. There were only a few recent messages on it. Briefly, it spoke about some group of stalkers, who stole an artifact from the monoliths, and they chased them. The artifact had destructive influence on people, it was said something about psyche, too abstruse. That is why they put it in a container, and the stalkers stole this container from the monoliths.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_34">
        <text>Container, you say? Isn't that the container...?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_35">
        <text>Maybe it is. Anyway, listen to me. During the chase, some stalkers were killed, but the rest managed to get lost. So the monoliths brought in their undercover agents to find the kidnappers. I don't know how many of these agents there were, but an undercover agent got here to Cordon. He tracked one of the stalkers to a rookie village, but the bandits got him. I don't know why they had to do that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_36">
        <text>I don't get it. So, what, so Dubolom is one of those stalkers? That can't be right. He's only been in the Zone for a couple of weeks, he only went to the Dump the other day, stayed there for a day, and then came back. The same day he brought me that container. I told you what happened next.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_37">
        <text>So Dubolomk found this container at the Dump. Most likely, the stalkers who stole the artifact hid it at the Salvage, and Dubolom accidentally stumbled upon it. He couldn't have killed them. Or could he? I mean, somebody killed Stupid. And then there's the artifact. What do you think the artifact is in the container, Skidan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_38">
        <text>Who knows? Artifacts pop up every day. But come to think of it, I do recall one artifact with a similar effect. It's called a pendulum. Only it's an extremely rare artifact, only two have ever been found. It's worth a lot of money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_39">
        <text>What's it worth so much?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
        <text>Stop telling me that! Who else could have snagged the alarm? It's designed for humans, not to be activated by a marmot or a dog. Which means only a human could have stepped on that tripwire. And if not you, then who?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_40">
        <text>This artifact is double-edged. On the one hand, it absorbs all psi radiation, and on the other, it radiates it with incredible power. The poles of absorption and emission change, with each other over a period of time, after an hour or so. That's why it has to be flipped constantly if you carry it on your belt.\nThis artefact was first found by Broker's group. The properties of the Pendulum weren't immediately clear to them, so only Corkscrew made it to the science camp on Amber alive. He could hardly stand on his feet. The botanists took him by helicopter to the Great Land, but naturally, they kept the artifact for themselves to study. Several of their own lab assistants almost died while they were trying to put together a suitable protective container. I learned this later, from a copy of the report. Sakharov slipped it to me. Since then nothing is known about the first artifact. They're probably still studying it in some secret research institute.\</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_41">
        <text>What about the second one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_42">
        <text>Oh, there's a much more interesting story. You ever heard of the Strelka?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_43">
        <text>No, I haven't heard of him. What's the shooter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_44">
        <text>Oh, brother, he's not a stalker, he's a legend! I don't know when he appeared in the Zone, but he knew his job by heart - sometimes he brought such artifacts that you could not believe it. And where he found them, no one still understands. One day he was lucky enough to find the Pendulum. He was a clever fellow, and as soon as he felt bad he immediately understood that the artifact had a negative influence. I do not know how many days he studied the artifact, but he found out almost the same thing about it as scientists in their labs did. And that in the field, can you imagine?! After that, he started dragging that artifact around. It's also how he got his group through the Brain Burner. They brought back so much stuff, there'd be enough loot for a small island in the Pacific. Merchants from all over the Zone almost lined up for artifacts, but he was stubborn, sold a few of them, and left the rest for himself or something else to do. Ah, he was a good man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_45">
        <text>Why was he? What happened to him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_46">
        <text>Couple years ago, Shooter suddenly disappeared. At the time, we thought he'd died from a massive explosion. I've never seen anything like this before. And believe me, I've seen a lot around here. But a few months later, Strelok was found alive in one of the death trucks. No one knows how he got there. He didn't remember anything himself, not even his name. I didn't recognise him at first - he was scary to look at: skinny, bruised, weathered face, unidentifiable scars all over his body. And there was this mark on his arm, as if he had been branded by beasts - a S.T.A.L.K.E.R. tattoo. But the strangest thing is that his PDA only had one entry to Kill Strelok. That's himself, can you imagine?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_47">
        <text>And then what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_48">
        <text>I don't hide it. The Swordsman, Sidorovich called him for his tattoo, had his own agenda. He had to find Strelok, so he could probably find his hiding place too. But the most interesting thing for us was the way to the north of the Zone, because there is a Klondike of artifacts. Well, Sidorovich and the other dealers decided to use the Swordsman for dark purposes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_49">
        <text>I'm not surprised.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
        <text>Skidan, honestly, we didn't mean for any of this to happen. We agreed with the Watcher that he'd let us see the tunnel and the catacombs. We didn't mean anything by it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_50">
        <text>Ahem. So the Gunslinger, that is, the Swordsman, set out in search of himself. So he followed his own footsteps to the North of the Zone. The scientists helped him with a prototype of a psi-blocker, so his brains wouldn't boil. In return, the Swordsman, unknowingly, gathered all the information for them about the inaccessible parts of the Zone. At the same time and two emitters turned off: one at the lake Amber, the other on Radar - the very same brain burner. The way to Pripyat and the centre of the Zone was open. Shouldn't have done that, but who knew how it would turn out.\nEveryone in the Zone went crazy. Only the laziest went to the centre. Everyone wanted to get to the grantor first. I then rejoiced, I thought that the way to the Pripyat and Chernobyl NPP open, now artifacts to me like a river flow. But there was no way out - no one came back. We took a loan of equipment and headed for Sarcophagus. And as soon as they reached Pripyat, the majority were killed there - the entire city was simply crawling with monoliths. And the factions with their own principles unleashed the war again - no one wanted to retreat, all just wanted to go forward. Later on, the military also joined in. In general, such a ruckus began. And in the end there was a blowout. I can't count the number of people killed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_51">
        <text>And the shooter? Did he make it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_52">
        <text>I don't know. No one's seen him since the incident. Couldn't even find a psi-locker with a transmitter, even though it had a GPS module. The blowout must have damaged it. The last coordinates indicated the entrance to the Sarcophagus, which means that the gunman had reached it a couple of minutes before he got there. He may have survived, but we'll never know. It's been a year since then, a lot of people have been in the centre. In one of the bunkers near Chernobyl some strange laboratory was found - there were corpses in capsules. It was as if they had been shot in their sleep. The stalkers found a lot of documents - they gave them all to the scientists. And it said so much that no one believed it. It was beyond belief.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_53">
        <text>What did it say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_54">
        <text>There was technical information about psi emitters, generators and the wishbone. Turns out the Monolith was an artificial object, used to brainwash fanatics. This explained the fact that no one found the Wish Executor afterwards - there was nothing but a destroyed reactor in the Sarcophagus. Using this device some scientists from the O-Consciousness Project, as they called themselves in documents, hypnotized stalkers who got too close to the mystery of the emergence of the Zone. Recruited agents were given hidden tasks and sent to the borders of the Zone. Apparently Shooter somehow became one of these agents and was tasked to kill himself. But then the Monolith was destroyed. Monolith fanatics began to let go - a few dozen squads from the centre back, do not remember anything. They were almost killed here at first, because they were former enemies. But it turns out that not everyone has recovered from the hypnosis. Judging by your story there are a lot of puppets without puppeteers. And they are up to something, they did not put the Pendulum in the container for nothing. I wonder if that's the same artifact that belonged to Shooter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_55">
        <text>You should be writing books, Skidan. You'd be famous in a heartbeat and get all the writing prizes. I feel like I'm hearing a novel in your retelling. All the laws of the genre: Prologue - plot - climax - denouement. Is that really how it happened? I can't even believe it. The Zone is full of wonders. We'll look around a bit, see if we can find anything interesting. Do you mind?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_56">
        <text>Hang on, Savannah. There's a case. In light of these events, I propose we make a deal: I'll outfit you with first-class weapons at my expense, and you find the Pendulum and sell it to me, and I'll pay good money. I'll even pay you more than it's worth. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_57">
        <text>I don't know, Skidan. What if we don't find anything? What if it's just a stalker story? A legend and nothing more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_58">
        <text>Well, then you'll get it all back and pay the minimum rent for your gear. The main thing is to stay alive, or else we'll look for you and take the armour off the corpses. It's not gonna be pretty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_59">
        <text>Thanks, that's reassuring. We need to think it over. Come on, we'll come back later, okay? In the meantime, we'll wander around, maybe we'll find the Oakleys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_6">
        <text>Wait a minute, so the Watcher let you in? You mean you didn't come in through the chimney?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_7">
        <text>What pipe? We took the stairs. What's a chimney?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_8">
        <text>Well, that's a nasty one, isn't it? You may act like a fool sometimes, Savannah, but you can't lie. Which means there's been three break-ins in the last week, not counting you. So what did you say you were looking for here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_9">
        <text>I didn't say we were looking for anything. Come on, Skidan. We just wanted to see what's going on, that's all.\</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_0">
        <text>I've thought about your offer. We're in. We'll bring you the artifact. Give me your cool guns and armor. I also need a code and a key card to get into the underground lab under the Cordon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_1">
        <text>Now, that's another conversation. Now, here's where I've got it stashed. There you go! Just as I told you, it's not the hottest piece of equipment in the Zone, but it has been proven in many walks. You can only get it on order from the Big Land. Or on the Bar, if you're lucky. Give me your PDA, I'll text you the master code. It's better than any key card. It's a hundred percent good, unlike the usual service ciphers. I'll know the password any minute, and I'll radio it to you on your PDA. Here's the ammunition, as promised. I've already provided Borland with armor and weapons and he's waiting for you downstairs. I'm about to open my private secret passage to the catacombs for you. All right, ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1">
        <text>Independence is something I value very much, because I've always been on my own and only worked for myself. But when I heard the stalkers were squeezing out the military and setting up their base, I came straight here. I, you know, have crossed paths with many people in the Zone, but as far as I'm concerned, stalkers are the best. Well, how can I put it... they're normal, you know? Without all that stupid stuff with codes and rules, like in other factions. In the long run, the only people in the Zone should be stalkers: then there'd be mutual assistance everywhere, and it'd be quieter. So I decided to support these guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11">
        <text>It's rare to meet a technician in the Zone. Tell me, what can you do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_111">
        <text>Well, don't expect any fancy gadgets or fancy stuff from me. But don't hold your breath, either: I've got a pot that still works, and I've got my hands in the right place.\nAnything that could save your life, I'm good at it. Repairing most weapons and armour, and if the necessary parts turn up, I may even be able to improve your gun or armour. If you want to know what I do, take a look at the Upgrades, I think you'll find it easy to figure out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1111">
        <text>I take it you've been around the Zone a while? Seen anything unusual?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11111">
        <text>Unusual? I was coming here through Agroprom just after that powerful one. I looked - well, wonders... There's a patch of mangled earth in the old place where there wasn't a damn thing before. And it's so phoned up that you have to run past it. Then the guys told me that this anomaly is the most powerful: the energy comes out not just as a fountain, but as Niagara Falls! The place is the most dangerous, but the trick is that the rarest artifacts happen there most often. So if you come across this place, keep an eye out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_1">
        <text>I'm a trader... a beginner. As you can see, we've only been here a short while. As soon as the Shaman told me everyone could be anything they wanted, I decided I'd be a merchant and no nails. Why, I've got skills, and Skidan's right there, a living example... If you want to know, back in high school I had an electronic toy - you know, the dog used to catch chicken eggs? - I used to sell this thing to my classmates for ten kopecks a batch. I've got that vein, you know? Yeah, those were the golden days... Now I'm getting the hang of it, getting into the trade, so to speak. I'm taking Skidan's merchandise for sale, so the prices, you know, aren't great yet. But there's something interesting to be found: the guys have already started bringing me their stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_111">
        <text>Oh, man, we're gonna live like Christ in the palm of our hands... or whoever's in charge of us sinners. The soldiers won't be oppressing us any more, now everything will go for the stalker's benefit. And after the raid will be able to rest on Cordon, and the equipment will appear... For the loot will also get real money, not like before: the scraps for us, and the cream for the military. Wait, we'll have another go at the warriors! Why? They can't relax, you know, they're not in a fairy tale! In a word, let's get on with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_2">
        <text>Do you think life will change on Cordon?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_3">
        <text>Oh, mate, we're going to live like we're in God's good graces now... or whoever's in charge of us sinners. The soldiers won't be oppressing us any more, now everything will be for the stalker's benefit. And after the raid will be able to rest on Cordon, and the equipment will appear... For the loot will also get real money, not like before: the scraps for us, and the cream for the military. Wait, we'll have another go at the warriors! Why? They can't relax, you know, they're not in a fairy tale! In a word, let's get on with it.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_0">
        <text>Thank you very much, comrade stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_1">
        <text>You're welcome, comrade. Where do they send you to the Zone from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm from Novosibirsk. You know, in Akademgorodok...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_3">
        <text>What's going on?! Why are you telling me this? It was a rhetorical question. That's it, I've done my job, let the others suffer with you now. Good luck!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey, Student. Shall we go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_1">
        <text>Good day to you, sir! So you'll be my escort? Pleased to meet you. Are you an experienced stalker? Isn't it dangerous? Won't the bandits shoot us on the way? What about mutants? I hear there's a lot of mutants out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_2">
        <text>First of all, we're all on a first-name basis here. Secondly, we go quickly and silently. I emphasize silent! Thirdly, I'm a very experienced stalker, and I'll be fine. Let's go!</text>
    </string>
	
	
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_dialog_0">
        <text>Are you the new mechanic?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes, Stjepka disappeared somewhere, now I'm in his place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_0">
        <text>I wanted to know about the tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_1">
        <text>About what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_2">
        <text>Well, I was bringing Stoepka some tools...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_3">
        <text>Yes, well, not all of them are still needed, if you find them, bring them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_4">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_0">
        <text>I brought you the tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_1">
        <text>Oh, great! What kind do you want to share?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_11">
        <text>For the rough stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_111">
        <text>Oh, that's great! Now if I could just get some more tools for fine work and calibration...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_12">
        <text>Fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_121">
        <text>Great! Now if I could just get some more tools for rough work and calibration...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_13">
        <text>For calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_131">
        <text>Oh, that's great! Now if I could just get some more tools for the rough work and the fine work...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_14">
        <text>So far, none.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_141">
        <text>Oh, great! If I could get some more calibration tools, I'd be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_151">
        <text>Cool! I wish I had some more tools to do the fine work and I'd be all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_161">
        <text>Oh, great! I wish I had some more tools for the rough stuff, and I'd be all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_171">
        <text>Wow! Well, that's... Where'd you find those?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_0">
        <text>If tools are the problem, I can get them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_1">
        <text>That'd be great! I'm working like in the Stone Age. Only soldering iron from the new age, and that's more like a shaman's rod... If I have the tools, I'll have first-rate tunes. And you'll get a penny or two.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_11">
        <text>All right. I'll look for something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_12">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_3">
        <text>Come on, it's a good subject. I get to make tunes, you get to make money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_1">
        <text>Hi. Need any tools?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_2">
        <text>You're asking! Of course I do. Show me what you got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_3">
        <text>For rough work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_4">
        <text>Oh, that's great! Now I can modify your weapons and armour.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_5">
        <text>For fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_6">
        <text>Great! Now our local science and technology progress will take a leap forward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_7">
        <text>For calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_8">
        <text>Great! Now I can make you such an automaton... such that Sidorovich would give you his soul for it, hehe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_9">
        <text>Haven't found any tools yet. I'll keep looking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_0">
        <text>Heh-heh. Welcome to our humble corner of happiness, sir. You're welcome to see our price list.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_1">
        <text>Huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_10">
        <text>Oh, man! You're quite a magician, aren't you? What's his name? Kupperfield! I respect that. All right, you can go through the tunnel one or two times. Me and my buddies will take care of the healing. The way's open, you can go wherever you need to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_11">
        <text>Already gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_2">
        <text>What's up? Give me the money, that's what!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_3">
        <text>Uh, I ain't got no money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_4">
        <text>Heh-heh. You're funny. Where do you think you're going without the money, fool? No dough, no gear. No gear, no art. And no art... What's next? It was kinda nice... Oh, no art, no dough. Oh, yeah! It's called a vicious circle. You got it? Heh-heh. So why don't you get out of here while you're still in one piece? You'll thank me later. Look at you, a superhero. Heh-heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_5">
        <text>Guys, I gotta get to the other side. I really do. Why don't we make a deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_6">
        <text>He needs it. You never know who needs what. Maybe I need a hangover. Well, I'm not bothering you with my problems. Get out while you still can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_7">
        <text>Well, why don't you get some vodka? I got some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_71">
        <text>Guys, it's my first day in the Zone. Why don't you let me pass?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_72">
        <text>Heh-heh! Well, that's quite a turn-up, isn't it? Not even cats are born for that! So it's pay or get out - there's no third way!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_73">
        <text>Well, the hell with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_8">
        <text>You seem like a nice kid. Give me your vodka. But I won't let you in anyway. Heh-heh! And you thought you were in a fairy tale? Get out of here while I'm nice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_9">
        <text>And I've got another bottle. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
        <text>Thank you. Mutants have been going crazy lately, giving me a hard time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
        <text>You're welcome, Granddad. You're the Watcher, aren't you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_10">
        <text>You didn't live under the Soviet Union. They used to do things like turn back rivers. Oh, yeah! And digging holes in the ground was a piece of cake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_11">
        <text>Grandpa, how do you get there, in those catacombs? I really want to see it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_12">
        <text>You're so quick. Why should I let you into the tunnel? My superiors strictly told me not to let anyone in without my knowledge.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_13">
        <text>Grandpa, what bosses? There hasn't been a Zone here for a long time - there's no boss left.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_14">
        <text>What do you mean, gone? Who's making noise there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_15">
        <text>Where?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_16">
        <text>In the tunnel. There's a noise every night. If it's not the bosses, who is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_17">
        <text>You never know. Creatures, mutants. Do you want to see?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_18">
        <text>You're trying to trick me, aren't you? All right. I kind of owe you one. All right, here's a spare key to my place. Just don't touch anything in the house!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_19">
        <text>All right, Grandpa. Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
        <text>Yeah. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
        <text>They call me Savan. I was just looking for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
        <text>Me? Wow. What can I do for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
        <text>Tell me about the tunnel under the village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_6">
        <text>Oh, boy. I see you're a straight shooter. You don't beat around the bush, you're a straight shooter. Well, I respect a straight shooter. All right, I'll tell it to you straight. But, you know, not a word to anyone, all right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_7">
        <text>Grave!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_8">
        <text>After the Great Patriotic War, the Soviet leadership was extremely concerned about protective measures and escape routes for high-ranking officials. Therefore it was decided to create a secret extensive underground communication network. First and foremost, the network was to provide emergency evacuation from besieged cities such as Kiev, Minsk and Moscow. One of the underground railroad branches of this network is located here, under the Zone, which is the Kiev-Minsk route. Along with this branch, underground communications were built to service rolling stock, as well as to deliver materials to other important objects, which at the time were in short supply everywhere. And I was assigned to guard the back door. I've been guarding it ever since.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_9">
        <text>You mean the tunnel under the village leads to the railway? It can't be!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
        <text>Oh, you're here! What more do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
        <text>Grandpa, what's wrong? Why are you so angry?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_10">
        <text>Son, find the bastard who went through my wardrobes without asking, I beg you. People have no shame and no conscience. And give me back my key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_11">
        <text>I'll do anything, Grandpa, don't worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
        <text>He's also mocking me. Why were you messing around in my house? What were you looking for? Money, valuables? I ain't got nothing but a watch, and that ain't even working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
        <text>Grandpa, come on, I wasn't looking for anything! I have nothing else to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
        <text>And who's been going through my cupboards? The ghost? They also stole the map.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
        <text>What card?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_6">
        <text>The access card. A key, to put it simply.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_7">
        <text>Not the door to the underground lab, is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_8">
        <text>How'd you know that? You definitely took it. Give it back!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_9">
        <text>What a coincidence, and I was just about to ask you for that key. I don't have the map, Grandpa. But I think I know who might have stolen it from you. Well, we'll have to go to the merchant for help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_0">
        <text>What's there to see around here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1">
        <text>This place is for newcomers. There's a trader on the outskirts of the village called Skidanem. There's a military roadblock on the other side. That's where you came from. On the other side of the roadblock is the road deep into the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11">
        <text>Tell me about the Rookie Village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_111">
        <text>What can I tell you about this place? All who are more elegant, procured from Skidan the most necessary and move to the dump: there and artifacts thicker, and not as dangerous as closer to the centre of the Zone. One can gain experience. Although it is also possible to die in a jiffy: mutants, bandits, anomalies - there is an abundance of it all. Like everywhere else, more risk, more profit. And the only ones left here are complete... dickheads, to put it mildly. Sometimes such a miracle comes along - almost in slippers and with a handbag. He wanted romance, you know! Or some docent who's never held anything more serious than a slide rule. Such guys get screwed up fast, that's for sure. Sometimes veteran stalkers drop in to drop some loot for Skidan after a long way out, listen to the gossip from the Big Land, and have a rest for a day or two in a quiet place. It's not often, it's been a long time since anyone from the north came.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1111">
        <text>It's a nice place you got here. Just a resort. Doesn't the military bother you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11111">
        <text>The military don't press, they don't have time for us now. They say there's no use wasting ammunition on those stalkers, they can die in anomalies anyway. And we, in response, don't get too cocky: if they're looking for someone, we don't get in the way - when there's a raid or a checkpoint from the HQ, we shelter in basements. In general, you can see for yourself that we're quiet and non-conflictual people.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_22">
        <text>Tell me about Skidan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_222">
        <text>He's stingy, like all traders. Been trading on Cordon for years. His main customers are rookie stalkers new to the Zone. He has many connections, including contacts with the military, various factions in the Zone, and even bandits. The military smuggles his goods across the roadblock. That's the business. Rumor has it that he's been into trade since childhood, when he was a student he sold weak drugs illegally. Maybe not weak drugs. And kind of got in trouble with the penal code for it. I don't know if that's true or not. You can't believe every word of it, you know. Stalkers make up gossip, like old grannies on a bench outside the door. Almost all the stalkers in the Zone worked for Skidan in the beginning, so he knows about everyone, and has an opinion on everyone. In short, every dog in the Zone knows him!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_1">
        <text>I'm kind of in charge of this village. Kind of like a mentor to the newbies. I'm teaching the green stuff, the greenhouse goggles, so they don't get pinched on the first go-round by the bony one. Oh, it's hard to teach! Some are unlearnable in principle. You look at one and you think: What can you teach him?! He's read two books in his life - an ABC book and this blue one. And it's logical that they die in the first anomaly, forgetting to throw a nut in front of them. I've already tramped through the Zone myself, I've left a piece of my life here. I think I can get out of here, how much longer can I go on. Only an evil witch or some hex, no otherwise, and I can not get out in any way: either the soldiers with the raid, or over there blowout blows. And the money, frankly... sometimes there's a lucrative job offer, so why not take it? You know how it is, you think you're gonna make that last exit, and then I'm out, and then it's just like that over and over again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're at Kordon now. To the south, beyond the army roadblock, is the outside world, and further north is the Zone. There is little reminiscent of it: anomalies are few, almost no artifacts, and the monsters are rare. There is not much noise here, too, because the military are trying to keep everything under strict control. In general, the place is quite quiet - of course, compared to the rest of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're at Cordon now. Beyond the army roadblock is the outside world, and further north is the Zone. There is little reminiscent of it: anomalies are few, almost no artifacts, and the monsters are rare. There is not much noise here, too, because the military are trying to keep everything under strict control. In general, the place is quite quiet - of course, compared to the rest of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're at Cordon now. Beyond the army roadblock is the outside world, and further north is the Zone. There is little reminiscent of it: anomalies are few, almost no artifacts, and the monsters are rare. There is not much noise here, too, because the military are trying to keep everything under strict control. In general, the place is rather quiet - of course, compared to the rest of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the Rookie Village. On the outskirts is the bunker of Skidan, the merchant. Farther along is a military roadblock - that's actually where you came from. The other side of the roadblock is the road deep into the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the Rookie Village. At the edge is the bunker of Skidan, the merchant. Next is a military roadblock - that's where you came from. The other side of the roadblock is the road deep into the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the Rookie Village. At the edge is the bunker of Skidan, the merchant. Next is a military roadblock - that's where you came from. The other side of the roadblock is the road deep into the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_0">
        <text>Wolf, I thought about your offer and decided to sell you that artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_1">
        <text>Good call. Skidan would have given you half as much for it. I know that cheapskate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_2">
        <text>Yeah, well, I've seen it firsthand myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_0">
        <text>What's the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_1">
        <text>It's a dusty job, a passenger to the stalker camp at the ATP. Client's new to the Zone, but he's well provided for. Pays 10 grand. Half now, the rest on completion, if you bring him in alive. Mind you, he can't shoot. Don't expect any help on the road. Will you do it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_2">
        <text>It's a deal. Where's your passenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_3">
        <text>He's over there, calling himself Student. When you get to the base, come back and I'll give you the second part of the money. Student will let me know when you get to the ATP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_4">
        <text>All right, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_5">
        <text>No, Wolf, I'm sorry. I don't do deliveries. I'm a conductor like you're a ballerina. Maybe someone else can do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_6">
        <text>Suit yourself. That kind of money is hard to come by. And I'll always find someone willing. I thought of you first, I know you needed the money in a hurry. No, I don't.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_7">
        <text>Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_0">
        <text>I've been thinking... Anyway, I'm willing to take that rookie to ATP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_1">
        <text>I don't know about that. All right, there he is, call him Student. When you get to ATP, come back to me, I'll give you the other part. Student will let me know how he gets to ATP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_2">
        <text>Don't worry, Wolf, I'll do it right. It's only a short walk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_3">
        <text>Too late, Savan, too late. The rookie's already gone. You're not the only stalker in the Zone, there are others who want to make money. Dutyo thought he'd missed out on a free job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_4">
        <text>Didn't really feel like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_0">
        <text>Job done. A student at the TSA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_1">
        <text>So, everything okay? Nothing happened on the road?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_2">
        <text>There was... A student happened. Oh, he's such a big mouth. Couldn't stop myself from shooting him. I can see why it's a high-paying job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah, he likes to talk. He's a nerd, for crying out loud. Speaking of pay, here's the second part, as promised.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_4">
        <text>All right, Wolf. Anything else comes up, let me know.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_0">
        <text>Got your message. What's your pleasure?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_1">
        <text>I will, I will. Found you a teacher. Give me your PDA, I'll drop you a tag on a stalker. His name is Leshim. He's a hunter. Not just a hunter, but a real legend of the Zone. You could say he ate a bloodsucker in this business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_2">
        <text>What's in it for me? I'm not going to eat a bloodsucker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_3">
        <text>You don't know how lucky you are, Savannah. The woodsman can teach you which mutant is the best to kill. Not every rookie gets that chance. He just needs a partner right now, so I thought of you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_4">
        <text>Tag him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_5">
        <text>I texted you the tag. Leschii will be waiting for you out by the road, near the ATP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_6">
        <text>Thanks, Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_0">
        <text>Got your message. What kind of help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_1">
        <text>Good of you to come. I could've done it myself, but it'd be more fun with you. It'll teach you something, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_2">
        <text>What can I help you with?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_3">
        <text>Well, I got myself a new detector. I want to test it out in the field, so to speak. Let's go look for artifacts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_4">
        <text>Afrikatos? Where would you look?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_5">
        <text>Anomalies. More specifically, anomalous fields. And not Afrikata. Artifacts. In short, artifacts. The backbone of the entire stalker trade. And the source of money. Shall I teach you how to collect artifacts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_6">
        <text>You ask!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_7">
        <text>Well, then follow me. It's just around the corner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_8">
        <text>Lead the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_1">
        <text>Come on, tell me what kind of art you got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_2">
        <text>There!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_3">
        <text>Well, lucky you. You don't find many artifacts like this around here. You're a capable student. You've never been a stalker before? You sure about that? Just kidding.\nIf you want, I can buy that art from you for good money. Merchants will never give you full price, you know. I need that kind of art for a custom job. I can buy other art from you, but only rare ones. Think about it. If anything, you know where to find me.\nAll right, let's get to camp. You sure you can't wait around the campfire to tell the boys what you found?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_4">
        <text>Bragging ain't my style. If I find these artifacts, I'll bring them to you to sell. You know how much money you need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_gg_0">
        <text>All right, I found a path to the centre of the field. Detector says there's an artifact here. There's more than one. Now it's your turn. Here, I got you an upgrade, the bear detector. It not only shows you the distance to the artifact, but also the direction you're looking. Throw the bolts and go around the anomalies. When you see a signal on the screen, go in the same direction. Just be careful! You won't see the artifact right away. You have to get close to it first, that's when it will pop out of the anomaly field. Good luck!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_gg_1">
        <text>Don't mention it!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_strahovka_0">
        <text>Here we are. See that hole behind me? That's the anomalous field. You have to be very careful here. Any wrong move and you're a dead man. There's radiation and lots of gravitational anomalies. All right, here's what we're going to do: I'm going to survey the anomaly and find a passageway, and I'm going to test the detector. Meanwhile, you carefully watch my actions, but do not forget to watch out for mutants. You ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_strahovka_1">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey, Wolf. Do you happen to know where I can find the Watcher? He's not at home, the door's locked, and I have a question for him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
        <text>Well, he's gone. The day before yesterday.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
        <text>How far is he gone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
        <text>To the marshes. He collects some herbs there, and then makes tinctures. It's good for colds, I tell you. And for other ailments, too. And just to warm the soul.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
        <text>Oh, man. He'll be back soon, didn't he say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
        <text>Yeah, he'll be back today. How long has it been? Hmm, he should be here by now. Strange, he's never late, they don't call him the Watcher for nothing. Maybe something's wrong? Listen, Sawan, you've got a job to do. Run to the tunnel near the military roadblock. That's the tunnel the Sentinel's supposed to use to get back from the Swamp. You never know what's going on down there. He's an experienced man, all his life in the Zone, but age takes its toll. I texted you the coordinates. That's it, let's go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_6">
        <text>You're already there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_0">
        <text>Do you have a job, did you write me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_1">
        <text>Because I always have something interesting for you. How do you feel about safaris?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_2">
        <text>Not really, I've never been on a safari.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_3">
        <text>Would you like to? Well, it's not savannah here, no lions, sorry. But there's wild boars that would give your lion a leg up. That's what they need to be quieted down. They're getting out of hand. Wedge and his boys just left a few minutes ago to go shoot some mutants around the village. Care to join them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_4">
        <text>I don't see why not. There's a lot of beasts, I still can't forget those boars by the "electric train".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_5">
        <text>Good for you, good thinking. It's good for the camp, and it won't be a waste for you. By the way, the rate for a sweep is 6,000 roubles. Each! So it's a good salary. Agreed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_6">
        <text>You're still asking? Of course I do! Where to?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_7">
        <text>I texted you the coordinates on the PDA. They just got out, so I don't think they've started shooting yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_8">
        <text>Well, I'm gonna catch up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_0">
        <text>All right, we got the mutants!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_1">
        <text>Already? What do you think of our local safari?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_2">
        <text>It's great. We should do it again sometime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_3">
        <text>You're always welcome. There's always a lot of creatures around here. I don't know where they come from. All right, here's your reward. If there's any more work, I'll text you. Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_4">
        <text>Thanks Wolf! See you later!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_0">
        <text>Do you want to hang out while the clients are gone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1">
        <text>Sure. What's this about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_11">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_111">
        <text>Uh, brother, I used to be a businessman back in the Soviet Union! I was one of those... the "goddamn speculators." I got caught up in a big deal, and I got the whole thing. He did what he was sentenced to, and made some friends among the thieves. When he got out, he started working with thieves, taking their loot. In three years I got busted again, and when I got out, it was a couple of years since the Soviets got busted. Something didn't work out for me with the new rules, I had to work on trifles for a long time, I got really poor and then suddenly the Zone came along. I came here and it was like old times, almost like old times! With my experience, it's the best place to sell here now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1111">
        <text>I get the idea. Anything else you want to tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1112">
        <text>I got it. Well, that's enough talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_12">
        <text>What do you think of Speech Therapist?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_121">
        <text>I'll tell you this: Speech therapist ain't got long to be an ace. My gut says Koba's gonna get him, and he's gonna get him. It's all going to happen. Pakhan's got a big nose, he's just showing off. He's got a snake, but he doesn't notice it, which is clear to half of the boys. I'm not telling you this so that you'll get angry left and right: I've shown you trust, so that you can trust me too. Yeah, so if you come across anything interesting, bring it to me. I'll always be in my place with Speech Therapist or Kobe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_13">
        <text>Tell me about the junkyard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_131">
        <text>The boys there, in that dump, weren't too happy about it. Used to be they wouldn't even go in there: rubbish, radiation... Then a couple of stalkers got lucky and found some expensive stuff. And that was it-people from all over the Zone flocked here like sore throats on an old hen. It was a total mess, but then our guys cleaned it up. The main thing is to have a strong hand and hold this scum tightly. And the Zone should be like a zone: either red trash or black thieves. That's what the boys here have approved. It's clear as day that you gotta pay for order. Guys want to eat too, so they get a cut of everything. I'm not too shabby here, but I want to get to a better place...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_14">
        <text>What's the latest news in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_141">
        <text>I don't like that word "latest news". And you shouldn't use them so that you won't really make news that will be your last. Although we don't have such scary creatures here, but there was a story the other day... Anyway, a stalker showed up - white as a wall, hands shaking... Started confessing. Theme is this: he and a friend washed away from poltergeists, but then bam - a pack of jerks jumped out at them. So the guy gets all worked up, some crazy reflex kicked in, he slashes at his friend with a line and slices him open. He ran away at once, but the jerks jumped on the body - why would they run after meat when they had it ready? And then on the second bottle of vodka his consciousness began, and he began to howl at the whole dump: "Igor-o-ok, you gave me the only medkit then, and I'm like a bitch, like the last creature, finished you ...". Anyway, he hung himself in the night with his belt. That's what happens to people...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_15">
        <text>It's probably nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_151">
        <text>It's up to you.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_0">
        <text>Anything I can do to help?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_1">
        <text>No, thank you, Savan. We're fine on our own. Although... There's a job for you. But I don't think you'll take it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_2">
        <text>What is it, Pathogenic? Come on, spill it, I won't leave you alone. Tell me everything as it is, and I'll decide whether to take the job or not.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_3">
        <text>There's not much to tell. There's a creature that lives around here. A pseudo-dog. Sneaky bastard. When it gets dark, he comes to the camp and starts howling. It's been getting on our nerves. We tried to find his hole a couple of times, but we couldn't find anything, no sign of him or the creature, as if there was no one. But he still howled at night.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_4">
        <text>So you'd deal with him in the evening when he comes to the camp.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_5">
        <text>Ha, easy for you to say. I tell you, pseudo-dogs are sneaky, this one's elusive. And you'd have to be either an idiot or Chuck Norris to go after a mutant at night. You think you can handle it? I'll get you a helmet and an E.P.V. What's more, if you can do it, you can have the helmet for good. I'll throw in some extra cash on top of that. All right?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_6">
        <text>Come on. A night hunt, what could be better? Give me your helmet. I'll be back when I'm done.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_7">
        <text>No, thanks, I don't need any more pseudo dogs.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_8">
        <text>Well, I told you, you can't do it, you can't do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_9">
        <text>Only I know I can!</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_0">
        <text>I got your dog, Pathogenic. You were right, it's a sneaky creature, you can't hit it. But it's all right, I'm not a dick myself. It won't howl in the night again, I guarantee it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_1">
        <text>That's the spirit, I respect that! Here's another one from me, you deserve it. At least we'll get a good night's sleep tonight. Thanks, Sawan. Remember, you're always welcome here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_2">
        <text>You're welcome, Pathogenic. If there's any more trouble, you know who to call.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Why did you call? You got business for me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Yeah, I got a job just for you. We need to find a good dude to fix the boys' guns and gear. We'll pay him a trifle for each repair, as it should be, and the boys will give him respect and honor. You'll get one for your trouble, too. Will you do it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_2">
        <text>No problem.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_3">
        <text>All right, but don't take too long.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_4">
        <text>I'm on my way.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_11">
        <text>I don't mind...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_12">
        <text>What a dickhead, he can't... Go on, then.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_13">
        <text>He's gone.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey Boss, I found a mechanic for the brigade, he's a cool kid and a smart one, too.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_1">
        <text>That's the deal. Now we're gonna do even better.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_2">
        <text>Well, as you say, more frizzy is more frizzy.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_0">
        <text>Listen, Dubolom, how'd you like to get into gear repair?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_1">
        <text>I don't mind. Especially, as you know with free stalkerism I'm not very good at, and I can craft so that Stepka might be jealous. But wait, Logoped is offering stalkers a job now?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_2">
        <text>Logoped doesn't care that you were a free stalker. He promises pay and the respect of the fraternity.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_3">
        <text>Then I'm in.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_4">
        <text>You got it. I'll tell Mugwumped that.</text>
    </string>	
	
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_0">
        <text>Chimera neutralized, here's the PDA.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_1">
        <text>Great! Get a new mission. We have a soldier who has deserted. Private Nikita Sergeyevich Nefedov. Apparently, he escaped to the Zone. Find out where he's hiding or make sure he's dead.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_2">
        <text>All right. It'll be easier than a chimera.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_0">
        <text>I found the deserter.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_1">
        <text>And where is he hiding?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_2">
        <text>He's dead, here's his dog tags taken off the corpse.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_3">
        <text>Well, then, good riddance to him. You and your partner can get the hell out of here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_4">
        <text>Goodbye, I hope I never see you again.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_10">
        <text>He's in a bandit camp behind the railway tracks, posing as a stalker named Scar.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_11">
        <text>So that's how it is. I'll send a team to arrest him. You and your partner are free to go. Don't get caught again.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_12">
        <text>We'll do our best.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_0">
        <text>Look, Wolf, you're a seasoned hunter. There's a chimera I need to take out. It's keeping the soldiers alive. Can you tell me how to deal with a chimera alone?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_1">
        <text>You're not a bad hunter either, by the way. You got Leshny out, and you helped a lot with clearing the territory of mutants. So I'll tell you, hunter to hunter, there's an unorthodox way.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_2">
        <text>Unconventional? What do you mean?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_3">
        <text>You've heard of the Beastmaster? Well, he made a repellent based on the urine of a male chimera. If you smear it on unclothed parts of the body, the chimera smells a competitor and runs away. They'll run away and never come back. It's not that simple, though.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_4">
        <text>Well, it usually is. Side effects?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_5">
        <text>The fact is, the stronger the male chimera, the more special substances in the urine that signal the strength of the opponent. The female chimera will prefer to run away, the weaker male will also run away. But if you encounter a strong male, the smell of a competitor will drive him mad. Enraged. And, you know, an enraged, strong chimera male will tear you to pieces. Tear you apart like a dickens.\nBefore you can say meow.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_6">
        <text>All right, I'll take my chances. You got that repellent? How much are you asking for it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_7">
        <text>Here you go. I'm not taking any money, don't even think about it. Consider it my thanks for saving Leshy.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_8">
        <text>Thank you, Wolf.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_10">
        <text>No, I'd rather do without the miracle repilentant. A chimera is no gift in itself, and a chimera in a rage is a certain death. No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
		<text>Wolf, here's the thing. Has a soldier named Nefedov been in the village?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
		<text>Soldiers don't come here. We have a tense relationship with them. We don't shoot at each other, of course. But we try not to come into contact with them. They do not get close to us and we do not get close to them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
		<text>Have there been any newcomers lately named Nikita?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
		<text>Some time ago, there was a rookie named Nikita. He had this weird nickname. Kasha. Nikita Kasha. But he moved to ATP a long time ago.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
		<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Pathogenic. I have a question for you. Have you met a stalker named Kasha or Nikita? Or Nikita Kasha? Ex-military. Huh?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
		<text>No, I haven't met either Kasha or Nikita. And it's not customary for stalkers to use real names.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
		<text>Well, maybe you've met an ex-military man recently.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
		<text>How do you define ex-military? Who's the quickest to wake up and jump at the command: Company up!?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
		<text>Patogenych, don't talk to me like that. You're an experienced stalker, you've seen everything. Don't you have an eye for recognizing a soldier?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
		<text>Yeah, well, there was one stalker. He was nicknamed Pogon, and he had a scar on his face, so he was definitely one of the exes. And not by his nickname, but by the way he looked at the other stalkers. Like a soldier looking at a louse. Like Lenin looked at the bourgeoisie.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
		<text>And where is he now?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_7">
		<text>Fuck knows. Maybe he's dead, maybe he's gone to bandits. I haven't seen him around here for a long time.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_8">
		<text>Thanks for your help.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
		<text>Speech therapist, have you seen a man called Pogon amongst your people?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
		<text>Pogon? Not a cop?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
		<text>No, not at all. It's just a nickname. He's got a scar on his face, and he was supposed to be here recently.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
		<text>There's a little man with a scar on his face. That's what we call him, Scar.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
		<text>Is he here now?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
		<text>Yeah, he's around here somewhere.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
		<text>I'll talk to him.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
		<text>And hello to you, too. I got business for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
		<text>What business could you possibly have with me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
		<text>Nikita, I got an assignment from the boogeyman, but I can't do it alone. I need a guide, can you help me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, if it promises to be profitable... Wait, what did you call me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
		<text>I called you Nikita Nefedov, a former private in the Ukrainian army, now a wanted deserter. Kolyazin is all over the place to find you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
		<text>Damn it, my past won't let me go... Look, I can't go back anyway, but if Koljazin won't rest until he finds me, then help me. Here's my key chains, give them to him and tell him what you found on my dead body. And I'll go further north so they don't find me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
		<text>All right, come on.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_0">
		<text>Skidan, what happened to the prices?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_1">
		<text>What, what. Some smart-ass stalker messed with the military, now Kolyazin's raised the toll for shipping goods through the roadblock. And you wondered how the goods got to me? If I'd known who was shitting, I'd have ripped his head off myself. With these very hands.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_2">
		<text>So what now?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_3">
		<text>Now it's hard times for all the stalkers. Food, uniforms, ammunition and weapons have all gone up in price. And it's not profitable for me to trade here at Cordon. That's the way it is.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_4">
		<text>We have to do something.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_5">
		<text>What the stalkers will do, I don't know. If the situation with the military doesn't change, I'll move to the Dyatka checkpoint.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_6">
		<text>I see.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_0">
		<text>Patogenych, what happened to the prices?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_1">
		<text>Kolyazin has gone crazy, he's raised the price of transporting goods through the checkpoint. Now it's hard to supply, so the prices have gone up.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_2">
		<text>I see.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_0">
		<text>Antibiotic, what happened to the prices?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_1">
		<text>Kolyazin's gone rogue, he's raised the price of medical supplies through the checkpoint. So the prices went up.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_2">
		<text>I see.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_0">
		<text>Ticks, what happened to the prices?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_1">
		<text>Koljazin, the scumbag, is demanding triple-dollar fees for delivery of heaters through the barbed wire. I got to make sure I don't make a loss. Fucking business.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_2">
		<text>I see.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, Cousteau, what happened to the prices?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_1">
		<text>Kolyazin's gone fucking crazy, raised the price of carrying goods through the roadblock. Now it's hard to get supplies. Which means the prices have gone up.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_2">
		<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_0">
		<text>You paged? What do you need me for?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_1">
		<text>I've heard about Shmyga and how he's got a good deal. But he doesn't want to do it by the book: If it's a good deal, pay a tenth of the loot to the joint.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_2">
		<text>You're suggesting I get a share out of Shmyga?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_3">
		<text>You're smart, but not just knock him out, but punish him for his arrogance and unwillingness to live up to his code.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_4">
		<text>What kind of punishment?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_5">
		<text>Properly, like a boy. Bled him with a knife, so that he'll remember and others won't be harmed. Tell him if he wants to live, let him give up his share.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_6">
		<text>Will do.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_0">
		<text>Give me Skidan's briefcase, bitch.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_1">
		<text>What? You don't want the keys to the flat where the money is? Get the fuck out of here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_2">
		<text>What keys? Don't give me that shit. It's not your briefcase and you can't open it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_3">
		<text>Don't worry, what's mine, I can open it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_4">
		<text>I'm gonna shoot you now, asshole.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_5">
		<text>This is a fraternity base? You're gonna get yourself killed before you raise your gun on the right guy.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_6">
		<text>All right, I'll see you around.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Here's the scumbag's word: You didn't do what's right, you didn't pay off the spoils to the joint. That's why the gang won't fit in for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_1">
		<text>Bros? Well, fuck it. I'll have my own crew soon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_2">
		<text>No, you ain't. The speech therapist said to punish you and razor-paint your cheeky face.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_3">
		<text>What? I'm gonna stab you in the face with a razor, you little punk.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_4">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_0">
		<text>Have mercy, don't kill me, I'll give you your share.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, that's a good place to start. I'll tell the Speech Therapist you said yes.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_2">
		<text>You sure you won't kill me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_3">
		<text>Live a while.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_10">
		<text>Not so fast, bitch, you don't owe that money to Logoped, you owe it to Skidan.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_11">
		<text>But you said it was a share in the joint.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_12">
		<text>I lied! You owe all of Skidan's loot and your life. Dead men don't sweat. And secrets don't come out...</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_0">
		<text>I've dealt with Shmyga.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_1">
		<text>Great, now no one can squeeze a share out of the joint. Here's a little something for your trouble.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_2">
		<text>Not bad, not bad.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_10">
		<text>You've got a nerve, you were told to cut, not to go!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_11">
		<text>I agree, I overdid it. But it was hard to resist.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_12">
		<text>Next time do as you're told, don't make a mess. What about the loot?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_13">
		<text>We don't know, Shmyga didn't have anything on him. And where the loot is, we'll never know.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_14">
		<text>Yes, you've done something wrong. Get out of my sight before I order you to get killed too.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_15">
		<text>Already gone.</text>
    </string>
		
	
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_0">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_1">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_2">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_3">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	


	<string id="my_dialogs_01">
		<text>Skidan, why do you have such an assortment? Vodka, food, armour, first-aid kits and shotguns?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_02">
		<text>Anything you want for your money. Heh-heh. The assortment is rich, you got that right. Everything a real stalker needs! Heh-heh. A naked rookie comes in and packs me upside down. If only I had the money. The best-selling item, of course, is vodka. Would you take a couple of bottles? It's fresh, just dropped off yesterday.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_03">
		<text>No, you don't understand. The assortment is lousy, that's what I'm saying. The shotguns and 12-gauge hunting cartridges. Any military store on the mainland would be richer. Where are the machine guns, pistols, machine guns, grenades? You're buying it up. Under the counter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_04">
		<text>You ever been in the trade, Sawan? Run a shop in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_05">
		<text>No, of course not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_06">
		<text>That's what I thought. And here's my advice to you, and it's free of charge: Never, you hear me, never set up shop in the Zone. Every snot-nosed greenie will tell you every day that your range sucks. And the prices are high. Every greenhorn knows how to do business in the Zone, only Skidan doesn't, huh?\nYou think you're the first one to ask about the range? Every single day. It's probably the only reason I'm so bald. They've been all over my head about it. At first I explained to everyone that I was sitting in front of the military, and any commission from the checkpoint would go to my bunker. And I had to do everything right here, in accordance with all the laws of the country. I've got it all registered as a hunting shop, combined with a grocery shop. License, health and inspection certificates. All business. I pay taxes every month, what do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_07">
		<text>Taxes? Holy shit. Bribes, maybe?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_08">
		<text>I pay bribes too, that's what I do. I suppose you thought I was doubling the price of everything and pocketing the profits for my stalker brother, too? You thought Skidan was a bloodsucker? You did, didn't you? I can barely make ends meet. My main commodity is information. And the shop... I'm good if I'm breaking even. There are months when it's a loss. Weapons I buy off stalkers for pennies, I take to the roadblock. By weight. They make it out as confiscation. And they're good - they fulfil their plan of confiscating unregistered firearms, they get stars on their shoulder straps, and extra leave. And it's not bad for me, that's why I take it for a penny, I only give it back for a little more. At least I have a good relationship with the soldiers, they don't put me under pressure. The deeper into the Zone, the farther away from the roadblocks, the wider the range. If you get to Bara, you'll have all manner of rifles and grenades, and bazookas and armour like no one here has ever seen. It's the ABCs, the basics. Now I'm not explaining it to everyone, I'm just saying fuck you!\nI'll say the same to you, Sawan. Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_dialogs_09">
		<text>Skidan, I'm sorry. I didn't know. Let's just forget about this conversation like it never happened.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="xolod_dialogs_01">
		<text>Smoke, you've been on a scientific expedition for years. What do you know about the Zone? What is it? Where did it come from? Why is the Zone growing? And how will it end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_02">
		<text>I wish I knew how it was going to end. By the way, ten years ago, I knew exactly how it was going to end. The impenetrable cordons. A belt of emptiness fifty kilometres wide. Scientists and soldiers, nobody else. A terrible ulcer on the body of the planet, blocked solidly in place.\nAnd everyone thought so, not just me. What speeches were made, what bills were introduced...! Now, you won't even remember how this steely determination suddenly turned into a mush.\nIt seems to have all started when the stalkers took the first Battery packs out of the Zone. Yeah, I think that's where it started. Especially when it was discovered what properties they had. The sores turned out to be not so much sores, and not even sores at all, but something like a treasure chest... And now nobody really knows what it is - whether it's a sores, a treasure chest, a hellish temptation, Pandora's Box, hell, the devil... They take advantage of it little by little.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_03">
		<text>Wait a minute. Haven't scientists learned anything about artefacts over the years?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_04">
		<text>Funnily enough, almost nothing. We've discovered many wonders. In some cases, we've even learned how to use these wonders to our advantage. A monkey presses a red button and gets a banana; a monkey presses a white button and gets an orange; but it doesn't know how to get bananas and oranges without buttons. And what the buttons have to do with bananas and oranges, she doesn't understand.\nTake, say, artefacts. We've learned how to use them. But we still haven't managed to reconstruct any artifacts, we don't understand how they work, and it doesn't look like we'll understand it all any time soon...\nI'm pretty sure that the vast majority of the time we're hammering nails with microscopes. And yet we do use something: "batteries", "bracelets", life-stimulating artifacts... various types of quasibiological masses which have revolutionized medicine...\nWe have new tranquilizers, new types of fertilizers, a revolution in agronomy... Let us call this group of objects useful. One could say that to a certain extent humanity has been enriched by them, though we should never forget that in our Euclidean world every stick has two ends.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_05">
		<text>Two ends? You mean the anomalies that kill? Or the Ejections?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_06">
		<text>No, that one makes more sense. Death. You don't have to go there. That's not what I mean. Every useful artefact has been more or less explained to us.  It's more complicated with another group of artifacts, more complicated precisely because we have no use for them, and their properties, according to our current understanding, are wildly inexplicable. In short, the artefacts in this group are of absolutely no use to current human practice, although from a purely scientific point of view they are of fundamental importance.\nThese are answers falling out of the sky to questions we do not yet know how to ask. I won't go into details, but the existence of these objects has at once swept aside a whole field of recently flourishing theories and given rise to entirely new ideas. And then there's a third group...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_07">
		<text>Artifacts with negative properties, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_08">
		<text>No, no, no. All of these should fall into either group one or two. I mean objects that we know nothing about or only by hearsay, that we've never held in our hands. What the stalkers snatched from under our noses, they sold or stashed away. Things they keep silent about. Legends and semi-legends: the Pendulum, for example. Or the Death-Lamp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xolod_dialogs_09">
		<text>Hmm... legends, then. Thank you, Smoke, for the detailed story. I won't say I've understood anything, but I'm looking at things in a new way now. I'm going to do a lot of thinking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_01">
		<text>Wolf, there's one question that's been bugging me. It's about stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_02">
		<text>What do you want to know, Savannah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_03">
		<text>Look, the military knows about the stalkers. They see you guys flitting around every day right in front of the roadblock. And I think they know about the other stalkers deep in the Zone, too. What's more, all the stalkers in the Zone go through military checkpoints, there are no other ways. The minefields and the worse ones around the perimeter of the Zone, there is no way in. Only through the roadblocks. I mean it looks as if the military are letting stalkers into the Zone on purpose. They are supposed to fight the stalkers and keep them out. One does not fit with the other. I'm confused.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_04">
		<text>Oh! That was quick of you, Sawan, to start asking the right questions. Other newbies take months to get to this point. You're right. The military knows about the stalkers and lets them in on purpose. That's right. They pretend, of course, that they struggle with this ugly phenomenon. But even you've realized after the second day that it's only a circus, and the soldiers aren't even trying to put a spoke in our wheel. And here's the big question: Why is that? And there's an answer. It's pretty simple. Only a stalker can find an artifact, see it, take it, and bring it into the human world.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_05">
		<text>What do you mean, only a stalker? What's there to see? You turned on the scanner-detector, came to the point where the arrow on the screen indicates, the artifact itself will jump into your hands. Not rocket science. You're not telling me, are you, Dog?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_06">
		<text>And here's the most interesting part of the Marlezonian ballet. In the early years after the Zone, there were no detectors or scanners. Stalkers simply saw artefacts as objects lying around. Or hovering above the ground. Or bouncing. Glowing. Warm. And stalkers would pick them up. They brought them to fence dealers, scientists, collectors, spies of different countries, the military. There are many who wish to get the gifts of the Zone. When a stalker picks up an artifact, it becomes visible to all the people, you understand? Stalkers are like guides, they manifest the artefact in our world, like pull them out of.... I don't know, from what. From another dimension, from another universe, from another time? Scientists have been struggling for years trying to figure it out, haven't figured a damn thing out.\nThe fact is, ordinary people don't see artifacts until they've been in the hands of stalkers. At least be equipped with scanners and detectors from head to toe - you will not see. A stalker just sees. He feels it. And no one but a stalker sees that the artifacts glow, doesn't feel that they are warm. Doesn't see how beautiful they are. To the rest of the people, they're black pieces of unknowable stuff. Cold. I've talked to a lot of ordinary people, none of them see the glow and beauty of the artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_07">
		<text>You're full of shit, Wolf! There's no such thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_08">
		<text>The Zone, brother. It's not the kind of miracle that happens. In short, no stalkers, no artifacts. Why do you think gangsters or mercenaries or warriors don't collect artifacts? They do not see them. They do not feel them. But 90% of people in the Zone are unable to find artifacts in principle. That's the arithmetic. Maybe even 99%, I don't know the exact numbers. Do you know why Skidan gives every newbie the same first assignment - to find an artifact? Now you know it's a test. Skidan's checking to see if you've got that stalker talent or if you're just out for a stroll. Most people don't pass the test. And you can't tell in advance who's gonna be a stalker and who isn't. It's something innate, I think. It's only when you find an artifact that you can tell.\nThe military and scientists at first tried to adapt robots to mine artefacts. They built little machines with scanners and detectors, gripping devices, lead containers, remote control, artificial intelligence, you name it. Japanese designs. Launched five, I think, of these robots at once. And all five of them were buried in anomalies for 24 hours without finding a single artifact. And they collected all kinds of rubbish in their lead bins - stones, iron. So much for artificial intelligence. That was the end of the robot experience. They spent a shitload of money on it! Sakharov, a scientist from Yantar, told me this story - he was the chief scientist in the project at the time.\nThen we decided to do military stalkers. They recruited volunteers among military contractors, and began to train them in the search for artefacts. Hired free stalkers as teachers. I was one of them. The pay was generous. But it was useless. It is good, if 1 out of 20 could find an artifact, I can consider myself lucky. You can't teach it. It's like eye colour, you're born with it. You're either a stalker or you're not. There's still a lot of military men working in the Zone, but not many of them. That's why the soldiers let everyone into the Zone, so that the Zone itself can identify the real stalkers. And when a stalker reveals himself, he won't be left without work and money. I think you understood that already. And rest assured, that both the military and the SBU are watching every true stalker closely. I think they have a dossier on you, marked as top secret. That's the way it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_dialogs_09">
		<text>Well, Wolf, you surprised me. I'd say you surprised me. I feel like a bit of a mutant.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
