<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_0">
		<text>I'm from Vitalik. He asked me to tell you to step up your surveillance of the movement of critters and bandits out of the Dark Vale. Here, these are special devices for remote surveillance. Keep them with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_1">
		<text>Roger that. What kind of device is it? How does it work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_2">
		<text>I don't know. He said just to pass it on. I passed it on. Apparently, he'll explain himself later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_3">
		<text>Is this another one of those fancy gadgets from the Debtors?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_4">
		<text>Maybe, I don't know. All right, take care.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_0">
		<text>I'm from Vitalik. He asked me to tell you to step up your surveillance of free stalkers' movements from Cordon. Here, these are special remote observation devices. Keep it with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_1">
		<text>Good. Is it like a biolocator?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_2">
		<text>I have no idea. He said to just hand it over. He said he'd explain later what it's for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_3">
		<text>I see. What a man! I wish he'd send me a better gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_4">
		<text>All right, see you later.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_0">
		<text>I'm from Vitalik. He asked me to tell you to intensify surveillance of the bandits' movements from Agroprom. Here, these are special remote-scanning and surveillance devices. Keep it with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_1">
		<text>Good. What kind of devices are they? How do you use them in public?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_2">
		<text>Fuck knows. He said just to pass it on. He'll probably explain what it's for and how it works.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_3">
		<text>I wish you'd get me some gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_4">
		<text>All right, take care.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_0">
		<text>I'm from Vitalik. He asked me to tell you to intensify surveillance of stalkers' movements from the bar. Here, these are special locking and non-contact surveillance devices. Keep it with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_1">
		<text>Good. What kind of gadgets are they? Like a biolocator?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_2">
		<text>He said just to pass it on. I don't know what it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_3">
		<text>All right, another Duty megadget.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_4">
		<text>All right, take care.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_0">
		<text>I'm from Vitalik. He asked me to tell you to step up your surveillance of mutant movements from the Swamp. Here, these are special remote mutant surveillance gadgets. Keep it with you at all times.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_1">
		<text>Good. A biolocator or something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_2">
		<text>He said just to pass it on. I don't know what it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_3">
		<text>All right, that's the kind of man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_4">
		<text>All right, have fun.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
		<text>Got a job for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
		<text>Anyway, here's the thing. Although Bar is neutral territory, Duty plays a key role here. Group Command has been tasked with reinforcing positions and ensuring everyone's safety. Naturally, everyone is working in their own direction.\nMine is radio engineering, REB to be exact. A huge number of tramps, diggers and stalkers of all stripes from all over the Zone come here to conduct various deals and negotiations. Various methods and channels of communication are used in the process. And bugging their potential rivals or victims is one of the favourite tricks of mercenaries and bandits. And other criminal elements. That's what we're fighting.\nA group of stalkers recently disappeared from the Bar. They just disappeared and that's it, as if they never existed. Very likely a provocation on the part of the gangsters. The situation has heated up. Stalkers question Duty's ability to provide protection and security at the Bar. We need to find out who exactly is behind these disappearances. And eliminate the threat.\nTo that end, I suggest you join my radio-electronic reconnaissance team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
		<text>This is bullshit. I don't know as much about electronic reconnaissance as I know about ballet. And I don't know anything about ballet. I can't tell a soldering iron from a switch. I'm willing to help, but how?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_22">
		<text>Not right now. I'll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_222">
		<text>Fuck that. That's not my line of work. Sorry, not me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
		<text>We'll teach you everything. We got radio operators here, they can teach a monkey how to use a scanner. And you're smarter than any monkey, so you can do it. Now go to the radio operators. Do a little training. Then you come back to me and I'll tell you what the plan is. They're down in the basement.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm from Markov. I want to learn electronic warfare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_1">
		<text>No problem. Just watch yourself. You'll have to go through gradual training.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_2">
		<text>Let's go, shall we?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_3">
		<text>I'll come back later. I'm not ready right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_4">
		<text>I'll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
		<text>I've been through the course. Took me an awful long time. It's about zero use. It's a scam. Learned a little less than nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
		<text>Here's a little compensation for your time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
		<text>Is this for my beer or something? You can't be serious. Now what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
		<text>Now we figure out the best way to do this. Hold on a minute.</text>
	</string>
	
    <string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
        <text>So, have you made up your mind?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
        <text>You've got to help me do electronic reconnaissance, making various measurements with a special apparatus - an oscilloscope.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
        <text>An osci... What? You guys are out of your minds. You got hit by an ejection, didn't you? That's crazy. Why don't we just shoot someone? Or bring back an artifact? I'm a fucking stalker.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
        <text>Shooting is not our style. That's what combat quads are for. We're the elite, intelligence and counterintelligence. We conduct electronic warfare on several fronts. One, we jam the frequencies of mercenaries and other criminals. Second, we protect our own communications channels. That's what modulation and encryption are for. You'll be working on the first one. Check out the old abandoned hangar at the south roadblock. Our battle-quad guys were combing it recently and came across a bunch of working radio equipment. Maybe it's being used by one of our enemies. Here's an oscilloscope. Run a frequency sweep of the equipment. Bring me the results. Go!</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
        <text>I don't think I've ever seen such fun with an oscilloscope!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
        <text>Ah? Why the long face?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
        <text>Waiting for me. Mercenaries. It was an ambush. Someone's leaking information to the other side, aren't you, Markov?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
        <text>You talk, but don't talk too loud. Watch your language. There are no traitors in Duty, rest assured. I'll pass the information about the ambush on to whoever's in charge, an investigation will be conducted and action taken. You and I will continue to work together. The data is to be processed and analysed, it will take some time.  There's a new assignment for you. We have intelligence that there are mercenary spies infiltrated into Clear Skies. Go to Vitalik - he's the local Clean Sky leader. He's loyal to Duty. You'll be working with him. Let's go do it!</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
        <text>I'm from Markov. The investigation leads back to your people.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
        <text>I'm aware of that. Already told Markov I'll give you all the cooperation you need. Here, have a walkie-talkie scanner tuned to our five channels. So here's the plan. We need to narrow down the search area. The Jackal's either in the southern unit that's in the junkyard. Or it's somewhere here on Bara.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
        <text>I don't know what to do. In a nutshell, tell me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
        <text>Go to the misty woods for starters. You'll work it out. Turn it on, send a message. The message, of course, is fake. See who bites. After that, to the highest tower in Bara. Radio's already set up properly. All you have to do is call in all five channels we use to talk.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_4">
        <text>Copy that.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_0">
        <text>Done. Take the radio. Now what?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_1">
        <text>Now we wait for the results. Markov and the radio guys are already up and running. And you have a new assignment.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_2">
        <text>More oscilloscope bullshit? Who do you think I am? I'm not some nerd. I'm a stalker!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_3">
        <text>Oscilloscope? What oscilloscope? What are you talking about? No, the other thing: you need to collect special wiretaps - like personal radio bugs. We'll need to expose a particular enemy agent once we figure out which of our units he's lurking in. And we'll know soon enough, trust me. Now go to the dolgov's dealer for radios and other necessities. He's upstairs, third floor. There's signs and arrows on the walls. You'll find it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_4">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
        <text>I'm from Vitalik. Give me the radio parts.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
        <text>Yeah, I know. I've already prepared everything you need. Here, take it and sign for it. Everything in the best condition. Go to Markov, he'll give you a soldering station.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
        <text>Uh-huh.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
        <text>I need a soldering station, the supply man said you had one.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
        <text>Here you go. You're gonna solder bugs, huh? My advice to you, don't reinvent the wheel. Set it at 93 and 186 and you'll be fine. I've soldered a thousand of these bugs with these settings, and they work like clockwork. You solder the bugs, report back to Vitalik. Give him the soldering station, too. Soon it'll be clear whether to look for rats at the junkyard or here at the bar. Vitalik will tell you, he's in direct contact with our decryptors.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
        <text>Copy that.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_0">
        <text>The bugs are ready. Here's the blowtorch. What now?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_1">
        <text>All right, great. We found out where the mole is.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_2">
        <text>È?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_3">
        <text>The junkyard. Among our people at the junkyard. Your job is to bug them, identify the mole and his connections. The mole will be taken by Duty's counter-intelligence service. He'll need to be interrogated, and they're good at that. Your job is to eliminate the people in charge of the mole. I think they're holed up in a dump somewhere. I don't know how many there are. If it gets too hot, ask Duty for help on the radio. Go be a hero!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_4">
        <text>Roger that.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
        <text>Done. Got the mole, took out his masters. They're bandits.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
        <text>Nice work. The mole, after interrogation, is put up against the wall. Told me a lot of interesting things before, but that's none of your concern. On behalf of Duty, I'd like to thank you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
        <text>How much is the gratitude worth in terms of money?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
        <text>All right, now. Here's your reward. Well done, my friend.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_4">
        <text>Well, call me if you need anything.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_0">
        <text>Tell me about the rules of the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_1">
        <text>We have six types of combat in the arena: Duel, Hunt, Bodyguard, Partner, Survival and Avenger. Which one would you like to talk more about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_21">
        <text>Dueling...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_22">
        <text>Hunting...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_23">
        <text>Bodyguard...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_24">
        <text>Partner...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_25">
        <text>Survival...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_26">
        <text>The vigilante...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_31">
        <text>In this fight, you go head-to-head with the enemy. You get your combat gear from me, and you run into the arena. The one who survives wins, and his opponent leaves the Arena in a body bag. With each new stage I will pick a stronger opponent for you. In the final fifth stage you fight for the title of arena master in the Duel class. And remember the door to the arena is energized before the end of the duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_32">
        <text>In this fight you go out alone against mutants. I allocate you enough equipment for a successful hunt. Your task is to get the radioactive meat, but to keep all of yours with you. With each new stage, I'll pick stronger monsters. In the final fifth stage, you compete for the title of arena master in the Hunt class. The door to the arena is energised until the fight is over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_33">
        <text>In this fight, your job is to protect your partner who is unarmed. Grab your gun and armour and you're on your way. To win, you must kill all attackers, but the defender must survive. If the defender is as dead as the attackers, you don't get the reward and you're unlikely to continue fighting in this mode. With each new stage the attackers get stronger and more numerous. The final stage 5 sees you fighting to become the arena master of the 'bodyguard' class. The door to the arena is electrified until the end of the match.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_34">
        <text>In this fight your task, together with your partner, is to destroy your opponent's poison. Put your gun in your hands and get to the fight. To win, you must ensure that none of your opponent's squad survives. Your partner, on the contrary, must stay alive, if he dies, you will not receive a reward for the battle and battle in this form can not continue. With each new stage the enemy squad will be stronger and more numerous. In the final fifth stage you fight for the title of arena master in the class Partner. Finally, the door to the arena is energized until the fight is over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_35">
        <text>In this fight you go out alone against mutants. I allocate you minimal equipment. Your task is to survive for a certain amount of time. You can, of course, shoot the mutants, but it's unlikely you'll have enough ammo for all of them, and you'll only attract them that way. With each new stage, I'll pick stronger monsters. In the final fifth stage, you compete to be crowned arena master in the Survival class. The door to the arena is energized until the fight is over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_36">
        <text>In this fight it's your job to single-handedly destroy your opponent's reveries. Weapons and ammunition are plentiful. To win, it's imperative that none of your opponent's squad survives. With each new stage the enemy squad will become stronger and more numerous. In the final fifth stage you compete to become the arena master in the Avenger class. Door under electric shock until the end of the duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_41">
        <text>Interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_42">
        <text>That's funny.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_43">
        <text>Who comes up with this crap?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_44">
        <text>No way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_45">
        <text>That's funny.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_46">
        <text>It's educational.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_0">
        <text>You got it? Well done! Turn in all your gear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_1">
        <text>Here, it's all there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_21">
        <text>Your personal equipment's in the safe in the hallway, so you can have it. You'll get your reward for winning the arena in the lodge upstairs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_22">
        <text>Your gear's in the safe, as usual.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_31">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_32">
        <text>Got it, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_0">
        <text>I want my reward for the fight in the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_100">
        <text>Whatever I owe you, I already gave it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_111">
        <text>Here's the bounty for the Vigilante Stage 1 fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_112">
        <text>Here's the bounty for the Avenger bout, phase 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_113">
        <text>Here's the bounty for the Avenger bout, phase 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_114">
        <text>Here's the Avenger bout prize, phase 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_115">
        <text>Here's the bout award for Avenger stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_121">
        <text>Here's the bout award for Bodyguard stage 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_122">
        <text>Here's the reward for fighting Bodyguard stage 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_123">
        <text>Here's the reward for fighting Bodyguard stage 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_124">
        <text>This is award for Bodyguard stage 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_125">
        <text>Here is the reward for the fight Bodyguard stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_131">
        <text>Here is the bout award for Duel stage 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_132">
        <text>Here is the Duel Battle Award Stage 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_133">
        <text>Here is the Duel Battle Award Stage 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_134">
        <text>Here's the Duel Battle Award Stage 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_135">
        <text>Here is the Duel Battle Award Stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_141">
        <text>Here's the battle award for Duel stage 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_142">
        <text>Here's the battle award for Duel stage 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_143">
        <text>Here's the battle medal for Duel stage 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_144">
        <text>Here's the battle award for Dueling partner stage 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_145">
        <text>Here's the battle medal for the Partner stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_151">
        <text>Here's the battle medal for Hunt Phase 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_152">
        <text>Here's the battle medal for Hunt phase 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_153">
        <text>Here's the battle medal for Hunt phase 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_154">
        <text>Here's the bounty of battle Hunt phase 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_155">
        <text>Here's the battle Hunt award stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_161">
        <text>Here's the battle award Survival stage 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_162">
        <text>Here's the combat Survival Award Stage 2.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_163">
        <text>Here's the combat Survival Award Stage 3.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_164">
        <text>Here's the Survival Fighting Award Stage 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_165">
        <text>Here's the Survival Fighting Award for stage 5.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_2">
        <text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>Do you fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>For real, dawg.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>You're a dick, come back when you're really ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I wanna be in the arena too, would you like to join me in the bodyguard fight?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>I'm Vasya Styr of the Palenogo Brigade. I've decided to make a quick buck in the arena, of course, but the money is good Speech therapist promises for the guards. I don't have any armor, but I'll be a fly behind you, so these clowns can't hit me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>Not if you don't piss me off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>That's fine with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>All right. I'll see you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>You fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>I'm always here in case you change your mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I'd like to fight in the arena too, would you like to join me in the Bodyguard fight?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>Peter the Swampy, from the swamps you see, I used to be a clean sky warrior, now I moonlight as a bodyguard in the arena. I've got good armor and a helmet, but it's a bit restrictive, so I'd like you to keep a good eye on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>I don't mind if you don't mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>Yeah, I'm fine with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, let me think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>I'll see you at the arena. See you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>You fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>The monolith witnesses, yes!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>I'm here all the time, if not in prayer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I would like to join the arena as well, if you wish to join me in the Bodyguard fight?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>Innocent the Frozen. Former follower of the doctrine of the great Monolith. Now here in the arena, I fight the Bodyguard. My armor is powerful, praise be to the Monolith, but cumbersome, so be sure to look around and wait for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>I don't mind, as long as it's Monolith's will.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>That's fine with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>That's good. Monolith be with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_0">
        <text>What did you think of the last fight in the arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_100">
        <text>We haven't fought yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_111">
        <text>That's a hell of a way to take 'em down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_112">
        <text>All right, but I almost caught an olive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_113">
        <text>Listen, buddy, if this keeps up, you and me are gonna be wearing Versace trainers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_114">
        <text>You know, I almost lost it, you watch out for these pretzels. You're kind of retarded.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_115">
        <text>Hey, man, that's some good shit, man. Now I got money to spare.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_121">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_122">
        <text>Yeah, I think it went all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_123">
        <text>Not bad, not bad a couple more times, enough for a house in the country.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_124">
        <text>Oh her, I was on the verge of death, thank God it was alright.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_125">
        <text>That's nice of you, now I've made some good money, I don't have to take that risk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_131">
        <text>It's all right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_132">
        <text>That's great, it's going really well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_133">
        <text>It's going great, praise the Monolith.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_134">
        <text>It's all right, it's just a little bit of armour, that's all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_135">
        <text>It's great, I'm alive and well and my armour's fine, praise the Monolith.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_2">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>You fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>Yeah, bro.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>Anyway, I'm here if you need me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I'm looking to get in an arena fight, would you like to join me in a fight, partner?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>Gena Lopata of the Sopatogo Brigade. I like to, you know, fight with my mate. My gear's weak, but I've got my own gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>I'll cut someone up right now, no problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>Yeah, that's fine with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>See you later. See you at the slaughterhouse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>You fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>I see, I'll wait in case you change your mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I'm looking to get into the arena, would you like to join me in a battle partner?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>Kolya Lucky of the freelance stalkers. I earn my bread fighting with a partner. The jacket's not great, but it's not a bad weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>I don't mind if you don't mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>Yeah, I'm cool with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>All right, then. See you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_0">
        <text>You fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes, I am.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_10">
        <text>Come back later if you change your mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_21">
        <text>Talk about your specialty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_22">
        <text>I seek to fight in the arena, would you care to join me in battle, partner?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_31">
        <text>Mitya Kolovorot, ex-military, now deserter and freelancer. Wouldn't mind getting into a fight with a proper partner. Armor's a lightweight army-issue, but the weapon's a simple pistol.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_32">
        <text>I'm in, if that's all right with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_41">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_421">
        <text>Yeah, that's fine with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_422">
        <text>No, wait, I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_5">
        <text>All right. I'll meet you at the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_6">
        <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_0">
        <text>What did you think of the last fight in the Arena?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_100">
        <text>We haven't fought yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_111">
        <text>Great, just not enough. I'm not warmed up at all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_112">
        <text>That's awesome! All I did was fire my cannon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_113">
        <text>Bro, we really blew them up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_114">
        <text>Man, that was rough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_115">
        <text>Bro, you and me, we're two Terminators.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_121">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_122">
        <text>All right, we're good with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_123">
        <text>Great, we beat them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_124">
        <text>Not bad, but it doesn't hurt to keep an eye on the back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_125">
        <text>That's it, we're the champions! Now all the women are ours, all we have to do is find them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_131">
        <text>Not bad, you're moving well, you're covering well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_132">
        <text>Better and better, we'll definitely work together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_133">
        <text>All right! You and me, we're like the Special Forces, we got 'em all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_134">
        <text>It was tough, but we got the bad guys down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_135">
        <text>All right, we're brother champions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_2">
        <text>I got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_0">
        <text>I need some medical attention.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_1">
        <text>No problem, let me see...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_11">
        <text>[furthermore...]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_2">
        <text>You're driving, you're healthy!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_stard_dialog_barman_text">
        <text>Hey, buddy, happy humpbacking. What are you up to?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_0">
        <text>I want to sign up for a fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_1">
        <text>What kind of fight should I sign you up for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_10">
        <text>Suit yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_21">
        <text>I want to sign up for Duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_22">
        <text>I want to sign up for Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_23">
        <text>I want to sign up for Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_24">
        <text>I want to sign up for a fight - Partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_25">
        <text>I want to sign up for Survival.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_26">
        <text>I want to sign up for the fight - Avenger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_27">
        <text>No, I think I'm going to wait a little longer to die.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_311">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage one, Duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_312">
        <text>I'm putting you down for stage two duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_313">
        <text>I'm putting you down for stage three duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_314">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage four, duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_315">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage five, duel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_321">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage one, the Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_322">
        <text>Right, I'm putting you down for stage two, the Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_323">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage three, the Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_324">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage four, the Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_325">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage five, the Hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_331">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage one, Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_332">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage two, Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_333">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage three, Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_334">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage four, Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_335">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage five, Bodyguard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_337">
        <text>For this fight, you need a partner to guard. Make a deal with one of the stalkers. They're usually in the tunnel near the fans.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_338">
        <text>I told you before, make a deal with a stalker to be in the fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_339">
        <text>Unfortunately, your client is dead, and no one else wants to mess with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_341">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you on stage one, partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_342">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage two, Partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_343">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage three, partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_344">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage four, partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_345">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage five, partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_347">
        <text>You need a partner for this fight. Make a deal with one of the stalkers. They're usually in the tunnel near the fans.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_348">
        <text>I told you, make a deal with a stalker to be in the fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_349">
        <text>Unfortunately, your partner is dead, and no one else wants to mess with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_351">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage one Survival.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_352">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage two Survival.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_353">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage three Survival.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_354">
        <text>Right, I'm putting you down for Survival Fighting Phase 4.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_355">
        <text>Right, I'm putting you down for Survival Fighting Phase Five.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_361">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage one, Vigilante fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_362">
        <text>All right, I'm putting you down for stage two, Vigilante fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_363">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage three, Vigilante fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_364">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage four, Vigilante.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_365">
        <text>Okay, I'm putting you down for stage five, Vigilante.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_4">
        <text>You got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_5">
        <text>Personal effects in the safe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_6">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_7">
        <text>Here's your equipment for the fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_811">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_812">
        <text>Yep. [Chuckles]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_813">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_814">
        <text>Mm-hmm.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_815">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_821">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_822">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_823">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_824">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_825">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_831">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_832">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_833">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_834">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_835">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_841">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_842">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_843">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_844">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_845">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_851">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_852">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_853">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_854">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_855">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_861">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_862">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_863">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_864">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_865">
        <text>Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_9">
        <text>Good luck!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_0">
        <text>Is the arena working?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_1">
        <text>Yes, and what's more, we've expanded. And there are now several types of fights in the Arena, five stages each.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_2">
        <text>Great, I'd love to get into the fights.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_3">
        <text>No problem, you can get the details and rules from my assistant Stoner. He's downstairs at the entrance to the arena. You can also get the equipment you need to stage your fights from him. You'll get rewards for the fights you win from me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_4">
        <text>I see, so we'll meet again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_need_health_care_111">
        <text>There, that's good. You'll live.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!------------------------------------------------------------------------>
	<!--------------------------- ÑÞÆÅÒÍÛÅ ÄÈÀËÎÃÈ ÁÀÐÀ ---------------------->
	<!------------------------------------------------------------------------>
	
	<!------------>
	<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_0">
        <text>Whew, that was close! Are you in charge here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_1">
        <text>That's quite a blowout today, I don't like the sound of that.\nI'm Malandrinus. I run this place. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm Savannah. My partner is Borland.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_3">
        <text>I recognize Borland, I know him. All right, I get it. Skidan told me you'd show up. Now settle in, get yourselves together. We'll talk to you after this is over. Got a case for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_4">
        <text>I'm gonna take a nap. About 600 minutes.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_0">
        <text>In the X5 lab below Kordon, we found documents. It's all fancy, graphs, formulas, blueprints. You can't read it without half a bottle. Skidan said to give them to you. Not for free, of course.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_1">
        <text>Show me what you got.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_111">
        <text>Document One.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_112">
        <text>Document-2.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_113">
        <text>Document three.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_2">
        <text>I'll look through them at my leisure. If there's anything useful in them, I'll let you know. I almost forgot, here's to you for your hard work.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_3">
        <text>That's all there is.</text>
    </string>


	
	<!------------>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_0">
        <text>So, what's the case for us?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_1">
        <text>Skidan asked me to help you find the Pendulum artifact. Relax, don't shush me, everyone here knows about it. A lot of people are looking for it, too. What do you think? This is the Zone, rumors and gossip travel at the speed of light. Especially since the reward for finding him is unbelievably generous. More than generous. People are at each other's throats. To the point: just the other day I was lucky enough to get some unusual information about this case. Interested?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_2">
        <text>Go on.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_3">
        <text>An anonymous but very wealthy artifact collector has announced an incredible reward for whoever finds the Pendulum artifact. I'm gonna write the numbers on a napkin here. Surprised? Skeedan told you a different number, didn't he? The old fox won't shut up. He's trying to get his hooks into everybody. He doesn't understand that you can't keep a secret around here. The truth will come out. Well, God be his judge. Returning to our case: it is known that a private military company "Spectrum" has organized an expedition in search of this artifact, but they are unable to find it. Some stalkers claim that the monoliths are still guarding this artifact, and that it is stored somewhere in the dungeons of the Zone. In one of the underground laboratories. We don't know which one. Everyone was blown away by the amount of money that was declared for its discovery. Bandits, mercenaries, free stalkers, loners roam the dungeons, climb into the jelly, dying in anomalies just to find the "Pendulum". It's a hell of a lot of people already dead. I even counted at first, but then I gave up. Every day someone dies looking for that Pendulum.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_4">
        <text>Spectrum, huh? I crossed paths with them at the junkyard. They were aggressive. Had to reprimand them. Get to the point. Do you know where to find the artifact?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_5">
        <text>I don't know yet, but I will any day now. I've got a wide network of scouts, lots of my best stalkers and diggers working for me, pulling in scraps of information. And I collect it all and analyse it. And soon I'll know for sure.\nSo, Savannah, can I trust you? Are you and Borland on board? I need you to bring the artifact to me. Not to Skidan, to me. Is that clear? And the payment will be far, far more than the old fox from Cordon promised you. Let's say 10 times that.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_6">
        <text>We promised Skidanu, you understand. But in light of new information on the price of..... I need to consult with Borland. I can't decide this on my own.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_7">
        <text>All right, I'll give you a couple of days to think about it. Just don't take too long. I've got others in mind. The only reason I'm suggesting this to you first is because I've known Borland for years. And since you're with him, you must be reliable, too. And Skidan speaks highly of you. Which is extremely rare. I don't know what you did to him. Anyway, think about it, make up your mind. You got two days, that's all.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_8">
        <text>I'll see you later.</text>
    </string>
	
    <!------------>
	
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_0">
        <text>Oh, you're awake. You're a pillow-maker, I envy you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_1">
        <text>How are you? Are your gills still moving? I thought we were dead. But look - we survived. Now we have an important matter to decide, Malandrinus wants us to hurry up.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_2">
        <text>I don't feel good yet. I'm still recovering from the poisoning. I can't sleep, I close my eyes and nothing. No sleep. What does Malandrinus want from us?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_3">
        <text>Malandrinus is willing to give us information on the possible location of the Pendulum artifact. But we'll have to bring that artifact to Malandrinus, not to Sidor. The payment is ten times higher. What do you think, do we agree?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_4">
        <text>It's all anyone in the Bar is talking about. They're saying there's people prowling all over the Zone. A lot of stalkers are dead already. Some got shot by bandits, some burned up in an anomaly. And some just disappeared without a trace. They're also whispering about some kind of Spectrum.\nI've had enough adventure, Savannah, I've had enough of it. And I don't like this whole 10x award thing. It's not going to end well, I can feel it in my spine. Malandrinus is willing to outbid Sidor, that never happened. It's a very fucked-up situation, you know? No, it's not for me. Not for me, Savannah. No hard feelings. I'm used to living. I'm gonna get my shit together and go back to the mainland. I shouldn't have come back here. I've made up my mind, and I'm sorry, brother. And I advise you to get your claws out of the Zone. To hell with him, with the pendulum.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_5">
        <text>So you're not with me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_6">
        <text>No, no, no - don't even talk me into it. Malandrinus is a bug. Why do you think he chose you? Because he doesn't care who he sends to his death to test his hunches. He doesn't know where the artifact is. If he did, he'd have that pendulum in his safe by now. Did he tell you that you're a special and exceptional stalker, and even Sidor praised you? He did? And you fell for it? He says that to every stalker. He does not even change the text.\nNo, it's all without me. Sorry about that.\nI'll give the armor and the gun back to Skidan myself, don't worry.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_7">
        <text>I'm gonna try my luck, though. So long, friend.</text>
    </string>
	
   <!------------>	
   
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_0">
        <text>Here I am.</text>
    </string> 
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_1">
        <text>What do you think?</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_2">
        <text>I'm willing to cooperate on your terms.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_3">
        <text>Great, where's your buddy? Boorland.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_4">
        <text>He decided not to get involved. He's in poor health. He's going to the hospital on the mainland. Or a sanitarium.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_5">
        <text>That's all right, more for you. All right. The Dutyovs caught one of Logoped's henchmen at their base, the boss of the bandits at Cordon, you must have crossed paths with him. Now your task is to go and talk to the Duty's leader Captain Ivantsov. They got some information out of this gangster at the interrogation, before slapping the creep.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_6">
        <text>Is that it? Should I just go and talk to him?</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_7">
        <text>Yeah, that's all for now. You do that. I need to go through my channels and check your files.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_8">
        <text>Wouldn't it have been easier for you to ask Captain Ivantsov yourself? He'd be more willing to tell you. I don't even know him.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_9">
        <text>How come you're so smart? If I tell you to go, it's the right thing to do. I got up and went. Enthusiastic. Come on, get a move on.</text>
    </string>  
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_10">
        <text>All right, I'm off.</text>
    </string>  


   <!------------>	
   
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_0">
        <text>Good day to you! Malandrinus sent me. He asked me to ask you something.</text>
    </string> 
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_1">
        <text>So that's what you are, Northern... the one who started this whole mess. I know what Malandrinus is interested in. I'll tell you what we got out of that goon, no problem. You're just gonna have to do some work for it. You in?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_2">
        <text>I don't have a choice.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_3">
        <text>In a nutshell, underneath the Rostock factory where we are now, there's an underground complex - a secret X14 laboratory. From there, an underground railroad leads directly to the closed city of Kurchatov. I do not know anyone who returned from this Kurchatov alive. There are ominous rumors about this town, stalkers call it "Dead City". What interest gangsters have in Kurchatov we still do not understand, why they scouted the way there - it is not clear. The prisoner did not have time to tell us. He turned out to be weak and died under interrogation. These dungeons are entered through a door with a code lock, in the basement of our base. That's where we grabbed the bandit. Now we're watching that door around the clock... just in case. The three Quad units we sent out to scout didn't come back. We don't know what's in there. The key to the door has been lost, my fighter who had the key is missing without a trace. Unfortunately. Or luckily. Death in these catacombs, death to everyone.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_4">
        <text>That's enlightening. What do I owe you for this information?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_5">
        <text>It's a piece of cake! I need you to watch the north roadblock with my boys. Intelligence says there's a mutant breeding ground in the Wildlands. And they're gonna come after the Bar. It's likely to happen. You do 24 hours and you're free to go.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_6">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_7">
        <text>I'll let you know when your shift starts. Once every 24 hours, we change fighters at the roadblock, 6:00 p.m. usually. Be ready. Check your ammo. Don't go too far from Bara.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_8">
        <text>You got it.</text>
    </string>
	
	
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_dialog_0">
        <text>Hi. Listen up. You're going to stand here for 24 hours with my men. We're expecting a raid from the Wildlands. Unauthorized abandonment of your post is considered desertion and punishable by wartime law. Understood?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_dialog_1">
        <text>Roger that. I'm on it.</text>
    </string>
	
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, hero, our boys got you a little bit. You passed out a little, but now you're as green as a cucumber! Just as green!</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_1">
        <text>A little, huh?! Still got that ringing in my head and my left eye twitching.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_2">
        <text>Don't be mad, man. The main thing is that you're alive. You've done your duty. You're free to go.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_3">
        <text>I'm going.</text>
    </string>
	

 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_0">
        <text>Give me some water. My throat's dry and my head's ringing.</text>
    </string>	
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_1">
        <text>You all right?! Saw them drag you in here. Thought I'd run out of Savannah. You're as tough as a pseudo-dog. So, tell me what you learned from Captain Ivantsov.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_2">
        <text>It's a bit rough, it's not the first time. Anyway, he says that there are underground catacombs under Bar. Some kind of laboratory. It's locked with a code door. You've heard of Kurchatov?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_3">
        <text>Hmm... Interesting coincidence. I've been doing some digging lately. I recently sent a group of stalkers there on a reconnaissance mission. They went through the Army Depot and haven't been in touch for a week. Got killed somewhere along the way, I guess. And they were experienced stalkers, in good armor and with excellent weapons. So there's no way to get to Kurchatov from above. I think it would be safer for you to go to the town through the dungeons.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_4">
        <text>Captain Ivantsov said that three of Duty's quads died without a trace in those dungeons. And you're sending me alone. To certain death, huh? He said this town is dead. No one's ever come back from there.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_5">
        <text>Are you a stalker or something? You fall for Captain Ivantsov's lies and scares? You might be the only one who can get through. You have a chance, unlike everyone else. Everyone else has gone in blind, but you'll follow the map. I have a map with underground passages to Kurchatov, old Soviet ones. There were a few pieces missing - the mice ate just the place where the descents under the ground were marked near the Rostock factory. According to Captain Ivantsov, these underground catacombs may connect Bar with Kurchatov. And the entrance at the Dutya base. Luck! I'll give you the maps, you won't have to wander around. And according to my information, the artefact is in this underground laboratory, right at the exit to Kurchatov.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_6">
        <text>Captain Ivantsov said the passageway is locked with a code lock. And they lost the key.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_7">
        <text>Captain Ivantsov lost something. Heh. You're as naive as a Chukchi boy. He's lying. Doesn't want you in the lab. But I have some thoughts...</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_8">
        <text>Don't keep me in suspense.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_9">
        <text>We've got an acid swamp not far from here, beyond the misty woods, with a crazy man living in a cabin. I don't know who he is or where he's from. I don't much care either. People say that he used to work in the DISCUSSION laboratories, conducting experiments on people. That's the kind of work they say made him go off the rails. I do not believe this, of course. But you should check it out. Go to him, see if he knows how to get into the underground lab under the Bar.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_10">
        <text>All right, I will.</text>
    </string>
	

 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_0">
        <text>Greetings, kind friend. Haven't seen you in a while. Must be business, work... How's the wife?</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_1">
        <text>What?!</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_2">
        <text>Now, stop, Senka, don't mess with my head!</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_3">
        <text>Uncle, I'm here on business. I need the keys to the lab. Can you do me a favor?</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_4">
        <text>Shh... Quiet, it's always winter out there. Lights out. I can give you the code key. I bet you can find out about the hospital. The hospital's in Limansk. Not a word to anyone.</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_5">
        <text>Watch this, watch this. One, one. Concentrate. The key to the front door. It's a code. From the lab door. Where is it?</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_6">
        <text>Ha-ha, pencil, sharpener, swamp artifact! Swap. Exchange is possible, yes. Paid for with government funds. I swear. Quickly, quickly! I hear a voice, I hear a voice.</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_7">
        <text>Pfft... what else?</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_8">
        <text>Artifact! Artifacts!!! Everything is merging, I can't concentrate. It's like a dream. We're not dreaming, are we? I'm awake!!!!!</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_9">
        <text>No, we're not. You want the artifacts? I'll trade you for the key.</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_10">
        <text>Yeah... no, yeah, yeah. I'll trade. And the key is gold! All of earth's kind come from it. I am the original foundation of the world. Shh! It's a great mystery. We're being watched, they're watching me.... always watching...</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_11">
        <text>Eh, man... all right, you're a mess. So you want the artifacts? I'm just gonna go pick some up in your swamp. After that, you give me the key. Yes? Or I'll get it myself.</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_12">
        <text>Yeah, yeah. Swap... Swap... Cloud... Window...</text>
    </string>
	 	<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_13">
        <text>Wait here.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello again.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_1">
        <text>Why are you covered in mud? Ugh... and stinky.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_2">
        <text>But-but-but I bathed in the swamp. The one by crazy grandpa's house, God rest him.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_3">
        <text>What "eulogy"? Did you kill him or something?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_4">
        <text>I didn't do it on purpose. He's a mess. He's really fucked up. He was talking nonsense. He was being aggressive. Whatever. Anyway, I got the key to that door. Why'd you call me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_5">
        <text>If you have the key, it means you're about to go to the underground lab. What or who's waiting for you there, I don't know. I have a vested interest in you surviving and getting back here with the artifact, so I'm giving you a gun and a bulletproof vest. Free of charge. Just don't run off and sell them! They're rare... very, yes. If they turn up on the dealers, I'll be the first to know, and you'll have to answer for it. You got it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_6">
        <text>I'm not stupid. I'm off.</text>
    </string>
	
	
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_0">
        <text>Hi!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_1">
        <text>You from Sipy?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_2">
        <text>Seamy?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_3">
        <text>All right, forget it. There's a guy I'm waiting for. Maybe you've heard of him?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_4">
        <text>No, I haven't. Who are you, and what are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_5">
        <text>Who's asking? Identify yourself.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_6">
        <text>I'm Sawan. Walking by, I see people. Kind faces, I guess. I thought I'd ask them who they are. Maybe I'll get a job.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_7">
        <text>It's not an employment office. Go to Malandrinus, he's always happy to give you a job.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_8">
        <text>Thanks, I've already seen Malandrinus. I see you're not in the mood to talk.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_9">
        <text>You've got a lot on your mind. Clear skies. We're the last survivors of this group. You've heard of it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_10">
        <text>I've heard of it, but not specifically.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_11">
        <text>You new here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_12">
        <text>What do you think?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_13">
        <text>You're all right. Anyway, there was this group out on the Everglades. We did all sorts of things. Mostly our scientists studied artifacts, and we secured the whole event. We were all on the job until the devil made us go to Chernobyl. It's a long story, maybe I'll write a book about it someday, you can read it.\nWell, that's where the super-blowout hit us. Most people didn't expect that and predictably gave up right on the spot. I had enough sense to hide in some basement. After I got out, I looked - only corpses.  Well, I gathered those of ours who had also hidden and survived, and returned to the bar. That is the whole story. We're living from bread to water here. Duty hires us to guard different places. Nothing to talk about.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_14">
        <text>What are you waiting for? Easter? Why aren't you going to the bar?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_15">
        <text>It's just a meeting place over here. All the Chernobyl survivors are coming here. We're thinking of going through our old haunts. The ones where Lebedev and Suslov were hiding artifacts. They were examining the artefacts, and then returning them to the Zone. I don't know why they did it. That's where we're getting ready to do the march. Then we'll sell the artifacts, split the profits and go to the mainland. We've had enough of the Zone. Sorry, I'm not inviting you along, this is a Pure Sky affair only.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_16">
        <text>So you're looking for this artifact, too - the Pendulum?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_17">
        <text>Of course I am. Well, think about it, that kind of money, why not give it a try. Our ammunition and weapons are excellent, our armour's some of the best, homemade. We got scanners. Training also allows - not the first year in the Zone, we've found dozens, if not hundreds of artifacts. We're just waiting for Sieply, so if you happen to run into him, tell him we've been waiting for him. He went on a reconnaissance mission and fell off the radar. I don't like it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_18">
        <text>If I see him, I'll tell him. Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_19">
        <text>And don't cough.</text>
    </string>


	
	
</string_table>
