<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="wiz_mercs_base_key_name">
		<text>Old key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_mercs_base_key_descr">
		<text>Old key with inverted number 08803.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_merc_leader_base_key_name">
		<text>Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_merc_leader_base_key_descr">
		<text>The key to the mercenary group leader's room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radreazer_obrazec_name">
		<text>Flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radreazer_obrazec_descr">
		<text>A well sealed flask. There's a radioactivity mark on the casing! Got to be careful with this one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_millitary_maps">
		<text>Military maps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_millitary_maps_desc">
		<text>Military maps from a fallen MI-24 helicopter. The map has lots of markings: camps, outposts, bases and more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_notes_bizon_name">
		<text>Bison's note.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_notes_bizon_descr">
		<text>And everything started out so well, the guys were happy, everyone was planning what they were going to do when it was all over... Bitch... If I'd known how this whole thing was gonna end, I wouldn't have talked the guys into it, but now what? Now it's too late. Cutter, Raven, Greek, Brown: Rest in peace... Sorry guys, I meant well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_sokola_name">
		<text>Falcon's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_sokola_descr">
		<text>Among the various files, photos and notes, the entry marked IMPORTANT stands out the most:\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]No, I thought it would be farton! But I've already lost a lot, so it's karma...\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140,140]Agreed to meet the Huntsman near the abandoned church, now I just have to wait for him and get the supplies\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140,140]Bastard... Shot me in the back! Well, we'll see about that... The recording cuts out next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_pda_rezaka_name">
		<text>Cutter's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_pda_rezaka_descr">
		<text>Most of the data is locked, but you can still access the diary.
Last entry:\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Bison and the boys, still managed to find the entrance to the catacombs, and through them, we will be in place in less than five hours, just do not run into any creature ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_pda_bandita_name">
		<text>Bandit Leader's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_pda_bandita_descr">
		<text>The bulk of the data is of no value, but there is a small note that was made not too long ago.\
Note:\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Punk got busted, and they were lucky that he did not have time to do anything, the guys quickly undressed him, and put the stuff in the pot, I need at leisure to look at what he had there was valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_locked_flashcard_name">
		<text>Flash drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_locked_flashcard_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Blocked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="el_sp_flashcard_name">
		<text>Flash Card</text>
	</string>
	<string id="el_sp_flashcard_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]On the flash map, there are only coordinates to exit the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="el_pda_sos_name">
		<text>Nekrasov's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="el_pda_sos_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,193,66,66]-%c[0,193,66,66]Note #1: Looks like a group of mercenaries looking for an entrance to the complex, wonder what they needed there? We should send Lefty there, for a reconnaissance.\n%c[0,193,66,66]-%c[0,193,66,66]Note № 2: Lefty, said that the complex is empty, except for mutants and a couple of zombified.\n%c[0,193,66,66]-%c[0,193,66,66]Note #3: Mercenaries have found the entrance to the lab, but they appear to be followed by another recruit, need to be careful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ba1_pda_felix_pda">
		<text>Felix's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ba1_pda_felix_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]The PDA has several notes and a map of the area marked "Waste Land". In the notes, the stalker, mentions the Prometheus project, and that he went to the lab specifically for its mentions\documents. Further notes are cut off, but there is one more note not written: I should have dared to come here! I knew it would end... The mercenaries caught up with me, not enough ammunition.... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_case_starogo_name">
		<text>Sealed container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_case_starogo_descr">
		<text>Container marked "Y-023" - Closed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_old_writes_name">
		<text>"Old manuscript."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wiz_old_writes_descr">
		<text>Many of the entries are no longer readable, they have simply rotted away. Already in the middle of the manuscript there are surviving records of the Old Man:\n\
\n%c[0,153,255,255]"Record dated 29.08.2017"\n%c[0,140,140,140,140]These "greens" don't understand anything! They just get their hands on death and then complain that the Zone is punishing them... Fools! The main thing is that I managed to seal the entrance to the complex - there is nothing for them to do there! Key of the complex hid in the territory of the descent into the complex.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]"Record dated 06.09.2017"\n%c[0,140,140,140,140]A group of stalkers asked me to let them into the abandoned catacombs. At first I refused, but then I realized I couldn't talk them out of it anyway. I let the stalkers in and sealed the entrance, so now no one else can get into the catacombs through it, but the trouble is that there's another descent in the Old ATP.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_merc_lead_notebook_name">
		<text>The Mercenaries' Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_merc_lead_notebook_desc">
		<text>Among the mass of spam in the notebook's mailbox is a single message marked as important:\
\n%c[0,153,255,255]Message contents:%c[0,140,140,140]"Set up camp on a former military base - everyone involved will come to you. Don't wait for Griff: he'll be in the Dark Vale with his men, he has his own task. 
As soon as you find the artifact, do not rush to leave, first notice the traces. The Neutral Leader is expendable, he has completed his task. "\nJackal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_grek_pda_name">
		<text>Greek's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_grek_pda_desc">
		<text>%c[0,153,255,255]Last entry:%c[0,140,140,140]So much effort and all for nothing... Too bad for the guys, they believed that this shitty artifact would be a golden ticket to a prosperous existence, alas it wasn't. I'm already a dead man, and Bison, he went to that cabin in the swamp. He heard a couple of shots later, and that was it... Oh, and it all started out so well...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_dead_merc_pda_name">
		<text>Beast's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dl_dead_merc_pda_desc">
		<text>There's only one message in the PDA:\
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Your target is a veteran stalker, nicknamed Bison. He and a group of nonstrals were seen in the vicinity of Dead Lake. Your task: Eliminate the stalker and the group, and take from them all the media. I will mark the location of the meeting later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_nazar_name">
		<text>Nazar's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_nazar_descr">
		<text>Nazar's PDA has several audio notes:\
\n%c[0,153,255,255]Note #1:%c[0,140,140,140]Costa hooked me up on a search, a pretty rare artifact on mercenaries, said the "blues" promised good pay.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]Note #2:%c[0,140,140,140]Artifact - found, contacted Kosta, he said to wait near the swamp, should come mercenary.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]Note #3:%c[0,140,140,140]"Blue" took the art... And shot... Why do not. (coughs) K-Kos... [Audio cuts off].</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kat_pda_stalker_unlock_name">
		<text>Raven's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kat_pda_stalker_unlock_descr">
		<text>PDA has been scrubbed, but there are still a couple of entries in the notes:\
\n%c[0,153,255,255]Note #2:%c[0,140,140,140]I got a few mutants... It was to be expected, I got hit... [coughs] The guys wanted to carry me, but I told them not to... I would rather watch my back here than burden my shoulders. All right! Get ready motherfuckers... 
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kat_pda_stalker_lock_name">
		<text>PDA Raven</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kat_pda_stalker_lock_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Device:%c[0,193,66,66]Blocked</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_merc_lock_name">
		<text>Mercenary PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_merc_lock_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Device:%c[0,193,66,66]Locked</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_merc_name">
		<text>Mercenary PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wiz_pda_merc_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140,140]Notes:\n%c[0,153,255,255]- Krivoy had a great idea with this art! In fact, the only one to blame for the stalker's death was the bloodsucker. I wonder how he managed to talk the neutral leader into sending this vagabond into the jaws of the bloodsucker?
\n%c[0,153,255,255]- Crooked, sent to scout the trails so there would be no difficulty in retreating.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]- That's it, now you can go back to the guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ba1_pda_yara_pda">
		<text>Uncle Yar's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ba1_pda_yara_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Notes:\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]Wonder what the measures needed in this lab? I think it's worth following up with them.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]Damn, they're gone... We need to be more careful. 
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]That's weird, I couldn't find anyone... 
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]I walked all over the lab, but not a living soul...
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]Found an army radio station. After turning it on, it picked up someone's S.O.S. signal. I'll have to ask the locals for more info on these poor bastards.
\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,193,66,66]Damn! I knew it wasn't going to be that easy, it looks like it's over... The Controller was more resilient than I thought. This is the end...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Проект "Прометей" -->
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_name">
		<text>Project: Prometheus Part 5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]It didn't go according to plan! Project Prometheus is out of control! The lab staff, were found to have violated the quarantine zone. Laboratory assistant Chistyakov Ah.V. performed a heroic deed, he sealed the lower levels of the complex, in order not to let the contamination continue, but he died. Alas, the funding has been terminated, the project is closed and the test subjects are sealed in the complex.\n\nProfessor Zvyagintsev Ah.M\n\n\nDate: 15.06.2016.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_1_name">
		<text>Project: Prometheus Part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_1_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] 10.03.2016: \n
The project proved itself quite well, but there are still some points that require further development and experimentation. Most of all, we recommend that you do a field test of the project, because a huge part of our test subjects in the laboratory conditions showed quite striking results, but after conducting field tests, it became clear that the test subjects are only at the initial stage.\n14.03.2016: \n
After conducting the field tests, we discovered a spy who was having a detrimental effect on the project, not without the help of others. As we learned, the spy turned out to be Professor Romanov. It was impossible to find out how long he opposed the project. The professor committed an act of suicide. Let's hope that the other accomplices have so far gone into the shadows and the Prometheus project reaches its final stage.\n\nProfessor Zvyagintsev Ah.M\n\n\nDate: 14.03.2016.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_2_name">
		<text>Project: Prometheus Part 4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_doc_ba1_info_2_descr">
		<text>\n%c[0,153,255,255]-%c[0,140,140,140]Based on all of the above, we conclude that the subject does not produce uncontrolled aggression like its predecessors.
The most notable thing is that the subject began emitting a small amount of Psi Waves, but we were unable to figure out the cause of their appearance. Moreover, one of the lab assistants said that he was experiencing constant headaches when being in the immediate vicinity of the subject. I feel it necessary to inform you that Project Prometheus is unstable and more time is needed for observation.\n\nProfessor Zvyagintsev Ah.M\n\n\nDate: 09.04.2016.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_sokol_documents_name">
		<text>Document folder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_sokol_documents_descr">
		<text>Folder with documents, most of the documents are dated February 2016. Also the documents talk about, some kind of Prometheus project.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_sokol_treasure_name">
		<text>Fireproof case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_sokol_treasure_descr">
		<text>Not a large fireproof case, it appears to contain the money inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_scaner_radio_name">
		<text>Radio frequency scanner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_scaner_radio_descr">
		<text>The radio frequency scanner is designed to scan a range of frequencies, or channels. If the scanner finds a signal on a certain frequency, it stops for a preset time and then resumes scanning the given frequency range.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_petruhi_lock_name">
		<text>Petrukha PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_petruhi_lock_descr">
		<text>%c[0,153,255,255]•ЗАБЛОКИРО\n\n%c[0,153,255,255]-The PDA shows the inscription: Wild Group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_petruhi_unlock_name">
		<text>Petrukha's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_petruhi_unlock_descr">
		<text>%c[0,153,255,255]-Message #1 received: Petruha, your task is to infiltrate Tycho's group. The main task is to steal the medallion.\n%c[0,153,255,255]-Get Message #2: In a couple of hours, we'll provoke Tikhoy's group to raid the territories. This will be your chance, just don't pay for it.\n\n%c[0,153,255,255]-Personal note: Damned Wild, I'd rather hang out with those stalkers myself... Okay, I guess this will all be over soon.\n\n%c[0,153,255,255]-Personal Note: Still, the provocation worked.\n\n%c[0,153,255,255,255]-Personal note: The meeting place is not far from the north tunnel with the Zharks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_gar_medaliyon_name">
		<text>Old Medallion.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ex_gar_medaliyon_descr">
		<text>%c[0,153,255,255]-Old Medallion, with a chain. On the medallion itself you can see the initials I.Ah. There is a photo inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="real_habar_name">
		<text>Normal hiking backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="real_habar_descr">
		<text>Looks like an ordinary hiking backpack, but it is quite heavy and there may be valuables inside.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Квестовые предметы для циклических квестов -->
	<string id="medkit_case_name">
		<text>Medical case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="medkit_case_descr">
		<text>A fireproof backpack case with medicine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alko_treasure_name">
		<text>Alcohol backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alko_treasure_descr">
		<text>A pretty weighty backpack with fuel for Diesel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aiamop_treasure_name">
		<text>Backpack with ammunition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aiamop_treasure_descr">
		<text>Quite a lot of ammunition in the backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sqf_treasure_name">
		<text>Order of the Joker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sqf_treasure_descr">
		<text>Quite a lot of ammunition and provisions in the backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dl_lab_x6_info_name">
		<text>Research Papers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dl_lab_x6_info_descr">
		<text>The report describes a study of biological specimens and so-called artifacts sent from Laboratory X11. The specimens were exposed to information fields of varying degrees of intensity. The report details the mutations in living and non-living organisms caused by such exposures.\nThese documents must not fall into the wrong hands.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
