<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="topi_quest_medic_container_name">
		<text>ULM CASE 1</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_quest_medic_container_desc">
		<text>ULM CASE I Circulation III emergency case (WM 5302, included). Aluminum case with plastic interior, dimensions 52.6 x 40 x 17 cm, weight 7 kg, stowage compartments for accessories, 48 ampoule compartments. Contents: Tonometer, Stethoscope, Flashlight for pupil control, Neurological mallet, Tourniquet, Forceps 145x2 mm, Forceps 145x3.2 mm, Scissors, Multifunction scissors, Spatula, Curved clamp, Disposable scalpels, Infusion system with manometer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_spec_anomaly_scanner_1_name">
		<text>Anomaly scanner</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_spec_anomaly_scanner_1_descr">
		<text>A special artifact scanner developed by the Amber team. An indispensable thing to facilitate the search for artifacts, helping to determine their presence in the anomaly of one kind or another. There are different modifications of this scanner with individual parameters of work. For example - the scanner of acid anomalies, gravitational, electrostatic, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_example_taynik_item_name">
		<text>Army Backpack</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_example_taynik_item_descr">
		<text>Tactical backpack made of high-density cordura with water-repellent impregnation and polyurethane coating. This backpack was developed at one time for the US Army special forces. It is compact but has a good storage capacity.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_topi_main_quest_document_1_name">
		<text>The notes of a scientist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_topi_main_quest_document_1_descr">
		<text>The deceased scientist's notes. "...What a waste of a job we've done. "A great waste. We relied on the honesty of the partners. Clever scientist fools. They tricked us like children for three lollipops. Consider yourself condemned and dug your own grave. The shooter's a dead man anyway. He'll be killed sooner or later, whether he makes it to the barrier or not. Only we won't know about it..."</text>
	</string>    		
	<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_1_name">
		<text>Component #1</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_1_desc">
		<text>The first component, which is needed to create a high-explosive device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_2_name">
		<text>Component two.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_2_desc">
		<text>Second component, which is required to create a high-explosive device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_3_name">
		<text>Component No. 3</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_3_desc">
		<text>The third component, which is required for the manufacture of an incendiary explosive device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_name">
		<text>A high-explosive device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_desc">
		<text>Assembled from anti-personnel mines, a high-explosive device with pre-set detonation time and target sensor length.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_topi_anubis_fugascreate_device_name">
		<text>Explosive crafting equipment.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_topi_anubis_fugascreate_device_descr">
		<text>A special kit for the safe dismantling of land mines and the subsequent construction of an high-explosive bomb based on them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a6_trader_documents_name">
		<text>Documents folder.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a6_trader_documents_desc">
		<text>Documents given to you by a local merchant. Contains items of interest to bandit groups in the Junkyard and other areas under their control. Specific content unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_1_name">
		<text>Gas mask assembly device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_1_descr">
		<text>A special handheld device to prepare gas masks for field tests with various filters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_2_name">
		<text>Gas mask checking system mod. 8020Ì.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_2_descr">
		<text>The CBRN (chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear) gas mask test system is a portable unit which tests the suitability of a CBRN protective mask on a single soldier. The test results are displayed on the screen as a numerical fitting factor. The Gas Mask Tester does not require the use of aerosol or tear gas chambers to assess the suitability of the mask. It can be used almost anywhere - at gas mask distribution points, at training facilities and even in the field.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_item_name">
		<text>Dosimeter-radiometer "MKS-07H (DKG-07BS)".</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_item_desc">
		<text>The dosimeter is used for operational dosimetric control of radiation environment while preparing radiation maps of the area and study of radiation anomalies, to check the degree of contamination of clothing, equipment, buildings, structures, etc. It can be used as a portable (MKS-07H) or on-board and stationary measuring instrument (DKG-07BS).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_doc_name">
		<text>Measurement results.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_doc_desc">
		<text>A carrier with the results of measurements taken by the dosimeter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_item_name">
		<text>Radar Kredo-1E.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_item_descr">
		<text>Unified radar station for reconnaissance of moving targets Kredo-1E is designed for reconnaissance of ground targets (individuals, groups of individuals, equipment), as well as for maintenance of artillery fire at any time of day and night, including in the absence of optical visibility (fog, dust or smoke in the atmosphere).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_akum_1_name">
		<text>Battery.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_akum_1_descr">
		<text>One of the component parts of radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_kabel_name">
		<text>Connection cables.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_kabel_descr">
		<text>One part of the radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_naved_name">
		<text>Pointing device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_naved_descr">
		<text>One part of the radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_pered_name">
		<text>A transceiver unit.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_pered_descr">
		<text>One part of a radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_blok_name">
		<text>One part of the radar complex.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_blok_descr">
		<text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_comp_name">
		<text>One part of radar complex.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_comp_descr">
		<text>One of the components of radar complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_1_name">
		<text>VK 320 filter.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_1_descr">
		<text>Filter 320 À1is designed to purify inhaled air from organic vapours with a boiling point above 65°C (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, petrol, paraffin, haloid organic compounds (chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone, etc.), nitro compounds of benzene and benzene. The following are some of the most important gases and vapours (hydrogen cyane, sulphur hydride, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsines, hydrogen phosphate, etc.), except for carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and hydrogen sulphide. ), excluding carbon monoxide; acid gases and vapours (sulphur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, hydrogen fluoride, hydrogen bromide, sulphuric acid vapours, acetic acid, formic acid, nitric acid, phosphoric acid, etc. The filter is designed to filter out all hazardous chemical substances, such as ammonia and its organic derivatives, specific hazardous chemicals (chlorcian, sarin, soman, phosgene etc.), and aerosols in filter gas masks in continuous or periodic operation, as well as for emergency escape from the emergency zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_2_name">
		<text>Filter BK 600.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_2_descr">
		<text>Filter 600 À2is designed to purify inhaled air from organic gases and vapours with a boiling point above 65°Ñ (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, petrol, paraffin, haloid organic compounds (chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone, etc.), nitro compounds of benzene and other. etc.); inorganic gases and vapours (hydrogen cyane, sulphur hydride, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsine, hydrogen phosphate, etc, excluding carbon monoxide); acid gases and vapours (sulphur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, hydrogen fluoride, hydrogen bromide, sulphuric acid vapours, acetic acid vapours, formic acid, nitric acid, phosphoric acid, etc. The filter is equipped with a breathing apparatus which prevents the release of dangerous chemical substances such as ammonia and its organic derivatives, specific hazardous chemicals (chlorcian, sarin, soman, phosgene etc), and aerosols in filter gas masks in continuous or periodic operation, as well as for emergency escape from the emergency zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_3_name">
		<text>VK 450 filter.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_3_descr">
		<text>Filter 450 is designed to purify inhaled air from organic gases and vapours with a boiling point above 65°Ñ (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, petrol, paraffin, haloid organic compounds (chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone etc.), benzene and nitro compounds. etc.); inorganic gases and vapours (hydrogen cyane, sulphur hydride, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsine, hydrogen phosphate, etc, excluding carbon monoxide); acid gases and vapours (sulphur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, hydrogen fluoride, hydrogen bromide, sulphuric acid vapours, acetic acid vapours, formic acid, nitric acid, phosphoric acid, etc. ); ammonia and its organic derivatives; specific hazardous chemicals (chlorcian, sarin, soman, phosgene etc); aerosols in filter gas masks in continuous or periodic operation, as well as for emergency escape from the emergency zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_4_name">
		<text>DPG-3.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_4_descr">
		<text>Additional cartridge DPG-3 is designed for civilian gas masks GP-7, GP-7V and children's gas masks PDF-2D, PDF-2Sh to extend their area of application. Additional DPG-3 cartridge is designed for use with civilian gas masks GP-7, GP-7V and children's gas masks PDF-2D, PDF-2Sh to extend their area of application. A gas mask complete with DPG-3 provides protection from toxic substances (PS), radioactive dust (RP), biological aerosols (BA) and additional protection from accidentally hazardous substances (ACh): ammonia, chlorine, dimethylamine, nitrobenzene, carbon disulfide, tetraethyl lead, phenol, furfural, ethylmercaptan, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_5_name">
		<text>DOT 460 filter.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_5_descr">
		<text>The DOT 460 filter is designed to protect the respiratory system as part of a PFMG-96 filter gas mask against chemically hazardous substances. Gas masks with filters DOT 460 grade A2B2E2AX are used when the oxygen content in the air is at least 17% by volume and the content of hazardous substances (not more than 0.5% by volume), at ambient temperature from minus 40 to plus 40 ° C.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_1_name">
		<text>Mask to gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_1_descr">
		<text>First type full face mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_2_name">
		<text>A mask for a full face mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_2_descr">
		<text>First type full face mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_3_name">
		<text>Mask for gas masks.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_3_descr">
		<text>Gas mask of gas mask type 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_4_name">
		<text>Mask to a gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_4_descr">
		<text>Gas mask of gas mask type 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_5_name">
		<text>Mask to a gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_5_descr">
		<text>Mask for a first type gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_dathik_name">
		<text>Sensor for a gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_proto_dathik_descr">
		<text>Special sensor from the 8020M system, to record the parameters of a gas mask under test.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_1_name">
		<text>Gas mask of the first type.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_1_descr">
		<text>Test version of the RSH4 gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_2_name">
		<text>Gas mask of the first type.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_2_descr">
		<text>Test version of the PMK1 gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_3_name">
		<text>First type full mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_3_descr">
		<text>Test version of the PMK3 gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_4_name">
		<text>Protective mask of the first type.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_4_descr">
		<text>Test version of a PMG2 gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_5_name">
		<text>Protective mask of the first type.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_5_descr">
		<text>Test version of the IP4 gas mask.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="topi_b11_radiostation_name">
		<text>Radio R-168-5KDNE.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_radiostation_descr">
		<text>The R-168-5KDNE radio ensures open and crypto-protected radio communication in the CW/UKV bands of the tactical radio network under severe operational conditions, including the use of frequency hopping. It is manufactured by Yaroslavl Radio Plant.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b11_plata_1_name">
		<text>No.1 system board.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_plata_1_descr">
		<text>One of the radio system modules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_plata_2_name">
		<text>The system board number 2.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_plata_2_descr">
		<text>One of the components of the radio system modules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_name">
		<text>System board No. 3.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_plata_3_descr">
		<text>One of the components of system modules radio.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_plata_4_name">
		<text>System board number 4.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_plata_4_descr">
		<text>One of the RF system modules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_paika_name">
		<text>System board number 3.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_plata_3_paika_descr">
		<text>One of the RF system modules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_multimetr_name">
		<text>Multimeter AM-1083.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_multimetr_descr">
		<text>Multimeters AKTAK AM-1083 are designed for measuring DC and AC (40-400 Hz) current (up to 20 Ah!) and voltage, resistance, capacitance, diode checks and continuity-check.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_payalnik_name">
		<text>Lukey-852D+ soldering station.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_payalnik_descr">
		<text>Digital air-thermal soldering station with soldering iron. The digital indication of the actual hot air temperature will give the smallest error in operation. The wide temperature range will enable the unit to be used in a wide range of operating conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_components_1_name">
		<text>Capacitor.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_components_1_descr">
		<text>Aluminum miniature electrolytic capacitor. ECAP (K50-35 mini), 0.1µF, 50V, 4x7mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_components_2_name">
		<text>Transistor.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_components_2_descr">
		<text>KT117B, Low power N-base single junction transistor [metal]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_components_3_name">
		<text>Diode.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_components_3_descr">
		<text>1.5KE12(A), Protective diode, 1500W, 12V, [DO-201].</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b11_zaglushka_name">
		<text>Resistor.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b11_zaglushka_descr">
		<text>CF-100 (C1-4) 1W, 1.6 Ohm, 5%, Carbon Resistor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_item_name">
		<text>A chemical reconnaissance unit.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_item_desc">
		<text>The device is intended to detect in the air, on the ground and on the equipment warfare agents - sarin, soman, mustard gas, phosgene, diphosgene, hydrocyanic acid, chlorocyanine, as well as vapours of V-gases in the air. The principle of operation of the CAP is the following: when pumped through the indicator tubes analyzed air in the presence of toxic substances (PS), a change in the colour of the tubes' filler, by which approximately determine the concentration of PS.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_doc_name">
		<text>Measurement results.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_doc_desc">
		<text>A carrier with the results of measurements performed by the DPCR.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_1_name">
		<text>Radio station Barmitsa-RS</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a105_razia_type_1_desc">
		<text>The new radio "Barmitsa-RS" ensures open and masked telephone communication with radios of the same type as well as with the radio "R-159" and radio stations of the complexes "R-163" and "R-168". Contains a built-in speech masker. The radio is designed for operation in difficult field conditions. It has a low weight, high mechanical strength (the possibility of landing), compact. The unit has a sealed, metal, dust and watertight casing. Manufacturer: NPO "Rif", Voronezh, Russia.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_2_name">
		<text>Berkut-801MK" CB radio.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a105_razia_type_2_desc">
		<text>The radio station combines all the advantages of the "Berkut" radio family: 1. The effective threshold noise suppression operates with a signal in 0.05-0.07 mcV. 2. High sensitivity and selectivity of the receiver. 3. Exceptionally high efficiency: uniquely high transmitter efficiency (80% when working with regular flexible antenna) and super economical reception mode. 4. Uniquely small size and weight. 5. High reliability: the radio works in any weather and temperature conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_3_name">
		<text>Radio "Tulpan" (22RTP-2-FM).</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a105_razia_type_3_desc">
		<text>The portable single-channel simplex transistor VHF radio "Tulpan" (22RTP-2-FM) is designed for enquiry-free telephone radio communication with single-type radios and with radio systems in the 140-144 MHz range. The radio is used for communication organisation in different sectors of national economy - for construction sites, railway and motor transport, agriculture, for short distances up to 1-2 km.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_4_name">
		<text>Erica-302" radio station</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a105_razia_type_4_desc">
		<text>Erika-302 is a professional radio, designed to work in extreme conditions. The combined body of metal and impact resistant plastic can withstand bumps and drops, while high quality imported components allow the radio to operate at extreme temperatures. The radio has 16 channels, two scanning priorities, LED indication of operating mode. The radio was manufactured by the JSC "Urals Radio Stations", Izhevsk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_5_name">
		<text>Radio station "Granit 2R-44</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a105_razia_type_5_desc">
		<text>It is a modern development in the field of professional radio equipment. Possibility of operation of radio stations: simplex and half-duplex (operation through the repeater is possible). The radio is produced in two versions: 1. basic 10-channel model. 2. 100-channel model with the ability to scan in three different modes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_zam_protocrafter_name">
		<text>Equipment for crafting a poisoned gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_protocrafter_descr">
		<text>A special kit required to assemble a gas mask with a modified filter filling.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_zam_protivogaz_1_name">
		<text>Gas mask IP4.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_protivogaz_1_descr">
		<text>A variant of the IP4 gas mask from the batch for testing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_zam_maska_1_name">
		<text>Mask for the gas mask.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_maska_1_descr">
		<text>Mask from IP4 gas mask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_zam_proto_filtr_1_name">
		<text>Filter VK 600.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_proto_filtr_1_descr">
		<text>Filter 600 À2is designed for purification of inhaled air from organic gases and vapours with boiling point higher than 65Ñ (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, petrol, paraffin, haloid organic compounds (chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone, etc... etc.); inorganic gases and vapours (hydrogen cyane, sulphur hydride, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsine, hydrogen phosphate, etc, excluding carbon monoxide); acid gases and vapours (sulphur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, hydrogen fluoride, hydrogen bromide, sulphuric acid vapours, acetic acid vapours, formic acid, nitric acid, phosphoric acid, etc. The following are considered to be hazardous chemicals: ammonia and its organic derivatives, specific hazardous chemicals (chlorcian, sarin, soman, phosgene, etc.), aerosols in filter masks in continuous or intermittent operation, as well as in emergency exits from the emergency zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_zam_yad_1_name">
		<text>CWA capsule.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_yad_1_descr">
		<text>A capsule containing a sarin-based chemical agent. A special catalyst is required for activation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_zam_katalizator_1_name">
		<text>Chemical catalyst.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_zam_katalizator_1_descr">
		<text>A special catalyst required to activate the chemical agent.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b12_key_1_name">
		<text>The first key to the container.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b12_key_1_descr">
		<text>One of the two keys to the cache set up by Hasan's men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b12_key_2_name">
		<text>The second key to the container.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b12_key_2_descr">
		<text>One of the two keys to the cache set up by Hassan's men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_lider_copromat_1_name">
		<text>A file folder.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_lider_copromat_1_desc">
		<text>Documents with decent dirt on Hassan. Described many schemes to sell artifacts bypassing the clan's coffers, his contacts with mercenaries, and a list of undesirable clan stalkers, some of whom have already been eliminated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_lider_spectrometr_1_name">
		<text>Responder RCI Portable Spectrometer.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_lider_spectrometr_1_descr">
		<text>Responder RCI is a lightweight and portable spectrometer based on Raman technology, ideal for identifying unknown liquids and powders. You can choose the method of analysis from two options - taking a sample in a tube placed inside the unit, or identification using an optional module that allows the remote determination of the chemical composition of the substance in a transparent to IR-radiation container. In either case the result will be accurate and the analysis time will not exceed 30 seconds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_anubis_ukazanie_1_name">
		<text>Documentation folder.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_anubis_ukazanie_1_desc">
		<text>Additional instructions from Anubis: "The situation with the scientists has cleared up. This particular group can't be eliminated - it's too late. Prepare to eliminate them after you deal with the local stalkers."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_bomba_name">
		<text>Explosive device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_anubis_var_2_bomba_descr">
		<text>An explosive device with a pre-set detonation time and chemical warheads.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_detector_mine">
		<text>IMP-2.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_detector_mine_descr">
		<text>Induction mine detector, semi-conductor, personal use, IMM is designed to detect antitank and antipersonnel mines planted in the ground (snow), hulls or fuses which are made of metal. The mine detector can detect mines planted in bushes, grass and fords. It is developed in 70th years by Research Institute "Project" of Tomsk, is made by Tomsk factory of the measuring equipment. It is the improved version of mine detector IMP. It was widely used during the war in Afghanistan, is used in the army up to the present time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_1_name">
		<text>File of documents.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_1_desc">
		<text>Documents from one of the mercenaries in the syndicate. It says there's a "data transfer location". It's somewhere nearby - either caves or a village. Maybe it's a hiding place or something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_2_name">
		<text>File of documents.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_2_desc">
		<text>Files of the mercenaries from the syndicate. Some of the information contains an estimate for the supply of artefacts. It fiigures the name of the deputy leader of the freelance stalkers.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="topi_f1_radioscaner_name">
		<text>ARK-RP3 handheld direction finder.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_f1_radioscaner_descr">
		<text>Purpose: radio monitoring; estimation of electromagnetic field strength and radio signal parameters; direction finding and locating of radio emission source; recording of radio signals and transmissions.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b41_seleczia_device_name">
		<text>Artefact selection device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b41_seleczia_device_descr">
		<text>A special prototype device developed by scientists in the CEZ to conduct changes in the properties of artefacts in anomalous formations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b41_artefact_1_name">
		<text>Type 1 modifier.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b41_artefact_1_descr">
		<text>An artifact with altered properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b41_artefact_2_name">
		<text>Modifier of the first type.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b41_artefact_2_descr">
		<text>Artifact with modified properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b41_artefact_3_name">
		<text>Type one modifier.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b41_artefact_3_descr">
		<text>An artifact with altered properties.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_1_used_name">
		<text>TNK-7 portable night vision device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_1_used_descr">
		<text>TNK-7 is a multifunctional night vision device which is intended for surveillance, detection and recognition of objects (including veiled ones) when working at night and in other unfavourable conditions (fog, smoke, total darkness). Combined optical night vision device has 2 channels: thermal channel on the base of microbolometer matrix format 384õ288 and night channel on the base of EOP 2 ++ generation. The channels are combined in one housing and share a common eyepiece. You can quickly switch between the channels, observing in turn in the night channel or in the thermal channel, or you can switch to the "combined" mode. In "combined" mode, the "thermal image" is optically superimposed on the image obtained through the night channel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_2_used_name">
		<text>Night vision device "Contour SP-301/303".</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_2_used_descr">
		<text>Small-size night vision devices (NVD) are intended for qualitative observation, reconnaissance, protection of objects. They are effective for search-and-rescue operations and providing navigational safety. The devices are equipped with high-aperture optics, built-in and additional self-contained infra-red illuminators which allows seeing and recording of surveillance results at distances up to 500 metres.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_3_used_name">
		<text>Night vision device "Dedal-370-DK3".</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_3_used_descr">
		<text>Compact and lightweight night vision device "Dedal-370-DK3" is a truly versatile tool. Whatever the task, be it night surveillance, technical support of law enforcement forces, security, search, hunting or night photo and video shooting, "Dedal-370-DK3" will be stably effective. The design of device allows to use it as monocular independently, as well as in combination with other devices - optical and collimator sights, photo- and video-cameras, also to fix device on a headband or helmet of observer. Also, it is possible to combine two devices "Dedal-370-DK3" together, thereby "creating" a night vision binoculars! In addition, a number of interchangeable lenses are available to increase the magnification to 9.6x.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_1_name">
		<text>Druid D-06 jamming generator.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_c7_quest_device_1_descr">
		<text>A system of protection for negotiations, which allows you to conduct a conversation with up to 6 people simultaneously (when synchronized with 2 devices up to 12 people). Protects against all known listening methods, including all types of radio microphones, stethoscopes, sound recorders, passive resonators, wireline microphones, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_2_name">
		<text>Equipment of radioelectronic complex "Pelena-7K".</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_c7_quest_device_2_descr">
		<text>The equipment of radioelectronic complex "Pelena-7K" is intended for protection against radio-controlled explosive devices as well as for protection of technical information. At its application the modes of stationary and portable operation are supposed.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="topi_b65_zam_bomba_name">
		<text>Explosive device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_b65_zam_bomba_descr">
		<text>An explosive device with a timed detonation feature, packed with chemical warfare agents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="topi_a65_zam_bomba_name">
		<text>Explosive device.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="topi_a65_zam_bomba_descr">
		<text>A directional explosive device with a timed detonation timer packed with chemical warfare agents.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_topi_a2_main_tainik_title">
		<text>Stalker's Backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_topi_a2_main_tainik_descr">
		<text>A backpack used as a stash, where one of the free stalkers hid their modest loot.</text>
	</string>
	
	
</string_table>
