<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    
	<string id="st_gar_main_quest_lekarstvo_all_name">
		<text>Antidote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_main_quest_lekarstvo_all_descr">
		<text>A powerful experimental antidote capable of defeating poisoning by highly corrosive chemical compounds.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gar_b47_digger_pda_name">
		<text>PDA Digger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gar_b47_digger_pda_descr">
		<text>The PDA of a dead Digger. The information stored on it can be quite valuable.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codekey">
		<text>Doorkey</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codekey_descr">
		<text>Door key from the hiding place of the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_oszillograf_name">
		<text>C1-65A Oscilloscope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_oszillograf_descr">
		<text>Universal oscilloscope C1-65A is designed for examination of the form of electrical signals by visual observation and measurement of their amplitude and time parameters in the shop, laboratory and field conditions of operation. The oscilloscope meets the requirements of GOST 22261-76 and 9810 - 69. Accuracy of waveform reproduction, time interval and amplitude measurements, the oscilloscope C1 - 65A belongs to the II class of GOST 9810 - 69.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_labx5_quest_document_1">
		<text>Recorded papers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_1_descr">
		<text>The first part of the military records are from their closed design, developed in the X5 laboratory. Lots of obscure terms, mathematical and chemical formulas. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_2">
		<text>Recorded papers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_2_descr">
		<text>Second part of military documents on their closed project being developed at lab X5. Blueprints of some obscure devices, lots of formulas and numbers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_3">
		<text>Papers with records.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_3_descr">
		<text>Third part of military documents of their closed project developed at X5 lab. Partially burned. But readable.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codegrabber_name">
		<text>The codegrabber</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codegrabber_descr">
		<text>A special electronic device designed to intercept, recognize and decode radio signals. It's used to break into various types of electric locks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_gruz_safe_name">
		<text>Container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_gruz_safe_desc">
		<text>Closed container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_serious_business_pda_name">
		<text>PDA Colotoon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_serious_business_pda_desc">
		<text>Last message on the PDA:\n"Those bastards are out to get their kicks on our turf. They got a house right in front of our base. They ain't afraid of nothing, motherfuckers! All right, go over there and have a heart-to-heart talk with them. If they don't get it right the first time, you can lead them. And quick, before their leader goes to the junkyard!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_habar_name">
		<text>Money case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_habar_desc">
		<text>Skidan's money case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_money_merc_name">
		<text>A bag of money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_money_merc_desc">
		<text>A bag of money to pay mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="esc_sidor_habar_key">
		<text>Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_habar_key_descr">
		<text>The key to the box where Skidan's loot is hidden.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_name">
		<text>Yablonsky's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_desc">
		<text>"PDA LOCKED."</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_upd_name">
		<text>Yablonsky's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_upd_desc">
		<text>Message 64:\n"...the group did not appear at the specified time. Our informant reported no trace of it. The attempt to move the sacred part of the Monolith beyond the perimeter must be foiled at all costs."\nMessage 65:\n"In addition to us, the Spectrum faction has begun hunting for the artifact. Their aims and objectives are unclear, in any case - anyone involved in the theft must be destroyed and the artifact must be returned to the sarcophagus."\nMessage 66:\n"The artifact is extremely dangerous, the psi radiation is off the scale. Servants of the Monolith experience intense psychic strain upon contact. Opening the container by an ordinary human would result in instant death."\nMessage 67:\n"Coordinates have recently been received for a stalker who stole part of our sacred stone. You must move to the X5 lab area in the Cordon location and put the enemies of the Monolith to death."</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="st_esc_quest_shvabroid_pda_name">
		<text>Schwabroid's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_shvabroid_pda_desc">
		<text>Incoming message:\n"Get the hell out of this Libertarian and be done with it. Just make sure it's clean, we don't want any problems with Liberty later."</text>
	</string>	
	
	
	<string id="st_quest_help_nebo_radio_name">
		<text>Radio T-169-7KDNE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_quest_help_nebo_radio_desc">
		<text>The T-169-7KDNE radio ensures open and crypto-protected radio communication in the HF/UHF bands of the tactical radio network under severe operational conditions, including the use of frequency hopping. It is manufactured by Yaroslavl Radio Plant.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="st_esc_watchmaker_key_door">
		<text>Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_watchmaker_key_door_descr">
		<text>Sentry's house key</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="st_esc_quest_army_doc_name">
		<text>Warrant Officer PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_army_doc_desc">
		<text>Ensign's PDA containing information valuable to Colonel Kolyazin, for which he could send anyone to his death. The data is encrypted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_chimera_repilent_name">
		<text>Repellent for Chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_chimera_repilent_desc">
		<text>Repellent for the chimera. Made from the urine of a male chimera. Discourages females but infuriates males.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_army_brelok_name">
		<text>Deserter dog tags</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_quest_army_brelok_desc">
		<text>Deserter dog tags are proof of death. Standard information: name, date of birth, blood type and Rh factor.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_1_name">
		<text>Component 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_1_desc">
		<text>Special microcircuitry required to build the listening device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_2_name">
		<text>Component number 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_2_desc">
		<text>Capacitors with specific markings, required for building the listening device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_3_name">
		<text>Component #3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_3_desc">
		<text>Inductance coils of certain marking, necessary for creating the Listening Device.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_1_name">
		<text>Listening device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_1_desc">
		<text>A home-made bugging device, useful for covert eavesdropping. The device has the ability to record and transmit collected information to a special medium. The operating range is questionable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_2_name">
		<text>Spy Bugging device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_2_desc">
		<text>Improvised bugging device, useful for covert eavesdropping. Capable of recording and transmitting the collected data to a dedicated medium. The working range is questionable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_device_title">
		<text>Lukey-853D soldering station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_device_descr">
		<text>Advantages of Lukey-853D : modern design, compact size, antistatic PCB protection against static electricity. The built-in microprocessor controls temperature display and control, rapid temperature rise and precise setting. These advantages are characterized by lead free soldering and disassembly, so it is possible to carry out disassembly and soldering of such temperature sensitive components as SOIC, PLCC, QFP, BGA packages. Accessories: soldering tips, clip for assembly and disassembly of tips, holder, user manual, soldering iron, holder for soldering iron, power cord, test pen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_spec_razia_name">
		<text>R-250M2 Kit-M2 radio receiver</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_spec_razia_descr">
		<text>R-250/M/M2 (R-670/M) is a legendary shortwave, tube-based, mainline army radio receiver, loved by many radio amateurs. The radio was produced from 1948 to 1981 in several modifications: R-250/M/M2 (Kit/M/M2) for the Army; R-670/M (Rusalka/M) for the Navy. The receiver has an accurate mirrored optical tuning photo scale, thermostatic quartz heterodyne frequency stabiliser. Number of sub-bands: 12, 2 MHz each. Band selector switch is mechanical, drum-type.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bar_key_door">
		<text>Key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_key_door_descr">
		<text>Key to door leading to x14 Laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="labx14_access_card">
		<text>Old magnetic key card</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx14_access_card_descr">
		<text>Magnetic key card, for access to locked underground railway station, code "0519".</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="city_safe_container_name">
		<text>Container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="city_safe_container_desc">
		<text>Container with radio parts.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="city_bomb_c4_name">
		<text>C-4 explosive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="city_bomb_c4_desc">
		<text>Plastic explosive for military use. It is used for a variety of destructive tasks, also widely used as a weapon for the destruction of manpower and equipment.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="city_money_sp_name">
		<text>Cash case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="city_money_sp_desc">
		<text>The case is filled to the brim with 500 euro notes. Approximately 3 million euros here, maybe a little more. All this happiness together with the case weighs 12 kilos.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_labx14_csky_pda_name">
		<text>Siploch's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx14_csky_pda_descr">
		<text>Last message: ...it's so quiet here. Not even a rustle can be heard, it feels like I've already started moving silently, at other times it feels like someone is walking nearby. The sound strangely echoes off these tiled walls.
I don't know when I'll get out upstairs or if I'll get out of here. There is still hope...
Today I've walked in circles again, the route I've been taking for 3 days: stairs, tunnel, stairs, tunnel, stairs ... how do I get out of here? Who am I asking? No answer. Quick... I didn't even say where I was going. It's ridiculous to think of such secrets now, only to make the Zone laugh. They don't even know where to find me.
Now I'll have a tin and some vodka to help me sleep. In this darkness and silence, they taste different to me.
Stumbled across some cages today and the floor seems to have been drenched in something. There are slides of polished white bones everywhere in the corners. I hate to think they are human. And if they weren't, whose were they? And who had stacked them so neatly in a tent?
I can't see them, but I keep tripping over them, and they rumble to and fro across the floor.
The torch went out two days ago. 
I can see well in the dark now, or so it seems to me. Sometimes I see coloured highlights and hear some voices. I go towards them ... but there's nothing there. The darkness ... it's all darkness. I must walk my way in the darkness and come out into the light of God. I forgive and ask forgiveness.
</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="st_labx14_doc_1_info_name">
		<text>Report No. 1542</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_labx14_doc_1_info_descr">
		<text>TOTALLY SECRET.\nAfter daily intracavitary injections of broad-spectrum antibiotics, the subjects showed no positive dynamics. Tissue decomposition continued evenly throughout the body; subjects still had suppressed speech centre, they uttered one or two phrases; training and education had no apparent success - subjects still could not associate feeding with pressing the pedal; motor functions remained unchanged; aggression increased if infected subjects did not feed for long periods, then they began to attack each other, but cannibalism was not recorded.
Conclusion: the infection (if any) does not respond to antibiotics, the infected behave as before, retaining all known basic functions that they have retained after overcoming the "transformation" stage. 
\n26 April.
</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="labx14_doc_2_info_name">
		<text>Report #1556</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx14_doc_2_info_descr">
		<text>\n.\nFor two weeks the feeding of infected persons was carried out according to an approved truncated schedule, in order to determine the period of onset of critical exhaustion in the affected organism and to try to establish a relation between body composition and the time when exhaustion would reach a critical and fatal level. A few days into the experiment, the affected individuals began to exhibit aggressive behaviour. Attempts to break the restraining bars became more frequent. Remarkably, even without regular nourishment, the physical strength of the infected did not wane. It even seemed to increase, as they managed to loosen several bars of the bars. After feeding, the individuals calmed down considerably.  The longer the individuals starved, the more desperately they tried to get out. An enquiry has been sent to the relevant service regarding the reinforcement of the isolator. See attached for an interim report and conclusions. Observations are continuing.\n25 May.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
