<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    
<string id="st_x27_docs1_descr">
    <text>May 17, 2007. Archive. Top secret. Notification for the deputy of Laboratory X Branch 27 from Hoffman A.G. According to the order of the head of the third tier of the Chernobyl Anomalous Zone Territory, I hereby notify you: starting from August 1, 2007, the laboratory will switch to a 24-hour operation in 3 shifts. The laboratory will be divided into 3 departments on different floors. 1st floor: Technical Control Department; 2nd floor: Synthesis of the substance codenamed ALD-95 and its derivatives; 3rd floor: Transportation of finished products. All employees who have completed training and received corresponding permits of categories A, B, C should approach their supervisor to receive work instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs1_name">
    <text>Archived Document</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs2_descr">
    <text>April 23, 2009. Order IV-4231/a. In order to improve the quality of produced substances, a decision has been made to partially decommission Laboratory Complex X-27. I order to redistribute the space on the third floor of the complex for the needs of the laboratory, namely: 1. Construct isolated rooms for storing biomaterial. 2. Transfer and connect the necessary equipment to the underground complex area. 3. Establish an archive for storing up-to-date information. Approved by: Inaev V.N.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs2_name">
    <text>Order</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs3_descr">
    <text>Journal of conducted experiments. It contains descriptions of various experiments on "unreasonables with apathy" (most likely referring to zombies or zombified individuals). Judging by the latest entries, the scientists were testing a substance that reduces the effect of chemical burns on the body.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs3_name">
    <text>Experiment Journal</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs4_descr">
    <text>Lab maps. Only 2 pages have been preserved, schematically showing the plans of Laboratory X-27 and X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs4_name">
    <text>Old Folder</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs5_descr">
    <text>Hard drive from one of the computers in Laboratory X-27. It may contain valuable information.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs5_name">
    <text>Hard Drive</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_inaev_pda_descr">
    <text>Audio recording #534: I'm simply appalled by the negligence of the management towards our division. I've been working in this laboratory for four years, but after the change in leadership, everything just keeps getting worse. Unknown individuals invaded the laboratory, ransacked and looted the preserved floors, and it seems they'll soon reach our wing. Instead of providing suitable transportation, they decided that we should go on foot and carry valuable samples and documents ourselves. We won't even make it a couple of kilometers with such a heavy load, not to mention the danger in the Chernobyl Zone lately. And they've assigned some idiots from a group called "Monolith" to us, and I feel absolutely unsafe around them, if not the opposite. I suspect they're using our substances on themselves, although it's strictly prohibited. \n \n It's simply outrageous; I lack words to describe all my thoughts in this recording. I'm going now to demand an explanation. I won't tolerate such treatment towards myself or my subordinates.</text>
</string>
	
</string_table>
