<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- Quest: captive -->
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_1_name">
<text>Captive: find out what happened</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_1_text">
<text>We've escaped the anomaly, but I don't know what happened afterwards. Why am I in captivity? I need to figure out what's going on.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_2_name">
<text>Captive: speak to the captives</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_2_text">
<text>Savage didn't explain anything, but he's told me he'll help. It might be worth having a word with one of the other captives in the cell. Maybe they know what I'm doing here.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_3_name">
<text>Captive: go to sleep</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_3_text">
<text>Things are bad, I still have no clue how to get out of here. I should wait until morning. By then, Savage might have the chance to speak to this Saurel. The best way I can kill time is to sleep.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_4_name">
<text>Captive: wait for Savage to finish his plans</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_4_text">
<text>Time to rise and shine. Still have to wait until I get an answer. Savage should manage to find a way to get me out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_5_name">
<text>Captive: speak to the guard</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_5_text">
<text>A guard says that he wants to speak with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_6_name">
<text>Captive: speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_actor_prisoner_part_6_text">
<text>The guard has told me that Saurel, the head of the base, wants to see me.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: two friends -->
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_1_name">
<text>Two friends: find and kill Lefty</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_1_text">
<text>Saurel is the head of the stalkers at the Stronghold. He says that they had an emergency yesterday. A few stalkers got wasted, and things didn't end up well, leading to a fist fight. The morning after, one of these stalkers was found with his throat cut, and another stalker, Lefty, went missing somewhere. There's something shady going on here, and I need to figure it out. There's no need to get to the bottom of it, though, since it looks like Lefty cut up his wrongdoer and then realized what he's gotten himself into before hightailing it out of there. I need to find and punish him.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_2_name">
<text>Two friends: speak to Rasputin</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_2_text">
<text>The local barman, by the name of Rasputin, has asked me to go see him to talk about something.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_3_name">
<text>Two friends: find Lefty</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_3_text">
<text>Rasputin says that Lame couldn't have been killed by Lefty. Once I get the chance to see this Lefty, I should talk to him personally. Maybe he can shed a different light on the event.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_4_name">
<text>Two friends: speak to Lefty</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_4_text">
<text>I've found Lefty. Time to have a chat with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_5_name">
<text>Two friends: tell Saurel about your findings</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_5_text">
<text>Lefty tells me that he and Lame gathered a lot of artifacts not long ago and hid them in a container, later on having a drink with a couple of stalkers. Afterward, Lefty found out that Lame brought the artifact container with him to the base, and because of that, there was fighting. Lefty decided to leave, and after a while, Rasputin messaged him that Lame was killed by the other stalkers and that the container was stolen. His side of the story seems trustworthy; I should share it with Saurel.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_6_name">
<text>Two friends: return to Lefty</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_6_text">
<text>Saurel is allowing Lefty to return. I should give the news to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_7_name">
<text>Two friends: investigate the murder</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_7_text">
<text>Lefty's dead, and this definitely hasn't been done by any bandits. Whoever's responsible is likely covering their tracks. I need to search for clues here. Maybe I'll find something.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_8_name">
<text>Two friends: speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_8_text">
<text>I've found a knife at the murder scene. I should go to Saurel and tell him about the recent events.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_9_name">
<text>Two friends: speak to Rasputin about the knife</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_9_text">
<text>Rasputin is the barman here. He should know everything about what happens in the base. Perhaps he may know the owner of the knife.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_10_name">
<text>Two friends: return to the murder scene</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_10_text">
<text>Rasputin has told me that the knife I'm carrying belongs to Chemist. He's also told me that Chemist remembers where he lost his knife and has gone off to look for it. I need to return to the area where Lefty was killed and confirm whether this Chemist is there or not.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_11_name">
<text>Two friends: kill Chemist</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_11_text">
<text>It turns out that Chemist was the killer. He killed both Lame and Lefty, and now it's time for me to avenge them.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_12_name">
<text>Two friends: search Chemist's corpse</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_12_text">
<text>Chemist is dead. I should check out his possessions. Perhaps there's something that can verify that he really is the killer of both Lame and Lefty.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_13_name">
<text>Two friends: look for information in Chemist's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_13_text">
<text>Chemist's backpack held a PDA. I should check out his latest entries.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_14_name">
<text>Two friends: tell everything to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_search_killer_part_14_text">
<text>Chemist was definitely the one who killed Lame and Lefty. Time to share all the details with Saurel.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: active reconnaissance -->
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_1_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_1_text">
<text>Shaman has told me that Saurel's asked me to go see him. I wonder what he wants.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_2_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: remain at the sniper position</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_2_text">
<text>My task is to help the guys from a sniper position. I just have to wait for the bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_3_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: kill the bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_3_text">
<text>The bandits are already on the move near the northern farm. They have to be stopped.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_4_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: speak to Marchuk</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_4_text">
<text>We've taken out the bandits. I may want to speak to the detachment leader who helped me repel the attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_5_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: check the bandits' hidden channel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_5_text">
<text>I need to make sure that the bandits aren't planning anything else, and for that, I need to listen in on their comms.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_6_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: return to the sniper position</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_6_text">
<text>The bandits have sent yet another group, this time to the Panskiy farm. I need to return to the sniper position and put them down.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_7_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: repel the second bandit attack</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_7_text">
<text>The bandits are here. Time to tango.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_8_name">
<text>Active reconnaissance: return to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_night_shooter_part_8_text">
<text>We've taken out the bandit reinforcements and resisted the bandit attacks. I should return to Saurel and inform him about our success… and also get my reward.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: rest in peace -->
<string id="blck_val_kill_to_zombied_part_1_name">
<text>Rest in peace: kill the zombies in the cemetery</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_kill_to_zombied_part_1_text">
<text>Skew, a drunkard on the northern farm, has asked me to rid the nearby cemetery of zombified stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_kill_to_zombied_part_2_name">
<text>Rest in peace: return to Skew</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_kill_to_zombied_part_2_text">
<text>The zombies are dead… for good. I can now return to Skew.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: meet with Miklukha -->
<string id="blck_val_talk_to_miklucha_part_1_name">
<text>Meet with Miklukha</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_talk_to_miklucha_part_1_text">
<text>Miklukha, the leader of Freedom at the Outpost, has asked me to see him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: call of the Monolith -->
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_1_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: gather stalkers to disrupt the Monolith meeting</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_1_text">
<text>Miklukha has told me that a meeting between high-ranking members of the Monolith is taking place at the factory in the near future. There won't be many guards at the meeting; a good opportunity to take out their leader. Miklukha's also asked me to find a few people as backup.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_2_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: return to Miklukha</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_2_text">
<text>Miklukha has sent me a message and has told me it's time to finish preparations. The Monolith meeting is taking place soon. I should see him and discuss our plans.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_3_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: speak to Miklukha</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_3_text">
<text>We're almost at the factory. I should talk to Miklukha again.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_4_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: follow Miklukha</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_4_text">
<text>I need to follow Miklukha.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_5_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: speak to Miklukha</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_5_text">
<text>We've arrived. I should have a talk with Miklukha.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_6_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: ask the stalkers for help</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_6_text">
<text>The meeting turned out to be fake; an ambush was waiting for us at the factory. Miklukha and the others have covered me and have allowed me to slip out of the Monolith's hands, but we need to get back to base and ask Saurel to send reinforcements.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_7_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: return to the factory</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_7_text">
<text>Saurel has refused to send reinforcements to the factory, so it's up to me to save Miklukha and the others.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_8_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: search Miklukha's corpse</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_8_text">
<text>Miklukha and his group are dead. I wasn't able to save them. I need to see what Miklukha has in his backpack. Maybe I'll find something useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_9_name">
<text>Call of the Monolith: find a way to access Miklukha's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_call_part_9_text">
<text>I've retrieved Miklukha's PDA from his backpack, but it's encrypted. I need to find someone who can help me unlock it.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: shadows of the past -->
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_1_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: get to the space bubble at the factory</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_1_text">
<text>Petrovich has asked me to send the coordinates of the bubble exit to the stalkers who have gotten stuck inside. He tells me it's better if I send the coordinates myself while I'm close to the anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_2_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: send the exit coordinates</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_2_text">
<text>I'm near the anomaly. Now I can try sending the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_3_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: wait for an answer from the stalkers</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_3_text">
<text>The coordinates have been sent. I need to see if the stalkers inside have received them.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_4_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: speak to Fish</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_4_text">
<text>I know these stalkers well. I should speak with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_5_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: find out what happened from the stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_5_text">
<text>I woke up on the farm. I can't remember anything after taking a rifle butt to the head. I need to ask this stalker about what happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_6_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: speak to Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_6_text">
<text>I've most likely set Stronglav free. It'll be best not to tell any of the stalkers about this. In any case, I need to speak to Petrovich.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_7_name">
<text>Shadows of the past: speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_spatial_bubble_wound_part_7_text">
<text>Petrovich has told me to see Saurel to find out what's inside Miklukha's PDA.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: exchange -->
<string id="blck_val_wpn_vihr_search_part_1_name">
<text>Exchange: find an SR-3 Vikhr</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_wpn_vihr_search_part_1_text">
<text>The trader who can offer us two Monolith suits requires an SR-3 Vikhr rifle in return. I need to try to find one.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_wpn_vihr_search_part_2_name">
<text>Exchange: give the SR-3 Vikhr to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_wpn_vihr_search_part_2_text">
<text>I have an SR-3 Vikhr that I should hand it over to Saurel.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: easy prey -->
<string id="blck_val_hunt_dog_tail_part_1_name">
<text>Easy prey: acquire 6 blind dog tails</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunt_dog_tail_part_1_text">
<text>I need to get a hold of six blind dog tails for the hunters at the caravan.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunt_dog_tail_part_2_name">
<text>Easy prey: give the tails to the hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunt_dog_tail_part_2_text">
<text>I have all the tails. Now time to go turn them in.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: in the dead of night -->
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_1_name">
<text>In the dead of night: wait until night</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_1_text">
<text>Ratter has told me that he can find an SR-3 Vikhr rifle for me in exchange for helping him escape. I don't think there's any other way of getting that rifle. I need to help him by stealing the cage key, but first, I need to wait until Sologub goes to sleep.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_2_name">
<text>In the dead of night: steal the key from the nightstand</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_2_text">
<text>Sologlub should be asleep by now. The key's on the nightstand.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_3_name">
<text>In the dead of night: return to Ratter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_3_text">
<text>I have the key. I can now return to Ratter.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_4_name">
<text>In the dead of night: give the key to Ratter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_4_text">
<text>I need to give the key to Ratter..</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_5_name">
<text>In the dead of night: go to the meeting place</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_5_text">
<text>Ratter now has the key. I need to wait for him by the house while he escapes along with another bandit.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_6_name">
<text>In the dead of night: wait for Ratter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_6_text">
<text>Now I just have to wait for Ratter at the meeting place.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_7_name">
<text>In the dead of night: speak to Ratter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_7_text">
<text>I should speak to Ratter.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_8_name">
<text>In the dead of night: return the key back to its place</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_8_text">
<text>Ratter has successfully escaped and has told me that I can get the rifle in the morning. Until then, I should return the key.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_9_name">
<text>In the dead of night: return to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_prison_breack_part_9_text">
<text>Ratter has successfully escaped and has told me that I can get the rifle in the morning. I should now speak to Saurel.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: free time -->
<string id="blck_val_shaman_quest_talk_part_1_name">
<text>Free time: speak to Rasputin about work</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_shaman_quest_talk_part_1_text">
<text>Saurel has told me that I can't leave the Stronghold right now. Only a guide can lead me out of the area, but he's not at the Stronghold right now. While I wait for him, I might as well do some work, which I should speak to Rasputin about.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: anomalous grove -->
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_1_name">
<text>Anomalous grove: find the Kolobok artifact for Rasputin</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_1_text">
<text>Rasputin has told me that there's a Kolobok artifact in the anomalous grove, or rather, at the top of it. He's asked me to retrieve and return it.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_2_name">
<text>Anomalous grove: give the Kolobok to Rasputin</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_2_text">
<text>I have the artifact. I can now return to Rasputin.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_3_name">
<text>Anomalous grove: tell Rasputin about recent events</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_find_art_barman_part_3_text">
<text>Outside the anomalous grove, a group of bandits surrounded me and stole the Kolobok artifact. I need to inform Rasputin about this.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: a tooth for a tooth -->
<string id="blck_val_shmiga_revard_quest_part_1_name">
<text>A tooth for a tooth: retrieve the weapons from Ratter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_shmiga_revard_quest_part_1_text">
<text>Crooked has messaged me and says that Ratter is ready to give me my reward for setting him free in the form of two SR-3 Vikhr rifles.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: masquerade -->
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_1_name">
<text>Masquerade: wait for the package with the outfits</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_1_text">
<text>I've given an SR-3 Vikhr to Saurel. Now I have to wait for the delivery with the outfits.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_2_name">
<text>Masquerade: speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_2_text">
<text>Saurel has informed me that the outfit delivery has arrived. I should go see him.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_3_name">
<text>Masquerade: reconfigure the PDA with Petrovich's help</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_3_text">
<text>I have the outfit and the explosives. The last part of the disguise will be a reconfigured PDA so that Monolith will recognize me as one of their own.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_4_name">
<text>Masquerade: speak to Savage</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_4_text">
<text>Petrovich has reconfigured my PDA. Now I can speak to Savage and be on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_5_name">
<text>Masquerade: follow Savage</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_5_text">
<text>I need to follow Savage to the Monolith base.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_6_name">
<text>Masquerade: speak to Werewolf</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_6_text">
<text>The leader of the Monolith group has sent me a message and asked me to see him. Let's hope they don't see through us.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_7_name">
<text>Masquerade: plant the explosives on the second floor</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_7_text">
<text>We've arrived at the base. It's time to plant the explosives.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_8_name">
<text>Masquerade: put on the Monolith suit</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_monolit_base_part_8_text">
<text>Saurel has given me the Monolith suit. I should put it on.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: interesting proposal -->
<string id="blck_val_shaman_talk_line_part_1_name">
<text>Interesting proposal: speak to Rasputin</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_shaman_talk_line_part_1_text">
<text>Rasputin has messaged me and says that he has something to talk about. I wonder what he needs this time?…</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_shaman_talk_line_part_2_name">
<text>Interesting proposal: speak to Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_shaman_talk_line_part_2_text">
<text>Rasputin has told me about a stalker who's gone to the farm. His name is Hunter, and he needs help. I should speak to him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: pseudoflesh -->
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_1_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: find the pseudoflesh</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_1_text">
<text>I need to find the pseudoflesh.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_2_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: follow Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_2_text">
<text>Hunter has asked me to help him hunt down the pseudoflesh.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_3_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: wait for Hunter's orders</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_3_text">
<text>We've arrived at the garbage. I should wait for directions from Hunter.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_4_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: speak to Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_4_text">
<text>It seems Hunter hasn't found anyone. I should speak to him about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_5_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: follow Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_5_text">
<text>Hunter suggests that the pseudoflesh might be hiding in another part of the garbage. I need to check it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_6_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: kill the pseudoflesh</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_6_text">
<text>We've found the pseudoflesh. Time to end it.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_7_name">
<text>Pseudoflesh: speak to Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_hunter_hunting_part_7_text">
<text>The pseudoflesh is dead. I should now speak to Hunter.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: the right to choose -->
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_1_name">
<text>The right to choose: descend into the laboratory or speak to Saurel</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_1_text">
<text>Savage might be in danger. I need to help him. But I might want to speak to Saurel first.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_2_name">
<text>The right to choose: descend into the laboratory</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_2_text">
<text>I've spoken to Saurel. Now I can head into the laboratory to save Savage from the hands of the Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_3_name">
<text>The right to choose: reconfigure the PDA with Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_3_text">
<text>It seems I don't need to head into the laboratory after all, and in any case, I can't save Savage. I should see Hunter later to get out of the Stronghold, but first I should go talk to Petrovich.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_4_name">
<text>The right to choose: speak to Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_final_zastava_quest_part_4_text">
<text>I've decided not to rescue Savage; it's suicide. Saurel has told me that Hunter is ready to escort me out of the Stronghold. I should see him about that.</text>
</string>

<!-- Quest: collector -->
<string id="blck_val_petrovich_dop_quest_part_1_name">
<text>Collector: find a collection of mutant figurines for Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_petrovich_dop_quest_part_1_text">
<text>Petrovich has asked me to help him gather a collection of figurines of all mutants in the Zone. He already has a bloodsucker figurine. I need to find figurines of the following mutants: blind dog, pseudodog, boar, flesh, burer, controller, chimera, snork, and pseudogiant.</text>
</string>

</string_table>